<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H957F548B78384B06AEA32FC9B8DE4F07" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3004 EH: Kate’s Law</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3004</legis-num>
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend section 276 of the Immigration and Nationality Act relating to reentry of removed aliens.</official-title>
</form> 
<legis-body id="H63CE0E00CC2845888394FD00BB505A0E" style="OLC"> 
<section commented="no" id="H27981D13525945E889A72564036509EF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as <quote><short-title>Kate’s Law</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H99EB962396034EE0A697963FA809EA2C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Illegal reentry</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 276 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1326">8 U.S.C. 1326</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HB09FC6777C214E15BDA3C236D4026D43" style="traditional"> 
<section id="H1CD75F44F424425FAA021E1BD50BB65C"><enum>276.</enum><header>Reentry of removed alien</header>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7E0F20C58DC148AE8AD6B1291EAAF6BF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reentry after removal</header><text>Any alien who has been denied admission, excluded, deported, or removed, or who has departed the United States while an order of exclusion, deportation, or removal is outstanding, and subsequently enters, attempts to enter, crosses the border to, attempts to cross the border to, or is at any time found in the United States, shall be fined under title 18, United States Code, imprisoned not more than 2 years, or both.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HE7C714B8456B4FB6941C06293C094719"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reentry of criminal offenders</header><text>Notwithstanding the penalty provided in subsection (a), if an alien described in that subsection was convicted before such removal or departure—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA39BEECF881F47E69C37E4D15BEF8FF7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for 3 or more misdemeanors or for a felony, the alien shall be fined under title 18, United States Code, imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H3336212E323647D19D4C2F43800B162C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for a felony for which the alien was sentenced to a term of imprisonment of not less than 30 months, the alien shall be fined under such title, imprisoned not more than 15 years, or both;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H98B87AF07E6D4DA5BBCEE68C75F21587"><enum>(3)</enum><text>for a felony for which the alien was sentenced to a term of imprisonment of not less than 60 months, the alien shall be fined under such title, imprisoned not more than 20 years, or both; or</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H85B07711D36D400D825A2F61BDACC578"><enum>(4)</enum><text>for murder, rape, kidnapping, or a felony offense described in chapter 77 (relating to peonage and slavery) or 113B (relating to terrorism) of such title, or for 3 or more felonies of any kind, the alien shall be fined under such title, imprisoned not more than 25 years, or both.</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H5E4ADE7ED4DE441CA1B9CBCAC1D0F626"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reentry after repeated removal</header><text>Any alien who has been denied admission, excluded, deported, or removed 3 or more times and thereafter enters, attempts to enter, crosses the border to, attempts to cross the border to, or is at any time found in the United States, shall be fined under title 18, United States Code, imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HB96CB4158C8C4EDC803AF8BDB31F1461"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Proof of prior convictions</header><text>The prior convictions described in subsection (b) are elements of the crimes described, and the penalties in that subsection shall apply only in cases in which the conviction or convictions that form the basis for the additional penalty are—</text> 
<paragraph id="H140F50298BE84553A53300430B6804BB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>alleged in the indictment or information; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H01DEB08049CB4165B024D4BCC8DE0A7C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>proven beyond a reasonable doubt at trial or admitted by the defendant.</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H33A9E6BD67274155BCA6C913E9AC7E61"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Affirmative defenses</header><text>It shall be an affirmative defense to a violation of this section that—</text> <paragraph id="H6339308E3C414CC48FF136D9D796E20C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prior to the alleged violation, the alien had sought and received the express consent of the Secretary of Homeland Security to reapply for admission into the United States; or</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA00127F137194440885F237F84E69077"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with respect to an alien previously denied admission and removed, the alien—</text> <subparagraph id="HC8A98242DB0447929F75AE71DFDCDE60"><enum>(A)</enum><text>was not required to obtain such advance consent under the Immigration and Nationality Act or any prior Act; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1B398A44A0544382B43C410E894D7E01"><enum>(B)</enum><text>had complied with all other laws and regulations governing the alien’s admission into the United States.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H02CCB9ADDBCA4A53A72DDAD7AE40FD68"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Limitation on collateral attack on underlying removal order</header><text>In a criminal proceeding under this section, an alien may not challenge the validity of any prior removal order concerning the alien.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="HF49DFA5BB7924ADBBA5FFA84F21D7F51"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reentry of alien removed prior to completion of term of imprisonment</header><text>Any alien removed pursuant to section 241(a)(4) who enters, attempts to enter, crosses the border to, attempts to cross the border to, or is at any time found in, the United States shall be incarcerated for the remainder of the sentence of imprisonment which was pending at the time of deportation without any reduction for parole or supervised release unless the alien affirmatively demonstrates that the Secretary of Homeland Security has expressly consented to the alien’s reentry. Such alien shall be subject to such other penalties relating to the reentry of removed aliens as may be available under this section or any other provision of law.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HCFD4673604AE42BBB2DBCE7648285D81"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section and section 275, the following definitions shall apply:</text> 
<paragraph id="H8FA49D798F2C40DA8032F99459B759C9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Crosses the border to the United States</header><text>The term <term>crosses the border</term> refers to the physical act of crossing the border, regardless of whether the alien is free from official restraint.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HFB1A9CFB8EA44B54BE2B812F71DFF686"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Felony</header><text>The term <term>felony</term> means any criminal offense punishable by a term of imprisonment of more than 1 year under the laws of the United States, any State, or a foreign government.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD0FD0F338B0E4E4894833365D10DF820"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Misdemeanor</header><text>The term <term>misdemeanor</term> means any criminal offense punishable by a term of imprisonment of not more than 1 year under the applicable laws of the United States, any State, or a foreign government.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H56D47A47EF644372AC0509D279008E53"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Removal</header><text>The term <term>removal</term> includes any denial of admission, exclusion, deportation, or removal, or any agreement by which an alien stipulates or agrees to exclusion, deportation, or removal.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H730EA8BB28C645FA91C0E1407ED18DFF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, and any commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section> </legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20170629" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives June 29, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> <endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> </bill> 

