<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H0A8FBE42D3984C1EB166461B7836B302" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4231 IH: Better Evaluation of Science and Technology Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4231</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171102">November 2, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000190">Mr. Norman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001177">Mr. McClintock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001195">Mr. Mooney of West Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000588">Mr. Pearce</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000552">Mr. Gohmert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001297">Mr. Buck</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001290">Mr. Brat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000372">Mr. Allen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001071">Mr. Jody B. Hice of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 5, United States Code, to provide requirements for agency decision making based on
			 science.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H84122AB8A1F845F8924CF9D5D7174452" style="OLC">
 <section id="H765C052EA2D54CACB26286159F091251" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Better Evaluation of Science and Technology Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>BEST Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HF67F9193D5D841489290B754ECF3D608"><enum>2.</enum><header>Use of scientific information in rule making</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 553 of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2104A6818D8F42599FFF328D8DD57885" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H44C3C8A13DAB46DA8033C2036DC1CD03"><enum>(f)</enum><text>To the extent that an agency makes a decision based on science when issuing a rule under this section, the agency shall use scientific information, technical procedures, measures, methods, protocols, methodologies, or models, employed in a manner consistent with the best available science, and shall consider as applicable—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC83A522CFD1A4152B84B11F9BE83AE7C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the extent to which the scientific information, technical procedures, measures, methods, protocols, methodologies, or models employed to generate the information are reasonable for and consistent with the intended use of the information;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H02BBCC93F7CE4829B906DEB529AAE200"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the extent to which the information is relevant for use by the head of the agency in making a decision related to issuing the rule;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBEDDD18957C749CBB92AA94E91583AF0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the degree of clarity and completeness with which the data, assumptions, methods, quality assurance, and analyses employed to generate the information are documented;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9C6775F29FFF4AAF81310A798B4C70F5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the extent to which the variability and uncertainty in the information, or in the procedures, measures, methods, protocols, methodologies, or models, are evaluated and characterized; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD97D5B4A543A45E89B71918EEB5C4671"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the extent of independent verification or peer review of the information or of the procedures, measures, methods, protocols, methodologies, or models.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H91FA063A07C54E468D7D12E0A3D18F62"><enum>(g)</enum><text>An agency shall make a decision described in subsection (f) based on the weight of the scientific evidence.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H17420C642FCE40A9A792312EE417F522"><enum>(h)</enum><text>Each agency shall make available to the public—</text> <paragraph id="HB5147F4EF58C43A784581A01598D1D4B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all notices, determinations, findings, rules, consent agreements, and orders of the head of the agency in connection with a rule;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC6C444D9D5414E5C8819498E33D82ACB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a nontechnical summary of each risk evaluation conducted in connection with a rule; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF44F820634594A6F854E889123A8C755"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a list of the studies considered by the agency in carrying out each risk evaluation described in paragraph (2), along with the results of those studies.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


