<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H5084F5E3874B48548522473E560FFFD2" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2952 IH: Foster Youth Mentoring Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2952</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170620">June 20, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Al Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To support the establishment or expansion and operation of programs using a network of public and
			 private community entities to provide mentoring for children in foster
			 care.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H8DA6DF71291F48EA977F49C523668700" style="OLC">
 <section id="HDC2A9AE82F1F455AB8F457E396FFA58C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Foster Youth Mentoring Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HDCED87900941460F809DFADC8936C2B8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text>
 <paragraph id="HDABB98333B1841FE9DCF2CD2C18742B7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Research shows that mentors make a difference in children’s lives. At-risk youth who have mentors are 55 percent more likely to enroll in college. Students who meet regularly with their mentors are 52 percent less likely than their peers to skip a day of school. Youth who have mentors are also 130 percent more likely to hold a leadership position.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7C0972AFDF524B8D9FDB76E1CD9B8345"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Children that have mentors have improved relationships with adults, fewer disciplinary referrals, and more confidence to achieve their goals.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF2B16AA6FC834AE98A55171CDA1E927C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In 2014, 415,129 children were in foster care. Of those children 62,108 were between the ages of 10 and 13, and 120,567 were between the ages of 14 and 18.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDEDF8A6A24EC41049CEF62ADAD46F345"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Mentoring programs that serve foster children are unique and require additional considerations, including specialized training and support necessary to provide for consistent, long-term relationships for children in care.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1EAA5F5E75E545DFA92949827232E2AE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Mentoring programs can be used as an effective preventative or intervention strategy to support positive outcomes for foster youth.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HAD369FFC579E442381F933B0E1D3915C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Programs for mentoring children in foster care</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subpart 2 of part B of title IV of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/629">42 U.S.C. 629</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5F21EB4C0BC640F39693CCA7A0E147C4" style="OLC">
				<section id="H9F9F85315592405DAC1E70728A938A54"><enum>439A.</enum><header>Programs for mentoring children in foster care</header>
 <subsection id="HCF7E891155434CB5A4ADB88769C0CF46"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>It is the purpose of this section to authorize the Secretary to make grants to eligible applicants to support the establishment or expansion and operation of programs using a network of public and private community entities to provide mentoring for children in foster care.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2DF47E844F1B4B7DB143219625082ADA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H94756D3E6535472BADE5C863D7EF12B4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Children in foster care</header><text>The term <term>children in foster care</term> means children who have been removed from the custody of their biological or adoptive parents by a State child welfare agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H50DF6C123CDC480BA29CC375092C1A60"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Mentoring</header><text>The term <term>mentoring</term> means a structured, managed program—</text> <subparagraph id="H3B421ABA1F244B5281559F6843E6BE1E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in which children are appropriately matched with screened and trained adult volunteers for consistent relationships;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H315859F5F7E84E8082E35E2EEF3F6B70"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that can include direct one-on-one, group, peer, or a combination of these types of mentoring services;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3AF799C5F344449A89B402260BDFAC85"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that involves meetings and activities on a regular basis; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8899014AA5B4CB2983F294B1EA0FC2F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>that is intended to meet, in part, the child’s need for involvement with a caring and supportive adult who provides a positive role model.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1ADD326484294E7BB6D47001865AE971"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H25F7A94EF9964BF7A21AF4C416A62685"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a nonprofit organization;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H46F7C89B65174E61A4B6915AE95E7F4B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a State child welfare agency;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41968378FB284F9BB2C68DC3F4A845A4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a local educational agency;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H101010B936DF451A989FE9C4601812C8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an Indian tribe or a tribal organization; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2DD0F19CD735476C8F21FDAB2B0FCCC0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a faith-based organization.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD9C462CABAE24E8281EFBD91E436A07C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant program</header>
 <paragraph id="HFFF8982101C84803A9D1EF2912808D26"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out a program to award grants to eligible entities to support the establishment or expansion and operation of programs using networks of public and private community entities to provide mentoring for children in foster care.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAE467E87CFAF4A1982FF1599F19986EF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application requirements</header><text>To be eligible for a grant under paragraph (1), an eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary an application containing the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2F89BBDD1A5E4B39B2D2A364C7E9B45A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Program design</header><text>A description of the proposed program to be carried out using amounts provided under this grant, including—</text>
 <clause id="H8B2793BF77264E16A579DB85A327C829"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of mentor-child matches proposed to be established and maintained annually under the program;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1DDD472B2E0D465CBED7E1767068DA36"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the targeted age range of youth to be served by the program;</text> </clause><clause id="HF1BFC780F47F4C56A74FD32CA936A2A7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>such information as the Secretary may require concerning the methods to be used to recruit, screen, support, and oversee individuals participating as mentors, and to evaluate outcomes for participating children, including information necessary to demonstrate compliance with requirements established by the Secretary for the program; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H830A0806BA8B48B9ADB0F4A151C650CE"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary may require.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B9BBA03BFCB47B0A17DCF882A88D58B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Training</header><text>An assurance that all mentors covered under the program will receive intensive and ongoing training in the following areas:</text>
 <clause id="HDD573CC3D0E9463BB1A9EA7D3C0F4033"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Child development, including the importance of bonding.</text> </clause><clause id="H7CD3885ED441407EA398DF88EBB654C8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Family dynamics, including the effects of domestic violence.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H794CC483DD914456AF2A4B85229F88FB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The foster care system and foster care principles and practices.</text> </clause><clause id="HB135E057A659464EB093A8C494A7E976"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Recognizing and reporting child abuse and neglect.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAAFDB62D0713453487ECD4921AF1CD2A"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Confidentiality requirements for working with children in foster care.</text> </clause><clause id="H6DFF215B151D457B85A07926023199AC"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Working in coordination with the child welfare system.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H748F9C4D29EB484B916828FCDCB63942"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Other matters related to working with children in foster care.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB070C14CB28F457C8D72095708DC6626"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Screening</header><text>An assurance that all mentors covered under the program are appropriately screened and have demonstrated a willingness to comply with all aspects of the mentor program, including—</text>
 <clause id="H176DD94FB2A8408DAC499D04977FE907"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a description of the methods to be used to conduct criminal background checks on all prospective mentors; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H05CF1604D333491293835682CB2691A7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a description of the methods to be used to ensure that the mentors are willing and able to serve as a mentor on a long-term, consistent basis.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C7337CD72AF4C4C90A2C0262B0F61AF"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Community consultation; coordination with other programs</header><text>A demonstration that, in developing and implementing the program, the eligible entity will, to the extent feasible and appropriate—</text>
 <clause id="H5F3C6577B3DE469399E58B0A5BDEF02E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>consult with—</text> <subclause id="HDEAC10CA03BC47EDA335CF85F8DB4AD0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>public and private community entities, including religious organizations and Indian tribal organizations and urban Indian organizations; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H94239B37269547EAB464EF30CC9076BC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>family members of children who may be potential clients of the program;</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H75EB0526AE0946DBA304BB81DF77A1F9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>coordinate the mentoring program and the eligible entity's activities with other Federal, State, and local programs serving children and youth; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H06F6A21F215A42F58DB16F8C0631D0C0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>consult and coordinate with appropriate Federal, State, and local corrections, workforce development, and substance abuse and mental health agencies.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3DF3CF45FA8F45C8BECA05151C0D3C74"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Equal access for local service providers</header><text>An assurance that public and private entities and nonprofit community organizations, including religious organizations and Indian organizations, will be eligible to participate on an equal basis.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D7AA756ED6248F988208E472ED989A2"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Records, reports, and audits</header><text>An agreement that the eligible entity will maintain such records, make such reports, and cooperate with such reviews or audits as the Secretary may find necessary for purposes of oversight of project activities and expenditures.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3929120FD6E84B5F8A721B04395FC876"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>An agreement that the eligible entity will cooperate fully with the Secretary’s ongoing and final evaluation of the program under the plan, by means including providing the Secretary access to the program, the program’s staff, program-related records and documents, and each public or private community entity receiving funding under the plan.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E03BB2C84B945708C643B1B8547850C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Considerations in awarding grants</header><text>In awarding grants under this subsection, the Secretary shall take into consideration—</text> <subparagraph id="H754935EEC2F242F2ACFE745735F25864"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the overall qualifications and capacity of the eligible entity and its partners to effectively carry out a mentoring program under this subsection;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C24BE0253C84159BF3837C27EB47EA8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the level and quality of training provided to mentors under the program;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE77F2F14FC3A4DF78E1F85C04F3F312A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>evidence of coordination of the program with the social services and education programs of the State or political subdivision;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD260456BA230434DA9EEC638ABFE538F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the ability of the eligible entity to provide supervision and support for mentors under the program and the youth served by such mentors;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H111A798693A849F79E251B494A5E6F45"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the number of children in foster care served by the State or political subdivision; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E5EEEE27F40421C98E427E3F9B0CEFA"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any other factors that the Secretary determines to be significant with respect to the need for, or the potential success of, carrying out a mentoring program under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8FD371D307C549FE94A45B0001C7F2B8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under this subsection may use such funds to—</text> <subparagraph id="H0062461F475240FE9BDDEE7D57F995FA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop and carry out a training program and ongoing support for mentors;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7C308D942C044A3895665033C6AD703"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recruit mentors for children in foster care; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6BF8828C2D7247D49AEE60E8CF37F11D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide activities that will help the development of a child in foster care who is participating in the program.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7137A58552F462491E69A5544E428D9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Grant amount</header><text>In awarding grants under this subsection, the Secretary shall scale grants to account for the eligible entity's annual budget and capacity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8AF4C66FFA974A77AC6C93065DB6E4A0"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to Congress a report that includes the following with respect to the year involved:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4AAE1B0DFA1B4125955D44C38208D72C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of the number of programs receiving grant awards under this subsection.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9BACE44D36484D3FAB199A445AD4D39D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of the number of mentors who serve in the programs described in subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA601656EA28F48FCAE5CC671F5D1199E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A description of—</text> <clause id="H701A1439CFB24ED892765E550ED265C0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of children in foster care who participated in mentoring programs funded by the grant funds under this subsection;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H91D01E97CA02418286EFC487E9560B47"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>data on the academic achievement of the children in mentoring programs funded by the grant funds under this subsection; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8F91FBF2FAAA4E8DAD718748821DF491"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the number of children in foster care on waiting lists for such mentoring programs.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H985ADD0F39A14277B86C41019799E713"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Any other information that the Secretary determines to be relevant to the evaluation of the program under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7FD179F840C74F0198872D88A8181ADD"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section—</text> <subparagraph id="H49E9F8E8CFAB489ABD5724739FBBD938"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 and 2019; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0FFF5706C58D4DA5A238FB6797BEB3DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such sums as may be necessary for each succeeding fiscal year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section></legis-body></bill> 

