<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H72EE314414E344FA946953DFECB18AB4" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4509 IH: No Congressional First Class Flights Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4509</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171201">December 1, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001294">Mr. Blum</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the use of official funds for airline accommodations for Members of Congress which are
			 not coach-class accommodations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HF69400C225AB4304BC0DD48405E2D623" style="OLC">
 <section id="H6F7D2968AF364437A9216972D7750491" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Congressional First Class Flights Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HB9E7AFAADB7C470BA4E466FADFF552E1" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibiting use of funds for official travel expenses of Members of Congress for airline accommodations other than coach-class</header> <subsection id="H953ED25E4FED4421B072553F4C0F99D4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No funds appropriated or otherwise made available during a fiscal year for the official travel expenses of a Member of Congress may be used for airline accommodations which are not coach-class accommodations, unless the use of other than coach-class accommodations is necessary to accommodate a medical disability or other special need.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4CAC87F2145944D892AAEA56B8FB3023"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coach-Class Accommodations Defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>coach-class accommodations</term> means the basic class of accommodation by airlines that is normally the lowest fare offered regardless of airline terminology used, and (as referred to by airlines) may include tourist class or economy class, as well as single class when the airline offers only one class of accommodations to all travelers.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H02C12CB36FD347C49F493805EDFC0687"><enum>3.</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives (with respect to Representatives in, and Delegates and the Resident Commissioner to, the Congress) and the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate (with respect to Senators) shall each promulgate such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this Act.</text>
 </section><section id="HE81B2C70C7DE48109D1D438B00D90216"><enum>4.</enum><header>Member of Congress defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>Member of Congress</term> means a Senator or a Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress.</text> </section><section id="H600CB5EAE04946718107CD61EAE37D08"><enum>5.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2019 and each succeeding fiscal year.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


