<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H674383C59D4642C29FCC6DA4BD984CCB" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3523 IH: To require the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a study and submit a report on filing requirements under the Universal Service Fund programs.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3523</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170727">July 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young of Alaska</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a study and submit a report on
			 filing requirements under the Universal Service Fund programs.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HCA16DFC1D0334EE783AC95C993ADC7D9" style="OLC">
		<section id="H1B4380C4641E49BF9DAD893D4284265A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Study and report on filing requirements under Universal Service Fund programs</header>
 <subsection id="H2D143DFCB5ED461EB3CDA858DEB7F383"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="H02BA2E237062492BB2BAEB1E0BF1DF38"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>Administrative Procedure Act</term> means subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1C667538FF90421D9C598CF7B1FCE980"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Communications Commission;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0DDC441A165A4E88AFD2AF9FB82B2D32"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>covered carrier</term> means an eligible telecommunications carrier or service provider that receives universal service support under sections 214(e) and 254 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/214">47 U.S.C. 214(e)</external-xref> and 254) for the provision of service under a Universal Service Fund program; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3D5E0B847535454498395C2F70E6B276"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>Universal Service Fund program</term> means each program of the Commission set forth under part 54 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor thereto, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H97B998E2EB5A42B4B3731AFDE0DBB9C5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Connect America Fund set forth under subpart D of that part;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HECE86DA442A34689A97251AD6614E76D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Lifeline program set forth under subpart E of that part;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2A34B345B6A419186A5C2993A91575D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the E-Rate program set forth under subpart F of that part;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H717739444F4C4320AC4BF6C0DE8547F5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Rural Health Care program set forth under subpart G of that part;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF364C69E98E24A209FBAAC7EB767169A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Remote Areas Fund set forth under subpart J of that part;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3AD98598748242B1ABFB8D82A3FE2037"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Connect America Fund Broadband Loop Support program set forth under subpart K of that part;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B7D9A8A5F6940DBB694C3DC419F2F2A"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the Mobility Fund set forth under subpart L of that part; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA648EBCF49114418A2B068FAFE3C27A2"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the High Cost Loop Support for Rate-of-Return Carriers program set forth under subpart M of that part.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H32CFD55EB43E43E2B28532E082147317"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study and report</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study and submit to the Commission, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report, which shall include—</text>
 <paragraph id="H87B91EB572C24887BE934BEEE654598D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an analysis of the filing requirements for covered carriers participating in a Universal Service Fund program, including any filings required by the Universal Service Administrative Company;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE31DF7C359D7404CA4A529ED2648F6A7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an analysis of the financial impact of those filing requirements on covered carriers participating in a Universal Service Fund program; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC7C87BA6F734AD1AEA86DF65323EAEA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommendations, if any, on how to consolidate redundant filing requirements for covered carriers participating in a Universal Service Fund program.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H347FA297F42E4C7584C6B9E870266D9A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header>
 <paragraph id="H91E7065BF72643FE9EC7C99C84482244"><enum>(1)</enum><header>New or ongoing rulemaking</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (3), not later than 60 days after the date on which the report is submitted under subsection (b), the Commission shall—</text>
					<subparagraph id="HDDB6192D94EF4955AD995DEB25697F8E"><enum>(A)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H346E7E7C67564BF1AE70BE6AB3E3588F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>initiate a rulemaking to consolidate redundant filing requirements for covered carriers participating in a Universal Service Fund program; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF27F23F3E9154E2BA9020684DF6F7374" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>incorporate into the rulemaking under clause (i), and as part of that rulemaking seek comment on, the recommendations described in subsection (b)(3), if any, except to the extent that doing so would violate the requirements of the Administrative Procedure Act; or</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9A6242A1FBB4B31AB8A8C48DA7FE63B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>incorporate into an ongoing rulemaking relating to consolidating redundant filing requirements of the Commission, and as part of that rulemaking seek comment on, the recommendations described in subsection (b)(3), if any, except to the extent that doing so would violate the requirements of the Administrative Procedure Act.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE83F272C872E4722A5D9AB11B94DC14E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waste, fraud, and abuse</header><text>In a rulemaking in which the Commission is required under paragraph (1) to seek comment on the recommendations described in subsection (b)(3), if any, the Commission shall also seek comment on and consider whether the benefit of each recommendation is outweighed by any potential increased risk of waste, fraud, and abuse in the Universal Service Fund program affected by the recommendation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H23C2A2D016BE4F8D869F31F0443DCC98"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Previous rulemaking</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply if, on or before the date on which the report is submitted under subsection (b), the Commission completes a rulemaking to consolidate redundant filing requirements for covered carriers participating in a Universal Service Fund program.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


