<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HDCF02669BE694E4AAD7CE4E845598BC0" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1509 IH: Better Informing Veterans’ Healthcare Decisions Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1509</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170310">March 10, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000170">Mr. O'Rourke</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000387">Mr. Knight</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to post at certain
			 locations the average national wait times for veterans to receive an
			 appointment for health care at medical facilities of the Department of
			 Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H20AA93EAEBD84470B8519BD6A77B6CE8" style="OLC">
 <section id="H0E6663FFA4804A32AC504A0DA35DDEFE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Better Informing Veterans’ Healthcare Decisions Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H51E8292B5E094488AC74AF597AD9649E" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Posting of average national wait times for health care appointments and average processing times of disability compensation claims and appeals</header> <subsection id="H27D30A39F0624CFAA3B3362933CC5E9A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings; sense of Congress</header> <paragraph id="H341856DBFCCF463181A263B9B76452E8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCD937CE69A5D4DDEA6A761F7DE09AAC7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to the Suicide Data Report, 2012, of the Department of Veterans Affairs, 22 veterans commit suicide every day.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H189C5767D1A0407BB886F20DE134A071"><enum>(B)</enum><text>According to estimates of the Department, only approximately five of these 22 veterans are enrolled in the mental health care system of the Department.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7EAFFC4440E4F7193CD2BD78FE82F0D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <subparagraph id="H7A4550C4CD91447CB42042EBA58E3CC7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Department of Veterans Affairs must be more urgent and effective in its approach to addressing veteran suicide and providing veterans access to mental health care; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HECF1BC8856E143B2ACAB3D27C15CE124"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress urges the Department to ensure that preventing veteran suicide and providing veterans access to mental health care is the top reform priority of the Department.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3A333F646D504E5AB2093273D414334E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Provision of information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and on a monthly basis thereafter, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2630A9DC1AB147AFA76CACEDED1527B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine, with respect to the one-year period before the date of the determination—</text> <subparagraph id="H636B129618DD485186457968DECF519D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the average national wait times (in days) for a veteran enrolled in the health care system established under section 1705(a) of title 38, United States Code—</text>
 <clause id="H48FB7628BC2142708E3DEC921CC26375"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to receive an appointment for mental health care at a medical facility of the Department of Veterans Affairs; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8F6BA7C2634C42C69BCE24707DB8852A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to receive an appointment for primary health care at such a facility;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H993D1C245D0245928D115B691CAA72A3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the average claims processing time of the Secretary with respect to claims for disability compensation under chapter 11 of such title 38; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5EE28D34AE664555A65840881BC9A9D2"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the average appeals processing time of the Secretary to decide an appeal to such a claim for disability compensation; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3185746C07E94286B204EF1401B305F9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide the Secretary of Defense with such information determined under paragraph (1).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCC1829C6DB9844B89E26C384D90ABBDC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Posting of information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall place in a conspicuous location at each career counselor or career assistance advisor office a sign that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8913028CECC84259B555A94FCE378498"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is not less than 18 inches tall by 24 inches wide; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1E28F350909B49DB998E754159A32D07"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is continuously updated to display the most current information received by the Secretary pursuant to subsection (b)(2).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC3CE7E2D5EC94A03B6689E7DA783BAB4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H567FA9A0A46A478DAAFA4C762552DAD5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>appeals processing time</term> means, with respect to a veteran filing an appeal to a decision of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs denying a claim for disability compensation under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/11">chapter 11</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, the period beginning on the date on which the claimant files a notice of disagreement and ending on the date on which the claimant is informed of the decision to such notice of disagreement.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4874013B16024A0593702AE442B7C52B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>claims processing time</term> means, with respect to a veteran filing a claim for disability compensation under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/11">chapter 11</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, the period beginning on the date on which the claim is originally received by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and ending on the date on which the Secretary informs the claimant of the decision.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1B4A63F2944A4B5D8B1A4E9A6126D39C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>wait time</term> means, with respect to a veteran receiving an appointment for health care at a medical facility of the Department of Veterans Affairs, the period beginning on the date on which the veteran first requests such appointment and ending on the date on which such appointment occurs.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


