<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H98F7405D5E7E47BF8889319FE366794D" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3545 IH: Overdose Prevention and Patient Safety Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3545</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170728">July 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001151">Mr. Murphy of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001181">Mr. Meehan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000586">Mr. Renacci</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001190">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to protect the confidentiality of substance use disorder
			 patient records.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H5CF70DC032A0438D93EE37E9ABA4407D" style="OLC">
 <section id="HECE88593DCDB4374BB9BE52D63A4FEA2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Overdose Prevention and Patient Safety Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H5E2ED82A443D44CABFFDA6C84F86404C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Confidentiality of records</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 543 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290dd-2">42 U.S.C. 290dd–2</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA5E16F3FB11B4619A10ED7F3B06C0694"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <subparagraph id="H8595BECB79AD45B6867BCE0599FD1660"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>The content</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to paragraph (3), the content</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HACB4FFC2BFD9458591C2B225CB374238"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>Whether</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to paragraph (3), whether</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB45C41987FF45618A181CE26F628499"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H21815C76EA0A45738086879AA03D60CA" style="OLC">
						<paragraph id="HF0CE4169FBD34A6D939CF49515A3F17A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception</header>
 <subparagraph id="H1118A055C7E84EF8A2339675306316D3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a use or disclosure of the content of a record referred to in subsection (a) for purposes of treatment, payment, or health care operations, paragraphs (1) and (2), as applicable, and regulations issued under subsection (g), including any such regulations pertaining to redisclosure limitations, shall not apply, and the provisions of section 164.506 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation, shall apply with respect to such use or disclosure of such content by an entity in the same manner and to the same extent as such provisions apply with respect to the use or disclosure of protected health information by a covered entity.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H868D0440D2FC4D959411CC26F125B3F4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, the terms <quote>treatment</quote>, <quote>payment</quote>, <quote>health care operations</quote>, and <quote>protected health information</quote> have the meaning given such terms in section 164.501 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation, and the term <quote>covered entity</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 160.103 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD90A4B0A9DE24483BA76C1DD925C8476"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by amending subsection (c) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5DD3EFC850834C36924E32926DB0280D" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H68419E4270C84E13B3ABE0070BD2421D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of records in criminal proceedings</header> <paragraph id="H93F6F79BF2504D1BACAE94BBA12B72BA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as authorized by a court order granted under subsection (b)(2)(C), no record referred to in subsection (a) may be used to initiate or substantiate any criminal charges against a patient or to conduct any investigation of a patient.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H81C0BC8119234D3AB9C4CC26987A3162"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional protections</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a use or disclosure of a record referred to in subsection (a) for purposes of treatment, payment, or health care operations as provided for under subsection (b), no further disclosure or redisclosure of such record is allowed to initiate or substantiate any criminal charges against a patient or to conduct any investigation of a patient except as authorized by a court order granted under subsection (b)(2)(C) of this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H66B11FE6F35E4EB1BB88B3C14D665988"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exclusionary effect and dismissal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any record referred to in subsection (a) that has been used or disclosed to initiate or substantiate any criminal charges against a patient or to conduct any investigation of a patient in violation of paragraph (1) or (2), shall be excluded from evidence in any proposed or actual proceedings relating to such criminal charges or investigation and absent good cause shown shall result in the automatic dismissal of any proceedings for which the content of the record was offered.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


