<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H26A08491F5A847E89F6A26D54AECDE72" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4166 IH: To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow all employees of a firm to be counted as a single shareholder toward the shareholder limit of an S corporation.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4166</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171027">October 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001172">Mr. Smith of Nebraska</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow all employees of a firm to be counted as a
			 single shareholder toward the shareholder limit of an S corporation.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HAA36DBB0C6FC46BFBFC78EA5A93EC402" style="OLC">
		<section id="H9E9B8DC4D1FE421C909BF4725A8B03F9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Employees of a firm counted as a single shareholder toward shareholder limit of S corporation</header>
 <subsection id="H1347E5FE2739440FA6E2ED8C55596608"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (c) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1361">section 1361</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCAFB62F2F4824D018A451FA6CDF23830" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="HB819A70A7E2544DDAC5E5DC7B92B7F46"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Employees treated as one shareholder</header>
 <subparagraph id="H8C5ACC42137E4FCC9A8E3A1B9EBCC43C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of subsection (b)(1)(A), in the case of a corporation which has only employee shareholders, there shall be treated as one shareholder all employees (and their estates) of a corporation and any wholly owned business entities (as determined by the Secretary) of such corporation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10AEB1DF75894F6DA6098AB0ACAC97B2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Employee defined</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph—</text> <clause id="H86A06B7AECAA46A18179B48B9C5F7B74"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term “employee” means any individual (whether a resident alien, nonresident alien, or citizen) that would be an employee described under section 3121(d) (1) or (2).</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFAE5702FC3874CF58D37572EA7D36E43"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Certain determinations with respect to spouse disregarded</header><text>In making the determination whether a corporation has only employee shareholders, any current ownership in stock by a spouse of an employee by reason of a State community property law or other similar Federal, State, or foreign country law, shall be disregarded.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD3BC0745F7EF47C09801BD3102859E99"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception to nonresident shareholder prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (C) of section 1361(b)(1) of such Code is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC7AA6E43761541BEA2A956A626538129" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H4345B2D87F3644A9A6B1F3ABA1659C48"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have a nonresident alien as a shareholder (except for a nonresident alien that is a shareholder by reason of subsection (c)(7) or a nonresident alien spouse of an employee which is a shareholder in a corporation described in subsection (c)(7)), and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H28DB3CED52F743F4B0E8F0A57427D143"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Withholding with respect to nonresident aliens</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1373 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF09F63064CFE4CA4BF7C4AD0F59AB132" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HC804443D6FA2491E9A05775D0E5D19A7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Withholding with respect to nonresident aliens</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The principles of sections 1441 and 1446 shall apply to income allocable to, and distributions to, a nonresident alien shareholder of an S corporation (allowed by reason of section 1361(b)(1)(C)). The Secretary may prescribe regulations to carry out the purposes of this subsection.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H105B9089012D41BC9760CEB711E00DDA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Defining items of income for purposes of withholding tax on nonresident aliens</header><text>Subsection (b) of section 1441 of such Code is amended by inserting before the period at the end of the first sentence the following: <quote>, and any items of income described in section 1366(a) allocable to a nonresident alien that is an S Corporation shareholder by reason of section 1361(c)(7)</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB7CA8ED8AF854CDEB1CC69B70981351A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


