<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H28F877440F7B4549958E851B114D005A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1736 IH: To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to improve the process for inspections of device establishments and for granting export certifications.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1736</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170327">March 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001275">Mr. Bucshon</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001284">Mrs. Brooks of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001251">Mr. Butterfield</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to improve the process for inspections of device establishments and for granting export certifications.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4B386864FFFC4EABA8F90A6AFDF676A4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7028671EA9E34DBDA1CB2BA59700AE95" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds as follows:</text> <paragraph id="H6E6779BE5DF84ABF967719B2ED7DCF2B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>There is a lack of transparency and consistency concerning inspections by the Food and Drug Administration of medical device establishments around the world, which leads to inefficiencies and inconsistencies and undermines confidence in United States standards.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC30E8324985F4D34BDF3BB8C954A41ED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Inspections by the Food and Drug Administration of foreign device establishments are often conducted more efficiently than inspections of domestic device establishments.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF9B9B57A7D4A40DE8A2E55B29378A062"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The frequency and nature of inspections of device establishments are not consistently risk-based, and a comprehensive, transparent, risk-based approach to inspections would result in greater focus on the more significant risks to public health while reducing the burdens on establishments with a strong track record of compliance.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC83ED8C6226E4840B87EFC55E85A5510"><enum>(4)</enum><text>There is a lack of transparency and consistency among United States-based regional inspection offices with respect to the frequency of inspections of device establishments and the activities and concerns that trigger for-cause inspections of such establishments.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8F2FA09F377148FD918F76BD64A106C3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Greater transparency concerning the timing and nature of routine inspections of device establishments would improve the quality and efficiency of the inspection process.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H61212413A66D4FEFBDA1470445C8435A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Enhancing communications before, during, and after inspections in which deficiencies are identified, would assist the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the device industry in maintaining the safety and effectiveness of devices.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H446B72BA18EE442B888C622DEED3E6B7"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Guidance for device establishments is necessary to provide transparency and consistency concerning inspection-related communications.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD9412852B44D42C7BF8C3DF930871D08"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Enhanced training opportunities for device establishment investigators would improve the consistency and efficiency of the device inspection process.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H912A488ABFFA4CB490385A2621EC8073"><enum>(9)</enum><text>There is a lack of transparency in the export certification process with respect to device establishments for which FDA Form 483 has been used to document issues noticed during an inspection conducted pursuant to section 704 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/374">21 U.S.C. 374</external-xref>) or establishments that have received Warning Letters in connection with such an inspection, and between domestic and foreign establishments, resulting in devices that are lawfully marketed for United States patients being denied certification for marketing in other countries.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5D87293808384169B02ECDC26957780E"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Device establishments that have attempted to address deficiencies identified by inspections carried out by the Food and Drug Administration lack sufficient opportunities to confirm that such corrective actions are appropriate.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H8D4C514821E1491AAC92E5E748A3F436"><enum>2.</enum><header>Risk-based inspections for devices</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Paragraph (2) of section 510(h) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360">21 U.S.C. 360(h)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8623DD70B7BE437BBA82771BBC535FEA" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="HEB15FFFDA882458A8ACDF252BDECDC07"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Risk-based schedule for devices</header> 
<subparagraph id="H29D7C794784640F5B65E3FEA18AA633C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through one or more officers or employees duly designated by the Secretary, shall inspect establishments described in paragraph (1) that are engaged in the manufacture, propagation, compounding, or processing of a device or devices (referred to in this subsection as <quote>device establishments</quote>) in accordance with one risk-based inspection schedule established by the Secretary, applied consistently across regional offices.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5AF5F614C2304E5B9B1693622EB6E1F7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Factors and considerations</header><text>In establishing the risk-based schedule under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall—</text> 
<clause id="H3D338EB2DF48409D81E7145C9B81ED9F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>apply, to the extent applicable for device establishments, the factors identified in paragraph (4); and</text></clause> <clause id="HBD736F7FCFC9456586A35D8C054CB2A3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>consider the participation of the device establishment, as applicable, in international device audit programs in which the United States participates or the United States recognizes for purposes of inspecting.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="H2F6A0D23282E4E1995729C13C2F0180D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Improvements to inspections process for device establishments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 704 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/374">21 U.S.C. 374</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H16962ABBB6D141F59620D9A10BC3CB8A" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HD947C2C48A85485281A1B916879DA354"><enum>(h)</enum> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD744E58F900943BD872C0AE3964D1B8E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary shall adopt a uniform process and uniform standards applicable to inspections of domestic and foreign device establishments. Such process shall include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4D768D1463DC4FC6B1900D20EFEF4100" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>notifying the owner, operator, or agent in charge of the establishment of the type and nature of the inspection;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H00B13879CE1C444AB21DFF98B8736262" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>announcing the inspection the establishment within a reasonable time before such inspection;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8008FB3634E84C14A738B7F4C2DE2245" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the case of inspections other than for-cause inspections, providing a reasonable estimate of the timeframe for the inspection, an opportunity for advance communications between the officers or employees carrying out the inspection under subsection (a)(1) and the owner, operator, or agent in charge of the establishment concerning appropriate working hours during the inspection, and, to the extent feasible, advance notice of records that will be requested in order to expedite the inspection; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF260F21E55A14A4F963E62454908973F" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>daily communications with the owner, operator, or agent in charge of the establishment regarding inspection status, which may be recorded by either party with advance notice.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4897403B89514DC4BA6E052428059918" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In the case of device establishments that have received a report pursuant to subsection (b), and for which the owner, operator, or agent in charge of such establishment submits a timely response to such report that includes a request for feedback to the actions proposed in such response, the Secretary shall provide nonbinding feedback regarding such proposed actions within 45 days of receipt of such request.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H880F287986AD42D88D814FE12CE74694" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Nothing in this subsection limits the authority of the Secretary to conduct inspections otherwise permitted under this Act in order to ensure compliance with this Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8F55877F987C46CDA6AACC07135BFB2F" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H78CC5BB688A543D5ABA76EEC3E2E4461"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Secretary shall issue draft guidance that—</text> <clause id="H1C840227629D437F84D02E7ABD0EC84F" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>specifies how the Food and Drug Administration will implement the process described in paragraph (1) and the requirements described in paragraph (2);</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5CB7DAB23E1D4BC4A390BBB1C1A2FB80" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provides for standardized templates for communications described in such paragraphs;</text></clause> <clause id="HB2FC35ED66744C5D9B88936EFB77D0CE" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>establishes a standard timeframe over consecutive days that is applicable to both domestic and foreign inspections, to which each inspector shall adhere unless an investigator can identify to the establishment a reason that more time is needed; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA5ACBBB69A664F4EB636AA8EFA313619" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>identifies practices for investigators and device establishments to facilitate the continuity of inspections.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7663E1642A1549A3B0133196329BA567" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this subsection, after notice and opportunity for public comment on the draft guidance described in subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall issue final guidance consistent with this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="HA561D3B63DB24D358E3F457AD185CF33"><enum>4.</enum><header>Certificates to foreign governments for devices</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subsection (e)(4) of section 801 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/381">21 U.S.C. 381(e)(4)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HC1664634FB6A40FAA63896779F2D00F3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC8BFB585E2FE4BE8BA11BD598371FA69" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="H1F1C7555C9E1445DA16B6B195F77EAD7" indent="up2"><enum>(E)</enum> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0F7DA80FEADE4DB28991E4DCC4ABA060"><enum>(i)</enum><text>If the Secretary denies a request for certification with respect to a device pursuant to subparagraph (A)(ii), the Secretary shall provide in writing to the person seeking such certification the basis for such denial, and specifically identify the finding upon which such denial is based.</text></clause> <clause id="H31CD21562D314F0BBBB7CCC89CA07F20" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>If the denial of a request as described in clause (i) is based on grounds other than an injunction proceeding pursuant to section 302, seizure action pursuant to section 304, or a recall designated Class I or Class II pursuant to part 7, title 21, Code of Federal Regulations, the Secretary shall provide a substantive summary of the specific deficiencies identified.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3E943BEB863A470E999D082FB055E7BC" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>With respect to a device manufactured in an establishment that has received a report under section 704(b), the Secretary shall not deny a request for certification with respect to a device pursuant to subparagraph (A)(ii) if the Secretary and the owner, operator, or agent in charge of such establishment have agreed to a plan of correction in response to such report.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H81863F988F6242EFA0494A18D21D9850" indent="up2"><enum>(F)</enum> <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE72AD7662A6C4EDDB02D18A6AA438FF6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Secretary shall provide a process for a person who is denied a certification as described in subparagraph (E)(i) to request a review that conforms to the standards of section 517A(b).</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB1E6720DBC6E4F4A9EAFC8387C36FB52" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Notwithstanding any previous review conducted pursuant to clause (i), a person who has been denied a certification as described in subparagraph (E)(i) may at any time request a review in order to present new information relating to actions taken by such person to address the reasons identified by the Secretary for the denial of certification, including corrective actions to address deficiencies identified by the Secretary.</text></clause> <clause id="H141B466CB06D45108FC10041D008A300" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Not later than 1 year after date of enactment of this subparagraph, the Secretary shall issue guidance providing for a process to carry out this subparagraph.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2FF633C6A258481BA07DC20A134F156B" indent="up2"><enum>(G)</enum> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H956E5910608E4990BF93B61BAE1F239B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Subparagraphs (E) and (F) apply to requests for certification on behalf of any device establishment registered under section 510, whether the establishment is located in the United States or another country.</text></clause> <clause id="H4F5CD4E3B1CD494D9C0AC7C5D4F9D1EF" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Secretary may charge a fee for the issuance of a certification described in clause (i), and such fee is subject to the conditions and requirements of subparagraph (B).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7E5AD0C181174A3D9B74BA711CED86F8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by moving the margins of subparagraphs (C) and (D) 4 ems to the left.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

