<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H8DEF08B96E6647A891CFDD41DD0CA2B5" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3912 IH: Move America Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3912</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171002">October 2, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000813">Mrs. Walorski</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001185">Mr. Sean Patrick Maloney of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for Move America bonds and Move America
			 credits.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H0EF5661ADC4340628B9085669F6258BE" style="OLC">
 <section id="H88C91E41F5B5468D9B79D7977A9E7286" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Move America Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HAD6EB72AFB3042BDA072F762A0F75071"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purpose</header> <subsection id="H80A785E435C14E43AE8D4052F38D4F2B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress makes the following findings:</text>
 <paragraph id="H2A2648B1B224439FA0F3F174FF0FA8C6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Our Nation’s infrastructure network serves as a foundation of our economic competitiveness and national security. It is imperative that Congress maintain and revitalize the roads, bridges, ports, railways, airports, transit systems, water systems, and information networks of this country, enabling all industries to achieve the growth and productivity that make the United States strong and prosperous.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB2C7F01A4925445F8F2613CE7AFD5343"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Investing in transportation, water, and information infrastructure creates long-term capital assets for the Nation that will improve economic productivity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFC551B7994A6459282FC05D60457AB20"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Investment in infrastructure creates jobs and spurs economic activity to put people back to work and grow the economy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFFFBB1F0FA2B49BB9131FE605D241117"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The cost to maintain and improve our Nation's highways, bridges, and other critical transportation infrastructure significantly exceeds what is currently being provided by all levels of government.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF2EF5D12816742018CAB0B1E120F8517"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Investment in our Nation’s infrastructure must be multi-faceted, both by ensuring that there is a sustainable long-term funding source for infrastructure and through using innovative financing mechanisms.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1D1333EF0E5040198722180B0AB22A86"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Areas that are underserved by modern broadband connections are disadvantaged, and ensuring that those areas are connected will enable the Nation to benefit from the fuller participation of previously underserved citizens in the national economy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEE246337F91C4E3D847A1A69DA35C7F1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Investment in infrastructure is needed throughout the Nation, and it is essential that infrastructure legislation, including but not limited to this legislation, benefit urban and rural areas, and large and small States.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8C029D39156649B89198C39CFA61B48B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this Act is to provide tools to finance additional transportation, water, and information infrastructure capital investments, through an approach that provides assistance for financing of infrastructure to all States, rural and urban, and large and small.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HE6E736AA9E7D4A1B9FB654546AF89448"><enum>3.</enum><header>Move America Bond</header>
			<subsection id="HC6EA1011ACDA4DD894BFF052F31EA7A6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <paragraph id="H49814F5E8BAD45C59692F84D6D87A10F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Move America bonds</header><text>Subpart A of part IV of subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after section 142 the following new section:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1A7E51DE08CD4AD7AF4BD7B8ECED387C" style="OLC">
						<section id="H3D728C0D1F304B72AEB347BAB8369E25"><enum>142A.</enum><header>Move America bonds</header>
							<subsection id="HD90C5B4BEC4F4DED8B1357B99776169F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <paragraph id="H95E3602809334975ABA9A6C875F6D83E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Treatment as exempt facility bond</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this section, a Move America bond shall be treated for purposes of this part as an exempt facility bond.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="HF7B8FAEB9A0B4E7C9B20A9F417424747"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header>
 <subparagraph id="HAD056346209249109966C482E6212662"><enum>(A)</enum><header>No government ownership requirement</header><text>Paragraph (1) of section 142(b) shall not apply to any Move America bond.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80C234EE7E7640F687EF2E6168EBE8CA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Special rules for high-speed rail bonds</header><text>Paragraphs (2) and (3) of section 142(i) shall not apply to any Move America bond described in subsection (b)(4).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6B1D08C868F48DEBE7BADFF431C118A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Special rules for highway and surface transportation facilities</header><text>Paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) of section 142(m) shall not apply to any Move America bond described in subsection (b)(5).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA0C57D76BB2D4AF6A83FA1DB4E89611D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Move America bond</header><text>For purposes of this part, the term <term>Move America bond</term> means any bond issued as part of an issue 95 percent or more of the net proceeds of which are used to provide—</text>
 <paragraph id="H375926BCD1584724AFB768470965E284"><enum>(1)</enum><text>airports,</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H72397A627F044C49B67E8F9BDF60CB60"><enum>(2)</enum><text>docks and wharves, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0BB106AED53244BF942990B5F06C7D7A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>waterborne mooring infrastructure,</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE71EB869E714AB7A484A2FE3F0DB8E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>dredging in connection with a dock or wharf, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD298015183647FE9892D0EDA26D8199"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any associated rail and road infrastructure for the purpose of integrating modes of transportation,</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H27F9CF87FF82418ABB7F3CD432C6F309"><enum>(3)</enum><text>mass commuting facilities,</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE60E50F6E1B54197BFB91C4F3B33234C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>facilities for the furnishing of water (within the meaning of section 142(e)),</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9FE8E581A5BF426DA54A03F88EDFF271"><enum>(5)</enum><text>sewage facilities,</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H22715D0E2B404E65918E3E7498A98D02"><enum>(6)</enum><text>railroads (as defined in section 20102 of title 49, United States Code) and any associated rail and road infrastructure for the purpose of integrating modes of transportation,</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H33EF0AAEF8B24124B32F98023853FC18"><enum>(7)</enum><text>any—</text> <subparagraph id="H336275AC0C44435EA9538F9C8034E2EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>surface transportation project which is eligible for Federal assistance under title 23, United States Code (as in effect on the date of the enactment of this section),</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HECC4DCED088B4D9D97FE9C97CE716B48"><enum>(B)</enum><text>project for an international bridge or tunnel for which an international entity authorized under Federal or State law is responsible and which is eligible for Federal assistance under title 23, United States Code (as so in effect), or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5138B36ACFAC4CF58DC40D467A785F46"><enum>(C)</enum><text>facility for the transfer of freight from truck to rail or rail to truck (including any temporary storage facilities directly related to such transfers) which is eligible for Federal assistance under either title 23 or title 49, United States Code (as so in effect),</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H789FF7ED9BC245829BB670F3720F1CD5"><enum>(8)</enum><text>flood diversions,</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H54F53FE21ECB4E0391F232649CB39429"><enum>(9)</enum><text>inland waterways, including construction and rehabilitation expenditures for navigation on any inland or intracoastal waterways of the United States (within the meaning of section 4042(d)(2)), or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H26C62D2748584EB7B23BD94A84C5CEDD"><enum>(10)</enum><text>rural broadband service infrastructure.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HBF7A439FB6544B08B83BE7F78F5A93E2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H626E4450E6504A7EBD3E6C161A1333AF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Flood diversions</header><text>The term <term>flood diversion</term> means any flood damage risk reduction project authorized under any Act for authorizing water resources development projects.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H1C228EA96056419A9A1BEE452DBC4AF5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rural broadband service infrastructure</header><text>The term <term>rural broadband service infrastructure</term> means the construction, improvement, or acquisition of facilities and equipment for the provision of broadband services (as defined in section 601 of the Rural Electrification Act of 1936) which—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HD62528FCBDC24578BA35570E4DA9BD48"><enum>(A)</enum><text>meet the minimum requirements in effect under section 601(e) of such Act, and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H13112F50C27748ABB1F926E714C98264"><enum>(B)</enum><text>will be provided in an area which—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="HA240BA1494D645AF84F2B67B68E79ACA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is a rural area (as defined in section 601 of such Act), and</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H2E7E13674F9C4E16B2D141F0AECA36C3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>meets the requirements of clauses (i) and (ii) of section 601(d)(2)(A) of such Act.</text>
										</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H369D587DF9BA482BAC0A46EA945A9BDB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Move America volume cap</header>
 <paragraph id="HCF1A43D5AD13491FA8EB0CFF90919628"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The aggregate face amount of Move America bonds issued pursuant to an issue, when added to the aggregate face amount of Move America bonds previously issued by the issuing authority during the calendar year, shall not exceed such issuing authority's Move America volume cap for such year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3B882243FC9A4FAABD8B64CBE7E37F50"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Move America volume cap</header><text>For purposes of this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="H7240FB62848149C5800762ED1C7AED61"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Move America volume cap for any calendar year is an amount equal to 50 percent of the State ceiling under section 146(d) for such State for such calendar year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4016180944C4B2F93DF44A934A6D14C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Allocation of volume cap</header><text>Each State may allocate the Move America volume cap of such State among governmental units (or other authorities) in such State having authority to issue private activity bonds.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD32D48EF0714C7096AEFE4103B18391"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Carryforwards</header>
 <subparagraph id="HD719846D4E794BEFB8E9B6C789571CD5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If—</text> <clause id="HF49E6F35516A4744A216F14E31F6429C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an issuing authority's Move America volume cap, exceeds</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3D8AC6DF9C664A97BDECA295FBDBBE5E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the aggregate amount of Move America bonds issued during such calendar year by such authority,</text> </clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">any Move America bond issued by such authority during the 5-calendar-year period following such calendar year shall not be taken into account under paragraph (1) to the extent the amount of such bonds does not exceed the amount of such excess. Any excesses arising under this paragraph shall be used under this paragraph in the order of calendar years in which the excesses arose.</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBFF0B6A3AC4A43EABCB5B3ABC3ABDD76"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reallocation of unused carryforwards</header> <clause id="HEAE6345E9D6D40C4B91A301900EFF6F6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Move America volume cap under paragraph (2)(A) for any State for any calendar year shall be increased by any amount allocated to such State by the Secretary under clause (ii).</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF50411ECEEE74F94B4A9597AB514BE6B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Reallocation</header><text>The Secretary shall allocate to each qualified State for any calendar year an amount which bears the same ratio to the aggregate unused carryforward amounts of all issuing authorities in all States for such calendar year as the qualified State's population for the calendar year bears to the population of all qualified States for the calendar year. For purposes of the preceding sentence, population shall be determined in accordance with section 146(j).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H95949A19661A4E6D97498FCE0DF6D94C"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Qualified State</header><text>For purposes of this subparagraph, the term <term>qualified State</term> means, with respect to a calendar year, any State—</text> <subclause id="H7DC4AB40C3D045AC9BB3FDF93098FAAB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>which allocated its entire Move America volume cap for the preceding calendar year, and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H4B3888FA10694CD9B4C9E02D8BFD234B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for which a request is made (not later than May 1 of the calendar year) to receive an allocation under clause (ii).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H0C7BD339AA7448F3B67ABC2F14F21681"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Unused carryforward amount</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>unused carryforward amount</term> means, with respect to any issuing authority for any calendar year, the excess of—</text> <subclause id="HEA2F68B983B9453894F23488014DA079"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the amount of the excess described in subparagraph (A) for the sixth preceding calendar year, over</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H8E7185ED7E904ED3AA087C4A81D28BFA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the amount of bonds issued by such issuing authority to which subparagraph (A) applied during the 5 preceding calendar years.</text>
											</subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H438B2203A44340B7BF4857922447B7E1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Facility must be located within State</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HA9346E1385A64AF088515EF94BA11DFE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No portion of the Move America volume cap of an issuing authority for any calendar year may be used with respect to financing for a facility located outside of the authority's State.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1C91813D64FA4504A543F218D9ADFC00"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception for certain facilities where State will get proportionate share of benefit</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to any Move America bond the proceeds of which are used to provide a facility described in paragraph (4) or (5) of section 142A(b) if the issuer establishes that the State's share of the use of the facility will equal or exceed the State's share of the private activity bonds issued to finance the facility.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC17DACD88F7A41EFB02525367D2DDB29"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Applicability of certain federal laws</header>
 <paragraph id="HF4F35BCD5B4C421BAD992544D0196A38"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An issue shall not be treated as an issue under subsection (b) unless the facility for which the proceeds of such issue are used would be subject to the requirements of any Federal law (including titles 23, 40, and 49, United States Code) which would otherwise apply to similar projects.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5AFD62068E974384A75126832E921576"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public transportation capital projects</header><text>In addition to the requirements of paragraph (1), an issue the proceeds of which are used to finance a capital project (as defined in section 5302(3) of title 49, United States Code) relating to public transportation (as defined in section 5302(14) of such title) shall not be treated as an issue under subsection (b) unless such project complies with the requirements of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBCD5D41F49304BB983F4D778EF1BBA15"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Special rule for environmental remediation costs for docks and wharves</header><text>For purposes of this section, amounts used for working capital expenditures relating to environmental remediation required under State or Federal law at or near a facility described in subsection (b)(2) (including environmental remediation in the riverbed and land within or adjacent to the Federal navigation channel used to access such facility) shall be treated as an amount used to provide for such a facility.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6CFF2B4B615944C984D5A054361B0942"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this section, including regulations requiring States to report the amount of Move America volume cap of the State carried forward for any calendar year under subsection (d)(3).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1CD68E310F2447FA86D2801360F76BAC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subpart A of part IV of subchapter B of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 142 the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H05188A4594D04C8D81FC5FCD5BAD4758" style="OLC">
						<toc>
							<toc-entry idref="H3D728C0D1F304B72AEB347BAB8369E25" level="section">Sec. 142A. Move America bonds.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9380115D2A464466967E15DC156F2697"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application of other private activity bond rules</header>
 <paragraph id="H23E67B88334642058911D2A2C3710763"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Treatment under private activity bond volume cap</header><text>Subsection (g) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/146">section 146</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (3), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (4) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and by inserting after paragraph (4) the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1680352B12AF4953945EFA49177E3666" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H9F130B62E3F34BF89037A8E8A51CC150"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any Move America bond.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H17EE8F3EFB1C48DD97F7C7842DADEC88"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rule on use for land acquisition</header><text>Subparagraph (A) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/147">section 147(c)(1)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting <quote>(50 percent in the case of any issue of Move America bonds)</quote> after <quote>25 percent</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAD933819696543D49DF147050D3C0633"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Special rules for rehabilitation expenditures</header> <subparagraph id="HA54BC121855F4596AACAFBA8C0C6CFDC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Inclusion of certain expenditures</header><text>Subparagraph (B) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/147">section 147(d)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting <quote>, except that, in the case of any Move America bond, such term shall include any expenditure described in clause (v) thereof</quote> before the period at the end.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H254262A1E0734268B530D2531A86FB21"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Period for expenditures</header><text>Subparagraph (C) of section 147(d)(3) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>(5 years, in the case of any Move America bond)</quote> after <quote>2 years</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H58D4ED3247BE48149B577FF19A8FA36D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Treatment under the alternative minimum tax</header><text>Subparagraph (C) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/57">section 57(a)(5)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new clause:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9920700203B64AE3BC88E358EFA8770D" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H767969FC2C8F48C5997A27E3FE4E54C5"><enum>(vii)</enum><header>Exception for Move America bonds</header><text>For purposes of clause (i), the term <term>private activity bond</term> shall not include any Move America bond (as defined in section 142A).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="HECAD5B0E51F7468484E6701EB4DDD9A4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to obligations issued in calendar years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HCBF1AFFC5B1A4596887CEA383CE290FF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Move America credits</header>
 <subsection id="HDC6C562ECB9342E0BC03EA5725BDF50F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after the section relating to section 42 the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block act-name="" id="H5E73A83EFA59467D826672C71E1EC0FD" style="OLC">
					<section id="H348769E97BF4440F9802BCA079E1CF4B"><enum>42A.</enum><header>Move America credits</header>
						<subsection id="HF884C3B4416D452FADDEDE77E1C1C27B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Move America project credits</header>
 <paragraph id="HF2E9356FA6C94C3DA4946B3F071570D5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of section 38, the Move America project credit for any taxable year in the credit period is an amount equal to 10 percent of the qualified basis of each qualified project.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6649BD08A4EC46E59FAE11DD6B6C698C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <subparagraph id="H4D1F52F16F584A2E84BA1A7ED6F5AE9A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Qualified basis</header> <clause id="H45250B30B98949A18CF5D6DE2394A52B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The qualified basis of any qualified project is the portion of the eligible basis of such project to which the State has allocated an amount of the State credit limitation under subsection (c)(3)(C)(i).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H378091FDFDC94AB5A136B00869D83E9E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Determination</header><text>The qualified basis of a project shall be determined as of the date of the allocation for purposes of all taxable years in the credit period.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCBBB2554AB1144B9A31F4B507CA8E6AB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Qualified project</header><text>The term <term>qualified project</term> means a project which is for the construction of a facility described in section 142A(b), but only if such project—</text>
 <clause id="H108FD3DC16B3405481835E24E137FE83"><enum>(i)</enum><text>meets the requirements applicable to similar projects under any Federal law which would apply if the project were financed under any other Federal program (including titles 23, 40, and 49, United States Code),</text>
 </clause><clause id="H58EEA5CCC2F54DB3A7E17E6EE28895B0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>complies with the requirements of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, in the case of a capital project (as defined in section 5302(3) of title 49, United States Code) relating to public transportation (as defined in section 5302(14) of such title), and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5863DC7A9DA3400A9053D49F0D57339A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">will be generally available for public use throughout the credit period.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H88C4164B82E941CBB63182AB5A24C7C4"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Credit period</header> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC82715ED048E4C9B9D75C7AD15997E29"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (ii), the credit period with respect to any qualified project is the period of 10 taxable years beginning with the first taxable year beginning in the calendar year in which the project is placed in service.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0012F24C75624438848E472781126783"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Early termination</header><text>If at any time during the 10-taxable-year period described in clause (i) a project ceases to be a qualified project, or ceases and then recommences to be a qualified project, the credit period with respect to such project shall include only the taxable years in such 10-year-period in which the project was a qualified project for the entire taxable year.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5E73B5933E404C72B965BF2AA6CB2E6B"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Dispositions of property or interest relating to qualified project</header><text>A project shall not cease to be a qualified project solely by reason of the disposition of the project (or an interest therein) if it is reasonably expected that such project will otherwise continue to be a qualified project.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H456B7C85D7A542889DE65C746D2EE517"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Treatment of credit in case of disposition</header><text>If at any time during the 10-taxable-year period described in clause (i) a qualified project (or an interest therein) is disposed of—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB1A8BC8BEC1C43B9BB6860A3CEAACE56"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the credit under paragraph (1) for any year in such period beginning after the date of the disposal shall be allowed to the acquiring person, and not to the person disposing of the project (or interest), and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDDB11360A62040D4B21AA2BC7F0B61B9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the credit under paragraph (1) for the year of the disposal shall be allocated between such persons on the basis of the number of days during such year the project (or interest) was held by each.</text>
										</subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1E626DB2FF624F6C8297CD60CBE9E029"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reallocation</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCB0E5C2A1B964BC3B39D4B103819C7A7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If any qualified project is not placed in service within 3 years of the date of the allocation under subsection (c)(3), the State shall rescind the allocation under subsection (c)(3)(C)(i). Any allocation so rescinded may be reallocated by the State under subsection (c) (including to qualified infrastructure funds for purposes of the credit under subsection (b)) within the calendar year in which it is so rescinded.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2CE1BDB16C394ED58C1C5403E54F6BDF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reversion</header><text>Any rescinded allocation which is not reallocated under subparagraph (A) by the last day of the calendar year in which it is so rescinded shall revert to inclusion in the State's Move America volume cap under section 142A(d) as if it had never been exchanged under subsection (c)(1).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4D131B6D9E524BAD835FC330A229F175"><enum>(C)</enum><header>No multiple reallocations</header><text>Any rescinded allocation which is reallocated under subparagraph (A) and is subsequently rescinded shall not be further reallocated and shall immediately revert to inclusion in the Move America volume cap as provided in subparagraph (B).</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF1C3B83EA91846A4B8338F5B82A1253C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Coordination with deduction for depreciation, etc</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBB5E00B40C5244BAB07F968741FBEC8E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any taxable year in the credit period with respect to a qualified project, the total deduction allowable to the taxpayer for depreciation for the taxable year with respect to property which is part of such project shall be reduced (but not below zero) by the amount of the credit allowed under paragraph (1) for such taxable year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC4DBC786825741A4BD96A8D8D1BD992D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>No adjustment to basis</header><text>No reduction or adjustment in basis shall be made as a result of the application of subparagraph (A).</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD90C579D76CA44B0AC88B83156B22670"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Move America infrastructure fund credits</header>
							<paragraph id="HCB2813B71A234A0B862DBB43CA011016"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Allowance of credit</header>
 <subparagraph id="HAD0F840C7F1245479E7BB21A4A23FC24"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of section 38, in the case of a taxpayer who holds a Move America investment on a credit allowance date of such investment which occurs during the taxable year, the Move America infrastructure fund credit for such taxable year is an amount equal to 5 percent of the amount paid to the qualified infrastructure fund for such investment at its original issue.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7070D70C3766486F8476084AA1730C92"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Credit allowance date</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), except as provided in paragraph (3), the term <term>credit allowance date</term> means with respect to any Move America investment—</text> <clause id="H573559E74B344D4BAB49BEE0329AD512"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the date on which such investment is initially made, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5C67EE5B6F22436A8872283A2B2A2602"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>each of the 9 anniversary dates of such date thereafter.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H05D91D009A234C629DBAB6EDA3550685"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text>
								<subparagraph id="H8B4C127403B44B85937AC902DAF476C4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Move America investment</header>
 <clause id="H2CDD8E732417407BA79C03DA533A1AFD"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>Move America investment</term> means any equity investment in a qualified infrastructure fund, if—</text> <subclause id="H666C4D02640B43D6B1B83886FB09418B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>such investment is acquired by the taxpayer at its original issue solely in exchange for cash,</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H04260AEDFC05437785F96130925EB87A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>substantially all of such cash is used by the qualified infrastructure fund to make qualified investments, and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H6291A203A22646FCB88C3E3F5F97F6FD"><enum>(III)</enum><text>such investment is designated for purposes of this subsection by the qualified infrastructure fund, including a designation of the qualified investment which will be made with such investment.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HCAF0C634E03B4771A28A364A48A0B972"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The maximum amount of equity investments issued by a qualified infrastructure fund in a calendar year which may be designated under clause (i)(III) by such fund shall not exceed—</text>
 <subclause id="H19DF5C3503E84388AE4437C5E664BAF0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the portion of the State credit limitation allocated under subsection (c)(3)(A)(ii) to such fund in such calendar year, multiplied by</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H0FCBEA2E202B41C7B3740BC96CB1DCB7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>2.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H2E18144012014AFA8EA67B31440672D6"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Expiration</header><text>If the limitation determined under clause (ii) with respect to an infrastructure fund for a calendar year exceeds the amount of equity investments designated under clause (i)(III) by such fund in such year, the State shall rescind such excess allocation. Any allocation so rescinded may be reallocated by the State under subsection (c) (including to qualified projects for purposes of the credit under subsection (a)) within the immediately succeeding calendar year.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HE8E29FF4FB304670B2A539ECF0BF0DBE"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Reversion</header><text>Any rescinded allocation which is not reallocated under clause (iii) by the last day of such immediately succeeding calendar year shall revert to inclusion in the State's Move America volume cap under section 142A(d) as if it had never been exchanged under subsection (c)(1).</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA339ACEF313F4271B9588BF9C8DC04A1"><enum>(v)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">No multiple reallocations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any rescinded allocation which is reallocated under clause (iii) and is subsequently rescinded shall not be further reallocated and shall immediately revert to inclusion in the Move America volume cap as provided in clause (iv).</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6C47231CCAF84B98B4902CB50A27BF04"><enum>(vi)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Special rules</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rules similar to the rules of paragraphs (3) and (4) of section 45D(b) shall apply with respect to clause (i).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H210EA80A9EBA44E4B8DBA7BE87CB6D10"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Qualified infrastructure fund</header><text>The term <term>qualified infrastructure fund</term> means—</text> <clause id="HC3D973B2815E4934B9C1A2DEC603130F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a State infrastructure bank established under section 610 of title 23, United States Code,</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAB4F37E924F44E04B755F5459F193351"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a water pollution control revolving fund established under title VI of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1381">33 U.S.C. 1381</external-xref> et seq.),</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEF69501FB58C4C78B9516FC009E62ADB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a drinking water treatment revolving loan fund established under section 1452 of the Safe Drinking Water Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300j-12">42 U.S.C. 300j–12</external-xref>), or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF5EE302F45B74978BC347C4322F59CB0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an equivalent fund established or designated by the State or any instrumentality thereof.</text> </clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">In the case of a fund described in clause (ii) or (iii), the amount of any Move America investment shall not be included in determining the amount of State or other non-Federal contributions to such fund.</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9A4B3A5DE6634A22B5CF07C602D726DD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Qualified investment</header><text>The term <term>qualified investment</term> means an investment (whether by loan, loan guarantee, or equity investment) in—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="HD06326F6F0664B55B081FAB34F4B48BC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>qualified projects, or</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H1528B6E540D84E42A06E44C8795D732E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a fund described in clause (i), (ii), or (iii) of subparagraph (B), projects and activities for which such funds are authorized to be used under any other provision of law.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4FB419C1061B4D6EB4786B7F8AA253CF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Early termination</header>
 <subparagraph id="HA9F1F004091C4EC29F90093BD18EECD5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If at any time during the compliance period the fund which issued a Move America investment ceases to be a qualified infrastructure fund, or ceases and then recommences to be a qualified infrastructure fund, any date described in paragraph (1)(B) (including the date described in clause (i) thereof) occurring in—</text>
 <clause id="H16B54465E7024F21A479B48D2A70CA6B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the taxable year in which the fund ceased to be a qualified infrastructure fund, or</text> </clause><clause id="HBABD90CDCAA4497AAC0D4BD5ED6E47E3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any other taxable year in such period in which the fund is not a qualified infrastructure fund for the entire taxable year,</text>
 </clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">shall not be treated as a credit allowance date for purposes of paragraph (1).</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F71FF8C981441A7AA00F1D79328BE7C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Compliance period</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term <term>compliance period</term> means the 10-taxable-year period beginning with the taxable year that includes the date of the original issue of the Move America investment.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE6FD08FA07AA445E9BC40FEB2B41E20A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Loss of qualification</header><text>A fund shall cease to be a qualified infrastructure fund as of the date—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H3C2C08ED72A94AAA8F32CC395E389ABA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the fund redeems any Move America investment within the compliance period with respect to such investment,</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4C6FFC872AB3403DB9AEA61D5AA7DC2A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the proceeds of any Move America investment cease to be used for qualified investments, or</text> </clause><clause id="H7560E07448B942E788A5EAA5067CA953"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the fund makes any investment which is not a qualified investment.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22627FC8ACA24FFCA45DFB182901DBDC"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Expiration of credit</header><text>If substantially all of the cash paid for any Move America investment is not used to make qualified investments designated under paragraph (2)(A)(i)(III) within 3 years of the date of original issue of such investment, any date described in paragraph (1)(B) occurring in a taxable year which ends after the date which is 3 years after such date of original issue shall not be treated as a credit allowance date for purposes of paragraph (1).</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB761C3D3F26C4084A965FEA883610D83"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Move America credit allocation</header>
							<paragraph commented="no" id="HFF72B6F80DD241D7A750C13712E38CEF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exchange of Move America bond volume cap</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HEA8EF1EAD3A9483C946A6622743D5870"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a State has in effect a qualified allocation plan for a calendar year, the State may exchange (in such manner as the Secretary may prescribe) all or a portion of the State's Move America volume cap under section 142A(d) for such year for a State credit limitation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0ED4114DCB0C41C883FF734836855442"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The amount of a State's Move America volume cap for a calendar year which may be exchanged under subparagraph (A) shall not include any portion of such cap which is attributable to an amount of State credit limitation which has reverted under paragraph (3)(D) or subsection (a)(3)(B) or (b)(2)(A)(iv).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H931BA5DC9A664052A9AD70A26931529E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State credit limitation</header><text>For purposes of this section, the State credit limitation with respect to any State for a calendar year is a dollar amount equal to 25 percent of the Move America volume cap exchanged under paragraph (1) for such calendar year.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA2D4514B16654E38BE187E651C836605"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Allocation</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H0E2CE1932D1B4DCBA8C2D13B364FB71B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State may allocate the State credit limitation, according to the qualified allocation plan, for any calendar year among—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H6E1A9F54C89941D7856FCDE0C294D35A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>qualified projects in the State for purposes of the Move America project credit under subsection (a), and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H3B97833AAD324547A8B6DE59BE67D271"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>qualified infrastructure funds in the State for purposes of the Move America infrastructure fund credit under subsection (b).</text>
									</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H079442E75C2A42D59F73DD2DC017F1C5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Qualified allocation plan</header>
 <clause commented="no" id="H594155CE0D1942F99E9EE827C1A0E3DB"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>qualified allocation plan</term> means any plan—</text> <subclause commented="no" id="H85BCB58E13174770BB8BA304336FDE5A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>which sets forth selection criteria to be used in determining infrastructure priorities of the State and allocating the State credit limitation among projects (in accordance with clause (ii)) and infrastructure funds in the State, and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H999A7D1C99D04F56BE22FED728F1E222"><enum>(II)</enum><text>which provides a procedure that the State (or an agent or other private contractor of the State) will follow in monitoring for noncompliance with the provisions of this section and in notifying the Internal Revenue Service of such noncompliance.</text>
										</subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="H6AAD30BC9ED943D68565BE262F0B7395"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation based on project feasibility for Move America project credits</header>
 <subclause commented="no" id="H946FD2C975E74880B30CB23AB3D69E21"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of an allocation with respect to any qualified project for purposes of the Move America project credit under subsection (a), such allocation shall not exceed the minimum amount which the State transportation authority or other applicable agency determines is required for the financial feasibility of the project and its viability for completion and availability for public use throughout the credit period.</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H7F2DA2D0B4514E72B1CD77D13C16F3FD"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Minimum feasibility determination</header><text>In making the determination under subclause (I), such entity shall consider the sources and uses of funds and the total financing planned for the project, any proceeds or receipts expected to be generated by reason of tax benefits, the reasonableness of the developmental and operational costs of the project over the full expected operational life of the project, ancillary costs (including right-of-way and procurement costs), financing costs, and retained and transferred risk.</text>
										</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2295B236F4DA4F04AFCC1AF7BC0A2168"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Special rules relating to Move America project credit</header>
 <clause commented="no" id="H6CF07E92B3324FD6A3B8E11FE7AF9D9E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The amount allocated to a qualified project under subparagraph (A)(i) shall not exceed the eligible basis of such project.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H9606A3512DD64C5CAF096294188A887F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Eligible basis</header><text>For purposes of this section, except as provided in clause (iii), the eligible basis of any qualified project is the lesser of—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" id="HFD32B4B6D8134877BA141CBC69F64204"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the portion of the basis of such project which is attributable to the taxpayer's equity investment in the costs of the project which are subject to the allowance for depreciation (as estimated as of the date of the allocation), or</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HC0B963B89E7046D19E53CC0320FECFDB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>20 percent of the costs of the project which are subject to the allowance for depreciation (as estimated as of the date of the allocation).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="H807A1955799F4EF9962BE67988D2A84E"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Exclusion of government assistance</header><text>Eligible basis shall not include any portion of the basis of such project which is attributable to any assistance or financing provided by a Federal, State, or local government (as estimated as of the date of the allocation).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE4C92056619C4157B6EC0E7415DF8624"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Reversion of unallocated limitation</header><text>Any portion of the State credit limitation for any calendar year which remains unallocated as of the last day of such calendar year shall revert to inclusion in the State's Move America volume cap under section 142A(d) as if it had never been exchanged under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB67C646F73084CDFA455260CB895817C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Credits made part of general business credit</header><text>Subsection (b) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/38">section 38</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HE464368644E447019F00099A47337DF4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>plus</quote> at the end of paragraph (35),</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9BFA2F584B60481B82F697B3A33984E2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of paragraph (36) and inserting a comma, and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC872946641D84EBF97CA16FD6BAFF657"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text>
					<quoted-block act-name="" id="H22476B8AEB2741318B56E2607912211D" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HC2FB7CF6FB6B45D5A66074B04D96AF30"><enum>(37)</enum><text>the Move America project credit under section 42A(a)(1), plus</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE2CAC1948FE9463A8428F479C14603CB"><enum>(38)</enum><text>the Move America infrastructure fund credit under section 42A(b)(1).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3D4B113CB8764EC98912E17E43B44920"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 42 the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H819BB4230A73421E980BA8A36A0CDF07" style="OLC">
					<toc>
						<toc-entry idref="H348769E97BF4440F9802BCA079E1CF4B" level="section">Sec. 42A. Move America credits.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7062A30B9D3340688767110152041416"><enum>(d)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA43C68E21D3C4104A61EB750C287CF70"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>A State shall, at such time and in such manner as the Secretary of the Treasury shall require, report—</text>
 <paragraph id="H896888CD21BA486E96C61158DE767E8A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to the Secretary of the Treasury—</text> <subparagraph id="H821215415E564CAD834B12F1A17E7556"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amount of the Move America volume cap of the State for the calendar year which is exchanged under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/42A">section 42A(c)(1)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 for a State credit limitation,</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F7A031049DB4B87A10C844B9B4294F0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount (if any) of the State credit limitation allocated under section 42A(c)(3)(A)(i) of such Code to qualified projects, the amount so allocated to each such project, and the taxpayer with respect to such project (including the name of the taxpayer and any other identifying information as the Secretary of the Treasury shall require), and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A49CA43AFCE440FB85FDE5DD0CA9B6E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the amount (if any) of the State credit limitation allocated under section 42A(c)(3)(A)(ii) of such Code to qualified infrastructure funds, the amount so allocated to each such fund, and each taxpayer holding any Move America investment with respect to any such fund (including the name of the taxpayer and any other identifying information as the Secretary of the Treasury shall require),</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H53DBE42D89644389B952736EC35EE99E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to the Secretary of the Treasury and any taxpayer who is the project sponsor of a qualified project receiving an allocation under section 42A(c)(3)(A)(i) of such Code, the date on which the qualified project is placed in service, and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFBFB6B2A387242B9B9653F09E62CEC4C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to the Secretary of the Treasury and any taxpayer holding a Move America investment, a certification that the entity which issued the investment is a qualified infrastructure fund and that the investment will be used to make qualified investments designated for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/42A">section 42A(b)(2)(A)(i)(III)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
				</paragraph><continuation-text commented="no" continuation-text-level="subsection">For purposes of this subsection, any term used in this subsection that is also used in section 42A
			 or 142A of such Code has the same meaning as when used in such section.</continuation-text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


