<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H48F09741198D42CB9C8414CA4551A4C5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2523 IH: Preserve Rights Of States and Political subdivisions to Encourage Retirement Savings Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2523</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170518">May 18, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001038">Mr. Crowley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001069">Mr. Courtney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 with respect to the scope of employee pension benefit plans.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA638D94622F1496E90A2C8A3D02F78E3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H4BC947A123074925A93478A57DEA68AF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preserve Rights Of States and Political subdivisions to Encourage Retirement Savings Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PROSPERS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H4006D7E7BC224A1DAA0A584711BD4834"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1002">29 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HE749E655D6694D4D87B928A4DEFD882C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> <subparagraph id="HD1A708434DD24CCDBB591EC52E195A22"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>subparagraph (B)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraphs (B) and (C)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H24C5F5230BDA40748AA44BE81041CC5C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9C42363AB358408AB132E807F21635B5" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HFCAA901BF5314297AEC72F6FBB8E8525" indent="up2"><enum>(C)</enum> <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HEDA8DB1D9D8740689016AAE8966D6A25"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The terms <term>employee pension benefit plan</term> and <term>pension plan</term> do not include an individual retirement plan (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7701">section 7701(a)(37)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) established and maintained pursuant to a payroll deduction savings program of a State or qualified political subdivision of a State, provided that—</text>
<subclause id="HD810EB89B2C849CB99E3E24E7033D971" indent="up1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the program is specifically established pursuant to State or qualified political subdivision law;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H75116EF9DF6C4CDEAB51C73EC81611ED" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the program is implemented and administered by the State or qualified political subdivision establishing the program (or by a governmental agency or instrumentality of either), which is responsible for investing the employee savings or for selecting investment alternatives for employees to choose;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H8D21E98024154100974B739D076A0356" indent="up1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the State or qualified political subdivision (or governmental agency or instrumentality of either) assumes responsibility for the security of payroll deductions and employee savings, including by requiring that amounts withheld from wages by the employer be transmitted to the program promptly and by providing an enforcement mechanism to assure compliance with this requirement;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H8FA5CCDC48E949608FAEA113E6373DE3" indent="up1"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the State or qualified political subdivision (or governmental agency or instrumentality of either) adopts measures to ensure that employees are notified of their rights under the program, and creates a mechanism for enforcement of those rights;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H9620512A53FB4F75B119A78BFCA6EA04" indent="up1"><enum>(V)</enum><text>participation in the program is voluntary for employees;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H00202F8167CB48F0B45B35CDED0D7348" indent="up1"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>all rights of the employee, former employee, or beneficiary under the program are enforceable only by the employee, former employee, or beneficiary, an authorized representative of such a person, or by the State or qualified political subdivision (or governmental agency or instrumentality of either);</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HC052AF373D364779B6E5452DA2B162BD" indent="up1"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>the involvement of the employer is limited to—</text> <item id="H93CAC26F161B4F519CD95A59D8AF2359"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>collecting employee contributions through payroll deductions and remitting them to the program;</text></item>
<item id="H4F1ED504656546869BB58A53CDEDEAC5"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>providing notice to the employees and maintaining records regarding the employer’s collection and remittance of payments under the program;</text></item> <item id="H2CC20B07C8F04674B14FC6E83A44EBCB"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>providing information to the State or qualified political subdivision (or governmental agency or instrumentality of either) necessary to facilitate the operation of the program; and</text></item>
<item id="HCAF30A9999504BEC96182DF022A366A6"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>distributing program information to employees from the State or qualified political subdivision (or governmental agency or instrumentality of either) and permitting the State or qualified political subdivision (or governmental agency or instrumentality of either) to publicize the program to employees;</text></item></subclause> <subclause id="H24C91C511E944FE3AF07D0F168E1C527" indent="up1"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>the employer contributes no funds to the program and provides no bonus or other monetary incentive to employees to participate in the program;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H675B15DCA6EF4B44A5EFB9F9EA08D44C" indent="up1"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>the employer’s participation in the program is required by the law of the State law or qualified political subdivision;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HBF81F5BAF2CC4D5EB67C73A831D849DF" indent="up1"><enum>(X)</enum><text>the employer has no discretionary authority, control, or responsibility under the program; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HF4F3F24FB82443C69DCBD53681369CEF" indent="up1"><enum>(XI)</enum><text>the employer receives no direct or indirect consideration in the form of cash or otherwise, other than consideration (including tax incentives and credits) received directly from the State or qualified political subdivision (or governmental agency or instrumentality of either) that does not exceed an amount that reasonably approximates the employer’s (or a typical employer’s) costs under the program.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H2A0DEC87A52F4F22A0608DD6F27A0CC1" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A State savings program will not fail to satisfy the requirements of subclauses (I) through (XI) of clause (i) merely because the program—</text>
<subclause id="H250A68B392464C8FA1BC4DB53382A27A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is directed toward those employers that do not offer some other workplace savings arrangement;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HDAA05E3B581F4D9A9384F6601B266747"><enum>(II)</enum><text>utilizes one or more service or investment providers to operate and administer the program, provided that the State (or governmental agency or instrumentality of the State) retains full responsibility for the operation and administration of the program; or</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HE225C8F484854415BB8B974D1453675A"><enum>(III)</enum><text>treats employees as having automatically elected payroll deductions in an amount or percentage of compensation, including any automatic increases in such amount or percentage, unless the employee specifically elects not to have such deductions made (or specifically elects to have the deductions made in a different amount or percentage of compensation allowed by the program), provided that the employee is given adequate advance notice of the right to make such elections and provided, further, that a program may also satisfy the requirements of such subclauses (I) through (XI) without requiring or otherwise providing for automatic elections such as those described in this subclause.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HBFFAD1BD8C4841D884C9D3F4D745DF55" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>For purposes of this subparagraph, the term ‘<term>qualified political subdivision</term>’ means any governmental unit of a State, including a city, county, or similar governmental body, that—</text>
<subclause id="H1E55F08F4F0947DAB5E160196ACAEDA1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>has the authority, implicit or explicit, under State law to require employers’ participation in the program as described in clause (i); and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H84C64D3AC00448828E99BF54A9F00E05"><enum>(II)</enum><text>at the time of the establishment of the political subdivision’s payroll deduction savings program—</text>
<item id="HBF7035843E434C8EAE22553018C25D23"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>has a population equal to or greater than the population of the least populated State (excluding the District of Columbia and territories listed in paragraph (10));</text></item> <item id="H35B5953394614D40ABEE7C670E1C21CE"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>has no geographic overlap with any other political subdivision that has enacted a mandatory payroll deduction savings program for private-sector employees and is not located in a State that has enacted such a program statewide; and</text></item>
<item id="H8C573C75F9344185A15C5CCBFA1B2DDF"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>has implemented and administers a plan, fund, or program that provides retirement income to its employees, or results in a deferral of income by its employees for periods extending to the termination of covered employment or beyond.</text></item></subclause></clause> <clause id="H6282C50864904130B6C11F27E1FDC7B3" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>For purposes of clause (i)(III), amounts withheld from an employee’s wages by the employer are deemed to be transmitted promptly if such amounts are transmitted to the program as of the earliest date on which such contributions can reasonably be segregated from the employer’s general assets, but in no event later than the last day of the month following the month in which such amounts would otherwise have been payable to the employee in cash.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

