<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H5DFC1C55F634411688DBCBDB57B5FEF2" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3000 IH: To terminate the designation of the Islamic Republic of Pakistan as a major non-NATO ally, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3000</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170622">June 22, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000592">Mr. Poe of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000127">Mr. Nolan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000409">Mr. Rohrabacher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001183">Mr. Schweikert</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To terminate the designation of the Islamic Republic of Pakistan as a major non-NATO ally, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H8D6C643C29E1493E89DF00CDAB69C6A2" style="OLC">
		<section id="H9B43E43D1F5146708D6D5E3A8AC87D52" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Termination of designation of the Islamic Republic of Pakistan as a major non-NATO ally</header>
 <subsection id="H19D9C7936A52461D85A3CE3B4C484CE3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act—</text> <paragraph id="HE09F15649CAA4A3CB4084B80CE561F61"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the designation of the Islamic Republic of Pakistan as a major non-NATO ally pursuant to section 517(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2321k">22 U.S.C. 2321k(a)(1)</external-xref>) or any other provision of law is hereby terminated; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6A9880883BA747F5862A7EBCE0CF9949"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the President may not issue a separate designation of the Islamic Republic of Pakistan as a major non-NATO ally pursuant to section 517(a)(1) of such Act or any other provision of law unless the President submits to Congress a certification described in subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC0E2735279CC4003AC8B096C69DA9617"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A certification described in this subsection is a certification that contains a determination of the President that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H45384858E5F94E9CA1E62D7C6355BA8D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Pakistan continues to conduct military operations that are contributing to significantly disrupting the safe haven and freedom of movement of the Haqqani Network in Pakistan;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF73EB2F4D0664798952110B7984CCCDB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Pakistan has taken steps to demonstrate its commitment to prevent the Haqqani Network from using any Pakistani territory as a safe haven;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H72DE0609402E45988B8F37B42C9264BB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Government of Pakistan actively coordinates with the Government of Afghanistan to restrict the movement of militants, such as the Haqqani Network, along the Afghanistan-Pakistan border; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7F3DB704050D4463992160DC4EF341FD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Pakistan has shown progress in arresting and prosecuting Haqqani Network senior leaders and mid-level operatives.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


