<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H87DF1692A20B4DF78E7B0F5ABF1053B4" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2182 EH: Plum Island Preservation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2182</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To require the Comptroller General of the United States to submit a report to Congress on the alternatives for the final disposition of Plum Island, including preservation of the island for conservation, education, and research, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H254D4030556540F8AFFA8E7AFE2AD33E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H57D63216D8474AA389B6A52ECF9CDD2C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Plum Island Preservation Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H2B6C8D775E2442F1A6C31BB06E95DB0B" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H4584E584E38541FF9B392154588A3229"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Government has owned Plum Island, New York, since 1899.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H105CFCF080B84C9486D35E95668AF1E8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Since 1954, the Plum Island Animal Disease Center has conducted unrivaled scientific research on a variety of infectious animal-borne diseases, including foot-and-mouth disease, resulting, most recently, in the development of a new cell line that rapidly and reliably detects this highly debilitating disease of livestock.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H35F8651D01F54BDBB60EAC7026BA8181"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Over 62 years, the Center has had a strong, proven record of safety.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H8A05761D3CC74FB9BE7754FC7783D145"><enum>(4)</enum><text>$23,200,000 in Federal dollars have been spent on upgrades to, and the maintenance of, the Center since January 2012.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3D487CE32A5449A9B2C7D91D92485EA7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In addition to the Center, Plum Island contains cultural, historical, ecological, and natural resources of regional and national significance.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HF4163DCE61F54DC0B0875298A9B8F602"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Plum Island is situated where the Long Island Sound and Peconic Bay meet, both of which are estuaries that are part of the National Estuary Program and are environmentally and economically significant to the region.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8FFCA32E52C340F2948952E8C576C7A5"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Federal Government has invested hundreds of millions of Federal dollars over the last 2 decades to make long-term improvements with respect to the conservation and management needs of Long Island Sound and Peconic Bay.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H8660C490564F4EDAA6ED8AD9158E3F59"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In a report submitted to Congress on April 11, 2016, entitled <quote>National Bio- and Agro-Defense Facility Construction Plan Update</quote> the Department of Homeland Security noted that the new National Bio- and Agro-Defense Facility under construction on such date in Manhattan, Kansas, is, as of such date, fully paid for through a combination of Federal appropriations and funding from the State of Kansas.</text> </paragraph></section> 
<section id="HCE9ACBB34CB44C98BE6CAA76DF447252"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report required on final disposition of Plum Island</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report containing the following:</text> <paragraph id="HAE805B6D18304ADB8441CBBC4D370453"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The alternatives for the final disposition of Plum Island, including the transfer of ownership to another Federal agency, a State or local government, a nonprofit organization, or a combination thereof for the purpose of education, research, or conservation.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB44FC090337E41EE8FA833838E7A8269"><enum>(2)</enum><text>With respect to each such alternative final disposition, an analysis of—</text> <subparagraph id="HE113B780BAC044BAABD35C60CA6C924B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the effect such disposition would have on the island’s resources;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H30EBEFD32E14420CA24A0FE09F1F0794"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the remediation responsibilities under such disposition;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD57837772C074691AD16D1A5C6D9C08E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any future legislation necessary to implement such disposition;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCC19DDD938AF42DCB09927A9FE58596B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the possible implications and issues, if any, of implementing such disposition;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1C22F8687AA34EEDB1F0674020164817"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the costs of such disposition, including any potential costs related to the transition, hazard mitigation, and cleanup of property that would be incurred by a recipient of the property under such disposition; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H43F64DD1CBF44C1FA4B02C8EBAF9D76E"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the potential revenue from such disposition.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="H4C377D62FF9D4A4CB17DBFEDC9BB9BDA"><enum>4.</enum><header>Suspension of action</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No action, including any pre-sale marketing activity, may be taken to carry out section 538 of title V of division D of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/74">Public Law 112–74</external-xref>; 125 Stat. 976) until at least 180 days after the report required by section 3 has been submitted to Congress.</text> </section> 
</legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20170725" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives July 25, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> 
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> 
</bill> 


