<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HFCD0CE3DF2C14FC58163EDA7BDE8FAD2" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 387 : Email Privacy Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 387</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date date="20170207" legis-day="20170206">February 7 (legislative day, February 6), 2017</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To amend title 18, United States Code, to update the privacy protections for electronic
			 communications information that is stored by third-party service providers
			 in order to protect consumer privacy interests while meeting law
			 enforcement needs, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H13015BBDFF2B43FF998DB549C0311086" style="OLC">
 <section id="HC975F29E796D4407A5DE304FD8613B8D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Email Privacy Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HA86B1742CDE8479B85A2828BA06CECA3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Voluntary disclosure corrections</header> <subsection id="H557C263013F74C9FB397A42CED7054DA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2702 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H2F055E96190B4132A2E0428241BD0610"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="H66D9E2AA74634667A1EDF54D86B4A9CE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text>
 <clause id="H1B6937E20D484B66BF9D9B6BFA89DC5D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>divulge</quote> and inserting <quote>disclose</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="HCF236EEF9E8641938ADE813FD5AE4254"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>while in electronic storage by that service</quote> and inserting <quote>that is in electronic storage with or otherwise stored, held, or maintained by that service</quote>;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8186AAB4CA424B88A1548CE89DF0E9CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> <clause id="HAD253A2148DC434BA6D649773C855BAB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>to the public</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H18FF76E9869B4AC7A2365B50038B10D2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>divulge</quote> and inserting <quote>disclose</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="HDE0F3869BE0E41098C63EE39E97C5A02"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>which is carried or maintained on that service</quote> and inserting <quote>that is stored, held, or maintained by that service</quote>; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H627272744EB04C8C89F784B71956CE5D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text> <clause id="HFA6EA2DA34474C228901B51752A7E2D0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>divulge</quote> and inserting <quote>disclose</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4A0DA83D4BAE437D8C93BCFB720B1FAC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>a provider of</quote> and inserting <quote>a person or entity providing</quote>;</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D05FEF70D5D4F9F8B3412FBC2B09617"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H2F24369ECB934894A8409C0C6F673F75"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>wire or electronic</quote> before <quote>communication</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDEC2DD1027AE4B81AE8201D6B234B4D4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (1) to read as follows:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H33EE4E57C80C4DCEB7C87CD087E7F7CF" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HAA6DC6894CD74ECEA794AAF31C0B7DE1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to an originator, addressee, or intended recipient of such communication, to the subscriber or customer on whose behalf the provider stores, holds, or maintains such communication, or to an agent of such addressee, intended recipient, subscriber, or customer;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE528B5C1A946403487D158A420A49460"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (3) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H62AC5743C25342E49D3151F461ABE858" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H58A4B0802DA843AE8E6FA75E88A7402C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with the lawful consent of the originator, addressee, or intended recipient of such communication, or of the subscriber or customer on whose behalf the provider stores, holds, or maintains such communication;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2015F63F3ED84BD5B27990C85B0B0B37"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c) by inserting <quote>wire or electronic</quote> before <quote>communications</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB3A1E53A507E4A5FAF64EE0495A3A2BA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in each of subsections (b) and (c), by striking <quote>divulge</quote> and inserting <quote>disclose</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEF468ABE3D2442A2B7AE92018D7A5185"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by amending paragraph (2) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA192FACCEFDB45A19E69EF0AEFF627C6" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HFA6BAE1545A746D38A6136C999DF04B6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with the lawful consent of the subscriber or customer;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2109E72546C44EED8348316A1C5EB6CB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Amendments to required disclosure section</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2703 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H522EAF8772E04AE1BCFA8B4F9389247C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking subsections (a) through (c) and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEE667D35F8274E398BBC8A84DF40AE74" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H2639199177C441A09CC4516B9ECA9C4B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Contents of wire or electronic communications in electronic storage</header><text>Except as provided in subsections (i) and (j), a governmental entity may require the disclosure by a provider of electronic communication service of the contents of a wire or electronic communication that is in electronic storage with or otherwise stored, held, or maintained by that service only if the governmental entity obtains a warrant issued using the procedures described in the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure (or, in the case of a State court, issued using State warrant procedures) that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H86665785C0514ED5B10FA56CA924386B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is issued by a court of competent jurisdiction; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDFF4C9F7CD8F40ACA914107D51565BDB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may indicate the date by which the provider must make the disclosure to the governmental entity.</text>
						</paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">In the absence of a date on the warrant indicating the date by which the provider must make
			 disclosure to the governmental entity, the provider shall promptly respond
			 to the warrant.</continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="HD66A3DBC12FD4D9EB1D709CED6D2F99C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents of wire or electronic communications in a remote computing service</header>
 <paragraph id="HF30ED7F449984F93BFD6B22D4A485344"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsections (i) and (j), a governmental entity may require the disclosure by a provider of remote computing service of the contents of a wire or electronic communication that is stored, held, or maintained by that service only if the governmental entity obtains a warrant issued using the procedures described in the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure (or, in the case of a State court, issued using State warrant procedures) that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3E4EA32493514E9F8BF45490B21760E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is issued by a court of competent jurisdiction; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2EF601E91F94410E979C60232CF95F5E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may indicate the date by which the provider must make the disclosure to the governmental entity.</text>
							</subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">In the absence of a date on the warrant indicating the date by which the provider must make
			 disclosure to the governmental entity, the provider shall promptly respond
 to the warrant.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H24FFD29FA73344F2897E08EF5CDBE619"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Paragraph (1) is applicable with respect to any wire or electronic communication that is stored, held, or maintained by the provider—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF169D6FCF2C845D6B57564FAC1F7BD52"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on behalf of, and received by means of electronic transmission from (or created by means of computer processing of communication received by means of electronic transmission from), a subscriber or customer of such remote computing service; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4BFCD9CDDAD4EFDB554E43413FE4B16"><enum>(B)</enum><text>solely for the purpose of providing storage or computer processing services to such subscriber or customer, if the provider is not authorized to access the contents of any such communications for purposes of providing any services other than storage or computer processing.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8A15AF3157C74CD896E294BCD3D8EB40"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Records concerning electronic communication service or remote computing service</header>
 <paragraph id="H834743A3A7DD43F1ADD1EF0FA766D9A9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsections (i) and (j), a governmental entity may require the disclosure by a provider of electronic communication service or remote computing service of a record or other information pertaining to a subscriber to or customer of such service (not including the contents of wire or electronic communications), only—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDD15D86CF668446780B3456A33659869"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if a governmental entity obtains a warrant issued using the procedures described in the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure (or, in the case of a State court, issued using State warrant procedures) that—</text>
 <clause id="H5955A8B45CC84DB49C5C97419FDBA091"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is issued by a court of competent jurisdiction directing the disclosure; and</text> </clause><clause id="HDAB1F92438B54826A5C325507219989F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may indicate the date by which the provider must make the disclosure to the governmental entity;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2AACF476F3074ECAAC8808AE740CE3EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if a governmental entity obtains a court order directing the disclosure under subsection (d);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6FCB17820C4741059EB5849230C49E56"><enum>(C)</enum><text>with the lawful consent of the subscriber or customer; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5725A1A5BF5E409580A8ECD106F8D2FA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>as otherwise authorized in paragraph (2).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB14921B38BBB450D95E4CAA5E2D7A37D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Subscriber or customer Information</header><text>A provider of electronic communication service or remote computing service shall, in response to an administrative subpoena authorized by Federal or State statute, a grand jury, trial, or civil discovery subpoena, or any means available under paragraph (1), disclose to a governmental entity the—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4D26A9B0BF6F44539C49E896BDDDEED2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>name;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB968844E5AC45A081FE585032ECAD56"><enum>(B)</enum><text>address;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5847720DA0484E8C8862F38E4338225D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>local and long distance telephone connection records, or records of session times and durations;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB96207359F243798F9387C77780120D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>length of service (including start date) and types of service used;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB06C325F815B4511A67B7A1E4C90253F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>telephone or instrument number or other subscriber or customer number or identity, including any temporarily assigned network address; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HACFC23E5186549ACB5A46677511B7D08"><enum>(F)</enum><text>means and source of payment for such service (including any credit card or bank account number),</text> </subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">of a subscriber or customer of such service.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H902960EE2F444B2F9F9B8D6892C61A2F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notice not required</header><text>A governmental entity that receives records or information under this subsection is not required to provide notice to a subscriber or customer.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9BC65EB63BC04BCD88FED025354CF78A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (d)—</text> <subparagraph id="H76AA3508FC294F3EA94124C35BD92640"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(b) or</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9888EC6FE1C7446AB769FF2BF631BE93"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the contents of a wire or electronic communication, or</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00BE9B037BD44FC99CD6E12047328A05"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>sought,</quote> and inserting <quote>sought</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4D772B05E63343FE98B1497777483F0D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by striking <quote>section</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB83AC6272DA447788803A4AF4011919"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEF47AE66887B4EF89EE8E3969FE83517" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H0FE6292BF62F46F19A6A37D2C4798FDD"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in section 2705, a provider of electronic communication service or remote computing service may notify a subscriber or customer of a receipt of a warrant, court order, subpoena, or request under subsection (a), (b), (c), or (d) of this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H043A0AD361B04D18BAA1260FFC39EDBE"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Rule of construction related to legal process</header><text>Nothing in this section or in section 2702 shall limit the authority of a governmental entity to use an administrative subpoena authorized by Federal or State statute, a grand jury, trial, or civil discovery subpoena, or a warrant issued using the procedures described in the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure (or, in the case of a State court, issued using State warrant procedures) by a court of competent jurisdiction to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2DCDC6588DD8462381917A623E4A6140"><enum>(1)</enum><text>require an originator, addressee, or intended recipient of a wire or electronic communication to disclose a wire or electronic communication (including the contents of that communication) to the governmental entity;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H236020229F3E46EDB67CF846064C7517"><enum>(2)</enum><text>require a person or entity that provides an electronic communication service to the officers, directors, employees, or agents of the person or entity (for the purpose of carrying out their duties) to disclose a wire or electronic communication (including the contents of that communication) to or from the person or entity itself or to or from an officer, director, employee, or agent of the entity to a governmental entity, if the wire or electronic communication is stored, held, or maintained on an electronic communications system owned, operated, or controlled by the person or entity; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H59CBDB8C7C80484889A0BEBA8417A27E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>require a person or entity that provides a remote computing service or electronic communication service to disclose a wire or electronic communication (including the contents of that communication) that advertises or promotes a product or service and that has been made readily accessible to the general public.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3AE4F916FC64442787E6C882B6FCA336"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Rule of construction related to Congressional subpoenas</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section or in section 2702 shall limit the power of inquiry vested in the Congress by article I of the Constitution of the United States, including the authority to compel the production of a wire or electronic communication (including the contents of a wire or electronic communication) that is stored, held, or maintained by a person or entity that provides remote computing service or electronic communication service.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H3A7DADDAC7FE4278A271B16F21400533"><enum>4.</enum><header>Delayed notice</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2705 of title 18, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5E7615055CE04AE6AAA8E39F644988AD" style="USC"> <section id="HC6003C43320743BABEB269FC5A7C96CE"><enum>2705.</enum><header>Delayed notice</header> <subsection id="HEBBA377500A344CDB31EF6E2E763F4BF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A governmental entity acting under section 2703 may apply to a court for an order directing a provider of electronic communication service or remote computing service to which a warrant, order, subpoena, or other directive under section 2703 is directed not to notify any other person of the existence of the warrant, order, subpoena, or other directive.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA8A38B46400D4D078798FD19ED44AA6E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Determination</header><text>A court shall grant a request for an order made under subsection (a) for delayed notification of up to 180 days if the court determines that there is reason to believe that notification of the existence of the warrant, order, subpoena, or other directive will likely result in—</text>
 <paragraph id="H1AB62847B9734B0CBBC545347871D44C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>endangering the life or physical safety of an individual;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEDDF689508F2428DAE4D758A95C5F77D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>flight from prosecution;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3DDD6722A31B4B7CAD0670C1D832D6F8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>destruction of or tampering with evidence;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7BAFE648B4BC473BAD5C5E493FD70CAC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>intimidation of potential witnesses; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD6A128B304AE4346A966D9AFA1BEEC9A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>otherwise seriously jeopardizing an investigation or unduly delaying a trial.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H95CCF1EB6068486FBA1CFB77F44AA3D6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>Upon request by a governmental entity, a court may grant one or more extensions, for periods of up to 180 days each, of an order granted in accordance with subsection (b).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section commented="no" id="H4CBB2371094D4A1EABF079272D11DB27"><enum>5.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act or an amendment made by this Act shall be construed to preclude the acquisition by the United States Government of—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H8A69D83CD66747D1A3407AB5661522B6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the contents of a wire or electronic communication pursuant to other lawful authorities, including the authorities under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/119">chapter 119</external-xref> of title 18 (commonly known as the <quote>Wiretap Act</quote>), the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1801">50 U.S.C. 1801</external-xref> et seq.), or any other provision of Federal law not specifically amended by this Act; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HEDB9F7439DC345D0B5C64255C6E5B62D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">records or other information relating to a subscriber or customer of any electronic communication service or remote computing service (not including the content of such communications) pursuant to the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1801">50 U.S.C. 1801</external-xref> et seq.), <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/119">chapter 119</external-xref> of title 18 (commonly known as the <quote>Wiretap Act</quote>), or any other provision of Federal law not specifically amended by this Act.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20170206">Passed the House of Representatives February 6, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill>


