<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H79CE87D058724DEB863FC803FFB70480" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3791 IH: US Navy SEAL SCPO Tyrone Snowden Woods Ceremony Invitee Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3791</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170914">September 14, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001180">Mr. Schrader</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000791">Mr. Walden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To ensure that United States Government personnel, including members of the Armed Forces and
			 contractors, assigned to United States diplomatic missions are given the
			 opportunity to designate next-of-kin for certain purposes in the event of
			 the death of the personnel.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H0BF05E92E45542468D319A3E8D799E6D" style="OLC">
 <section id="H9B365A0F7A5E4E91BD06A404FF5ACDA2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>US Navy SEAL SCPO Tyrone Snowden Woods Ceremony Invitee Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HF6C92E49136348C492212921A31E517C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Invitation of designated next-of-kin to ceremonies honoring United States diplomatic mission personnel who die in service to the United States</header> <subsection id="H8F9A524F544F42C9931F3B7EC42C960A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text>
 <paragraph id="HC125ACFF48844BC9AD321A47DDDDB344"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Diplomatic mission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>diplomatic mission</quote> means any United States diplomatic or consular post or other mission under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of State.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H246B0BB5C5A047C68390D2115D4E454B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Member</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>member of a diplomatic mission</quote> means any Government official or employee, any member of the Armed Forces, or any United States citizen employed as a contractor, who is serving at, or is notified of imminent assignment to, a diplomatic mission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD23F580B0C504F33AAFD9934E461B2AC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Memorial service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>memorial service</quote> means an official event sponsored or held by a Federal agency to which members of the public are invited to honor the life of a member of a diplomatic mission who died in service to the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0396173D4ABD41618C168EA6CBD437BC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Next-of-kin</header><text>The term <quote>next-of-kin</quote>, with respect to a deceased member of a diplomatic mission, means the following individuals:</text> <subparagraph id="HF42436C6922246FAABA6D9EC458DAE1D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The surviving spouse of the deceased member.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5018B1373EB842B9BA26F372AF1FCFF9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The child or children of the deceased member (including stepchildren, adopted children, and illegitimate children).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0AD0BBC8D9A4943995D6ADECA50AFA2"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The parent or parents of the deceased member (including a natural parent, a stepparent, a parent of the member by adoption, a parent, stepparent, or adopted parent of the surviving spouse, and any other person who has stood in loco parentis to the member at any time for a continuous period of at least five years before the member became 21 years of age).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6BE26A708ADE486992F184308CC934A9"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The sibling or siblings of the deceased member (including stepsiblings and siblings by adoption).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A450D51837E4A63B467859FC3CA630F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The person authorized to direct the disposition of the remains of the deceased member.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1648EEFC32E949CFAF55D78C14E30D65"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Policy for Designation of next-of-Kin</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall—</text> <paragraph id="H3368D2637E6040A5B6862DA0CE27C380"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">proscribe a policy by which a member of a diplomatic mission may designate those next-of-kin who will be invited to, and be entitled to attend, any memorial service held to honor the life of the member of a diplomatic mission in the event of the death of the member in service to the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0A7D8228B4524189A0C46EE17C542D6E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">publicize the existence of the policy to each member of a diplomatic mission; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6501A93AC2AD4564979F0941CB848D42"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make forms reasonably available to each member of a diplomatic mission by which the designation of such next-of-kin may be made.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H67D0DF5612144ED0BEF42E9D513926D0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall carry out this section in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency, and the head of any other Federal agency that assign persons to serve as a member of a diplomatic mission.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAF6CB0D428314EB5B19F9C83C4126F2A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effect of failure To make designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a member of a diplomatic mission fails to complete the form described in subsection (b)(3) before the death of the member, the member shall be deemed to have designated all next-of-kin of the member for invitation to any memorial service held to honor the life of the member in the event of the death of the member in service to the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1481C9B824484A09A118244BFC849401"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of Construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section or the policy required by this section shall be construed to authorize a private cause of action or legal claim against the United States Government, a Department or agency thereof, or any private individual.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


