<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE amendment-doc PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/amend.dtd//EN" "amend.dtd">
<amendment-doc amend-degree="first" amend-type="engrossed-amendment"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 534 EAS: U.S. Wants to Compete for a World Expo Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<engrossed-amendment-form>
<congress display="no">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="no">1st Session</session><legis-num display="no">H.R. 534</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">In the Senate of the United States,</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20170504">May 4, 2017.</action-date></action><legis-type display="yes">Amendment:</legis-type></engrossed-amendment-form><engrossed-amendment-body><section id="id79b9f3988e7b4d61810361724b7a6d28" section-type="resolved"><text>That the bill from the House of Representatives (H.R. 534) entitled <quote>An Act to require the Secretary of State to take such actions as may be necessary for the United States to rejoin the Bureau of International Expositions, and for other purposes.</quote>, do pass with the following</text></section><amendment><amendment-instruction blank-lines-after="0"><text>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert:</text></amendment-instruction><amendment-block blank-lines-after="1" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic"><legis-body changed="added" display-enacting-clause="no-display-enacting-clause" id="H27ED6AC8946C402D827B6329E9A26E5C" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"><section changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" id="id2019d512-6ff3-41ee-a5a4-99d5f0aa2d95" reported-display-style="italic" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>U.S. Wants to Compete for a World Expo Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" id="ida50735e2-bd19-4bdd-842e-c3c43f5c3e4b" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="idde2a7d18-4a58-4172-988e-4d1347dce3cb"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Bureau of International Expositions (BIE) is the organization responsible for governing World Fairs and International Expositions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id23ebce53-6542-4a34-8251-6022522ee7ec"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 1(a) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/91/269">Public Law 91–269</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2801">22 U.S.C. 2801(a)</external-xref>) found that <quote>international expositions . . . have a significant impact on the economic growth of the region surrounding the exposition and . . . are important instruments of national policy</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idca049d17-0581-40af-affd-3e3ac64ce5b4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The United States has not been an active member of the BIE since 2001.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf49b4e92-5729-4f6d-bb00-5c392028a2e4"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">State and local governments and private entities in the United States have continued to participate in international expositions held in foreign countries as a means of promoting United States exports and creating jobs, but face significantly higher costs for such participation because the United States is not an active member.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id243fd12c-95a1-4279-ab83-a65e23a31e92"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">State and local governments and private entities in the United States have expressed interest in an international exposition being hosted in the United States, but the bid of a United States city, region, or State to host an international exposition is unlikely to be successful if the United States is not a member of the BIE.</text></paragraph></section><section changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" id="idd632239d-dac5-4d84-9504-5694f7b5cadd" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="id72811a93-7b1f-440f-b369-6f09dee7459e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the United States should rejoin the BIE immediately to promote domestic job creation, global branding, and tourism to the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6d3fd264-a445-4787-aaa6-90df62e0f600"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary of State, in partnership with the Secretary of Commerce, State and local governments, and private and non-profit entities, should take all necessary steps to facilitate the timely submission of a request to rejoin the BIE.</text></paragraph></section><section changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" id="id04036d6d-f7a0-4839-a13f-ca73e10f996c" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authorization</header><subsection id="idd986fdc8-f086-4fef-925d-3249847c2a4f"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State is authorized to take such actions as the Secretary determines necessary for the United States to rejoin and maintain membership in the BIE.</text></subsection><subsection id="id422da29f-5cdd-4141-b655-a1f5bc009f05"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization To accept private contributions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to funds otherwise available to the Secretary to carry out this section, the Secretary is authorized to accept contributions for such purpose.</text></subsection><subsection id="id3fec1da7-0932-430f-9d09-4501ab634b9f"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall notify the Committees on Foreign Affairs and Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Foreign Relations and Appropriations of the Senate upon taking any action under <internal-xref legis-path="4.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>.</text></subsection></section><section changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" id="id4249FB38B9E54CF2A3CF5DA95852C4B1" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>5.</enum><header>Continuation of prohibition on use of Federal funds for world's fair pavilions and exhibits</header><subsection id="idD052C6A534624464BCC61E35DF123891"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Continuation of prohibition</header><text>Nothing in this Act may be construed to authorize any obligation or expenditure prohibited by section 204 of the Admiral James W. Nance and Meg Donovan Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 2000 and 2001 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2452b">22 U.S.C. 2452b</external-xref>) (relating to limitations on the obligation or expenditure of funds by the Department of State for a United States pavilion or exhibit at an international exposition or world’s fair registered by the BIE).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBCD37CDF2B0A4AF1B9D63A99E8DB4A89"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on solicitation of funds</header><text>Section 204(b)(1)(C) of the Admiral James W. Nance and Meg Donovan Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 2000 and 2001 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2452b">22 U.S.C. 2452b(b)(1)(C)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after <quote>expositions</quote> the following: <quote>, except that no employees of the Department of State may, in their official capacity, solicit funds to pay expenses for a United States pavilion or other major exhibit at any international exposition or world’s fair registered by the Bureau of International Expositions</quote>.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></amendment-block></amendment></engrossed-amendment-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestor></attestor><role>Secretary</role></attestation-group></attestation><endorsement></endorsement></amendment-doc>


