<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HED003F9A66C14E11B4B5B209FA825C33" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2504 IH: To ensure fair treatment in licensing requirements for the export of certain echinoderms.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2504</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170517">May 17, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="P000611">Mr. Poliquin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To ensure fair treatment in licensing requirements for the export of certain echinoderms.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H1CEC09C283024D2495895449587CFBF3" style="OLC">
		<section id="H64DE9FA3A5F94D5ABC0FF51F3F7ECBED" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Exemption of exportation of certain echinoderms from permission and licensing requirements</header>
 <subsection id="H2021946E2610424187D5C57661047155"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service shall amend section 14.92 of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations, to clarify that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC19CA0D6176B42BCA8894777082A0215"><enum>(1)</enum><text>fish or wildlife described in subsection (b) are fishery products exempt from the export permission requirements of section 9(d)(1) of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1538">16 U.S.C. 1538(d)(1)</external-xref>); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA32B8E3C28414E598206483FBFF584F4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any person may engage in business as an exporter of such fish or wildlife without procuring permission under such section of that Act or an export license under subpart I of part 14 of such title.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H28778875ED2C4DA3997E056E2B58BF51"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered fish or wildlife</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The fish or wildlife referred to in subsection (a) are members of the phylum Echinodermata that are commonly known as sea urchins and sea cucumbers, including products thereof, that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H3ABA8F895B0047DBA9633E2BB5E78D3A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>do not require a permit under part 16, 17, or 23 of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H64CC389D381C4F85A57A963CD73F25D6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>are harvested in waters under the jurisdiction of the United States or are processed in the United States; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA4A669464F3E415280EC7AB4E5116042"><enum>(3)</enum><text>are—</text> <subparagraph id="H1CC22C6E3F514E84A3FD7D6E9461A7F9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>exported for purposes of human or animal consumption; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F8C41D7958D4D47B9E47E246594AE5E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>taken in waters under the jurisdiction of the United States or on the high seas for recreational purposes.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


