<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H7533E501C50C4301ABEB30A2E7E97548" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3025 IH: Fostering Unity Against Russian Aggression Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3025</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170622">June 22, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001245">Ms. Bordallo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001069">Mr. Courtney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001227">Mr. Brady of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001202">Mrs. Murphy of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000598">Mrs. Davis of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001304">Mr. Brown of Maryland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000754">Mr. Cooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001170">Ms. Shea-Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000465">Ms. Tsongas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001200">Mr. McEachin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000608">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001050">Ms. Hanabusa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000171">Mr. O'Halleran</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To strengthen security and deterrence in Europe and to hold the Russian Federation accountable for
			 violations of the Intermediate-Range Nuclear Forces Treaty, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H130F3F18335D4F87BF12274A592AABCE" style="OLC">
 <section id="H6B5C85CE847745398B0F66BA6675C9C5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fostering Unity Against Russian Aggression Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H0F3178CC9CA0410AB8190AA485F45D3F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and sense of Congress</header> <subsection id="H95B99760DF704BE4A80FF854EE326CAB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HDAAEF41F8B8A4D68B20DAB8269A439B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">General Curtis M. Scaparrotti, Commander of the United States European Command, testified before the House Armed Services Committee on March 27, 2017, that <quote>Today we face the most dynamic European security environment in history.</quote> and that <quote>Russia’s malign actions are supported by its diplomatic, information, economic, and military initiatives.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDB70F3A14C91498B8E4E5815747EA43E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Russian Federation continues to be in violation of INF Treaty as a result of testing and deploying a new nuclear-capable cruise missile.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H313DD0238DC44DAFA471579F6926B4EE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Russian Federation has shifted to a military doctrine that envisions using nuclear weapons in an attempt to end a failing regional conventional conflict. On June 25, 2015, Deputy Secretary of Defense Robert Work and then-Vice-Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff Admiral James Winnefeld testified before the House Armed Services Committee that <quote>Russian military doctrine includes what some have called an <quote>escalate to de-escalate</quote> strategy—a strategy that purportedly seeks to deescalate a conventional conflict through coercive threats, including limited nuclear use. We think that this label is dangerously misleading. Anyone who thinks they can control escalation through the use of nuclear weapons is literally playing with fire. Escalation is escalation, and nuclear use would be the ultimate escalation.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2F7AA108917A4139AE9C46D543D3065F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>General Scaparrotti noted in his March 27, 2017, testimony before the House Armed Services Committee that <quote>Moscow’s provocative rhetoric and nuclear threats increase the likelihood of misunderstanding and miscalculation.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H68A627490F2840D2B049496E37DF799F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Russian Federation continues to conduct ongoing influence campaigns aimed at undermining democracies around the world. According to an assessment by the intelligence community, <quote>Russian President Vladimir Putin ordered an influence campaign in 2016 aimed at the U.S. presidential election</quote>, which included the use of the Russian military intelligence organization. The intelligence community also assessed that Russia would apply lessons learned to future influence efforts worldwide, including against United States allies and their election systems.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE559EAB153304BCB8A750E1194F4E897"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Russian Federation continues its aggression on its periphery. In 2008, the Russian Federation fomented conflict in Georgia. The Russian Federation has also illegally occupied and attempted to annex Crimea. Further, the Russian Federation is directing combined Russian-Separatist units in eastern Ukraine, actively inciting violence and prolonging the most significant conflict in Europe.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8856CA4AA7294D66ACA05EFE56A27426"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The investment of over $5 billion in the European Reassurance Initiative (ERI), now the European Deterrence Initiative (EDI), has proven successful in significantly enhancing the ability of United States forces, NATO allies, and regional partners to deter Russian aggression. EDI has not only assured our European allies and partners but supported essential investments in NATO’s military capacity, interoperability, and agility.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9319AE3ABDDF4C699DD3BDBF3D21F8D0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="HD06CE42D446D462B98D908464320A5D3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Russian Federation should return to compliance with the INF Treaty in a verifiable manner as soon as possible;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H146EE0DEA87747D8880BAA6E575983C4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the risks of miscalculation in a crisis are exacerbated by the Russian Federation’s shift to a military doctrine of <quote>escalate to de-escalate</quote>, lowering the threshold for Russian use of nuclear weapons and thereby increasing the risk of using nuclear weapons, potentially escalating in to a massive nuclear exchange;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD0789EC3EBFD46A09EBBA0872475BF47"><enum>(3)</enum><text>strengthening effective and credible conventional deterrence, particularly on the northeastern flank of NATO, is a political and military priority;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H53498078272A40F4AE754812C06BA5E6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>NATO’s formal adoption at the 2014 Wales Summit of the goal for each member state to allocate at least two percent of its gross domestic product to its national defense budget within a decade should be commended, as increased defense spending by NATO member states is strongly encouraged to maintain the alliance’s strategic vitality through the enhancement of its collective capacity;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD5BE1387876147C782482E407276E994"><enum>(5)</enum><text>reaffirming support for the principle of collective defense in Article 5 of the North Atlantic Treaty for NATO allies is vital to a strong and meaningful alliance and is not conditional;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H22F4ACDF395A453DA864A01D98E2DD45"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subversive and destabilizing activities by the Russian Federation targeting NATO allies and partners causes concern and should be condemned;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2E38F178A63B4F3E891FBFF50C052202"><enum>(7)</enum><text>strengthened deterrence efforts by NATO allies, including NATO’s Enhanced Forward Presence, should be commended and enhancing defense cooperation efforts with NATO allies and partners should be encouraged;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H446709EC998A4A9BAB9AD6EC52F55E00"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">European Deterrence Initiative (EDI) investments are long-term and, as such, Congress expects future budgets to reflect United States commitment by planning for funding in the base budget, and further EDI should build on United States presence by increasing the United States permanent force posture; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB0E096D70A554143B97BE0AB123C4E44"><enum>(9)</enum><text>credible deterrence requires steadfast cooperation and joint action with NATO allies and partners and other United States allies and partners in Europe.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H7A5456ABA8214C36B8474032FBA45FA6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Strategy to counter threats by the Russian Federation</header>
 <subsection id="H80DD02C61D544850B923A5FD5658BE6B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Strategy required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with each of the Secretaries of the military departments, the Joint Chiefs of Staff, and the commanders of each of the regional and functional combatant commands, shall develop and implement a comprehensive strategy to counter threats by the Russian Federation.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HE9A4A410C6B44B3A905E3A4605F1FB88"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report required</header>
 <paragraph id="HDBB26CC3EBBC494291490EB669543685"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the strategy required by subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H43BDD509ACD84216A821CFA19417007A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by this subsection shall include the following elements:</text> <subparagraph id="HF5D06A1D2D4C4CBEA980C9146EEB3CF2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An evaluation of strategic objectives and motivations of the Russian Federation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF9050D7B614407CB6C934750B16FCAC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A detailed description of Russian threats to the national security of the United States, including threats that may pose challenges below the threshold of armed conflict.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F2BCADC923644EBB3FA06C5601547B1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A discussion of how the strategy complements the National Defense Strategy and the National Military Strategy.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35DD5280A51946B290B1DFA12B7CFC3D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A discussion of the ends, ways, and means inherent to the strategy.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8869E65A7840438EAA2AC76C6A263E0E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A discussion of the strategy’s objectives with respect to deterrence, escalation control, and conflict resolution.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7A74FC3FF4541ACB17E9555B580BF43"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the military activities across geographic regions and military functions and domains that are inherent to the strategy.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10D50031D96F434EA30D2CE63E677341"><enum>(G)</enum><text>A description of the posture, forward presence, and readiness requirements inherent to the strategy.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9AF1F95CDB4408F8778D2A35863E914"><enum>(H)</enum><text>A description of the roles of the United States Armed Forces in implementing the strategy, including—</text>
 <clause id="HAE39130B43C949B0AEF866881FC41A2E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the role of United States nuclear capabilities;</text> </clause><clause id="HBA95F94D603C449494BAFE669803B935"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the role of United States space capabilities;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8396C3E473EB4736B980DFD7BF3C4457"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the role of United States cyber capabilities;</text> </clause><clause id="H475FF1350AE64EC5B60B3F404C8E88C8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the role of United States conventional ground forces;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9C7DC60E000F4395BBB7456765828973"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the role of United States naval forces;</text> </clause><clause id="H940DFC39CD3A486D957B917DD61174B1"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the role of United States air forces; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H268443DD64D845619E8697AAEE123BF7"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the role of United States special operations forces.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22EE96F205FE497AB5C76AA3DB42FE1B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>An assessment of contributions of United States allies and partners in countering Russian threats and a description of the roles of allies and partners in implementing and sustaining the strategy.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H329EB2FB6B2E4D9897C6B01071D0A57E"><enum>(J)</enum><text>An assessment of the force requirements needed to implement and sustain the strategy.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BA8241AB5B0438891AF1367694F7399"><enum>(K)</enum><text>A description of the logistical requirements needed to implement and sustain the strategy.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5916FFF0551D400FBB7762983360DACD"><enum>(L)</enum><text>An assessment of the technological research and development requirements needed to implement and sustain the strategy.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D3D394565ED4773959092209EEFD6A8"><enum>(M)</enum><text>An assessment of the training and exercise requirements needed to implement and sustain the strategy.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8790437E6E448F6AFE72CDBD0028CAF"><enum>(N)</enum><text>An assessment of the budgetary resource requirements needed to implement and sustain the strategy through December 31, 2030.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE06F2BFA1B7B442DBDB212302C270200"><enum>(O)</enum><text>A discussion of how the strategy provides a framework for future planning and investments in regional defense initiatives, including the European Deterrence Initiative.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB328E6CE04274C17B8C24E9B4ABAF2C2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by this subsection shall be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0F045A953EF0471E9AB0E33E86E78C39"><enum>4.</enum><header>Strategy to increase conventional precision strike weapon stockpiles in the United States European
			 Command’s areas of responsibility</header>
			<subsection id="HDD6CADDD03FC49C5AD02364285085B6D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Strategy required</header>
 <paragraph id="HEA88F56D9D6E4CE4A9F5DAE8025F8756"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall develop and implement a strategy to increase conventional precision strike weapon stockpiles in the United States European Command’s areas of responsibility.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7F0EC187E0E8491F801511C102FEFE76"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The strategy required by this subsection shall include necessary increases in the quantities of such stockpiles that the Secretary determines will enhance deterrence and warfighting capability of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization forces.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4BE57A94B6E847318437B1697B701B3D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report required</header>
 <paragraph id="H384C7B14E1F1485DB45CE23C4C74529D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than April 1, 2018, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the strategy required by subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9A8FD9DCB8E1471A82801398044F3E21"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by this subsection shall be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA4E55A688EE749D7AB0638C7E842B697"><enum>5.</enum><header>Plan to counter the military capabilities of the Russian Federation</header>
			<subsection id="HF1F6E548446A403BB3F711E08A445C75"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Plan required</header>
 <paragraph id="H5D6D5C0AB74F4DF4B47626D590805C7D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall develop and implement a plan to counter the military capabilities of the Russian Federation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF59EE7B67CD24074AC9C3A79E75EA0FD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The plan required by this subsection shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H1AE16960EA7F4D2A8C77F5E255C59AA0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Accelerating programs to improve the capability of United States military forces to operate in a Global Positioning System (GPS)-denied or GPS-degraded environment.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6EE97D3665204E46AE6A2430BDEA8BB5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Accelerating programs of the Department of the Army to counter Russian unmanned aircraft systems, electronic warfare, and long-range precision strike capabilities.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H270B006B03D342A289CE7DCC5EAD4C98"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Countering unconventional capabilities and hybrid threats from the Russian Federation.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92D5CB7278594E2087C83DF42AC2D4EC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Any other elements that the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF703587033894FC1A99A35CCF7E23B0C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report required</header>
 <paragraph id="HF8289F5194604EB8AEAC1749D497108A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than April 1, 2018, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the plan required by subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBDF968409795436990F523E8E9077858"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by this subsection shall be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H84BB04E9BB60460196A89DF4D2BE9685"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="H40D5FA077FF744C6BD80F6953179F1E9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the strategy for the Department of Defense to counter unconventional warfare threats posed by adversarial state and non-state actors required by section 1097 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/92">Public Law 114–92</external-xref>) has not yet been submitted to the congressional defense committees and should be submitted without further delay; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H96D87F7D5FAC4BA881538169E7EA3C00"><enum>(2)</enum><text>concerns persist over the growing sophistication of unconventional and hybrid state-sponsored threats by the Russian Federation as demonstrated through its advancement and integration of conventional warfare, economic warfare, cyber and information operations, intelligence operations, and other activities to undermine United States national security objectives as well as the objectives of United States allies and partners in Europe.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H5C2CC6D0A6244C6DAAF4AC2A1732557B"><enum>6.</enum><header>Plan to provide training to the national security forces of United States allies and partners to
			 counter cyberspace operations and information operations of the Russian
			 Federation</header>
 <subsection id="H82510FDDFC4A401AB2BF1BE87618C6AC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="H76CEF728C68943EAA4276520BE1F2E5E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the establishment by the Commander of the United States European Command of the interagency Russian Information Group to counter Russian information operations against the United States and United States allies and partners should be supported and cooperation and synchronization of efforts and activities with the Department of State’s Global Engagement Center and with the NATO Strategic Communications Center of Excellence should be encouraged;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H500FAF027D02415FB448E80E0A9F4909"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Defense should, to the extent appropriate, prioritize the transfer of funds as authorized under section 1287(e) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>; 130 Stat. 2546) to the Department of State’s Global Engagement Center specifically for the purpose of countering Russia state-sponsored propaganda aimed at undermining the national security interests of the United States and United States allies and partners; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1C173A5F50424D75ACDFEEB95A7E5B41"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Defense should prioritize providing funding to the NATO Cooperative Cyber Defense Center of Excellence and the NATO Strategic Communication Center of Excellence or purposes of enhancing cooperation with NATO allies to counter cyberspace operations of the Russian Federation against the national security interests of the Untied States and United States and allies and partners.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCEAFEE9BC7D647AF9D0B28255930B186"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Plan required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall develop and implement a plan to provide training to the national security forces of United States allies and partners for the purpose of building the capacity of such forces to counter cyberspace operations and information operations of the Russian Federation.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H6BFB89DCC2394127847257D0E1CEAE31"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report required</header>
 <paragraph id="HA7283A51A44D401895650A08AC7F953B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than April 1, 2018, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the plan required by subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H06D0CED338234CD092E6D529F7A0F52B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by this subsection shall be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HDC23D9089D304C2EB13178B60AC20556"><enum>7.</enum><header>Report on maintaining and expanding forward presence of United States military forces and personnel
			 in Europe</header>
 <subsection id="H022149024C0A4E0B9B7464430343224E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than April 1, 2018, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the strategy of the Department of Defense maintaining and expanding forward presence of United States military forces and personnel in Europe.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H99AAC0B1304D4E83A2A6DCDEC0C4ADFE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include the following with respect to United States European Command areas of responsibility:</text>
 <paragraph id="HA636B4280D2540B2B0B3867D8C500F23"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An assessment of the additional permanently stationed forces in Europe required to meet United States strategic requirements and the operational requirements of the geographic combatant commander.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H206CA39066BE4E949901768DCD86F23C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An assessment of the infrastructure capacity of existing European locations and their ability to accommodate additional forces.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB7C8BEC1619141A5A8C134ECB3C85787"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An overview of new locations in Europe that might be considered for permanently stationed forces and the estimated cost and scope of infrastructure investments, to include improvements to training areas, which would be required at those locations to support permanently stationed forces, including an assessment of what infrastructure investments might be provided by the host-nation as well as new construction or modernization of existing facilities that would be funded by the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H429291064A614734ACDAABDC6DAC5D79"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A detailed list of investments in equipment, supplies, logistics, storage, and maintenance, at current and new locations in Europe, required to support additional permanently stationed forces.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4CFAA73A73054D1FBFDBC42ABDD0635D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An assessment of the readiness advantages and disadvantages associated with stationing additional permanent forces at European locations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7F2FC3816E3C447EA796096E87840A71"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A discussion of potential challenges with stationing additional permanent forces or developing new locations for permanently stationed forces as a result of treaty obligations, international agreements, or other legally binding instruments.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5621B16534DB4DFA84146E9554775245"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H30DE79A1CD424506BC4C61C4E7E2475D"><enum>8.</enum><header>Report on improving training areas in the United States European Command’s areas of responsibility</header>
 <subsection id="HBA049692863B4CB7A1AA74EB414F870D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than April 1, 2018, the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretaries of the military departments, the Commander of the United States European Command, and the Commander of the United States Special Operations Command, shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the location, capabilities, and capacities of training areas in the United States European Command’s areas of responsibility, including air and ground ranges, range complexes, military training routes, and special-use areas.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H75C48FBB160544499146F4506EAD5641"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="HB4E362CD723144D798AB32CD9E63A55E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An inventory of such training areas that are utilized by United States Armed Forces or with respect to which United States Armed Forces have access.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE38165E7E77C451C9A3F28BE7058F511"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An overview of the capabilities and capacity of such training areas to support permanent and rotational forward presence of United States Armed Forces.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFD28C53A10484896ABD18C561480D577"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An assessment of any capability gaps of such training areas that limit the ability to meet training standards of United States Armed Forces.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6DE0278C3C934975AEE2F5D03D6C32D5"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Details of current and planned investments in training infrastructure to mitigate identified capability gaps, help meet United States training standards, and support additional permanent or rotational forces in Europe, to be funded by the NATO, the United States, or United States allies or partners.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H145114765D4C448590A2A0904838823B"><enum>9.</enum><header>Sense of Congress on enhancing maritime capabilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress notes the 2016 Force Structure Assessment (FSA) that increased the requirement for fast attack submarine (SSN) from 48 to 66 and supports an acquisition plan that enhances maritime capabilities that address this requirement.</text>
		</section><section id="H84BFA6C0FC7C4EE3AF8481FC981DF32A"><enum>10.</enum><header>Plan to reduce the risks of miscalculation and unintended consequences that could precipitate a
			 nuclear war</header>
 <subsection id="H5AC3399F00A745988A49D4FB21B8271D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text> <paragraph id="HFD964BB4FEF84667994BE113E5CAFD04"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Russian Federation has adopted a dangerous nuclear doctrine that includes a strategy of <quote>escalate to de-escalate</quote>, which could lower the threshold for Russian use of nuclear weapons in a regional conflict; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDCC4D58CEF9746B0A1D9ACD1853413A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such nuclear doctrine exacerbates the risks of miscalculation and unintended consequences that could precipitate a nuclear war.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H04C3C7755E73486F91B1FB8DAD36B3BB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Plan required</header>
 <paragraph id="HA472FD71DC004CAA8FEA131428D7BE38"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than March 1, 2018, the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Chairman of the Joint Chief of Staff, the Commander of the United States Strategic Command, and the Commander of the United States European Command, shall submit to the congressional defense committees a plan that includes options to reduce the risk of miscalculation and unintended consequences that could precipitate a nuclear war.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCD67197EC76C4A31BEB76FBD44DB5EEA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The plan required under this subsection shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="HE281CC34A1AD42BB8BAF3F0EA793AB9D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an assessment of the value of military-to-military dialog to reduce such risk; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H723AEAE42AF1444C84B93CF9266EB9BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other recommendations the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H483739EAC9574C539CA5FBA8A96DA50D"><enum>11.</enum><header>Plan to impose sanctions with respect to the Russian Federation by reason of non-compliance by the Russian Federation with the INF Treaty</header> <subsection id="HDC7C293973334FA180A18250BCE20E7F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than April 1, 2018, the President shall submit to the congressional defense committees a plan to impose sanctions with respect to the Russia Federation by reason of non-compliance by the Russian Federation with the INF Treaty.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9F31E820920C4C0FAC221936C8AA7E2A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The plan required under subsection (a) should include expanding asset freezes and travel bans, prohibiting financial transactions, prohibiting government-to-government contracts, and any other sanctions that the President determines to be appropriate.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC819D259CE6342BE9EFFE2F4B6D4E495"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The plan required under subsection (a) shall provide for termination of sanctions described in the plan beginning on the date on which the President submits to the appropriate congressional committees a certification that the Russian Federation has verifiably returned to compliance with the INF Treaty.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H66C46612D0AB46D8B46E6A4F99ABCFA1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Cooperation</header><text>The Secretary of State shall seek to cooperate with United States allies and partners to maximize the effect of sanctions described in the plan required under subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H583A2CF341104239A9F7FF47C7C59A34"><enum>12.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H9309F2B0FBE94361BA6CA88B4F5A60A4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Congressional defense committees</header><text>The term <term>congressional defense committees</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101 of title 10, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2DC616F1B4F84CFC92DFCB4FC511F196"><enum>(2)</enum><header>INF Treaty</header><text>The term <term>INF Treaty</term> means the Treaty Between the United States of America and the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics on the Elimination of Their Intermediate-Range and Shorter-Range Missiles, commonly referred to as the Intermediate-Range Nuclear Forces (INF) Treaty, signed at Washington, December 8, 1987, and entered into force June 1, 1988.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H833FA53F61814564947F6A5255928812"><enum>(3)</enum><header>NATO</header><text>The term <term>NATO</term> means the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.</text> </paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

