<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H63402245208F4AFCA7EB31AC30611017" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 509 IH: ATF Elimination Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 509</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170112">January 12, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000244">Mr. Sensenbrenner</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To abolish the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives, transfer its functions
			 relating to the Federal firearms, explosives, and arson laws, violent
			 crime, and domestic terrorism to the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and
			 transfer its functions relating to the Federal alcohol and tobacco
			 smuggling laws to the Drug Enforcement Administration, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HDA2532FC02A04D6BA95FC2F22C2A698B" style="OLC">
 <section id="HCDEBCF49558E4EB5A2E7655D5925BD74" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>ATF Elimination Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H76197C46DDBE49068A4D8DF0472E9903"><enum>2.</enum><header>Elimination of hiring authority of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The hiring authority of the Director of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives is rescinded.</text>
		</section><section id="H96FB47FE45F64CB391B32F8C5748ADEA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Transfer plan</header>
 <subsection id="H39EFA069E95D4CFC8244574EB271EB82"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Within 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and the Administrator of the Drug Enforcement Administration shall jointly develop and submit to the Congress a plan for winding up the affairs of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives pursuant to this Act. The plan shall, to the maximum extent practicable, without compromising core functions, eliminate and reduce duplicative, unnecessary functions or waste.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9BCBC37DB3D74FCEA3B994021B1249B2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>FBI report to GSA on excess property To be transferred to the FBI</header><text>Within 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall transmit to the Administrator of the General Services Administration a report that specifies the property to be transferred to the Bureau pursuant to this Act that the Director has determined will not be needed by the Bureau.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H318D2AF5ED394C4898C2C9AB7665A2C3" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header>Abolition of Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives is abolished.</text> </section><section id="H95129CAF22754572A694C25755D9CC68"><enum>5.</enum><header>Transfer of functions relating to the Federal firearms, explosives, and arson laws, and to violent crime and domestic terrorism, to the Federal Bureau of Investigation</header> <subsection id="HCF0EB611A5224B8EB9BEF5BA02498987"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The functions relating to the investigation and enforcement of criminal and regulatory violations of the Federal firearms, explosives, and arson laws, and the investigation of violent crime and domestic terrorism, which on the effective date of this Act, were performed by the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives, are hereby transferred to the Attorney General.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE609596B90CF4382A1776BA88EAE9973"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Delegation of functions</header><text>The Attorney General shall delegate to the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation the functions transferred under this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4307B8AAA80341EE91CBF64890BBB986"><enum>(c)</enum><header>References</header><text>Any reference in any other Federal law, Executive order, rule, regulation, or delegation of authority, or any document of or pertaining to the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives with respect to functions transferred by this section—</text>
 <paragraph id="HECCCFFE9FC4C4BF2A4CD9D3B787670FB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to the Secretary of the Treasury or the head of that bureau is deemed to refer to the Attorney General; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC9EAF08838A249BBB6B32AA0CEDF2303"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to the Department of the Treasury or that bureau is deemed to refer to the Department of Justice or the Federal Bureau of Investigation, as appropriate.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD7FF542D2F8B4952B3F8397944D2B90E"><enum>6.</enum><header>Transfer of functions relating to the Federal alcohol and tobacco smuggling laws to the Drug
			 Enforcement Administration</header>
 <subsection id="H4204A317B12C47A082C56F6841432493"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The functions relating to investigation and enforcement of criminal ad regulatory violations of the Federal alcohol and tobacco smuggling laws, which on the effective date of this Act, were performed by the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives, are hereby transferred to the Attorney General.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCF4C1EF078F543999F09DF4BB88E5F62"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Delegation of functions</header><text>The Attorney General shall delegate to the Administrator of Drug Enforcement the functions transferred under this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA1F6973D1A474780B0F9CFE2EC6B975C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>References</header><text>Any reference in any other Federal law, Executive order, rule, regulation, or delegation of authority, or any document of or pertaining to the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives with respect to functions transferred by this section—</text>
 <paragraph id="H67CA8A5F59904F9E9A934F4AB97D7AC2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to the Secretary of the Treasury or the head of that bureau is deemed to refer to the Attorney General; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H62878B8B60CF41A3A84BDB1336901B94"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to the Department of the Treasury or that bureau is deemed to refer to the Department of Justice or the Drug Enforcement Administration, as appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF40F95D4536F4957902981F44ECE3DB9"><enum>7.</enum><header>Property and records</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The contracts, liabilities, records, property, and other assets and interests of, or made available in connection with, the functions transferred by this Act are hereby transferred to the Attorney General for appropriate allocation.</text>
		</section><section id="H4B74F1F430B546AC8506CC702AE370D4"><enum>8.</enum><header>Personnel</header>
 <subsection id="HB754B7BE514C45FC894EF4D60401441F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The personnel employed in connection with the functions transferred by this Act are hereby transferred to the Attorney General.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H07D107D6CC9841599951C115481F5E14"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effect</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the 1-year period beginning on the effective date of this Act, any full-time or part-time personnel employed in permanent positions shall not be separated or reduced in grade or compensation because of the transfer under this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HD9DDC67EA5CD4DF09C74C2B58ABA2497"><enum>9.</enum><header>Savings provisions</header>
 <subsection id="H81F08C7ABB974593BA40E069B01CE702"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Legal documents</header><text>All orders, determinations, rules, regulations, permits, grants, contracts, certificates, licenses, and privileges—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9D415B6E4EBF4DFAB0CF016535F17CB9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>that have been issued, made, granted, or allowed to become effective by the President, by the head of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives, the Attorney General, the Secretary of the Treasury, any other Government official, or a court of competent jurisdiction, in the performance of functions of the head of that bureau that are transferred by this Act, and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8A0E21BFFB3A4CE1952BD2AD228A8ACE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that are in effect on the effective date of this Act (or become effective after such date pursuant to their terms as in effect on such date),</text>
				</paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">shall continue in effect according to their terms until modified, terminated, superseded, set
			 aside, or revoked in accordance with law by the President, the Attorney
			 General or other authorized official, or a court of competent
 jurisdiction, or by operation of law.</continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="H425A44CE2DC34811BCCC8090CBF9D506"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Proceedings</header><text>The provisions of this Act shall not affect any proceedings or any application for any benefits, service, license, permit, certificate, or financial assistance pending before the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives on the effective date of this Act, but such proceedings and applications shall be continued. Orders shall be issued in such proceedings, appeals shall be taken therefrom, and payments shall be made pursuant to such orders, as if this Act had not been enacted, and orders issued in any such proceeding shall continue in effect until modified, terminated, superseded, or revoked by a duly authorized official, by a court of competent jurisdiction, or by operation of law. Nothing in this subsection shall be deemed to prohibit the discontinuance or modification of any such proceeding under the same terms and conditions and to the same extent that such proceeding could have been discontinued or modified if this Act had not been enacted.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H50F850FEA8E4413EB82BFB105810CE79"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Suits</header><text>The provisions of this Act shall not affect suits commenced before the effective date of this Act, and in all such suits, proceeding shall be had, appeals taken, and judgments rendered in the same manner and with the same effect as if this Act had not been enacted.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H84046CE8A9B44706B6993D71703BF318"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Nonabatement of actions</header><text>No suit, action, or other proceeding commenced by or against the head of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives, or by or against any individual in the official capacity of such individual as an officer of such bureau shall abate by reason of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7324BFC9EDC24DC7835EFE66731B57AF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Continuance of suits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, before the effective date of this Act, any agency or officer thereof in the official capacity of such officer, is party to a suit, and under this Act any function of such agency or officer is transferred to the Attorney General or any other official of the Department of Justice, then such suit shall be continued with the Attorney General or other appropriate official of the Department of Justice substituted or added as a party.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HA1A29AC97494400C9ABC2DF04E61CEBA"><enum>10.</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
			<subsection id="HF88C6B04D804499CB27FB7062BF1A7C8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendments to the Homeland Security Act of 2002</header>
 <paragraph id="HD6921096CBB94DA3A49001204EDDF0DC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 1111(d) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/531">6 U.S.C. 531(d)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6594B00F00F04E97BF46D4454FDC8375" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H572222ED6BA54B8F88A7E630AE42B2C1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Personnel management demonstration project</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Personnel Management Demonstration Project established under section 102 of title I of division C of the Omnibus Consolidated and Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act for Fiscal Year 1999 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/105/277">Public Law 105–277</external-xref>; 112 Stat. 2681–585) shall be transferred to the Secretary of the Treasury for continued use by the Tax and Trade Bureau.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8177404B575149CB95A4BA348ACD7554"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 1114(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/532">6 U.S.C. 532(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>Bureau</quote> and inserting <quote>Federal Bureau of Investigation</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H68D42087265842248BAF0AAAED81BFD8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amendments to the Enhanced Border Security and Visa Entry Reform Act of <enum-in-header>2002</enum-in-header></header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2(4) of the Enhanced Border Security and Visa Entry Reform Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1701">8 U.S.C. 1701(2)(4)</external-xref>) is amended by striking subparagraph (J) and redesignating subparagraphs (K) and (L) as subparagraphs (J) and (K), respectively.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3C5F96CB36A6499F8556A6841838ECC1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Amendment to the Firefighters’ Safety Study Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3(1) of the Firefighters’ Safety Study Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2223b">15 U.S.C. 2223b(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H34C4D3E9568649F5B1F2DC512390E69E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by adding <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (C);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H033502E5957D4EAE995361D9C8BBBFD7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>; and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (D) and inserting a comma; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA9CD8599A1B04DC183BFF7373D472CD0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (E).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6C862243A45742FA91976DE004C9251B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Amendments relating to title <enum-in-header>18</enum-in-header>, United States Code</header>
 <paragraph id="H4AC65868180A412082E954AD4CAEDA2C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 846(a) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>, together with the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives,</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H769CEA3EFDC24C6489E77D54890CDAF1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 514(b) of division B of the Consolidated and Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2013 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/923">18 U.S.C. 923</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/6">Public Law 113–6</external-xref>; 127 Stat. 271) is amended by striking <quote>Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives shall include in all such data releases</quote> and inserting <quote>Federal Bureau of Investigation shall include in all releases of data from firearm tracing studies</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H608CA4017CC24715B54C71BD6899AB5A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitations on use of funds for disclosure of firearms trace data</header>
 <subparagraph id="HD571859D2EED41098BBA80D28562B7F5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The 6th proviso under the heading <quote>Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives—Salaries and Expenses</quote> in title I of division B of the Consolidated and Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/923">18 U.S.C. 923</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/55">Public Law 112–55</external-xref>; 125 Stat. 609–610) is amended by striking <quote>Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>Federal Bureau of Investigation</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9100507683C749C38257E50930876B74"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The 6th proviso under the heading <quote>Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives—Salaries and Expenses</quote> in title II of division B of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/923">18 U.S.C. 923</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/117">Public Law 111–117</external-xref>; 123 Stat. 3128–3129) is amended by striking <quote>Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>Federal Bureau of Investigation</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0ACFE8F2DDFC4129A2A0200309C0DA83"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The 6th proviso under the heading <quote>Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives—Salaries and Expenses</quote> in title II of division B of the Omnibus Appropriations Act, 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/923">18 U.S.C. 923</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/8">Public Law 111–8</external-xref>; 123 Stat. 574–576) is amended by striking <quote>Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>Federal Bureau of Investigation</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2595DB43F78247DE8A0C73AF9D86104B"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The 6th proviso under the heading <quote>Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives—Salaries and Expenses</quote> in title II of division B of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/923">18 U.S.C. 923</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/161">Public Law 110–161</external-xref>; 121 Stat. 1903–1904) is amended by striking <quote>Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>Federal Bureau of Investigation</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBD8170CEE8354664800A32E55264B22B"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The 6th proviso under the heading <quote>Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives—Salaries and Expenses</quote> in title I of the Science, State, Justice, Commerce, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/923">18 U.S.C. 923</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/108">Public Law 109–108</external-xref>; 119 Stat. 2295–2296) is amended by striking <quote>Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>Federal Bureau of Investigation</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42789B5AF6044EEEA8DBB81537F7EC80"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The 6th proviso under the heading in title I of division B of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/923">18 U.S.C. 923</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/447">Public Law 108–447</external-xref>; 118 Stat. 2859–2860) is amended by striking <quote>Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>Federal Bureau of Investigation</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC8C0F6B6CCC4A0FAEFC630ED98C7B76"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Section 2343(c)(1) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives</quote> and inserting <quote>Drug Enforcement Administration</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8AEEF47FB2774670AA8698B36BEE0D0C"><enum>(5)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1E1DDF3920054ED7900C765AD969237A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 3051 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H955CD90D2D32489AAA8CC678A849A1F2" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the section heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">Special Agents of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">certain investigators and officers of the Department of Justice</header-in-text></quote>;</text> </clause><clause id="H04E81FE9DB4542E1B65C0FCFAED95944" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>(a) Special agents of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives, as well as any other</quote> and inserting <quote>Any</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H610323A31EC94EEC9422D77A07687DD7" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking subsection (b).</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D8DE7C195B14C4AB56BB49E102456E5" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The item relating to section 3051 in the table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/203">chapter 203</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE6D3D42FECFB4C27B3CB1C8E023A35DC" style="USC">
							<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
								<toc-entry level="section">3051. Powers of certain investigators and officers of the Department of Justice.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H654D577CFD6B4242980FEE7106500252"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Amendment to the National Drug Control Policy Reauthorization Act of <enum-in-header>1998</enum-in-header></header><text>Section 716(c)(1)(B) of the National Drug Control Policy Reauthorization Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/1714">21 U.S.C. 1714(c)(1)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>Agency, the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives,</quote> and inserting <quote>Administration</quote>.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H8A8740AD5C6A4356A855C6AD9BC83B15"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Amendments to the Internal Revenue Code of <enum-in-header>1986</enum-in-header></header>
 <paragraph id="HD61B13C47E0A426583A64E1F718C6132"><enum>(1)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">Section 6103(i)(8)(A)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">26 U.S.C. 6103(i)(8)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>making—</quote> and all that follows through <quote>(ii)</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD7B6656F128F46BE8B483155A7071E6D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 7801(a)(2)(A) of such Code (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7801">26 U.S.C. 7801(a)(2)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives</quote> and inserting <quote>Federal Bureau of Investigation</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA1ED8DB80106450DAC60E874ABDD5981"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Amendments to title <enum-in-header>28</enum-in-header>, United States Code</header> <paragraph id="HF83188B4D74442F9AB3D1BB540625FC5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 530C(b)(2) of title 28, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>for the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives,</quote> each place it appears.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE58734D2A1CF44A1A99B72D2553022A0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Chapter 40A of such title (28 U.S.C. 599A–599B) is repealed.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0744189E426C4D1AA41320715E18661C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Section 2006(2) of such title is amended by striking <quote>, the Director, Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives, Department of Justice,</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9A738C74736646CEA99A569DF1D05494"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Amendments to the Violence Against Women and Department of Justice Reauthorization Act of <enum-in-header>2005</enum-in-header></header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1107(a) of Violence Against Women and Department of Justice Reauthorization Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/28/534">28 U.S.C. 534</external-xref> note) is amended by striking paragraph (2) and redesignating paragraphs (3) through (13) as paragraphs (2) through (12), respectively.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H1EDBD49F36E5495DB4C7FF5E61E0215B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Amendments to title <enum-in-header>31</enum-in-header>, United States Code</header>
				<paragraph id="HC43EF79D5C0C48E3922B639CB83ED68C"><enum>(1)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF2336A6478C24B0FB2D06B79A284351B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 713 of title 31, United States Code, is amended—</text> <clause id="HA1950FDC20954A90AA93AA824B5DD345" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the section heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">Service, Tax and Trade Bureau, and Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">Service and Tax and Trade Bureau</header-in-text></quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDAA744C9D87D4D61BFA9490E012E4784" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>, and the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives, Department of Justice of the Department of the Treasury</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2C2E49D909D84831B11F861916FE46F0" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <subclause id="HFC459D2B01D7420E95B5431386440207"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in each of paragraphs (2) and (3), by striking <quote>either</quote> and inserting <quote>the</quote>; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H735B6AC1A4424361A016724844A0A592"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>, the Tax and Trade Bureau, Department of the Treasury, and the Director of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives, Department of Justice</quote> and inserting <quote>and the Tax and Trade Bureau, Department of the Treasury</quote>.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C533849532D48309EBF1599AE2B1CF8" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The item relating to section 713 in the table of sections for chapter 7 of such title is amended to read as follows:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H624A7572CE4B4C1C81E484F7141D3280" style="USC">
							<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
								<toc-entry level="section">713. Audit of Internal Revenue Service and Tax and Trade Bureau. </toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8483210992334ECA988E80BAECED7E95"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 1344(b)(6) of such title is amended by striking <quote>Director of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2208B56F288C4272BC4E2D1FA0DF56BC"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Amendment to the Justice Assistance Act of <enum-in-header>1984</enum-in-header></header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 609N(2) of the Justice Assistance Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/10502">42 U.S.C. 10502(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H3F7573F8E1D64C859C4506A40EA37FE6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by adding <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (L); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5F3FE7D4F6BE433D9B6B745907A8FD17"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (M) and redesignating subparagraph (N) as subparagraph (M).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H13F2DF92DB134DA4891A71961BF29A23"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Amendment to the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of <enum-in-header>1994</enum-in-header></header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 32401(a)(3)(B) of the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/13921">42 U.S.C. 13921(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives, Department of Justice</quote> and inserting <quote>Federal Bureau of Investigation</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H371E6944AFBA4F67B738CF9ED34063D7"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Amendment to title <enum-in-header>49</enum-in-header>, United States Code</header><text>Section 80304(d) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives, Department of Justice</quote> and inserting <quote>Drug Enforcement Administration</quote>.</text> </subsection></section><section id="HAE41C91733D54911982A77D46DA25600"><enum>11.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act (except sections 2 and 3) and the amendments made by this Act shall take effect 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


