<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H3BDE1E64308D468FB525294E90CFA27F" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2185 IH: Iran Sanctions Relief Review Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2185</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170427">April 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000606">Mr. Pittenger</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="Z000017">Mr. Zeldin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the President to transmit to Congress determinations and certifications of whether
			 foreign financial institutions listed in Attachment 3 or Attachment 4 to
			 Annex II of the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action have facilitated
			 transactions or provided services for foreign terrorist organizations,
			 sanctioned foreign persons, or Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps or any of
			 its officials, agents, or affiliates, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H2B0F4275E42B4C148D25B180A1A1CE98" style="OLC">
 <section id="H9C5D8D0B114A426D9D33B30F0803A374" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Iran Sanctions Relief Review Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H369BD1F78F2847BBAAF867EF1C41BBA6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Determination and certification of whether certain foreign financial institutions have facilitated transactions or provided services for covered persons</header> <subsection id="HD0522628762842AD98101E5EC6AFC683"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter for a period not to exceed 5 years, the President shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6A8C394A16D44119B7BDB5BE8C67962D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to each foreign financial institution, including an Iranian financial institution, listed in Attachment 3 or Attachment 4 to Annex II of the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action, determine whether the institution has, on or after January 30, 2016, knowingly facilitated a significant transaction or transactions or provided significant financial services for any person described in section 4; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9DC6C28C0A6742CEA4AE79E721C876BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a certification of each determination with respect to a foreign financial institution, including an Iranian financial institution, made under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H386C9C4E6667449C87CA9EB6BFB77E2F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text>A certification described in subsection (a)(2) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0EE87214A42C4217B0183E463FA8F833"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Determination of significant transaction or transactions and significant financial services</header><text>For purposes of this section, a transaction or transactions shall be determined to be significant and financial services shall be determined to be significant in accordance with section 561.404 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HA5841957FDC6456A8D5F57D648101082"><enum>3.</enum><header>Determination and certification of whether certain foreign persons have supported covered persons</header>
 <subsection id="HAFD5EE6F088E4AB58CC3EADB20DF11EE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter for a period not to exceed 5 years, the President shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2D01EC3469304BFB989E02812BE34A92"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to each foreign person listed in Attachment 3 or Attachment 4 to Annex II of the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action, determine whether the foreign person has, on or after January 30, 2016, knowingly, directly or indirectly, materially assisted, sponsored, or provided financial, material, or technological support for, or goods or services in support of any person described in section 4; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4A2EE1EE389C4019B957043AD664E83E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a certification of each determination with respect to a foreign person made under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H11087D236BC747D294AD50C02FF4C205"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A determination described in subsection (a)(2) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HB470719164D34EEB8BAE28448FA03CB2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Covered persons</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A person described in this section is—</text> <paragraph id="HC9C168B4E00E49AF99B71E4503CB4027"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an organization that is designated by the Secretary of State as a foreign terrorist organization pursuant to section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3B2B880D389E40EC96131A03567146ED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a foreign person the property or interests in property of which are blocked pursuant to—</text> <subparagraph id="HF5F667D8A91F4D43BB3D07DECB259688"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Executive Order 13224 (September 23, 2001; relating to blocking property and prohibiting transactions with persons who commit, threaten to commit, or support terrorism);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H48936FEB7ED449B0949FE42F03C63427"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Executive Order 13382 (June 28, 2005; relating to blocking property of weapons of mass destruction proliferators and their supporters);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H31351D15BF3944FABFBF0A367CD4796F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Executive Order 13094 (July 28, 1998; relating to proliferation of weapons of mass destruction);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H963EA33B3B4342D8A8FF59025BF2EFF4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Executive Order 12938 (November 16, 1994; relating to proliferation of weapons of mass destruction);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F983B80CD0D4CD08782B9C85E630BEF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Executive Order 13338 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note; relating to blocking property of certain persons and prohibiting the export of certain goods to Syria);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4A1CE621C874133B62905699060792A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Executive Order 13399 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note; relating to blocking property of additional persons in connection with the national emergency with respect to Syria);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD30F79A85E864865B6458AB5D3CA9BFC"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Executive Order 13460 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note; relating to blocking property of additional persons in connection with the national emergency with respect to Syria);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8B7DBBE59E340AAA47D52A3B3FE68EF"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Executive Order 13572 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note; relating to blocking property of certain persons with respect to human rights abuses in Syria);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE679C3170B1F4C31A6BF6AF436A481A7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Executive Order 13573 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note; relating to blocking property of senior officials of the Government of Syria);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF248393FFDC64E739F4A3E9CB47757B4"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Executive Order 13582 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note; relating to blocking property of the Government of Syria and prohibiting certain transactions with respect to Syria);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C69CE357ABF4E449E08C5BC0C8C5A6D"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Executive Order 13608 Prohibiting Certain Transactions With and Suspending Entry Into the United States of Foreign Sanctions Evaders With Respect to Iran and Syria;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90087ACBA1AA41F8BB0636C3EC7974F2"><enum>(L)</enum><text>Executive Order 13606 Blocking the Property and Suspending Entry Into the United States of Certain Persons With Respect to Grave Human Rights Abuses by the Governments of Iran and Syria via Information Technology;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED2AFD41692140759D800BF3CA64C0DD"><enum>(M)</enum><text>Executive Order 13553 Blocking Property of Certain Persons With Respect to Serious Human Rights Abuses By The Government of Iran and Taking Certain Other Actions; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F3617F7D775454CBC676680959C4552"><enum>(N)</enum><text>any other Iranian person the property or interests in property of which are blocked pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.); or</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEAE83E67636640AC82BFAE63928E2EB1"><enum>(3)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB1AFC1E58332494A8371B5D249049E4C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps or any of its officials, agents, or affiliates; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEEC66322969A40FDB55C1CA28CC18F09" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a person acting on behalf of or at the direction of, or owned or controlled by, a person described in subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H6BC67FB6E93746A6B6248CA0452733BA"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H6BE8FEBFD189493E86EEDD05579D1842"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> has the meaning given the term in section 14 of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/172">Public Law 104–172</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H9EC64135BB95459EB246FA0843239D79"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign financial institution</header><text>The term <term>foreign financial institution</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1010.605 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3437294E302A40B08A14B8C66E765B4C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <term>foreign person</term>—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HC8A0E8EE641B4D128CE1B7B350F832EF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HC6B976FD7F1541B287C84F448ABC5778"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a natural person who is not a United States person;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HE1062DE77D3745C8A4112CD33F812DEF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a corporation, partnership, or other nongovernmental entity which is not a United States person; or</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HC04205913DF3443E911353B948D8A55D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any representative, agent or instrumentality of, or an individual working on behalf of a foreign government; but</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE3373CB68E9E49BF96D24553A1C78E02"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include a foreign financial institution, including an Iranian financial institution, described in section 2(b).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H5ED92D0064EB42C79E906B7BA29D63A1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Foreign terrorist organization</header><text>The term <term>foreign terrorist organization</term> means any organization designated by the Secretary of State as a foreign terrorist organization in accordance with section 219(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189(a)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF6E463AFB4344A50AADF9F9DF3C9515C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Iranian financial institution</header><text>The term <term>Iranian financial institution</term> has the meaning given the term in section 104A(d)(3) of the Comprehensive Iran Sanctions, Accountability, and Divestment Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8513b">22 U.S.C. 8513b(d)(3)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H82C04F5ACFBA447780121995054D2A39"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Joint comprehensive plan of action</header><text>The term <term>Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action</term> means the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action, agreed to at Vienna July 14, 2015, by Iran and by the People’s Republic of China, France, Germany, the Russian Federation, the United Kingdom and the United States, with the High Representative of the European Union for Foreign Affairs and Security Policy, and all implementing materials and agreements related to the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action, and transmitted by the President to Congress on July 19, 2015, pursuant to section 135(a) of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, as amended by the Iran Nuclear Agreement Review Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/17">Public Law 114–17</external-xref>; 129 Stat. 201).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H065B2582A1DF440BBEC13BFAA6548A36"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Person</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>person</term> has the meaning given the term in section 14 of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/172">Public Law 104–172</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H77FD644555DC48B1A271E51FA780D12E"><enum>(8)</enum><header>United States person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> has the meaning given the term in section 14 of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/172">Public Law 104–172</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note).</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


