<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5920CAC5F62946A1B85FD56F7DD01A5D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2720 IH: Procurement Fraud Prevention Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2720</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170525">May 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001170">Ms. Shea-Porter</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001069">Mr. Courtney</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require notice of cost-free Federal procurement technical assistance in connection with registration of small business concerns in procurement systems.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H64800A223DEA4B848A53DB9E3ECAA244" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H22177BFECE6B4BEA9343C5A2ABA353D8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Procurement Fraud Prevention Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB395D40052484A0DB29FB981347944B5" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Notice of cost-free Federal procurement technical assistance in connection with registration of small business concerns in procurement systems</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Administrator of General Services, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, shall establish procedures to ensure that any notice or direct communication regarding registration of a small business concern in a procurement system contains information about cost-free Federal procurement technical assistance services that are available through the Small Business Administration, Procurement Technical Assistance Centers of the Defense Logistics Agency, the Department of Commerce (including the Minority Business Development Agency), and other Federal agencies and programs.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

