<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HDC3D00A5CEDF45859154FDC458B3686A" key="H" public-private="public"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3639 IH: Science Laureates of the United States Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-08-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3639</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20170801">August 1, 2017</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000563">Mr. Lipinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000608">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001111">Mr. Crist</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001050">Ms. Hanabusa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001166">Mr. McNerney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To establish a position of Science Laureate of the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HEA1791CD74894411826E44FBC4067554" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7D1C8D96B6EE4E16B02584077A584DEE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Science Laureates of the United States Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H3B0C91361FE84832A4FA7FEF0BFC64E5" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and recognition</header> <subsection id="H45BA16915D724644BFA3EC1D2B1B549E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H8718258850EE4E9C92F65F7FADF2E393"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Scientific research and advancement has driven success in the United States and global success for centuries.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HCD662983B3CF46BB8446B82BE2F2F1F2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Scientific research has saved, improved, and extended lives, increased the standard of living, expanded economic opportunity, and advanced human understanding.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H191466F493704AA09CE2AB5614541888"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Such research holds the promise of continuing this progress, protecting the environment, creating jobs, growing the economy through innovative ideas and discoveries, and generally advancing all mankind.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H8CB7273C005544AEBB51AF19F3980BE6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>People in the United States can benefit when scientific research is conducted and communicated in a transparent manner to better inform citizens about the nature and status of such research.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5FF4E89254C840BEA3C0BEC03025CEEF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Scientific education is a critical element of preparing our Nation and our citizens for a technology-intensive future and ensuring that the United States remains the world leader in innovation and high-tech success.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H1DD916C3D929407EA78923BE0F6DE6D4"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A spokesperson who can embody, demonstrate, and articulate the importance and excitement of scientific research and education will help improve the current and future state of science to the benefit of all people in the United States.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3ECEA9C02C664769B6403831E803F5CE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Congressional recognition</header><text>Congress recognizes that science contributes to the economic prosperity and general welfare of the United States, and that increasing the public’s awareness about the sciences will increase such benefits. Congress also recognizes that scientists who are both accomplished in their fields and who foster the public’s interest in science do a special service to the United States.</text> </subsection></section> <section id="H43F98A307AA5437EA5FA6290FB6F4DFB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of Science Laureates of the United States</header> <subsection id="H45727FC99B984F37BF84BBC0C915056F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Position established</header><text>The National Science Foundation shall establish the position of Science Laureate of the United States to honor the service of scientists.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H210634EAB1664093ABAEA549A45ABF0E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appointment by National Science Foundation</header><text>The Science Laureate of the United States shall be appointed by the National Science Foundation from among individuals nominated under subsection (c).</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H60926707AE14471685A7B06D40EA4559"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Nominations by National Academy of Sciences</header> <paragraph id="H927A34F48DD2444A89388856D01B4A08"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agreement</header><text>The National Science Foundation shall seek to enter into an agreement with the National Academy of Sciences to perform the services covered by this subsection.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBE9684C2D3784113B7C926066F1923F3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nomination</header> 
<subparagraph id="H6885709CB0C045BCAED9D767D625239E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Under an agreement between the National Science Foundation and the National Academy of Sciences under this subsection, the National Academy of Sciences shall, not less frequently than once each year and except as provided in subparagraph (D), nominate three individuals to serve as the Science Laureate.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA5518650CAA841ED89B7440593F1D5A4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Basis</header><text>Nomination under subparagraph (A) shall be on the basis of merit, particularly the ability of an individual to—</text> 
<clause id="HC8A73B91C44844568AAA9C9D73001BCF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>foster and enhance public awareness and interest in science; and</text> </clause> <clause id="H2D505C9780D24F6090F99F01E744479D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide ongoing significant scientific contributions.</text> </clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H628159E11B45479CA9E91EB3CF904490"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Variety of scientific disciplines</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In nominating individuals under subparagraph (A), the National Academy of Sciences shall strive to nominate individuals, in different years, from different scientific disciplines, including biology, physics, geosciences, astronomy, mathematics, chemistry, and other science disciplines.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6CCF4A295A714BCA92653B6B97CEE641"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The National Academy of Sciences shall not make any nominations under this paragraph for a year if the National Science Foundation notifies the National Academy of Sciences that such nominations are unnecessary because the National Science Foundation intends to extend the term of the current Science Laureate pursuant to subsection (f).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H911855E1318F4786BACAC2922B882886"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duties</header> 
<paragraph id="H8A08B4A525B14609B5B7B6842B2704C2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each Science Laureate shall engage the public, from time to time, to increase the public’s awareness about science.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HA1FBA81D7E5D4F059646184CD123188E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Continuation of scientific work</header><text>A Science Laureate is encouraged to continue the Science Laureate's scientific work.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFDEB5F01CB72452BAD331767EFB968FD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Facilitation of duties</header><text>The National Science Foundation shall facilitate the duties of a Science Laureate and the Science Laureate may accept assistance from the National Academy of Sciences in carrying out such duties.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6C05A82A0593420DA9DAD6C0F9A62A75"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Science Laureate position shall not have the effect of duplicating or superseding the role of the President’s Science Advisor.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HC3AB5ECC13B04F4CA4468544F8FFC466"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Term</header><text>Each Science Laureate shall serve a 1-year term and may be reappointed by the National Science Foundation for additional terms as the National Science Foundation considers appropriate.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H988C911B47F648DFB0DD10F5FA500F68"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Compensation; Reimbursement</header> <paragraph id="HF66C06CE79EA47E09297C88B46E92A89"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a Science Laureate shall serve without pay and shall not be considered to be a Federal employee based on such individual's appointment as a Science Laureate.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0C5674434B79481BACE6B3C0C1D6B4B1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reimbursement for travel</header><text>The National Science Foundation may provide a Science Laureate with reimbursement for travel expenses incurred while performing duties as a Science Laureate, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in accordance with applicable provisions in the same manner as persons employed intermittently in the Government service are allowed expenses under section 5703 of title 5, United States Code.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

