<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1E54DBEB16F342398146CDCBC58C2F46" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3326 RH: World Bank Accountability Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
		<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 214</calendar>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3326</legis-num>
		<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 115–298]</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20170720">July 20, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HBA00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<action><action-date>September 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsor: <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action>
			<action-date>September 7, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the
			 Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
			<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction>
			<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on July 20, 2017</action-instruction>
		</action>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-desc display="yes"><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To increase accountability, combat corruption, and strengthen management effectiveness at the World
			 Bank.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body changed="added" committee-id="HBA00" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H55DC5DA1C2F4436EB2089AD6A4638086" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <section id="HB0628C0F20A54D1C988CD207B31000DD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>World Bank Accountability Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HE74FA06218564E6ABBE69D3E681C9E06"><enum>2.</enum><header>Withholding of funds until certain conditions are met</header> <subsection id="H5C199E4BDAA640899F9E3518B3B343AC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Institutional reforms</header> <paragraph id="HD9928CBDAB8946C6AD238EFF566044DD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to each of fiscal years 2018 through 2023, in addition to any amounts withheld from disbursement under subsection (b), 15 percent of the amounts provided in appropriations Acts for the International Development Association for the fiscal year—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7716F7B5010C4CDAAB4372BBB2A69236"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be withheld from disbursement until the conditions of paragraph (2) or (3) are satisfied; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H099B864517B746D5B927799896585E91"><enum>(B)</enum> <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H9D7446268BDD4F369510264FBF6A227B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be disbursed after the conditions of paragraph (2) are satisfied; and</text>
 </clause><clause changed="added" committee-id="HBA00" id="H5161E495EE1847C3AC0C2F6B883DF66C" indent="up1" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may be disbursed after the conditions of paragraph (3) are satisfied</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A5DCBB6E8534A1A9BE30A22EEA149E8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The conditions of this paragraph are satisfied with respect to the amounts provided in appropriations Acts for a fiscal year if, in the fiscal year, the Secretary of the Treasury reports to the appropriate congressional committees that the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development—</text>
 <subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA2C5416D91B04650B7E054C2BD7C8885"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is implementing institutional incentives, including through formal staff evaluation criteria, that prioritize poverty reduction, development outcomes, and capable project management over the volume of the Bank’s lending and grantmaking;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6F0B8A056764FF483774C8DAA6DA92E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is taking steps to address the management failures described in Inspection Panel Investigation Report 106710–UG, and to prevent their recurrence in countries that are eligible for World Bank support; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F4BF5E83A6247DC837EB578ED2ABE3F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is taking measures to strengthen its management of trust funds, with the goal of increasing the accountability of the trust funds for poverty reduction and development outcomes.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC6A0B744EF244829730DDB4D9254790"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Subsequent conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The conditions of this paragraph are satisfied if the Secretary of the Treasury reports to the appropriate congressional committees, in each of the 3 fiscal years most recently preceding the fiscal year in which the report is made, that the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development has instituted the measures described in paragraph (2) of this subsection and the measures described in subsection (b)(2).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H96F99A842CE846889B4B9C344F41F6FC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Governance and anticorruption reforms</header>
 <paragraph id="H8F2E0B4A48FE436CB94B479E1BD55E57"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to each of fiscal years 2018 through 2023, in addition to any amounts withheld from disbursement under subsection (a), 15 percent of the amounts provided in appropriations Acts for the International Development Association for the fiscal year—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDDEF47D282BE485BB8070CE76DCFFD44"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be withheld from disbursement until the conditions of paragraph (2) or (3) are satisfied; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C2073F699E148BA9F4B581CDA4AF6C2"><enum>(B)</enum> <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H544E7DB08EDF42DAA3BA24ED83B5A0AB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be disbursed after the conditions of paragraph (2) are satisfied; and</text>
 </clause><clause changed="added" committee-id="HBA00" id="H0DF70BEC329041D5B40CE316477215A0" indent="up1" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may be disbursed after the conditions of paragraph (3) are satisfied</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3EEF0CC31670469896FEAE01AE29D167"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The conditions of this paragraph are satisfied with respect to the amounts provided in appropriations Acts for a fiscal year if, in the fiscal year, the Secretary of the Treasury reports to the appropriate congressional committees that the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development—</text>
 <subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAE326E7DA3204876B6FA856C3565D9D1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is emphasizing in appropriate operational policies, directives, and country strategies its support for secure property rights, due process of law, and economic freedom as essential conditions for sustained poverty reduction in World Bank borrowing countries;</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H16F463F917994797A4488460B4106B3F"><enum>(B)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H9C437DE7B09F4BC4A763FC4063537731"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the preceding fiscal year, has not approved any loans or grants assistance by the Bank to a country designated by the United States as a state sponsor of terrorism; and</text>
 </clause><clause changed="added" committee-id="HBA00" id="HB3C2F6E47E184AA1A983B4AAB7A72850" indent="up1" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is strengthening the ability of Bank-funded projects to undermine violent extremism;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2D8690F663B4E5A979CA0F5C097178C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is taking steps to conduct forensic audits of projects receiving assistance from the Bank, increase the number of the forensic audits, and strengthen the capacity of the Bank’s Integrity Vice Presidency, and that not less than 50 percent of the forensic audits initiated by the Bank in each fiscal year are of projects randomly selected from among International Development Association borrowing countries; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H26AE5CBC7DC245C3A8998FD4F5611EAE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is taking measures to detect and minimize corruption in all World Bank projects involving development policy lending.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE953AA54C874A3A8D7D18CB27FED47B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Subsequent conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The conditions of this paragraph are satisfied if the Secretary of the Treasury reports to the appropriate congressional committees, in each of the 3 fiscal years most recently preceding the fiscal year in which the report is made that the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development has instituted the measures described in paragraph (2) of this subsection and the measures described in subsection (a)(2).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBDE35B854A03473D8121232EE35E7BA4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means the Committees on Financial Services and on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Foreign Relations and on Appropriations of the Senate.</text>
 </subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H435DBE2E3316431EAF369F1E5EC7932C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Chairman of the National Advisory Council on International Monetary and Financial Policies shall include in the report required by section 1701 of the International Financial Institutions Act for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2023 a detailed description of the actions undertaken by the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development in the fiscal year covered by the report to institute the measures described in subsections (a)(2) and (b)(2) of section 2 of this Act.</text>
		</section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAA28B6B00AB14D01AB6DBA9CBC368307"><enum>4.</enum><header>Opposition to World Bank assistance for government that fails to implement or enforce measures
 required under an applicable United Nations Security Council resolution</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Bretton Woods Agreements Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/286">22 U.S.C. 286</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HBA00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA24C95256B784D2087693D1F6B577BE0" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
				<section id="H2AF272D61B6C4A5C9E554FC0053147FD"><enum>73.</enum><header>Opposition to assistance for government that fails to implement or enforce measures required under
 an applicable United Nations Security Council resolution</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury should instruct the United States Executive Director at the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development to use the voice and vote of the United States to oppose the provision of assistance to the government of a borrowing country of the International Development Association if the President of the United States determines that the government has knowingly failed to implement or enforce sanctions required under an applicable United Nations Security Council resolution (as defined in section 3 of the North Korea Sanctions and Policy Enhancement Act of 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/122">Public Law 114–122</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9202">22 U.S.C. 9202</external-xref>)) that is in effect.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H38F956580A2749ADB564F57E416609B7"><enum>5.</enum><header>Eighteenth replenishment of the International Development Association; reduction from IDA-<enum-in-header>17</enum-in-header> authorized level</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The International Development Association Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/284">22 U.S.C. 284</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HBA00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H07190406F01F4091B5D22782C52EDC23" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
				<section id="H3D4E16D1EE38449182136564A90D04C2"><enum>30.</enum><header>Eighteenth Replenishment</header>
 <subsection id="HE668B9256E9E48E4B0B7EE322AB8C88F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Contribution authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Governor of the International Development Association may contribute on behalf of the United States $3,291,030,000 to the eighteenth replenishment of the resources of the Association, subject to obtaining the necessary appropriations.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC4D3619FE6AD4294AC0B76B8213A345C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitations on authorization of appropriations</header><text>In order to pay for the contribution provided for in subsection (a), there are authorized to be appropriated, without fiscal year limitation, $3,291,030,000 for payment by the Secretary of the Treasury.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body>
	<endorsement display="yes">
		<action-date>September 7, 2017</action-date>
		<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the
			 Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill>


