<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF2D3EA91960B477E92CCA02278C46770" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4675 IH: Low-Dose Radiation Research Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4675</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171218">December 18, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001198">Mr. Marshall</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000563">Mr. Lipinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000583">Mr. Smith of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to provide for a low-dose radiation basic research program.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H2B168F86C1684E0DA12904F0E9353809" style="OLC">
 <section id="H28719BDD7DAB4B7D94B180ED5907BCBB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Low-Dose Radiation Research Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HBA73E483950F43E0A91642182D3CC38C" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Low-dose radiation research program</header> <subsection id="H3F8A3D847CFE4A30BE865BCC6CE71A40"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle G of title IX of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16311">42 U.S.C. 16311</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by inserting after section 977 the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H67BE5DE3533F419C9E552AC8C7AFD755" style="OLC">
					<section id="H1356F7B1D539410C9D391FC049E86E47"><enum>977A.</enum><header>Low-dose radiation research program</header>
 <subsection id="H2CEA91B0F5364FAE873E1D8A82EEE02B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out a basic research program on low-dose radiation to—</text> <paragraph id="H420E9C3A9D2D442A9C2494E821DFBFFB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>enhance the scientific understanding of, and reduce uncertainties associated with, the effects of exposure to low-dose radiation; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7262BA39D58B417FB78854269ECA828D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">inform improved risk-assessment and risk-management methods with respect to such radiation.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC2416DAC6EF2418EB5D9A38DE9445994"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program components</header><text>In carrying out the program required under subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H031604E618F34AAAB5FE034E1E651DF1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>formulate scientific goals for low-dose radiation basic research in the United States;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H116631E355F643FFAFADA5B95EBC3531"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify ongoing scientific challenges for understanding the long-term effects of ionizing radiation on biological systems;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H570FB1586A3C459FBFC05318AC9AE1C7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>develop a long-term strategic and prioritized basic research agenda to address such scientific challenges in coordination with other research efforts;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE9D17EA13BE4382A84701E9B45CDE86"><enum>(4)</enum><text>leverage the collective body of knowledge from existing low-dose radiation research; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H57F8025A73134D3CB652007DE9C63F29"><enum>(5)</enum><text>engage with other Federal agencies, research communities, and potential users of information produced under this section, including institutions concerning radiation research, medical physics, radiology, health physics, and emergency response.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAAE1141BEED8423F8A761758F0309730"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the program, the Secretary, in coordination with the Physical Science Subcommittee of the National Science and Technology Council, shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H571FCB39ECA7419F8F13FC9A37AF1829"><enum>(1)</enum><text>support the directives under section 106 of the American Innovation and Competitiveness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6601">42 U.S.C. 6601</external-xref> note);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8D2705769C8B4F119B534F865EA4DBCC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure that the Office of Science of the Department of Energy consults with the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the National Institutes of Health, the Environmental Protection Agency, the Department of Defense, the Nuclear Regulatory Commission, and the Department of Homeland Security;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9538CDFFC43F431093767D3E5CD65C1C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advise and assist the National Science and Technology Council on policies and initiatives in radiation biology, including enhancing scientific knowledge of the effects of low-dose radiation on biological systems to improve radiation risk-assessment and risk-management methods; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBE8A2F93B5A04999B23527DF56915895"><enum>(4)</enum><text>identify opportunities to stimulate international cooperation relating to low-dose radiation and leverage research and knowledge from sources outside of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HADBD234BC0B44415A4BA6D4F33BD2F0C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Research plan</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall transmit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a 4-year research plan that identifies and prioritizes basic research needs relating to low-dose radiation. In developing such plan, the Secretary shall incorporate the components described in subsection (b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H17E4E81CD4224834AACB641F777F7573"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definition of low-Dose radiation</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>low-dose radiation</quote> means a radiation dose of less than 100 millisieverts.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H339EECC3F1064DC78A993A5FF8C1DB29"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to subject any research carried out by the Secretary for the program under this section to any limitations described in 977(e) of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16317">42 U.S.C. 16317(e)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H506E7D1114044C0D9C2FE16723BB58F9"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>For purposes of carrying out this section, the Secretary is authorized to make available from funds provided to the Biological and Environmental Research Program—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF2A64E9E0B7B4D38A051DBFAD7B94C6B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$20,000,000 for fiscal year 2018;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA216F49EF891428CA8EEBD76E82D8BD1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$20,000,000 for fiscal year 2019;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE1B4AE237703454F89540AF25298A1F9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>$30,000,000 for fiscal year 2020; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8446B75AD6744015BC48A9A7ED3BCFA9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>$30,000,000 for fiscal year 2021.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD70ECD964FB94340981FA42C9DE635BF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for subtitle G of title IX of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 977 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H29C25F15ED4549989D7AD12C7EA91BCB" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">977A. Low-dose radiation research program.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


