<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HEC28B8C4423942A59A90805F00E26C71" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2283 IH: DHS MORALE Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2283</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170502">May 2, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000588">Mr. Richmond</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000132">Mr. Vela</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000627">Mrs. Demings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000602">Miss Rice of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to improve morale within the Department of Homeland
			 Security workforce by conferring new responsibilities to the Chief Human
			 Capital Officer, establishing an employee engagement steering committee,
			 requiring action plans, and authorizing an annual employee award program,
			 and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HA0B3289D2DFE49788EB72C6F0773FE49" style="OLC">
 <section id="H88402BB96FF84827A2FFBDE67697119D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Department of Homeland Security Morale, Recognition, Learning and Engagement Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote>DHS MORALE Act</quote>.</text> </section><section id="H83BD7DB4F5E241299EF195A77E80DEC4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Chief Human Capital Officer responsibilities</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 704 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/344">6 U.S.C. 344</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDEFB7F79A4FF4211A13BB127DC28D186"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <subparagraph id="HB59CE654D266459197ECB73B721932AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text>
 <clause id="H460DA14F56C84E119D88F236472D02AC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, including with respect to leader development and employee engagement,</quote> after <quote>policies</quote>;</text> </clause><clause id="H8AD027BE35B04672865844E942D832B2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and in line</quote> and inserting <quote>, in line</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H50B6F8E8D3B34ADC9A7D130E9F9714D7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>and informed by best practices within the Federal government and the private sector,</quote> after <quote>priorities,</quote>;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF08EFBEE2BE04D5B8EB3F71FCBFD8DCA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>develop performance measures to provide a basis for monitoring and evaluating</quote> and inserting <quote>evaluate, on an ongoing basis,</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7F6CD5BB74B4EB4AA2713567C397113"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by inserting <quote>that, to the extent practicable, are informed by employee feedback,</quote> after <quote>policies</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C8BE4CE334241B4BF4A8643859203AB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by inserting <quote>including leader development and employee engagement programs,</quote> before <quote>in coordination</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5EA7A2870F5C469D968913CAA0F56DC0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by inserting before the semicolon at the end the following: <quote>that is informed by an assessment, carried out by the Chief Human Capital Officer, of the learning and developmental needs of employees in supervisory and non-supervisory roles across the Department and appropriate workforce planning initiatives</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H569B8B12B0AB452DB9A5DBD703A72ADA"><enum>(F)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (9) and (10) as paragraphs (11) and (12), respectively; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4700D0CA134242FA83B16E68B20EFEB2"><enum>(G)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (8) the following new paragraphs:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H073FA0A3B39D442FB3BC27A0438F918C" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H299CC2177C57423CB74442319E51FE0B"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maintain a catalogue of available employee development opportunities, including the Homeland Security Rotation Program pursuant to section 844, departmental leadership development programs, interagency development programs, and other rotational programs; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEB24F31CF69C4980B9873A0D4D8E204B"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that employee discipline and adverse action programs comply with the requirements of all pertinent laws, rules, regulations, and Federal guidance, and ensure due process for employees;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H978B058CE29F41D895CEB72AE809C7FE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (d) and (e) as subsections (e) and (f), respectively;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE02130619153468E8E120045EAA606EC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (c) the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4352A2D35FB1415F8F644DE7267C9B94" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H7BF1F64A1613478C89970CC0193CD5E4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Chief Learning and Engagement Officer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chief Human Capital Officer may designate an employee of the Department to serve as a Chief Learning and Engagement Officer to assist the Chief Human Capital Officer in carrying out this section.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H93C09BF7B65A4A44B3A54DB33AAF8E64"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (e), as so redesignated—</text> <subparagraph id="HF6F8FA7F6B8142DEB93ACF8651622277"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) as paragraphs (5), (6), and (7), respectively; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42000AA1880D403C851523DB293901CD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (1) the following new paragraphs:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEDC1148F20E04A4FB2706BC53FE09946" style="OLC"> <paragraph commented="no" id="HE8AE51D461C6495CAD28F58AA42D4FA9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on employee development opportunities catalogued pursuant to paragraph (9) of subsection (b) and any available data on participation rates, attrition rates, and impacts on retention and employee satisfaction;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4FABA1F803CE4A71BA0BA2BA2C69E3FA"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on the progress of Department-wide strategic workforce planning efforts as determined under paragraph (2) of subsection (b); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3BCC5FB4C9694804BFEBD1FA4B4A400C"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on the activities of the steering committee established pursuant to section 710(a), including the number of meeting, types of materials developed and distributed, and recommendations made to the Secretary;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H05AF8B51B88C4B71B831EEF975CC07F0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Employee engagement steering committee and action plan</header>
 <subsection id="HFD587A05F3F9473E9F169E480563A059"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title VII of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/341">6 U.S.C. 341</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H933AFEEAE4E14947BC365B9A62FF27BC" style="OLC">
					<section id="H0AFB28BD1F6540B98B1456149CA5ACC9"><enum>710.</enum><header>Employee engagement</header>
 <subsection id="H2B2EDE3985A249EB84D5DA8EAB08763A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Steering committee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall establish an employee engagement steering committee, including representatives from operational components and headquarters, including supervisory and non-supervisory personnel, and employee labor organizations that represent Department employees, and chaired by the Under Secretary for Management, to carry out the following activities:</text>
 <paragraph id="HC56D9DE5305D4B85BF795669086C0353"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identify factors that have a negative impact on employee engagement, morale, and communications within the Department, such as perceptions about limitations on career progression, mobility, or development opportunities, collected through employee feedback platforms, including through annual employee surveys, questionnaires, and other communications, as appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H55A0E346FCFD4E189CC943E5597C79B5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Identify, develop, and distribute initiatives and best practices to improve employee engagement, morale, and communications within the Department, including through annual employee surveys, questionnaires, and other communications, as appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4B6957E4078B48F39C56D0C33A060A6C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Monitor efforts of each component to address employee engagement, morale, and communications based on employee feedback provided through annual employee surveys, questionnaires, and other communications, as appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE0C9B2DD2545469184FEC561FBD3700D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Advise the Secretary on efforts to improve employee engagement, morale, and communications within specific components and across the Department.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0BB7805D39AF45C68E2967041FECCDE7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Conduct regular meetings and report, not less than once per quarter, to the Under Secretary for Management, the head of each component, and the Secretary on Department-wide efforts to improve employee engagement, morale, and communications.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H226AE69B818847E59C52D3810623F052"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Action plan; Reporting</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Chief Human Capital Officer, shall—</text> <paragraph id="H392CC9C4672A4E0CA9E7CD53FE273878"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 120 days after the date of the establishment of the steering committee under subsection (a), issue a Department-wide employee engagement action plan, reflecting input from the employee engagement steering committee established pursuant to subsection (a) and employee feedback provided through annual employee surveys, questionnaires, and other communications in accordance with paragraph (1) of such subsection, to execute strategies to improve employee engagement, morale, and communications within the Department; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBDA80375DB2A4A448E89701C1834C249"><enum>(2)</enum><text>require the head of each component to—</text> <subparagraph id="HA9A890BCCC8D4F4C8BD3D5F956283E88"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify and assign a senior executive to serve on the steering committee;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0FDB4B76F5B4550AB5CB443DD9E9D32"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop and implement a component-specific employee engagement plan to advance the action plan required under paragraph (1) that includes performance measures and objectives, is informed by employee feedback provided through annual employee surveys, questionnaires, and other communications, as appropriate, and sets forth how employees and, where applicable, their labor representatives are to be integrated in developing programs and initiatives;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC20B2F8145B44A91B099B56FC1E9B2C3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>monitor progress on implementation of such action plan; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB94803D64E6A4C08A41AF39163068D84"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provide to the Chief Human Capital Officer and the steering committee monthly reports on actions planned and progress made under this paragraph.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC23448F16CC941CDAAD9A759C2707568"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 709 the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H02F8D273251E467BBEEE75B2FFDF0256" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 710. Employee engagement.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H85A1DC470DFF43B2B411D22FA7D95F20"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Submissions to Congress</header>
 <paragraph id="HA8CF30C926034388A52CEFD35B574F66"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Department-wide employee engagement action plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through the Chief Human Capital Officer of the Department of Homeland Security, shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate the Department-wide employee engagement action plan required under subsection (b)(1) of section 710 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (as added by subsection (a) of this section) not later than 30 days after the issuance of such plan under such subsection (b)(1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD8C93AF69E7F4BBCA73F8D01D64DBF0D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Component-specific employee engagement plans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each head of a component of the Department of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate the component-specific employee engagement plan of each such component required under subsection (b)(2) of section 710 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (as added by subsection (a) of this section) not later than 30 days after the issuance of each such plan under such subsection (b)(2).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H55FBC05C11634CA3980A501A06BD5AE8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Annual employee award program</header>
 <subsection id="HDD975E87C989430092774002DD72A7A7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title VII of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/341">6 U.S.C. 341</external-xref> et seq.), as amended by section 3 of this Act, is further amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF1A9FB0DF11748A9B07EB61E87155410" style="OLC">
					<section id="H3908E240C47E49CEAE8C92BEFD5BFF98"><enum>711.</enum><header>Annual employee award program</header>
 <subsection id="HCC48D695327A4A9EB205E21C80B13B06"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may establish an annual employee award program to recognize Department employees or groups of employees for significant contributions to the achievement of the Department’s goals and missions. If such a program is established, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H277050BC69F9421091FDE69442B41E43"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish within such program categories of awards, each with specific criteria, that emphasizes honoring employees who are at the non-supervisory level;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0ED53E4A36B746959FB83890D768870B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>publicize within the Department how any employee or group of employees may be nominated for an award;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3DFE7575FB724B0FAD84A9FCCA97A6D8"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish an internal review board comprised of representatives from Department components to submit to the Secretary award recommendations regarding specific employees or groups of employees;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7C622ED2D0774250835277648B409C96"><enum>(4)</enum><text>select recipients from the pool of nominees submitted by the internal review board under paragraph (3) and convene a ceremony at which employees or groups of employees receive such awards from the Secretary; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD36B98095074419A818616F52D11439A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>publicize such program within the Department.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1F58873A58BA47CEB02A93E8D651E0D6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Internal review board</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The internal review board described in subsection (a)(3) shall, when carrying out its function under such subsection, consult with representatives from operational components and headquarters, including supervisory and non-supervisory personnel, and employee labor organizations that represent Department employees.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5ABF6CA15FC74D2582B3D2C101F508B6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section may be construed to authorize additional funds to carry out the requirements of this section or to require the Secretary to provide monetary bonuses to recipients of an award under this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCD20CC44246746FCBE0BA95DE0EE8622"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, as amended by section 3 of this Act, is further amended by inserting after the item relating to section 710 the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3B999337C8ED4442B53105F76321158E" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 711. Annual employee award program.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="HA0B4FADE6DE44E9799768E9DEA091491"><enum>5.</enum><header>Independent audit</header>
 <subsection id="H51485203F3A2490CB356444475F86EA9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the issuance of any comprehensive report by the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security on the administration of the disciplinary and adverse action program within the Department but in no case later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall execute an agreement with an entity outside the Federal Government to conduct an independent audit of how disciplinary processes are administered throughout the Department.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H47FC0F2D582047C29041781EACFAA952"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the agreement described in subsection (a) is executed, the entity referred to in such subsection shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate the audit required under such subsection, including findings regarding whether disciplinary processes of the Department of Homeland Security are administered in a consistent manner within components and across the Department, and recommendations for actions to promote greater uniformity and transparency in the administration of such disciplinary processes. The audit shall specifically review whether such disciplinary processes administered within each component of the Department result in the same or substantially similar disciplinary outcomes for misconduct by a non-supervisory or supervisory employee who engaged in same or substantially similar misconduct. In carrying out the audit, the entity shall consult with representatives of Federal employee labor organizations that represent Department employees.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H33C9832A553248B0B898531AEC89EF9E"><enum>6.</enum><header>Prohibition on new funding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No funds are authorized to carry out this Act and the amendments made by this Act. This Act and such amendments shall be carried out using amounts otherwise made available.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


