<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HFE71D1E05EB54638893C40F2C1AB9C19" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4251 IH: Rebuilding Resilient Energy Systems Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4251</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171103">November 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000248">Mr. Serrano</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000582">Miss González-Colón of Puerto Rico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000535">Mr. Gutiérrez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001227">Mr. Brady of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To promote the use of resilient energy systems to rebuild infrastructure following disasters.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HDA01FAEB661A4D64B9AC48E49DE6E4B5" style="OLC">
 <section id="H36C2D98B564B4559B0B3F9574BA3ADA3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rebuilding Resilient Energy Systems Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HB0E99C7FE03D493FAB0894200BA66C29"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="H60C6E34C934C49A8A9961BCD9ECD61DB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Efficient</header><text>The term <quote>efficient</quote> means, with respect to a technology, product, material, equipment, or practice, the use of the technology, product, material, equipment, or practice in a manner that results in reduced energy consumption or energy costs for the same level of service or a higher level of service.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H33720B63FB19444CA6B08B3CAB5E45C3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Resilient</header><text>The term <quote>resilient</quote> means, with respect to a system or a component of a system, the ability of the system or component to adapt to a changing condition and withstand and rapidly recover from a disruption.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H677CCB8B30C8499DAF0A70C080227C9D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Use of resilient energy systems to rebuild following disasters</header>
 <subsection id="H6E58E14C1D1343FDA142A113E01B8819"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any amounts awarded under sections 403, 404, 406, 408, and 428 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170b">42 U.S.C. 5170b</external-xref>, 5170c, 5172, 5174, 5189f) may be used to build, repair, restore, reconstruct, or replace an energy system or building as a result of a major disaster or emergency designated by the President under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121</external-xref> et seq.) during calendar year 2017 in a manner that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8A82DF934D294AE29E5874E27F1F4E8E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is more resilient;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6A78BC46E45D41BFBF60D597DD0E323C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is more efficient;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H35A91D2AF0D84F43A3C2608329A6E31B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provides continuous flow of power to facilities critical to public health, safety, and welfare;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB7E91EA8EDD14E17A57E61748B8CB5C9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>maximizes the use of clean energy resources and energy storage technologies; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H21B48267867E412198FEB856BF59AE81"><enum>(5)</enum><text>promotes lower energy bills to the extent feasible.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H20DC3EBD8FFD43EF918161E9F1FE2FF5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in subsection (a) creates eligibility for assistance for any energy provider that is not otherwise eligible for assistance under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H00884A8160654442B4A73CC6288A152F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination with private entities</header>
 <paragraph id="HEF4E7F27AA62491EA53F273548593130"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall designate a representative of the Agency to coordinate with one or more private entities that are interested in donating energy system technologies and services to rebuild in accordance with subsection (a) following a major disaster or emergency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB0B5DFFF1B674BAE96F7E3F470E209B7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination among agencies</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency is encouraged to coordinate with the Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H27852695A0EE42B2BC0AD20B99D74447"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header>
 <paragraph id="HD27C74D809FA4AC6A2268F427527E9E5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, each National Laboratory (as defined in section 2 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15801">42 U.S.C. 15801</external-xref>)), in coordination with the programs of the Department of Energy that provide assistance to States and industry, shall make technical assistance available to Federal, State, and local agencies and private entities that are interested in—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4B67E96E11734A8D8833A6FEEAD08498"><enum>(A)</enum><text>developing plans or providing guidance on the design of a resilient and efficient energy system or building; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB78F5DC1947748829ACCB937DF404133"><enum>(B)</enum><text>building, repairing, restoring, reconstructing, or replacing an energy system or building in accordance with subsection (a) following a major disaster or emergency.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H43C85C50699B4FE3991DBE7498BD4D42"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation among agencies</header><text>The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency is encouraged to consult with the Secretary of Defense regarding the experience of the Department of Defense in building resilient power systems.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


