<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC8E0DBF3D3F646E48D3AA684331F1D41" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2305 IH: Computer Science in STEM Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2305</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170503">May 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000293">Ms. Esty of Connecticut</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Education to award grants to State educational agencies to develop
			 comprehensive plans to strengthen elementary and secondary computer
			 science education, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HD94ED659D890428B9E6EE5D02078C353" style="OLC">
 <section id="HAEFFD0FCD44B45BF985ADF34D846C6C4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Computer Science in STEM Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HC836CBAA51DD4B3799838B74EDCB4BA7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H4174D70333074D86ABC70886F1A9AD92"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Computer science is transforming industry, creating new fields of commerce, driving innovation in all fields of science, and bolstering productivity in established economic sectors.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6B0D1076B6904E96A55616541BD80234"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Computer science underpins the information technology sector of the United States economy, which is a significant contributor to the economic output of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2A8CCCCD55224FAD83B30AFD2C34E00C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Bureau of Labor Statistics projects that from 2008 through 2018 more than 1,500,000 high-wage computing jobs will be created in the United States economy, making high-wage computing one of the fastest growing occupational fields.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD1FF244CAD524C768FADCC9B303284E0"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The breadth of industries requiring computing professionals is diverse, two-thirds of computing jobs are in sectors other than information technology, including manufacturing, defense, health care, finance, and government.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H50A74B98E1294B3F99507FC2A1442F21"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providing students with computer science education in elementary and secondary school is critical for student success in the 21st century and for strengthening the workforce.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9A6E3F061746497289DC8DA6E4A4DBBD"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Elementary and secondary computer science education gives students a deeper knowledge of the fundamentals of computing, yielding critical thinking skills that will serve them throughout their lives in numerous fields.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9C42ED68949D43958F3B48F5E1228670"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Computer science courses in elementary and secondary schools are fading from the national landscape at a time when they are most needed. The Computer Science Teachers Association (CSTA) has found that introductory secondary school computer science courses have decreased in number by 17 percent since 2005 and the number of Advanced Placement (AP) computer science courses has decreased by 33 percent.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H65158112F2F24EDCB0E7233D81882FBF"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Significant disparities in access to computer science education exist for minorities. Research in the Los Angeles Unified School District, the second largest and one of the most diverse school districts in the United States, found college-preparatory computer science courses were commonly missing in schools with high numbers of Latino and African-American students.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9ED002D016C1426689324635FB469A51"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Only 14 States allow computer science courses to count toward a student’s secondary school graduation requirements, chilling student interest in computer science courses.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H76947F784B294B478E1A1750CFF34203"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The CSTA has found that many States do not have a certification or licensure process for computer science teachers, and where certification processes do exist, such processes often have no connection to computer science content.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9BDDF0E09B3E4BB2A7C9736D30A854C3"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Computer science education has been encumbered by confusion regarding the related but distinct concepts of computer science education, technology education, and the use of technology in education.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H69910B00178843518F9E09D83EA970E8"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Computer science education courses have often been placed within the vocational education pathways in schools, creating a focus on applied information technology skills rather than a focus on developing fundamental computer science knowledge.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H45289B57A3D745F897D2A6F070D6C6A6"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With the growing importance of computing in society, the need for students to understand the fundamentals of computing, and the significant challenges computer science education faces in elementary and secondary education, broad support for computer science education is needed to catalyze reform.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section commented="no" id="HDD206EC611A14D4AB9EF41769EE51BE0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Amendment to the America COMPETES Reauthorization Act of 2010</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2(2) of the America COMPETES Reauthorization Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6621">42 U.S.C. 6621</external-xref> note) is amended by inserting <quote>, and computer science</quote> after <quote>and mathematics</quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="HE09510E4D5C7407598EC034433E45FA9"><enum>4.</enum><header>State comprehensive planning grants</header>
 <subsection id="H9C193B459E54486EA1513465B0532A47"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Education shall award grants to State educational agencies to develop comprehensive plans to strengthen elementary and secondary computer science education in accordance with this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8CF4E07DF0B34BBE8F4B1EBFCA68D91B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Objectives</header><text>A comprehensive plan developed under this section shall outline strategies for achieving the following objectives:</text>
 <paragraph id="H7B81931DE0BB4FBFA8FCDA22F379A288"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Provide an engaging and rigorous computer science education intended to ensure students are prepared for the 21st century.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H68A08DF193834B77BAA507C0A0B39AEC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Assess the State’s needs for computer science education, particularly for underrepresented populations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0A0EDD79D0F04C96B3660396E8058F61"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Ensure access to computer science courses, particularly at low-performing schools and for low-income students and students underrepresented in computing.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H56DD3DCD2980422DB3CDFDCC9A2D9A9C"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ensure that students are exposed to grade-appropriate computer science concepts in kindergarten through grade 12 and that computer science courses at the secondary level are viewed as part of the standard curriculum students need to be ready for postsecondary education and careers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8A2ADB4D15224267A03EE77DD0DDE346"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Ensure that teachers have the appropriate background, skills, and access to resources to teach computer science.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3CDC90072A4F45308D53B37D55AEBC0B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Contents of comprehensive plans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State educational agency that receives a grant under subsection (a) shall develop a comprehensive plan that meets the objectives described in subsection (b) and includes the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H051513576E944B5CBCCE4ADD07513E45"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An assessment of elementary and secondary computer science education in such State.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8068F96B316D42048D2D89333C36C69F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Proposals to improve elementary and secondary computer science education in such State through the development and implementation of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6AEC1B0581CB4D07BD95BD81128BA18E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>challenging and grade-appropriate academic content standards for computer science at elementary and secondary education levels;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8F12227BF2746DDA17229F2A7981DA1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>grade-appropriate assessments of computer science learning;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H983394DB314E471688BD1AF515D36A00"><enum>(C)</enum><text>programs to increase access to computer science courses for students at low-performing schools and students underrepresented in computing;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB197FD548AFB469AAE666807A879A5F5"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improved computer science teacher certification or licensure requirements and processes;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H276AC064E5C846A7AB61D56424B5D281"><enum>(E)</enum><text>professional development programs for computer science teachers; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1D4AA44FA094D7C85BF3051CD4C93B9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>programs for ensuring that computer science courses at the secondary level are considered an integral part of the curriculum students need to be well prepared for higher education and employment.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD2023D3DF86C448C90D6E03583291E4C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In developing a comprehensive plan under this section, a State educational agency shall collaborate with representatives of institutions of higher education, with other interested parties, and, where they exist in such State, with State P–16 or P–20 councils.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9A94187B20EA408B8E9C689F33DF89F3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Duration of grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall award each grant under subsection (a) for a period of 2 years.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H2982797467B04BC6A54F57F9DFE372CC"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Funding structure</header> <paragraph id="H9CED99C6E2494E3D851B68C571B75ABC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall award grants under subsection (a) proportionally among the State educational agencies that apply for grant funding under this section based on the number of low-income children served by the State educational agency compared to the total number of low-income children served by all of the State educational agencies that apply for grant funding under this section.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HD4EFB8CE3FD5452281290762BD2B29EA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Counting low-income children</header>
 <subparagraph id="HA242780FDD0A49CBAE012D50422198BF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Categories of children</header><text>The number of low-income children to be counted for purposes of this section is the aggregate of—</text> <clause id="H105D415AA1EC4E019F7A3EBC3D22349E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of children aged 5 to 17, inclusive, in the State from families below the poverty level, as determined by the Secretary on the basis of the most recent satisfactory data;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H111DA47F54BA42859422371BF1187C9B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number of children (determined for either the preceding year or for the second preceding year, as the Secretary finds appropriate) aged 5 to 17, inclusive, in the State in institutions for neglected and delinquent children (other than such institutions operated by the United States); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE4E130A91DD64DB681EEC1473977EB6C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the number of children aged 5 to 17, inclusive, in the State from families above the poverty level as determined under paragraph (4)(A) of section 1124(c) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6333">20 U.S.C. 6333(c)(4)</external-xref>).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB29B6A843727404C8FF79FEE1418DECF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Methodology</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making computations under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall use the methodology described in paragraphs (3) through (5) of section 1124(c) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6333">20 U.S.C. 6333(c)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H508E6B7E78324B108EC1AA4BFC6A64E3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Minimum grant</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), each State educational agency approved by the Secretary to receive a grant under this section shall receive a minimum grant of $250,000.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H78FBD61F7C7C4540BC8C19F420B9A726"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated such sums as necessary, subject to the availability of appropriations, to carry out this section.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HA79F57363BC84FEBA6FF127326CBFB85"><enum>5.</enum><header>Implementation grants</header>
 <subsection id="HA06EC2FD792247279F584994E86E5021"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall award grants to State educational agencies in accordance with this section to implement computer science education improvements proposed in comprehensive plans that meet the requirements of subsections (b) and (c) of section 4.</text>
 </subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H71D33CE6BE6A45528EEEBAC0A500E6EC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Benchmarks</header><text>Each State educational agency applying for a grant under this section shall—</text> <paragraph id="H86DF55D389BE4EECA1FD051070E5587B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop quantifiable benchmarks for the activities supported under such grant, which may include benchmarks for increasing—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H93C42FBF8339404D9A342BB14689D033"><enum>(A)</enum><text>student knowledge and competency of grade-appropriate computer science concepts;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6A9AA11B0824277B9A867776F721FEF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of students that take computer science courses;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C63E82AC201488AB2BF2AA52C73BCF7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the diversity of students who take computer science courses;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H14F6829300604B2AA6F99F973B534788"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the number of students who plan to pursue postsecondary computer science degrees;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H583F43F0B0A949469C4D53A8832041F7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the diversity of students who plan to pursue postsecondary computer science degrees; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B26765FCBFE486292B141B8D1DFD3CB"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the number of teachers who are certified to teach computer science; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC33F09EB86E44CEDBFD669A89395D7DC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit such quantifiable benchmarks to the Secretary for approval.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2B586B3635E746D98805418EBDEAA9BA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>Grant funds received under this section shall be used by each State educational agency for the development and implementation of—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6B48A5245E8A46D8B8BF06A9602ED34A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>challenging and grade-appropriate academic content standards for computer science;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H423FCF91E34A4A468112C7EA4E5019D2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>grade-appropriate assessments of computer science learning;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5055F0BF3E554094BF9E7F2DA610BAC8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>programs to increase access to computer science courses for students at low-performing schools and students underrepresented in computing;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H726E6F0ED19E4C59B651CE85E2B999EC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>improved computer science teacher certification requirements and processes;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H185DD58910234B22A93E26A0924045F8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>professional development programs for computer science teachers;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3DB38832EF774D1EACE29B50DC6F9B8E"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">programs for ensuring that computer science courses at the secondary level are considered an integral part of the curriculum students need to be well prepared for higher education and employment;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEB9955032EA644018F1222AB8230937E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>effective computer science curricula;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2791215CC8284250B27C83F225B272CF"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">computer science distance learning programs; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5F878D372F3641F0BE9EBD32D66C7D5A"><enum>(9)</enum><text>such other activities that strengthen computer science education and that such State educational agency considers appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7CAC06E574BB481FA048795C3026EAE7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Administrative expenses</header><text>A State educational agency may use not more than five percent of a grant received under this section for administrative expenses.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFADEF1026A184BFE98128F2DB7F2D0FE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Partnerships</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In performing the activities required under subsection (c), each State educational agency shall partner with institutions of higher education and local educational agencies, and may partner with nonprofit organizations, businesses, and other State educational agencies.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HE3FA8D4639D24070A43FE529B21E7931"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Non-Federal share</header>
 <paragraph id="HCA64AC6114AA4CA1B6EFE7D0D00B5D0F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State educational agency receiving a grant under this section shall provide a non-Federal share, in cash or in-kind, of the funding for the activities described in subsection (c) of not less than 20 percent of the total cost of such activities in any fiscal year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA753709C9C044DD3BB2A320B0AF97B69"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Financial hardship waiver</header><text>The Secretary may reduce or waive the requirement to provide a non-Federal share under paragraph (1) for a State educational agency if such State educational agency demonstrates a need for such waiver or reduction due to extreme financial hardship.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H79A50759A2964BF7BE69FE8FFAE0B596"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Duration of grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall award each grant under subsection (a) for a period of five years.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H0AC4D34C2A0B4A0199F9F7BDF1BAEADC"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Subsequent grants</header><text>At the end of the 5-year period for a grant, the grant recipient may apply for an additional grant under this section by submitting an updated comprehensive plan that meets the requirements of subsections (b) and (c) of section 4. In considering an application for a subsequent grant under this section, the Secretary shall take into consideration the reports filed under subsection (l).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0532EFCF7D394F0C891A254AEB4790E9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Competitive basis; priority</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="HFD2B0E5CA9D948D5996508120D3063CA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>award grants for a fiscal year on a competitive basis among State educational agencies that meet the requirements for funding under this section; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA5C5ED102D654359B52BF7C6A97AAD09"><enum>(2)</enum><text>give priority to State educational agency proposals that include an emphasis on serving low-performing schools and on increasing participation in computer science by students underrepresented in computing.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H669A09389D554D8BA7E3FDD445DFC307"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Funding Priority</header><text>In allocating grant funds received under this section, a State educational agency shall give priority to proposals that include an emphasis on serving low-performing schools and on increasing participation in computer science by students underrepresented in computing.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H348FE3BBB1CE4B5DB2654221283F522D"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds made available to carry out this section shall be used to supplement, and not supplant, other Federal and State funds available to carry out the activities described in this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H44C752FDB6F2412A8626F0A8C3C9CA84"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Each State educational agency receiving a grant under this section shall—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H7B78288A0C9C479FA6A5CC57740C315F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>measure the progress of such State educational agency in achieving the benchmarks developed under subsection (b)(1);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HBA154CE6654D4CBFB5DEC71C36AF5CD5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>collect data relating to student-related benchmarks developed under subsection (b)(1) in a form that is disaggregated by student race, ethnicity, gender, disability status, migrant status, English proficiency status, and low-income status, except that such disaggregation shall not be required when the number of students in a category is insufficient to yield statistically reliable results or the results would reveal personally identifiable information about an individual student;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7607FDCC68DE47ABBA6DD7B498180EA6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>collect such other performance information as the Secretary may reasonably require for the national evaluation conducted under section 6;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H874A00D5D80F4C20BDF27E802D4A3471"><enum>(4)</enum><text>submit a report to the Secretary addressing each item in paragraphs (1) through (3) not later than four years after the date on which the State educational agency receives an initial grant under this section; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6FD764159EA14A3097C241007CB1861C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>not later than two years after the date of the submission of the report required under paragraph (4), and biennially thereafter until the State educational agency no longer receives grant funding under this section, submit to the Secretary an update of such report.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H64B7ABE16B5F4D0A8A07AE0417E72E13"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>The Secretary shall provide guidance to State educational agencies regarding acceptable data sources and methodologies for—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA3FF592BDB3B417EA58F45170918CB27"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establishing performance benchmarks; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H45196C1539C24FC9B8C9F37C76FA1F15"><enum>(2)</enum><text>measuring progress by State educational agencies receiving grants under this section.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3922DA35A37E4CAB8ED9694C46F09233"><enum>6.</enum><header>National evaluation</header>
 <subsection id="H3FFDBE0868D24C27800D864CD1D516D6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not earlier than 4 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall contract with an independent organization for a comprehensive, scientifically valid, and quantitative evaluation of the performance and effectiveness of the activities funded by grants received under this Act in improving the availability and quality of computer science education, the overall participation rate of students in computer science courses, and the participation rate of students underrepresented in computing in computer science courses.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HD747015173634A52B3EDDB60AFBF6DF1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header>
 <paragraph id="HE3B46B0E4C0847AFB59133EE48F80A90"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the results of the evaluation described in subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC0635F2528254820AFA899CCC6BC0CBE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report updates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date on which the Secretary submits the report required under paragraph (1), and biennially thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress an update of such report.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF71AD72751054048B49105C4E354182E"><enum>7.</enum><header>Expanding teacher preparation programs for computer science teachers</header>
 <subsection id="HF12B543F566543F996DA4E10484DCD3E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Computer science model teacher preparation program</header><text>Part B of title II of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6661">20 U.S.C. 6661</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HC24C90DF1DD44713BB9279090D16A9ED" style="OLC">
					<section id="H3FF18C7828E7469DA50D2F6DEE21C4A0"><enum>2204.</enum><header>Computer science model teacher preparation program</header>
 <subsection id="HA7F5239461824C70B0C7747488D66C7F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary is authorized to award grants to institutions of higher education to improve training for elementary school and secondary school computer science teachers.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD4BB7EC93C5041DBBCFD754F4A9D116C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>The Secretary shall award a grant under this section to an institution of higher education that—</text> <paragraph id="HFCCA31FAE17149E885FE0FEC208F0914"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has, at minimum—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3B34CEC861CE4772B69EB53BD81B6E6A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a program in teacher education; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H76781544BAF74FF4998AA3E7BE357019"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a program in computer science or informatics; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1D68EC40C794FA49929B068CE9D5117"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submits an application at such time, in such form, and containing such information and assurances as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEB0B36A0ACA14D778AB17B27A15A7AED"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An institution of higher education that receives a grant under the section shall use the grant funds to carry out not less than one of the following activities:</text>
 <paragraph id="H77FDE2FCEA504F99851DFB9723F5C66A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Develop courses for undergraduate students that—</text> <subparagraph id="HEFFDB4C1C81B4858B4F9527428EAEEC7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prepare such students to teach computer science in elementary schools and secondary schools;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC2DDE3C821B4714A78B2B4DA34B1053"><enum>(B)</enum><text>address content and pedagogy in informatics or computer science education; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64B0BB124BFC4A998D9A656C610EEE85"><enum>(C)</enum><text>engage the teacher education department and other relevant departments at the institution of higher education.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H14DCD295740642E5A6C0F4B9A303D83C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Develop and fund teacher mentoring programs to support elementary school and secondary school computer science teachers who are new to the profession.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4D5B8E5C906E484FB4C78C0FFE9FD0A0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duration of grants</header><text>Each grant awarded by the Secretary under this section shall be for a period of 5 years.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H51099E258D9A4790AA222DEEC4FD5D42"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the conclusion of the grant period described under subsection (d), an institution of higher education that receives a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary and Congress a report that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H704D61B713CE4889A19C977935A58477"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifies the number of teachers served under the grant;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDB92CE2F2DB045F7B0191FD836F50A2C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifies the number of teachers described in paragraph (1) who obtain a teaching position in a computer science classroom; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDED494F98A0E411ABE8FC7A385422624"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluates the activities carried out under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H417353465EE7451C8C9654D70A18F8CF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for such Act is amended by inserting before the item relating to part C of title II the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC21FF1F47F3548539134B539A3FB14E8" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2204. Computer science model teacher preparation program.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section id="H05BAC3F6AE7541BD8CCC15C4A4ED3AC1"><enum>8.</enum><header>Computer science in the Robert Noyce teacher scholarship program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 10 of the National Science Foundation Authorization Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1862n-1">42 U.S.C. 1862n–1</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFB29E37F9B204897B3BF42AC3D7D0F60"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and mathematics</quote> and inserting <quote>mathematics, informatics, and computer science</quote> in each place it appears;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA5C89DD4AD5340A890B290191D67E4C1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(3)(B), by striking <quote>or mathematics</quote> and inserting <quote>mathematics, informatics, and computer science</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB51B3C16E37A410D87ECFC7D970AC3FE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsections (b)(1)(D)(i), (c)(1)(A), (d)(1), and (i)(7) by striking <quote>or mathematics</quote> in each place it appears and inserting <quote>mathematics, informatics, or computer science</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6223CFFB1E36494EAC20122C364CBC74"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (i)(5), by striking <quote>or mathematics</quote> and inserting <quote>mathematics, or computer science</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H2778C681402141C583ED0F408D527354"><enum>9.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H779C2BF0E66C476DA013D101F6829A69"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Computer science</header><text>The term <term>computer science</term> means the study of computers and algorithmic processes and includes the study of computing principles, computer hardware and software design, computer applications, and the impact of computers on society.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5DA64D88DE104848A9E388FCEAA37BED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Computer science education</header><text>The term <term>computer science education</term> includes computing education in any of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H09156C3D4ACB42718E3DA5978DA0DA0C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Software design.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAEB03B850E87488F8CFC29DC019634F8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Hardware design.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70F377402A4C408DA5BBE7FF2E667F93"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Creation of digital artifacts.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H209CB4657E9049738AC9AF7BF81A0300"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Abstraction.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB39DFBEF0624D7C84A6DE758682BB0D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Logic.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFCC6F4D6BCB4836AB523B4B48CC3C76"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Algorithm development and implementation.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF18DDF3E190940E395E50BA741174BB0"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Programming paradigms and languages.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D55A71D8BEB419BB4C9E8148890D5F1"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Theoretical foundations.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8BB97A07893049EA9B57032F4D9D8D7D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Networks.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1504B8BEF3A94C2FB8DAFF28703F53A5"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Graphics.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H806C1C12E1054877A9CF2293415727AD"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Databases and information retrieval.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HACA1B16BAAE444B4AD5F3ECE15AE0257"><enum>(L)</enum><text>Information security and privacy.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8CEB773818A94789864B47233797CCE4"><enum>(M)</enum><text>Artificial intelligence.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE8339AE2CFC48E19B98B87A0B44ABE5"><enum>(N)</enum><text>The relationship between computing and mathematics.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCDFC3CD56C8E44D9B8759E971B509CE8"><enum>(O)</enum><text>The limits of computation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98B539B5EE944A709793C11858BD294F"><enum>(P)</enum><text>Applications in information technology and information systems.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2FAA8402F6E24096910D91B3FD657097"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>The social impacts of computing.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4EC6CAABCA4F423088ABB66AAFE13F57"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H29A365D474414577A777546D99860427"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Local educational agency</header><text>The term <term>local educational agency</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="H02BA2638475C44BE881C7F2B8E926B7A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>subject to subparagraph (B), has the meaning given that term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C7CE725E0664A84941ADF3E8694E78B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes any charter school (as defined in section 4310 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7221i">20 U.S.C. 7221i</external-xref>)) that constitutes a local educational agency under State law.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F59C34959AB493BAACABF62FA63DB3E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1BBF536A5DC0426F9F87277A5B76EC82"><enum>(6)</enum><header>State educational agency</header><text>The term <term>State educational agency</term> has the meaning given that term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HADB4F98A09EA445483A7E7B5C7AEEB9C"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Students underrepresented in computing</header><text>The term <term>students underrepresented in computing</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="HFE975F0F47144F31869F28FC9FB19582"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means populations historically underrepresented in computer science disciplines; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF55A4E4A259A467FBDD73C0035E7A0B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes females, racial minorities, and low-income students.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

