<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2CE7EA67E23345F7A5CE09B22F6F8DB1" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3249 IH: Project Safe Neighborhoods Grant Program Authorization Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3249</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170714">July 14, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001105">Mrs. Comstock</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Project Safe Neighborhoods Grant Program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HB80B65F5D35D4CD8BF60B4DCD16CA906" style="OLC">
 <section id="H1E5753B7BB3A48FBA15D9D8595C671B0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Project Safe Neighborhoods Grant Program Authorization Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HA456736911A04427A0C78FAEFBD5CBF2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the purposes of this Act—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC4AB9B942FC6422A8213E05F0EB14326"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>criminal street gangs</term> has the meaning given such term in section 521 of title 18, United States Code;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0865FCE7F5DD4178AB3606C4EF924EEB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>gang crime</term> means a felony or misdemeanor crime, under State or Federal law, committed by one or more persons who are a member of, or directly affiliated with, a criminal street gang;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC7147ED10A0148FE892556D4D7DA8751"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>transnational organized crime group</term> has the meaning given such term in section 36(k)(6) of the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2708">22 U.S.C. 2708(k)(6)</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H86F36B6406294B1EA0658F2E5120B267"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>transnational organized crime</term> has the meaning given such term in section 36(k)(5) of the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2708">22 U.S.C. 2708(k)(5)</external-xref>); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5B98A5E4B82B4E60AD32E1EF811CE79F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>firearms offenses</term> means an offense under section 922 or 924 of title 18, United States Code.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H41919F9F60A6415289D1ACBA0DF127DF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Attorney General of the United States is authorized to establish and carry out a program, to be known as the <quote>Project Safe Neighborhoods Block Grant Program</quote> or, in this Act, as the <quote>Program</quote>, within the Office of Justice Programs at the Department of Justice.</text>
 </section><section id="HF3AF30DB1F5D4A42B6118FDC970841C7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of the Project Safe Neighborhoods Block Grant Program shall be to foster and improve existing partnerships between Federal, State, and local agencies, including the United States Attorney in each Federal judicial district, to create safer neighborhoods through sustained reductions in crimes, including violent crimes and homicides, committed by criminal street gangs and transnational organized crime groups.</text>
		</section><section id="H806C6136C1044883B6FB5FF216A2B43E"><enum>5.</enum><header>Rules and regulations</header>
 <subsection id="H2B0D06541CF047E49E5C44D09605233D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall, not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, make rules to create, carry out, and administer the Program in accordance with this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCBDEFACD41204F75B4B0BF86E2195784"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Funds To be directed to local control</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts made available as grants under the Program shall be, to the greatest extent practicable, locally controlled to address problems that are identified locally</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H302D89606FA448F5BB5D35AA8F3454A4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regional Gang Task Forces</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">20 percent of the amounts made available as grants under the Program each fiscal year shall be granted to established Regional Gang Task Forces in regions experiencing a significant or increased presence of, or high levels of activity from, transnational organized crime groups posing threats to community safety in terms of violent crime, firearms offenses, human trafficking, trafficking and distribution of illegal opioids and heroin, and other crimes.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HB358B26024DB4DEA95E039DEB61577E4"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated for the Program under this Act $70,000,000 annually for fiscal years 2018 through 2022.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


