<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HDBCF3BD20AF24D43BC71101CF117F0D9" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3867 IH: To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to create care management demonstration programs for chronic kidney disease under the Medicare program, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3867</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170928">September 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001190">Mr. Mullin</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001065">Mr. Holding</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001251">Mr. Butterfield</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to create care management demonstration programs
			 for chronic kidney disease under the Medicare program, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HFC09C2200BFB498097209DAD48A3F5C0" style="OLC">
 <section id="HF4D3D92303794663BEB43DAA479F6486" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Care management demonstration programs for chronic kidney disease</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by inserting after section 1866E the following new section:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF5B8DC5EA69E487CA8D7EA7B86859B91" style="OLC">
				<section id="HDD15D16C50584FD6949F0E0DA3C08359"><enum>1866F.</enum><header>Care management demonstration programs for chronic kidney disease</header>
					<subsection id="H6118B7F5305947DC902E0E5F61FC0540"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Demonstration program for earlier and improved detection and treatment of chronic kidney disease</header>
 <paragraph id="HBBCC4F806E4C43DA9532C2B4EA5AC1E7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall establish a demonstration program (referred to in this section as the <quote>CKD early detection and treatment demonstration program</quote>) of the use of the payment system described in paragraph (2) that, with respect to an enrolled CKD–EDT individual (as defined in paragraph (8)(D)), provides to a CKD–EDT practitioner (as defined in paragraph (8)(A)) a single monthly care management payment for all CKD–EDT services (as defined in paragraph (8)(B)) furnished to such individual by such practitioner in a month.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H10292B176B2A43AAA85E61CE8F579B46"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Payment system described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The payment system described in this paragraph is a payment system that, with respect to all CKD–EDT services furnished in a month by a CKD–EDT practitioner to an enrolled CKD–EDT individual, provides a care management payment to such practitioner in an amount that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC3861A5603624F93A59C17380B817D30"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is greater than the amount of payment that such practitioner otherwise would receive pursuant to this title for furnishing such services to such individual if the practitioner had not elected to participate in the CKD early detection and treatment demonstration program (to be calculated in a manner that includes, as part of such amount that the practitioner otherwise would so receive, any amounts that the practitioner would receive as cost-sharing amounts from the individual);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA49C0F11A9DB479A9E3AE5203FAA6980"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to a fiscal year that is after the first fiscal year in which the CKD–EDT practitioner participates in the CKD early detection and treatment demonstration program, is, to the extent feasible, adjusted based on the performance of the practitioner during the prior fiscal year with respect to the measures developed by the Secretary pursuant to paragraph (3); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1FBECE9B82B64AAC806A4E4EC0E265F3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is determined through the use of a computation that is developed in consultation with—</text> <clause id="HC1890B6A78CD4E538E10E21CDE7FBF95"><enum>(i)</enum><text>chronic kidney disease patient advocates;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEDAC2AC033054C8684023E073483B619"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>clinicians in the primary care community; and</text> </clause><clause id="H88B52E930220460D97114C98BA288AA9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>such other entities as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text>
								</clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">For purposes of applying subparagraph (A) with respect to CKD–EDT services that are furnished via a
			 telecommunications system by a CKD–EDT practitioner to an enrolled CKD–EDT
			 individual, the Secretary shall calculate the amount that the practitioner
			 otherwise would so receive with respect to such services in a manner that
			 makes such amount equal the amount that such practitioner otherwise would
			 so receive for such services if such services had been furnished without
			 the use of a telecommunications system.</continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9000E7FBD5743BF91ED2A87CC87BB64"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Measures</header>
 <subparagraph id="HC1E91A5728CE40EBA8F35AA3AE57962B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (2)(B), the Secretary, in conjunction with stakeholders (including chronic kidney care patient advocates, clinicians in the primary care community, and experts in the development or use of evidence-based guidelines for the detection, diagnosis, and management of chronic kidney care), shall specify measures of performance with respect to the tasks described in subparagraph (B). Such measures shall be in accordance with clinical guidelines in existence with respect to chronic kidney disease at the time of such specification.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45B2F67BC0B441C9BEA4B53F1E5C801A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Tasks described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The tasks described in this subparagraph, with respect to a CKD–EDT practitioner, are the following:</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H575F032E018F4AFAA7E468FB2537DA76"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Administering, as appropriate, an annual serum creatinine and urine albumin testing in accordance with published chronic kidney care practice guidelines to individuals for whom the practitioner is the primary care practitioner and that either are CKD–EDT individuals or are at the highest risk for chronic kidney disease.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5DF7EC3B6E7148A69AF9FE3C572DD212"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ensuring that, when appropriate, individuals that are enrolled CKD–EDT individuals with respect to the practitioner receive timely consultations, in accordance with published chronic kidney care practice guidelines, with nephrologists located in the geographic area in which the individual resides.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5EB1EAA2B61470D9BEBA4FAE74D8731"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Flexibility in measure specification</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the Secretary may specify measures that the Secretary develops for purposes of such subparagraph or that the Secretary did not develop for such purposes.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H87C77839FB844FB8B98AB095A1413E21"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Waiving of cost-sharing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A CKD–EDT practitioner that participates in the CKD early detection and treatment demonstration program shall, with respect to any CKD–EDT services for which payment is made under the payment system described in paragraph (2), accept any payment made under such paragraph for such services as payment in full for such services, and may not collect any amount of cost-sharing (including any amount of deductible, coinsurance, or copayment) from an enrolled CKD–EDT individual for the furnishing of such services to such individual.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9D6721A9372948A88C7A90C49085AAB2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Geographic distribution of providers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent practicable, the Secretary shall ensure (including through targeted outreach to physicians, nurse practitioners, and physician assistants that are primary care practitioners with respect to enrolled CKD–EDT individuals) that the individuals who receive CKD–EDT services for which payment is provided under the CKD early detection and treatment demonstration program are evenly distributed—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEF4AD08B194F461ABBABB5545CC22373"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in different regions of the United States;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H52BDAEAFFF684DA4B67E191B3CAED935"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in urban and rural areas; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D99416DB7C54646A0C031D40CC262E1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>among appropriate facilities, including—</text> <clause id="H67135969AF354E6ABA0E72E54FBF9BA2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>federally qualified health centers; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCA2CDD8D08EE463FBDDEA19ED7D8B90E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>community health centers that receive assistance under section 330 of the Public Health Service Act.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6114909A30124B86BC72BD2FC7369F40"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Duration and scope of demonstration</header>
 <subparagraph id="H6E28D233F22249ACA026EE32257023BF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Three-year minimum</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (C), the Secretary shall conduct the CKD early detection and treatment demonstration program for a period of three years.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC10DE35C91954FCC843E17FEAF59A592"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Scope</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (C), the Secretary shall enroll, subject to paragraph (10), not more than 5,000 CKD–EDT individuals for participation in the demonstration program. Such an individual may participate in the demonstration program on a voluntary basis and may terminate participation at any time.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H26B4ED18C9E643B192F7A25E227EE540"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Option to extend</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may, through rulemaking, expand (including implementation on a nationwide basis) the duration and the scope of the CKD early detection and treatment demonstration program, to the extent determined appropriate by the Secretary, if—</text>
 <clause id="HCA1B6E32E1824837B29D9452483E25FA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Secretary determines that such expansion is expected to—</text> <subclause id="HB1E6ACD449A248E28EE1C14C145D486F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>reduce spending under this title without reducing the quality of care; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H1389E9722F644963919A2DA03FBC7770"><enum>(II)</enum><text>improve the quality of patient care without increasing spending under this title;</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H7F30E9F94A614B3FA33FF027A9279779"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Chief Actuary of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services certifies that such expansion would reduce (or would not result in any increase in) net program spending under this title; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7AB23AAF1662420591C91316FA3F0EF2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Secretary determines that such expansion would not deny or limit the coverage or provision of benefits under this title for applicable individuals.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF3B145300B49465FAEDFEEFD737D79B7"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Consultation with stakeholders</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HADDE07BFFED54988B1A95F9FBF481097"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall consult with stakeholders regarding the establishment and implementation of the CKD early detection and treatment demonstration program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H133107B0BE214B99A170DC1A9D51609F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Timing of consultation</header><text>The Secretary shall begin to consult with stakeholders pursuant to subparagraph (A) not later than six months after the date of the enactment of this section.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA144C923D9F143EDA6CB28B81687C900"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the following definitions apply:</text> <subparagraph id="H011D12C2A7B14F1FB0292E4D8669E9FC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>CKD–EDT practitioner</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (9), the term <term>CKD–EDT practitioner</term> means, with respect to an enrolled CKD–EDT individual, a physician, nurse practitioner, or physician assistant who—</text>
 <clause id="H0F993EB0432747E292DBAB1DB7638247"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is the primary care practitioner for such individual;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HF5151C0A8F854DEB8AB0C8D3D6F69CCA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">agrees, with respect to each fiscal year in which the practitioner participates in the CKD early detection and treatment demonstration program, to—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" id="HEE4BB34E2AF144EA93EEA756C11FBDD2"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assess the at-risk patient populations of such physician, nurse practitioner, or physician assistant (as applicable) for chronic kidney disease pursuant to published clinical practice guidelines with respect to chronic kidney disease; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H32E34C95CEC942FEB21FFF60592128E1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>submit to the Secretary the results of the assessments described in subclause (I);</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HAB3F4843608F46F098D01CFE3F0841A5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">uses certified EHR technology (as defined in section 1833(o)(4));</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6900179302314F0990B07DF6C1D0C495"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">elects to participate in the CKD early detection and treatment demonstration program with respect to all enrolled CKD–EDT individuals for whom such physician, nurse practitioner, or physician assistant (as applicable) is the primary care practitioner;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8A6F825B9B804CE38DBB80860A30666D"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">agrees, with respect to each fiscal year in which the practitioner participates in the demonstration program, to assess annually (pursuant to established clinical guidelines with respect to the monitoring of the progression of chronic kidney disease) all enrolled CKD–EDT individuals for whom such physician, nurse practitioner, or physician assistant (as applicable) is the primary care practitioner and that are either—</text>
 <subclause id="HF5BB76B9CFB5476CAE07CADD3B99B38B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>confirmed to have chronic kidney disease; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="H47BB829A03CA4201A2298B5D4023FA44"><enum>(II)</enum><text>at the highest risk of becoming an individual with confirmed chronic kidney disease;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H100E7046A9A84B078111CA66A603A8C9"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">agrees to provide to each enrolled CKD–EDT individual for whom such physician, nurse practitioner, or physician assistant (as applicable) is the primary care practitioner—</text>
 <subclause id="H77205714A1664D2F806BC4534A59AF55"><enum>(I)</enum><text>educational materials that provide background information about chronic kidney disease and that are developed by credible organizations, as specified by the Secretary, with expertise in the development of clinical guidelines and patient educational materials with respect to chronic kidney disease; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H1B02960A467247F190CA377324B6A8D1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a notification of the potential benefits that the individual may receive as a result of the practitioner participating in the CKD early detection and treatment demonstration program; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="H2114ADC4E6244474926ED9B247AC1B9D"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>agrees to comply with the requirements of paragraph (10).</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9060F86B6E804C47A81506A33197006A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>CKD–EDT services</header> <clause id="HEF7956F1A8F946C89B283471B0DC2CFD"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>CKD–EDT services</term> means administration and evaluation of such services as the Secretary may specify that are screening services and care management services for chronic kidney disease and for which, subject to clause (iv), payment may otherwise be made under this title.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H89823344416244C8894C19B86EE9C46B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Consultation required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining which services to specify for purposes of clause (i), the Secretary shall consult with—</text>
 <subclause id="HE7D11CCCCA4E4B6CA61297ED0B76B6A2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>chronic kidney disease patient advocates;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HFDA67D3DBF92487D8A000D74EC98B997"><enum>(II)</enum><text>clinicians in the primary care nephrologist community; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HF83D41184C9A44BAB3243DE8785C8CAE"><enum>(III)</enum><text>experts in the development of evidence-based guidelines for the detection, diagnosis, and management of chronic kidney disease.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HA833FA456AC549C3B269405D374BD870"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Considered services</header><text>In specifying services for purposes of clause (i), the Secretary may, in addition to considering other services and patient benefits, consider the following services with respect to the screening, care, and management of chronic kidney disease:</text>
 <subclause id="H9B049EE1A7CB41639310B801BB09C1DB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Blood pressure management.</text> </subclause><subclause id="HEF83FB193BD64684AD87FACC173CD85B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Lipid management.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H21DDA641298B4AB984DA063EDBE4AAF3"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Assessment for bone and mineral metabolism abnormalities, anemia, nutritional needs, mental health, and availability of family and other social support networks.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H56F424F9B64A418C988CD8EEF5314831"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Delivery of patient education on self-management strategies for chronic kidney disease.</text> </subclause><subclause id="HBFA23FBEC26A47028C5A273D1914C5D4"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Development of care plans with respect to chronic kidney disease.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HCC10E65172B84BB987BBC5931ED781ED"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>Medication reconciliation and dosage adjustments.</text> </subclause><subclause id="H3C5BD7DD130B41098D0AF3F0F7FBA568"><enum>(VII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Review of laboratory tests.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H01C3BC3448BD4DF2B4BB434CDEA2958C"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Medical nutrition therapy.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HF4571DE2E9E2455D8997C16335AF911C"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Permissible inclusion of telehealth services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>CKD–EDT services</term> may include services that are furnished via a telecommunications system by a CKD–EDT practitioner to an enrolled CKD–EDT individual and that would have been CKD–EDT services under clause (i) if such services had been furnished without the use of a telecommunications system.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB04B7002DEC34E9886E38089E7BA9B00"><enum>(C)</enum><header>CKD–EDT individual</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>CKD–EDT individual</term> means an individual who—</text> <clause id="H8DF0EC884B534708A30B55165277F997"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is not under the care of a nephrologist or nephrology practitioner;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H82C3BB8A87FF4DED916AEBC2B6BC1C88"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is an individual with confirmed chronic kidney disease at a stage equal to, or greater than, stage 3; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3B9E008922B448588B95C0748D665E12"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is entitled to benefits under part A and enrolled under part B.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H518019012B0141BDA3575F90E55911EC"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Enrolled CKD–EDT individual</header><text>The term <term>enrolled CKD–EDT individual</term> means a CKD–EDT individual who is enrolled to participate in the demonstration program under paragraph (6).</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC86DF72102C44269778D8D6B7D8DDC6"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Integrated care strategy</header>
 <subparagraph id="H9CF20A40792640B5909BB0899F496E1C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under the demonstration, a CKD–EDT practitioner, with respect to enrolled CKD–EDT individuals, shall develop and submit for the Secretary’s approval, subject to subparagraphs (B) and (C), a CKD–EDT integrated care strategy.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0178E329075F4329A18C23EA41BE8571"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Integrated care strategy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In assessing a CKD–EDT integrated care strategy, the Secretary shall consider the extent to which the strategy includes elements, such as the following:</text>
 <clause id="H07D8CD2757B54648A22DD94041AA1DD7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Interdisciplinary care teams led by at least one nephrologist, and comprised of registered nurses, social workers, and other representatives from alternative settings described in clause (vi).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H42AB79D98EEB40A881A679BAFAE7023A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Health risk and other assessments to determine the physical, psychosocial, nutrition, language, cultural, and other needs of enrolled CKD–EDT individuals involved.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7DA2F06E62F74B10B9B867C7C9A78BE1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Development and at least annual updating of individualized care plans that incorporate at least the medical, social, and functional needs, preferences, and care goals of enrolled CKD–EDT individuals.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF84475BC5DCC435AA8795331A836FF7D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Coordination and delivery of non-clinical services, such as transportation, aimed at improving the adherence of enrolled CKD–EDT individuals with care recommendations.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2888D0FB80074B60B24F7B913B3BF5E0"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Services, such as transplant evaluation and vascular access care.</text> </clause><clause id="H82DBEAFDB0FD446C98295423D9461869"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>In the case of an individual who, while enrolled in the demonstration, receives confirmation that a kidney transplant is imminent, the provision by an interdisciplinary care team described in clause (i) of counseling services to such individual on preparation for and potential challenges surrounding such transplant.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H531B54F7F9554714B602FB04EE292A65"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Delivery of benefits and services in alternative settings, such as the home of the enrolled CKD–EDT individuals, in coordination with the provider or other appropriate stakeholder involved in such delivery serving on an interdisciplinary care team described in clause (i).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9F6C9C7A09AE42F5A10A05920BDE2573"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Use of patient reminder systems.</text> </clause><clause id="H5015D4EEF0B24D5AA0016FDE86F0097F"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>Education programs for patients, families, and caregivers.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H58154645EDC041E4B343F7E98A739D98"><enum>(x)</enum><text>Use of health care advice resources, such as nurse advice lines.</text> </clause><clause id="HC8A1B7BB04294506A515C720772B21A9"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>Use of team-based health care delivery models that provide comprehensive and continuous medical care, such as medical homes.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8B3515A852E1446BBE0F3882070A3300"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>Co-location of providers and services.</text> </clause><clause id="H2D84EE977C42464C8B7EB074E7370CB0"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>Use of a demonstrated capacity to share electronic health record information across sites of care.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC061BE4083C54D5887C4DAB9EE57B488"><enum>(xiv)</enum><text>Use of programs to promote better adherence to recommended treatment regimens by individuals, including by addressing barriers to access to care by such individuals.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE9A93823E9C04070B54191582BF77903"><enum>(xv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Other services, strategies, and approaches identified by the CKD–EDT practitioner to improve care coordination and delivery.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CC34E3B607A443FBDBA0ACFCCD6457C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not approve a CKD–EDT integrated care strategy of a CKD–EDT practitioner unless under such strategy the pracitioner—</text>
 <clause id="H98EC4E5093BD4618A65422CFE01BB4BA"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides services to enrolled CKD–EDT individuals through a comprehensive, multidisciplinary health and social services delivery system which integrates acute and long-term care services pursuant to regulations; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HECD532EE473947E39623A7FB518C50D3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>specifies the covered items and services that will not be provided directly by the practitioner, and to arrange for delivery of those items and services through contracts meeting the requirements of regulations.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H62D84DE240754FD794AA3AFDC52ABC55"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Beneficiary protections</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HFB05EC2B7ADA4A05B884D7CD7E2DADFE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Antidiscrimination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a CKD–EDT practitioner that participates in the CKD early detection and treatment demonstration program that is treating a CKD–EDT individual and such individual elects for the practitioner not to so participate in such demonstration program with respect to such individual, such practitioner may not participate in such demonstration program with respect to such individual (but may so participate with respect to other CKD–EDT individuals).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HCDCAF732DCC6419C8C8C7CDDD2F793BF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>No impact on quality of care</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A CKD–EDT practitioner that participates in the CKD early detection and treatment demonstration program may not allow the participation of such practitioner in such program to affect the quality of services furnished under this title to an individual, regardless of whether the practitioner participates in such demonstration program with respect to such individual.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7D31391C1D93419E9FCE25170707EA59"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Quality assurance; patient safeguards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall require that each CKD–EDT practitioner that participates in the CKD early detection and treatment demonstration program has in effect—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="HB627603CEDF34F02BF0AA0EE87293BFB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a written plan of quality assurance and improvement with respect to CKD–EDT services for which payment is made under such demonstration program, and procedures implementing such plan, in accordance with regulations; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HE4A7486D16194910AD654AAC461406CC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">written safeguards of the rights of enrolled CKD–EDT individuals for whom such practitioner is the primary care practitioner (including a patient bill of rights and procedures for grievances and appeals) in accordance with regulations and with other requirements of this title and Federal and State law that are designed for the protection of patients.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE43CA6BAC2974815908F63DAAC939DFF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Demonstration program for advanced chronic kidney disease</header>
 <paragraph id="HA499EC4D0E5A417AAD9E48C550E4646A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall establish a demonstration program (referred to in this section as the <quote>advanced CKD demonstration program</quote>) of the use of the payment system described in paragraph (2) that, with respect to an individual entitled to benefits under part A or enrolled under part B with confirmed chronic kidney disease at a stage equal to, or greater than, stage 4 (as confirmed by testing serum creatinine and urine albumin in alignment with evidence-based chronic kidney disease clinical guidelines), provides to an advanced CKD practitioner (as defined in paragraph (5)(A)) a single care management payment for all advanced CKD services (as defined in paragraph (5)(B)) furnished to such individual by such practitioner in a month.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H62CF0CAC41F84D1EAA420320F1568F09"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Payment system described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The payment system described in this paragraph is a payment system that, with respect to all advanced CKD services furnished in a month by an advanced CKD practitioner to an individual described in paragraph (1), provides a care management payment to such practitioner in an amount that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCE21020524C242C0A98147C1DBDCAC74"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is greater than the amount of payment that such practitioner otherwise would receive pursuant to title XVIII for furnishing such services to such individual if the practitioner had not elected to participate in the advanced CKD demonstration program (to be calculated in a manner that includes, as part of such amount that the practitioner otherwise would so receive, any amounts that the practitioner would receive as cost-sharing amounts from the individual);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D04FFA12AF24539BED201575A92E396"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a fiscal year that is after the first fiscal year in which the advanced CKD practitioner participates in the advanced CKD demonstration program, is adjusted based on the performance of the practitioner during the prior fiscal year with respect to the measures developed by the Secretary pursuant to paragraph (3);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5CD748B4F3C42F99F0E510B319B1B1C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is determined through the use of a computation that is developed in consultation with—</text> <clause id="HD50416AEA7804B3E84AD730D7EE9FBDE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>chronic kidney disease patient advocates;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H239BB381CB15470990BC1182BE0AC5BB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>clinicians in the nephrology community;</text> </clause><clause id="H2999C6589C7F4B55837EA564B7754B5D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>experts in the development of evidence-based guidelines for the detection, diagnosis, and management of chronic kidney disease; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD5165F3087944A8394C8048B80D73B12"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>such other entities as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text> </clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">For purposes of applying subparagraph (A)(i) with respect to advanced CKD services that are furnished via a telecommunications system by an advanced CKD practitioner to an individual described in paragraph (1), the Secretary shall calculate the amount that the practitioner otherwise would so receive with respect to such services in a manner that makes such amount equal the amount that such practitioner otherwise would so receive for such services if such services had been furnished without the use of a telecommunications system.</continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0A15F2CE8A74A298F0AB6E4561946F3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Measures</header> <subparagraph id="HEEB38EE2FD8348EEAF4C38549E78D2FB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (2)(B), the Secretary, in conjunction with stakeholders (including chronic kidney care patient advocates, clinicians in the nephrology community, experts in the development of evidence-based guidelines for the detection, diagnosis, and management of chronic kidney care, and such other entities as the Secretary determines appropriate), shall specify measures of performance with respect to the tasks described in subparagraph (B). Such measures shall be in accordance with clinical guidelines in existence with respect to chronic kidney disease at the time of such specification.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22A60BF62211470690C180594A2C0212"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Tasks described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The tasks described in this subparagraph are the following:</text> <clause id="H653960A4229D4F038184200BF3678AD6"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reducing costs associated with hospitalizations of individuals described in paragraph (1) that are furnished CKD–EDT services by such practitioner.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9011A2ACC5F349FEAA92353E01AE4217"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providing education to such individuals regarding the importance of avoidance of non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs for patients with confirmed chronic kidney disease.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6DA8D2C8DD7840F495BE31BE7049E5C3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Providing appropriate prescription of kidney-protective blood pressure medications to such individuals for such chronic kidney disease (unless contra-indicated for individuals with confirmed chronic kidney disease), elevated urine albumin, and elevated blood pressure in alignment with evidence-based guidelines.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0F40819657064EC39876AA9AF673FE58"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Providing such individuals, as appropriate, with planned starts of renal replacement therapy through the receipt by such individuals of preemptive kidney transplants, the initiation of home dialysis, the initiation of outpatient in-center hemodialysis through arteriovenuous fistula or arteriovenous graft, or supportive care.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE774C289EE24BF196902AA192C0AE6C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Flexibility in measure specification</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the Secretary may specify measures that the Secretary develops for purposes of such subparagraph or that the Secretary did not develop for such purposes.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BB150402CCB4D6D99A68ED248643E9E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Application of early detection and treatment demonstration program provisions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, under this subsection, apply the provisions of paragraphs (4), (5), (6), (7), and (10) of subsection (a) to the advanced CKD demonstration program, advanced CKD practitioners, advanced CKD services, and individuals described in paragraph (1) to the same extent that such provisions apply under subsection (a) to the CKD early detection and treatment demonstration program, CKD–EDT practitioners, CKD–EDT services, and enrolled CKD–EDT individuals, respectively.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6789EF49C10C4B81AE78BDD880BFE221"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the following definitions apply:</text> <subparagraph id="H35FE1E0B24974B8691DDAA4C5D4B5271"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Advanced CKD practitioner</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (6), the term <term>advanced CKD practitioner</term> means, with respect to an individual described in paragraph (1), a nephrologist who—</text>
 <clause id="H63B120EA319F4BB79465B51B635FE36C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>participates in the Medicare program under this title;</text> </clause><clause id="H423AF91A04124604B6B85704F96BA41D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subject to subsection (a)(10)(A) as applied pursuant to paragraph (4), elects to participate in the advanced CKD demonstration program with respect to all individuals described in paragraph (1) who receive care from the nephrologist;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5CA6B2EC81E247438903B0252C63037C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">agrees to provide to each individual described in paragraph (1) who receives care from the nephrologist—</text>
 <subclause id="HE4D4EE2E83BE498C8143361C0A561F25"><enum>(I)</enum><text>educational materials that provide background information about chronic kidney disease and that are developed by credible organizations with expertise in the development of clinical guidelines and patient educational materials with respect to chronic kidney disease; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H29AAC1C7DBB742CFAFEEEE9F9CEB0B84"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a notification of the potential benefits that the individual may receive as a result of the practitioner participating in the advanced CKD demonstration program; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="HC58CC7F0F873489C88AD41C4DC374A7C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>agrees to comply with the requirements of subsection (a)(10), as applied pursuant to paragraph (4).</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20573366CAC8471F9934E6F8EBAC13CB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Advanced CKD services</header> <clause id="HB3A620BA079941ABA28185B87BFA25F1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>advanced CKD services</term> means, with respect to individuals described in paragraph (1), such services as the Secretary may specify that are care and management services for chronic kidney disease and that, subject to clause (iv), are services for which payment may otherwise be made under this title.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H343900096F4244518A3FC5E9C3C7C549"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Consultation required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining which services to specify for purposes of clause (i), the Secretary shall consult with—</text>
 <subclause id="H87E67819D1B74315AB3B564B78600E02"><enum>(I)</enum><text>chronic kidney disease patient advocates;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H14B7838B7BC745AD905D04049724214B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>clinicians in the nephrology community;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H49D23B00281947CA94318FB3CB642450"><enum>(III)</enum><text>experts in the development of evidence-based guidelines for the detection, diagnosis, and management of chronic kidney disease; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H5729DE96C1914CDB97BA3CACDF7C8C71"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>such other entities as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H033EC07974054F7A84983CF0747261E8"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Considered services</header><text>In specifying services for purposes of clause (i), the Secretary may, in addition to considering other services, consider the following services with respect to the care and management of chronic kidney disease:</text>
 <subclause id="HBCFCB6961CDB49C5A7E3FCBD6FA86066"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Kidney disease education benefit sessions.</text> </subclause><subclause id="HDC4FD6AB2B864938AB6688B1F0A72E41"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Patient care planning (including patient choice of renal replacement therapy or palliative or advanced care planning).</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H95C93DF2DF19420FB533E6F06C52CD11"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Comorbidities assessment and management (with respect to conditions such as anemia, bone and mineral abnormalities, and cardiovascular disease).</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H35B9F37814F14B0E9610850BB08BB856"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Mental health assessment and referral.</text> </subclause><subclause id="H5A5CDF3E0DF544EBB32057AD44CB0F90"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Practitioner consultation and coordination with cardiologists, endocrinologists, mental health specialists, primary care practitioners, and other appropriate health care providers and suppliers.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H88CE03603E0E4204A5BCABEC355CC654"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>Vascular or peritoneal dialysis access assessments and coordinations with surgeons.</text> </subclause><subclause id="H6CD7F8F30F68446C8E10E1D015E607A5"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>Referrals and coordinations with transplant centers.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H0ED962D20D5341CFAAACFB854BEB3AEF"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>Medication reconciliations and coordinations with pharmacists.</text> </subclause><subclause id="H037C960262764D07B5636948245997C3"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>Medical nutrition therapy administered by dieticians.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="H044FD0B191E740A692DB7C2A93970707"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Permissible inclusion of telehealth services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>advanced CKD services</term> may include services that are furnished via a telecommunications system by an advanced CKD practitioner to an individual described in paragraph (1) and that would have been advanced CKD services under clause (i) if such services had been furnished without the use of a telecommunications system.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFDAE721BC6804730B62DE106D1DED7A6"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Participation of care teams</header>
 <subparagraph id="HC91D891730BA41E3AD4507B0E890C490"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to an individual described in paragraph (1), a nephrologist for such individual may participate in a care team described in subparagraph (B) that, with respect to the furnishing of advanced CKD services to such individual, participates in the advanced CKD demonstration program as an advanced CKD practitioner. In applying this subsection, such group shall be treated as such an advanced CKD practitioner.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAEE97F7D13874D968535887E00974421"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Care team described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A care team described in this subparagraph, with respect to an individual described in paragraph (1), is, subject to subparagraph (C), a group of providers—</text>
 <clause id="H6415854287954A2D82F7BFF430C18261"><enum>(i)</enum><text>each of which participates in the Medicare program under this title;</text> </clause><clause id="H64AAB67165344C9985F5C060A9BD9504"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each of which elects to participate in the advanced CKD demonstration program with respect to all individuals described in paragraph (1) for whom the nephrologist described in subparagraph (A) is the nephrologist; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3C06C7F33DD247EB87F78E78DCD408C7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that agrees to provide to each individual described in paragraph (1) for whom the nephrologist described in subparagraph (A) is the nephrologist—</text>
 <subclause id="H2BBE3AE37E7448C489B6463C2842ED0D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>educational materials that provide background information about chronic kidney disease and that are developed by credible organizations with expertise in the development of clinical guidelines and patient educational materials with respect to chronic kidney disease; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB4E9F3F3488D40E0AE980A400E62C6E0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a notification of the potential benefits that the individual may receive as a result of the practitioner participating in the advanced CKD demonstration program.</text>
									</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD6847879CB2B4573B1F74A24A740B43B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Permissible assembly and administration by third party-administrator organizations</header>
 <clause id="H45E4F039891F480B9E3D19BC7AE07D3E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A care team described in subparagraph (B) may be assembled and administered by a third party-administrator organization.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC5B6D07CF4884F869B234CBBDCB003CE"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Third party-administrator organization</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>third party-administrator organization</term> means the following:</text> <subclause id="HDED7C0E0B0A34BBF89B8ECF6B745A5CE"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Medicare Advantage plan described in section 1851(a)(2) or a Medicare Advantage organization offering such a plan.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H29DE0CE9FCE1444AB8481275070C6177"><enum>(II)</enum><text>A prescription drug plan (as defined in section 1860D–41(a)(14)).</text> </subclause><subclause id="HA927A96E815941E2814D18915530CDDD"><enum>(III)</enum><text>A medicaid managed care organization (as defined in section 1903(m)).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


