<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB432591FBC9F4BB085015B52DA72E7D6" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2993 IH: Guantanamo Recidivism Reduction Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2993</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170621">June 21, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000813">Mrs. Walorski</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Defense to make available to Congress certain information relating to
			 individuals formerly detained at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo
			 Bay, Cuba, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H8D70A889AA87414C89325A5C96C3D313" style="OLC">
 <section id="H07F13EF5503C4F749EF82A2DDC50A408" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Guantanamo Recidivism Reduction Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H977A9ECC95284EA682647119AC92A4D7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Availability of information relating to activities of individuals formerly detained at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba</header> <subsection id="HD8826168CC184FED862C5CFCE7A20453"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual briefings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall provide to the following congressional committees annual briefings on the current activities and locations of covered individuals who the Secretary determines have engaged in acts of terrorism or support for terrorism after their transfer or release from detention at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba:</text>
 <paragraph id="H895D6F9B661D42A6A0FFEC83AC68BAE0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HED910414CE8D470DAEDB9054947CE62A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H400ADFAC1D2A4B0EA2FB4C8A3D4A4647"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability of agreements relating to former detainees</header><text>The Secretary of State shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8C58284E5E9E4F5ABAEB0DDA0A63C08E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>maintain written records containing the exact terms of any bilateral agreement between the United States and a country to which a covered individual is transferred or released relating to such transfer or release; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1EE15E80129D4EE8B6A1C56A20227087"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make such records available to Congress not later than 90 days after the conclusion of any such agreement.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9D0BF479D94F45AC958AA1F8B8FA29FA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Covered individual defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>covered individual</quote> means an individual who—</text> <paragraph id="HA1A1885F81984E119581934FF5750EB0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is not a member or former member of the Armed Forces;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB0DF7556E8C74DCD9B06494CEC5F161D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>on or after September 11, 2011, was detained by or otherwise under the effective control of the Department of Defense at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3B6F1A62C4AD4537BC74523D562422A0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>was transferred or released from such detention.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

