<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H02706DC8EAAC435A865B54422FDA98D2" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4313 IH: Fair Credit Reporting for Servicemembers Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4313</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171108">November 8, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Fair Credit Reporting Act to provide protections for active duty military consumers,
			 and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HA2974F0221914EE59920EA51AB0089B3" style="OLC">
 <section id="HAFC45221F46D4278A84A2E6065B31BE7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fair Credit Reporting for Servicemembers Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H25D22767E30A48F3B4703F7F1268897B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Notice of status as an active duty military consumer</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Fair Credit Reporting Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1681">15 U.S.C. 1681</external-xref> et seq.) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H3CFC1852A6404B9AA804981441E6DCD0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 603(q)(1)(B), by inserting before the period the following: <quote>for a period of not less than 90 days</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBB87EBF768204E4FBFBE9719E90C84DE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 605, by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3AB904366D8A418796E18C09C04BF4FF" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H184525F1DEC04D82A599B0CAC11339BF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Notice of status as an active duty military consumer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to an item of adverse information about a consumer, if the action or inaction that gave rise to the item occurred while the consumer was an active duty military consumer, the consumer may provide appropriate proof, including official orders, to a consumer reporting agency that the consumer was an active duty military consumer at the time such action or inaction occurred, and any consumer report provided by the consumer reporting agency that includes such item of information shall clearly and conspicuously disclose that the consumer was an active duty military consumer when the action or inaction that gave rise to the item occurred.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H39478371239B452B88EF89CE0B5718E8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 605A—</text> <subparagraph id="H03F7E6B6A4604D75B9069CC4DCC7B308"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text>
 <clause id="H0FB3412DBEE946A8922030F121DD24D9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Upon</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBB62782598464326BB2856EA34215D9A" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H7EF38D47080045088943A83FD1BA0D3B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause><clause id="HC4FB1B4581E54800AA055DCCBB8044A1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) as subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C), and moving such redesignated subparagraphs 2 ems to the right; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H018D97CDEB8D41288A0E804175924FAE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H86CF4C19318E40388D94F2D71D735077" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H21E167425C1F4A1CA73E5DBCDE1A47DA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Negative information alert</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any time a consumer reporting agency receives an item of adverse information about a consumer, if the consumer has provided appropriate proof that the consumer is an active duty military consumer, the consumer reporting agency shall promptly notify the consumer—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF19B8AC5B3A7465E9DDECAE32C3035C3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that the agency has received such item of adverse information, along with a description of the item; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A634DE560614ACA8DC464BB1684CA48"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the method by which the consumer can dispute the validity of the item.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB025F3FB4164A028A4448D2D77C53B0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contact information for active duty military consumers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to any consumer that has provided appropriate proof to a consumer reporting agency that the consumer is an active duty military consumer, if the consumer provides the consumer reporting agency with separate contact information to be used when communicating with the consumer while the consumer is an active duty military consumer, the consumer reporting agency shall use such contact information for all communications while the consumer is an active duty military consumer.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA80EACB011D94F70B79790A821846E4D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that any person making use of a consumer report containing an item of adverse information should, if the action or inaction that gave rise to the item occurred while the consumer was an active duty military consumer, take such fact into account when evaluating the creditworthiness of the consumer.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A0499B97B5C457DB879042C315FE22B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (e), by amending paragraph (3) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H02F25018D3F14B1A8013ADF9042B1E61" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H7FBEC90515E54F1F9FC2FCCE11C73DD8"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (c)(1), in the case of a referral under subsection (c)(1)(C).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H548D2E56866C45458B8AB9EB76EBD0F8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in section 611(a)(1), by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4906CAB98000466588A6A26A9F2122AC" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H164554B49FD54680A07B45CCC3262346"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Notice of dispute related to active duty military consumers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to any item of information described under subparagraph (A) that is under dispute, if the consumer has notified the consumer reporting agency, and provided appropriate proof, that the consumer was an active duty military consumer at the time the action or inaction that gave rise to the disputed item occurred, the consumer reporting agency shall include such fact in the consumer’s file and shall indicate that fact in each consumer report that includes the disputed item.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


