<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H172AE057288240649DF144B810F85D50" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3765 IH: To redesignate certain clinics of the Department of Veterans Affairs located in Montana.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3765</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170913">September 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000584">Mr. Gianforte</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To redesignate certain clinics of the Department of Veterans Affairs located in Montana.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HF8E70A95DC4F4251AD1E6390A2CAE736" style="OLC">
		<section id="H10E319B4E3AD4FB192BAC808DDC9564B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Redesignation of certain Department of Veterans Affairs Clinics in Montana</header>
			<subsection id="H488C7E030BAB47B7903EF77488DD1BB3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>David J. Thatcher Department of Veterans Affairs Clinic</header>
 <paragraph id="H76F76A9AD50B4AD7B8CFA8AAE89BA8CC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The clinic of the Department of Veterans Affairs located at 2687 Palmer Street in Missoula, Montana, shall after the date of the enactment of this Act be known and designated as the <quote>David J. Thatcher Department of Veterans Affairs Clinic</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5AE91974350244DCA031C21963725633"><enum>(2)</enum><header>References</header><text>Any reference in any law, regulation, map, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the clinic referred to in paragraph (1) shall be considered to be a reference to the David J. Thatcher Department of Veterans Affairs Clinic.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H36D340AC5AA444ED9CC635602973FA4A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Dr. Joseph Medicine Crow Department of Veterans Affairs Clinic</header>
 <paragraph id="HE205F83E80C94E77899F0E7F7E2709AA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The clinic of the Department of Veterans Affairs located at 1775 Spring Creek Lane in Billings, Montana, shall after the date of the enactment of this Act be known and designated as the <quote>Dr. Joseph Medicine Crow Department of Veterans Affairs Clinic</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5507D28AC5EC449FA19DD1F51934E81A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>References</header><text>Any reference in any law, regulation, map, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the clinic referred to in paragraph (1) shall be considered to be a reference to the Dr. Joseph Medicine Crow Department of Veterans Affairs Clinic.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H41BF4510BFBD4B6D8D7A83CA2AE27A25"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public display of name</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAAA923AC88B4495D8EFC3011828A0BD9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any local public display of the name of the clinic referred to in paragraph (1) carried out by the United States or through the use of Federal funds shall include the English name, Dr. Joseph Medicine Crow, and the Crow name, Dakaak Baako, of Dr. Joseph Medicine Crow.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H17D06907EADB48168B7A164BAB11F384"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Local display</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), a local public display of the name of the clinic referred to in paragraph (1) includes a display inside the clinic, on the campus of the clinic, and in the community surrounding the clinic, such as signs directing individuals to the clinic.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFB5204F03A7A49B5B8CEF0D966E2521F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Benjamin Charles Steele Department of Veterans Affairs Clinic</header>
 <paragraph id="H185047A13A614D12A0EE420C2648A448"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The clinic of the Department of Veterans Affairs located at 1766 Majestic Lane in Billings, Montana, shall after the date of the enactment of this Act be known and designated as the <quote>Benjamin Charles Steele Department of Veterans Affairs Clinic</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H29BD11ECCF0A497295AB424EAE8302DC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>References</header><text>Any reference in any law, regulation, map, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the clinic referred to in paragraph (1) shall be considered to be a reference to the Benjamin Charles Steele Department of Veterans Affairs Clinic.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


