<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H16362D77F0F84F1984BC9B7BECA8E6F3" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2428 IH: Accurate Workplace Injury and Illness Records Restoration Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2428</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170516">May 16, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001069">Mr. Courtney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001177">Mr. Sablan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001170">Ms. Shea-Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000410">Mr. Gene Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000108">Mr. Visclosky</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 to clarify when the time period for the
			 issuance of citations under such Act begins and to require a rule to
			 clarify that an employer’s duty to make and maintain accurate records of
			 work-related injuries and illnesses is an ongoing obligation.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H1EBABFC099EC416685108EF3ED7B365E" style="OLC">
 <section id="H1CE9F97664C346AFA45263B7414CC333" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Accurate Workplace Injury and Illness Records Restoration Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H751BE467299548B1BCA92BAB235890C5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Period for issuance of a citation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 9(c) of the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/658">29 U.S.C. 658(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>For purposes of this subsection, a violation continues to occur for as long as an employer has not satisfied the requirements, rules, standards, orders, and regulations referenced in subsection (a).</quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="H916A127431124D278F3D3F7C37198858"><enum>3.</enum><header>Rulemaking</header>
 <subsection id="H0FE8D7728B1D460E9623BDB4FA6B954C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rule required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Occupational Safety and Health Administration shall issue a final rule amending its recordkeeping regulations under section 8(c) of the Occupational Safety and Health Act to clarify that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB088E0031C9B4834B4F678100B859F5D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the duty to make and maintain accurate records of work-related injuries and illnesses is an ongoing obligation;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4DE16E24035343A9994957FE7A8BC200"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the duty to make and maintain such records continues for as long as the employer is required to keep records of the recordable injury or illness; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H023AE0BB4903459891A7BB037380F805"><enum>(3)</enum><text>such duty does not expire solely because the employer fails to create the necessary records when first required to do so.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0B8031EFFB6941C2902645B3DFC327DF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) shall be considered a specific authorization by Congress in accordance with section 801(b)(2) of title 5, United States Code, with respect to the issuance of a new recordkeeping rule.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


