<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD5BED653C7E34284A5CB414746B5891C" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1119 IH: SENSE Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1119</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170216">February 16, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000598">Mr. Rothfus</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001269">Mr. Barletta</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the bases by which the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall
			 issue, implement, and enforce certain emission limitations and allocations
			 for existing electric utility steam generating units that convert coal
			 refuse into energy.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H955170EE8C53466DA6FB305D903A5E75" style="OLC">
 <section id="H627CCA4265574F2E861CB7418C655337" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Satisfying Energy Needs and Saving the Environment Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote>SENSE Act</quote>.</text> </section><section id="HE05FF9B34BF54D06AB94F87349EAEBAD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Standards for coal refuse power plants</header> <subsection id="H82D13C6DBB964108A2714077675B98FC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="H75B122B53D6848449D622E5398EC4F61"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6645547554C14441A78CDAEEF17FC687"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Boiler operating day</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>boiler operating day</term> has the meaning given such term in section 63.10042 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H83E296E10AFD4E52B71899D379F8E3C8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Coal refuse</header><text>The term <term>coal refuse</term> means any byproduct of coal mining, physical coal cleaning, or coal preparation operation that contains coal, matrix material, clay, and other organic and inorganic material.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC840A99C1D64449D8E2ADFBCF9A5CFBA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Coal refuse electric utility steam generating unit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>coal refuse electric utility steam generating unit</term> means an electric utility steam generating unit that—</text> <subparagraph id="H4035894493D545A39BBA1014C2FF656F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is in operation as of the date of enactment of this Act;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE598A5BEA4214651AA5470B323B741B5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>uses fluidized bed combustion technology to convert coal refuse into energy; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78FDE29A38B94C7DB923650F5F3F7F50"><enum>(C)</enum><text>uses coal refuse as at least 75 percent of the annual fuel consumed, by heat input, of the unit.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HEABD4D47A063425D83957BEA48A4CAEE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Coal refuse-fired facility</header><text>The term <term>coal refuse-fired facility</term> means all coal refuse electric utility steam generating units that are—</text> <subparagraph id="HD5F53F6A5C554DFE8FD50DF8A32BBF1C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>located on one or more contiguous or adjacent properties;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF0ED1BC03428452989495597E7455338"><enum>(B)</enum><text>specified within the same Major Group (2-digit code), as described in the Standard Industrial Classification Manual (1987); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81DB58B3C27D4FE1852C23B181305621"><enum>(C)</enum><text>under common control of the same person (or persons under common control).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6CB040A817534A0F93A08379D85B47DB"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Cross-State Air Pollution Rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>Cross-State Air Pollution Rule</term> and <term>CSAPR</term> mean the regulatory program promulgated by the Administrator to address the interstate transport of air pollution in parts 51, 52, and 97 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, including any subsequent or successor regulation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H783A59CD3B6D417CBF913015266EA2FF"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Electric utility steam generating unit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>electric utility steam generating unit</term> means either or both—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H2E8CD7C3946C4D7EBFA55A62DBF0B74C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an electric utility steam generating unit, as such term is defined in section 63.10042 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5AFA80B247634E0FA5F72307A363552F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an electricity generating unit or electric generating unit, as such terms are used in CSAPR.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE191137F9A1640689498F6F0AE2D6D94"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Phase I</header><text>The term <term>Phase I</term> means, with respect to CSAPR, the initial compliance period under CSAPR, identified for the 2015 and 2016 annual compliance periods.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H15A46C415D9848429B7D789DE55483BB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application of CSAPR to certain coal refuse electric utility steam generating units</header>
				<paragraph commented="no" id="H31C8BEFB0A7844F681C3DF7899B4A686"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Coal refuse electric utility steam generating units combusting bituminous coal refuse</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H1A1D1356B98044F3B51D4EB65A2B1FD1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This paragraph applies with respect to any coal refuse electric utility steam generating unit that—</text> <clause id="HD850BCB2262B464F87AA074B38500F11"><enum>(i)</enum><text>combusts coal refuse derived from the mining and processing of bituminous coal; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H284613400EA842468B223FB3DB6209AA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is subject to sulfur dioxide allowance surrender provisions pursuant to CSAPR.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H909FA3905580436AA7304C9F84004BFA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Continued applicability of Phase I allowance allocations</header><text>In carrying out CSAPR, the Administrator shall provide that, for any compliance period, the allocation (whether through a Federal implementation plan or State implementation plan) of sulfur dioxide allowances for a coal refuse electric utility steam generating unit described in subparagraph (A) is equivalent to the allocation of the unit-specific sulfur dioxide allowance allocation identified for such unit for Phase I, as referenced in the notice entitled <quote>Availability of Data on Allocations of Cross-State Air Pollution Rule Allowances to Existing Electricity Generating Units</quote> (79 Fed. Reg. 71674 (December 3, 2014)).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9378DA0D14974D76AD96332B9F1097E0"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Rules for allowance allocations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For any compliance period under CSAPR that commences on or after January 1, 2017, any sulfur dioxide allowance allocation provided by the Administrator to a coal refuse electric utility steam generating unit described in subparagraph (A)—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="HFB7A1D1633ED42F39F00FC0A57EF1F00"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall not be transferable for use by any other source not located at the same coal refuse-fired facility as the relevant coal refuse electric utility steam generating unit;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H970150A844314424A666C7BF1E44D184"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may be transferable for use by another source located at the same coal refuse-fired facility as the relevant coal refuse electric utility steam generating unit;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1A8196DFBF9247A6A6CCB637793131E1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may be banked for application to compliance obligations in future compliance periods under CSAPR; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H41EC54BDCC3947B2B44C863CE3358E0F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>shall be surrendered upon the permanent cessation of operation of such coal refuse electric utility steam generating unit.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H16BDA95178A345C7A5C4658CFF7C08CB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other sources</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H8717F981D0D04DB28CEA38D377C0825A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>No increase in overall State budget of sulfur dioxide allowance allocations</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), the Administrator may not, for any compliance period under CSAPR, increase the total budget of sulfur dioxide allowance allocations for a State in which a unit described in paragraph (1)(A) is located.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H151636DF015C44A388D232FA80FF8085"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Compliance periods 2017 through 2020</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For any compliance period under CSAPR that commences on or after January 1, 2017, but before December 31, 2020, the Administrator shall carry out subparagraph (A) by proportionally reducing, as necessary, the unit-specific sulfur dioxide allowance allocations from each source that—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="HEAACE12115DD47458E446D3E3B44FDEE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is located in a State in which a unit described in paragraph (1)(A) is located;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HF9BE5120E0BD42B6B22C6410F2DDE912"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>permanently ceases operation, or converts its primary fuel source from coal to natural gas, prior to the relevant compliance period; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H44108CB1E84243DD8D32398F204A37BD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>otherwise receives an allocation of sulfur dioxide allowances under CSAPR for such period.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H7249F51E1B984409AFE5D7F989E17A6B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Emission limitations To address hydrogen chloride and sulfur dioxide as hazardous air pollutants</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="H167F67461C964A0395F700542BEC5F6E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>For purposes of regulating emissions of hydrogen chloride or sulfur dioxide from a coal refuse electric utility steam generating unit under section 112 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7412">42 U.S.C. 7412</external-xref>), the Administrator—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HA001FD2028DB426F8ED233F16F7D7DF1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall authorize the operator of such unit to elect that such unit comply with either—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H10D88D460EF04FD1A9A2246ED054BC12"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an emissions standard for emissions of hydrogen chloride that meets the requirements of paragraph (2); or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H872F83FEBEA3481692AD1E3DDE9A06F7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an emission standard for emissions of sulfur dioxide that meets the requirements of paragraph (2); and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H097D221DE007452CAF094641203F6576"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may not require that such unit comply with both an emission standard for emissions of hydrogen chloride and an emission standard for emissions of sulfur dioxide.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H42F2ED407AD745B0A50BD9FF115A861A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rules for emission limitations</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H719BE68BCA3C4E24BE17FC06F5F5412C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall require an operator of a coal refuse electric utility steam generating unit to comply, at the election of the operator, with no more than one of the following emission standards:</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="HFE330572FB0743D69224642CEF1B5C10"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An emission standard for emissions of hydrogen chloride from such unit that is no more stringent than an emission rate of 0.002 pounds per million British thermal units of heat input.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H78A8FD36CC334795BB6734B0B89A6197"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>An emission standard for emissions of hydrogen chloride from such unit that is no more stringent than an emission rate of 0.02 pounds per megawatt-hour.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H44CE9D68200F4BAF8714054F4E5EF638"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>An emission standard for emissions of sulfur dioxide from such unit that is no more stringent than an emission rate of 0.20 pounds per million British thermal units of heat input.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HA54EC701B7DA41BAA083D6623E89610B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>An emission standard for emissions of sulfur dioxide from such unit that is no more stringent than an emission rate of 1.5 pounds per megawatt-hour.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H9363CB45F7934D0682C920A26B69159D"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An emission standard for emissions of sulfur dioxide from such unit that is no more stringent than capture and control of 93 percent of sulfur dioxide across the generating unit or group of generating units, as determined by comparing—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" id="H42FCD415CB1F49EF95FBD710A558C70A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the expected sulfur dioxide generated from combustion of fuels emissions calculated based upon as-fired fuel samples, to</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H804413446B9E4286985857C08E7740BB"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the actual sulfur dioxide emissions as measured by a sulfur dioxide continuous emission monitoring system.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H785C9846D1804029B1007DEA7C4A0056"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Measurement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An emission standard described in subparagraph (A) shall be measured as a 30 boiler operating day rolling average per coal refuse electric utility steam generating unit or group of coal refuse electric utility steam generating units located at a single coal refuse-fired facility.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


