<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H0E541F85F21846BAA922BCADCFC0BF0F" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1795 IH: DUE PROCESS Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1795</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170329">March 29, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000244">Mr. Sensenbrenner</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000289">Mr. Jordan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000573">Mr. Labrador</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C000266">Mr. Chabot</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 18, United States Code, to reform certain forfeiture procedures, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HB55E0910966844818D37679936780A2A" style="OLC">
 <section id="HF4322D9B67CA4567AD908C0972F10C67" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>DUE PROCESS Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Deterring Undue Enforcement by Protecting Rights Of Citizens from Excessive Searches and Seizures Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="H398412C132FA4803B9DE67FC4DF5B261"><enum>2.</enum><header>General rules for civil forfeiture proceedings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 983(a) of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HD7D7AB0C56D049379DC18F870F7E8322"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="USC">complaint</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="USC">complaint; initial hearing</header-in-text></quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBCF6F3A8A8954828B3AD80B8F8D25E5C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H3D6467923CD54CB5B1FA9A1B9C1A5DC0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (A)—</text>
 <clause id="H1D255F220D0D4EAD9258E5BB76CF47CC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>60 days</quote> and inserting <quote>30 days</quote>;</text> </clause><clause id="HD66F44E459714123B7BE9F0A7255546C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking clause (ii);</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC5183DB605134F669189F0B66096679E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in clause (iii)—</text> <subclause id="HEAA128AC85D645979085B2716CE94C7D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subclause (I)—</text>
 <item id="H45D9CE92D82C415D9F409E8C4213B552"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>by striking <quote>60-day</quote> and inserting <quote>30-day</quote>; and</text> </item><item id="HF63316A1B1244E72BBAACC64C4C47D95"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>by striking <quote>does not file</quote> and all that follows through <quote>obtain</quote> and inserting <quote>obtains</quote>; and</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="HEA80FC3C75604B028909712F03C0CF5B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in subclause (I), by striking <quote>60 days</quote> and inserting <quote>30 days</quote>;</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H8C1759324E5443E2A360E20AEC59ED5F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in clause (iv), by striking <quote>90 days</quote> and inserting <quote>60 days</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2336239605AA42D6BDD2A47949EA58FD"><enum>(v)</enum><text>in clause (v), by striking <quote>60 days</quote> and inserting <quote>30 days</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H3999E719259A4FA59044853CB12A01AE"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA581CC2180FB43F7AB46B83A90BC20F1" style="USC">
 <clause id="H3DC14183D8B94AB1AAE84ED2C7BC07E8" indent="up2"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The notice under this subparagraph shall include an address, which shall also be widely published, at which the seizing agency can receive until 5 p.m. on any business day an interested party’s claim contesting a seizure or forfeiture. The interested party may send such a claim to that address by courier or overnight mail. For the purpose of determining compliance with any deadlines in filing such a claim, an interested party completes the filing by placing the communication making the claim in the control of an independent third party delivery service such as a courier company or the United States mail. In determining whether any legal deadline for the filing of such a claim has been met a court shall allow for the equitable tolling of the deadline in appropriate cases.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF8408A8CD91B4338852363B43A54C4FF" indent="up2"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>The seizing agency shall make publicly available for each nonjudicial forfeiture, with respect to which a request for mitigation or remission is made, a statement of the agency’s disposition of that request, redacted if necessary, including the reasons for the decision.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H59AEA5B830CA48C1ADAAFD941B170763"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)—</text> <clause id="HEB5A00BE172648A9A9E93C0D8FCA4C64"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>60</quote> and inserting <quote>30</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1C216C2DB28141C9867111ABA829372C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>which period may</quote> and all that follows through <quote>as necessary,</quote>;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64853A4234904A6193DDEE8D7A40910A"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H55F5B37B5EC140BA8374FB9AE2505567" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H52149E07F3FB45DE98F87E46847F3BB3" indent="up1"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Any notice described in subparagraph (A) that is provided to a party shall include notice of—</text> <clause id="H23AE10AC2CB24D9390BCF1266D43AF30"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the right of the party to request an initial hearing in accordance with paragraph (5);</text>
 </clause><clause id="H127418B61B3A444E88E6E0408EFE3119"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the right of the party to be represented by counsel at the initial hearing described in clause (i) and any civil forfeiture proceeding under a civil forfeiture statute; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD641467E38AB4BA795EDC5369058DF8B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the right of the party to request that the party be represented by counsel at the initial hearing described in clause (i) and any civil forfeiture proceeding under a civil forfeiture statute if the party meets the requirements described in subsection (b).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96486BC708114D49A707E370CB917497"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>nonjudicial</quote> each place it appears;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC80E6EB9CE8C46CD8944F2AD473DFA26"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(A), by striking <quote>nonjudicial</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE4D8DD13F1B84CF8BE413918D2F6194A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(B)—</text> <subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9D2D4C50E8CD44F69EAA58FFF536BA30"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>35 days</quote> and inserting <quote>65 days</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F7F10BE984E4F0AB1339F3D569E49C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>30 days</quote> and inserting <quote>60 days</quote>;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB4038F193FDF4855A392A5CB211AC1F7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>so that subparagraph (A) of paragraph (3) reads as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0F97F8BF5B2447C6A112F3685E2FAF99" style="USC">
 <subparagraph id="H768C4E09D61A47A1A93E2AC915D3B0C8" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after a claim has been filed, the Government shall file a complaint for forfeiture in the manner set forth in the Supplemental Rules for Certain Admiralty and Maritime Claims or return the property pending the filing of a complaint, except that a court in the district in which the complaint has been filed may extend the period for filing a complaint upon agreement of the parties.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9888AA55F58346D1B2211CA12AF2023D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4D6E479308BA42139528BBEE9EFF96A2" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H699A9B2CCB3045D88135F3A9F0EF4F7F"><enum>(5)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H88D28FD717F34755B128168E81C76841"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A party claiming property seized in a civil forfeiture proceeding under a civil forfeiture statute may request, not later than 30 days after the date on which a notice described in paragraph (1)(A) is received or if notice is not received, not later than 30 days after the date of final publication of notice of seizure, an initial hearing to take place before a magistrate judge in the appropriate United States district court not later than the date on which a civil forfeiture proceeding under a civil forfeiture statute relating to the seized property commences.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13F37E3235F44E76B5F0BB6D84988410" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If a party makes a request under subparagraph (A), a magistrate judge shall conduct an initial hearing not later than 10 days after the date on which the request is made.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H39983074279D4F5EB0DDFC7297622800" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>At the initial hearing—</text> <clause id="HBA3153D3A6A94B9E9680373C4D2A1312"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the magistrate judge shall—</text>
 <subclause id="H88C57356D9054E55BCEDA19B1960BDEF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>inform the party in easily understood terms of—</text> <item id="H48E51CCCF35F4A87AB2C0DA376E8A02D"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the right of the party to be represented by counsel at the initial hearing and any civil forfeiture proceeding under a civil forfeiture statute;</text>
 </item><item id="H3F02D942482F4A79BA838EAA318BDC7F"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the right of the party to request that the party be represented by counsel at the initial hearing and any civil forfeiture proceeding under a civil forfeiture statute if the magistrate judge finds that the party meets the requirements described in subsection (b);</text>
 </item><item id="H377097B69A834D819B780AB328219C45"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>sufficiently detailed facts regarding the seizure of the property if the property was seized pursuant to a warrant described in the matter preceding subparagraph (A) of section 981(b)(2); and</text>
 </item><item id="H241369A0949F4BA7806D3074BA7F410C"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>the right of the party to challenge the lawfulness of the seizure of the property, including on the grounds that at the time the property was seized—</text>
 <subitem id="H21A815018A344EC580FB4FE77EB05524"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>if the property was seized pursuant to a warrant described in the matter preceding subparagraph (A) of section 981(b)(2), the warrant was not supported by probable cause; or</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="HE1A4925A58FE4EE098D4F5495E17200A"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>if the property was seized without a warrant described in subitem (AA), none of the exceptions described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of section 981(b)(2) apply to the seizure of the property; and</text>
 </subitem></item></subclause><subclause id="H2B875ED91C3D4BD09BA3B3222C49DF34"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if the party meets the requirements described in subsection (b), authorize counsel to represent the party or insure that the party is represented by an attorney for the Legal Services Corporation, as applicable, in accordance with that subsection; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HCF4EFE5A791046C3A509176E9EA09ECD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the burden of proof is on the Government to establish that at the time the property was seized—</text> <subclause id="HD60A7E6C02A04E82BC71A1852E1323F6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>if the property was seized pursuant to a warrant described in the matter preceding subparagraph (A) of section 981(b)(2), the warrant was supported by probable cause; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H13B6F61AED23478BA98192DF6B13E9B3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if the property was seized without a warrant described in subclause (I)—</text> <item id="H496A91FCC451460B8E25E9CC09A3054B"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>sufficiently detailed facts regarding the seizure of the property; and</text>
 </item><item id="H5E0B6BB187CD404981D065DEA7F3E5F6"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>an exception described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of section 981(b)(2) applies to the seizure of the property.</text>
 </item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E9A96FB27794970A9C3609927CE03B6" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The magistrate judge shall enter an order for the immediate release of the seized property with prejudice to the right of the Government to commence a civil forfeiture proceeding at a later time if the magistrate judge finds that—</text>
 <clause id="H3FA3293CD85D4A6BA6993FC58BE0390B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the requirements described in subparagraphs (A) through (E) of subsection (f)(1) are met; and</text> </clause><clause id="H0C0505D564CA46299A57D499DF063570"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Government did not meet the burden of proof described in subparagraph (C)(ii).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H553D2AC7C3FD45B0BFC17FE1CBB051BF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Representation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 983(b) of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H1129D8C9A3BC4E318EA008385744AA37"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(A), by striking <quote>judicial</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA986126A2AF44561A4E4786BC62AB40E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(A), by striking <quote>judicial civil forfeiture proceeding under a civil forfeiture statute is financially unable to obtain representation by counsel, and the property subject to forfeiture is real property that is being used by the person as a primary residence</quote> and inserting <quote>civil forfeiture proceeding under a civil forfeiture statute is financially unable to obtain representation by counsel</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H9CBF977BB35842D5AEA7446A0B5115B1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Burden of proof</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 983(c) of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HA1E86D961CCE42C5B247D36BF93EDCCD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>a preponderance of the evidence</quote> and inserting <quote>clear and convincing evidence</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFF3AE57B6DB9442FA62A220C786618CB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>a preponderance of the evidence</quote> and inserting <quote>clear and convincing evidence</quote>.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H5F6B4373F679476F9B682D3BF1375184"><enum>5.</enum><header>Right to request hearing on pretrial restraint of property to retain counsel of choice</header> <subsection id="HDD57CDC09A924E4F9EFCA30A090D344A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Title 18</header><text>Section 1963(d) of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA84F0DCA86544017822ED831FD5CEB83"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking paragraph (1) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8EA25F6D3E624C2ABD87D301AF024840" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H4834BE6EFA4D4F769179778E1646082E" indent="up1"><enum>(1)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H5E20DA7157D94B2386044C283AAB0267"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Upon application of the United States, the court may enter a restraining order or injunction, require the execution of a satisfactory performance bond, or take any other action to preserve the availability of property described in subsection (a) for forfeiture under this section—</text>
 <clause id="H25104020B3764C2E9E5A794B4117D6A8" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>upon the filing of an indictment or information charging a violation of section 1962 and alleging that the property with respect to which the order is sought would, in the event of conviction, be subject to forfeiture under this section; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD58F1E87EA664441B25ECE7F90880F3A" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>prior to the filing of such an indictment or information, if, after notice to persons appearing to have an interest in the property and opportunity for a hearing, the court determines that—</text>
 <subclause id="H72620F09DE5F4819996EFD4F6844727F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>there is a substantial probability that the United States will prevail on the issue of forfeiture and that failure to enter the order will result in the property being destroyed, removed from the jurisdiction of the court, or otherwise made unavailable for forfeiture; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE0EBBB9777B44A0291E920331179EC31"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the need to preserve the availability of the property through the entry of the requested order outweighs the hardship on any party against whom the order is to be entered.</text>
									</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C3C93AEDC7C4D0DB0C2E4993B8B5F97" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD15DCE22CEB4479B83F72E4527C9E09A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Upon motion of a defendant charged with a violation of section 1962 for which criminal forfeiture is ordered under this section and against whom the order is entered, supported by an affidavit, the court shall hold a hearing to determine whether to modify or rescind, in whole or in part, an order entered under subparagraph (A) to allow the defendant to use the property subject to the order to retain counsel of choice.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2D963C04D29B4B59BB14452EB7E6F58E" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>At the hearing, the court shall consider—</text> <subclause id="HD3159AF792BC45CBA95049AF370EB97F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the weight of the evidence against the defendant with respect to the violation of section 1962 for which criminal forfeiture is ordered under this section;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H44D791F7BF9440B9896DDADE2FE5ECC3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the weight of the evidence with respect to whether the property will be subject to forfeiture under this section;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H476AD3EF6C15445AB50C364A5E4944C9"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the history and characteristics of the defendant; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HEBEA46040CFE42FC852C4851F08ADD25"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the nature and circumstances of the case.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5DCC6825AEFE42A39C95CB42825EBD26" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An order entered pursuant to subparagraph (A)(ii) shall be effective for not more than 90 days, unless—</text>
 <clause id="H71E00E838A3A466B83FC72B6C4D2E731"><enum>(i)</enum><text>extended by the court for good cause shown; or</text> </clause><clause id="HA2637CC9C86C473B8EF6587C414146E3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an indictment or information described in subparagraph (A)(i) has been filed.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB9B22F831A424459B445E444AA32EF75"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by inserting <quote>that the defendant committed a violation of section 1962 for which criminal forfeiture may be ordered under this section and probable cause to believe</quote> after <quote>believe</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD682F2B75B5A4F0486828E759DD98CE8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Controlled Substances Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 413(e) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/853">21 U.S.C. 853(e)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H6BD8706F491A4F6C9FC53CB115079AAC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking paragraph (1) and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H667EE9AE10BE4FFCAB36A6F8DCAE1CCA" style="OLC">
						<paragraph id="HB9E93856BAA34A8EAD0EE7BBEB1D2B31" indent="up1"><enum>(1)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H024FE361A73945F4A4274D48B0EFDBC4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Upon application of the United States, the court may enter a restraining order or injunction, require the execution of a satisfactory performance bond, or take any other action to preserve the availability of property described in subsection (a) for forfeiture under this section—</text>
 <clause id="H26ED4BC37D9A4DBE8142827D0DF4F2F8" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>upon the filing of an indictment or information charging a violation of this title or title III for which criminal forfeiture may be ordered under this section and alleging that the property with respect to which the order is sought would, in the event of conviction, be subject to forfeiture under this section; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9033FE520F514521A8A8566384FD6308" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>prior to the filing of such an indictment or information, if, after notice to persons appearing to have an interest in the property and opportunity for a hearing, the court determines that—</text>
 <subclause id="H164FAABE62744A4DA391C10BF6E2418E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>there is a substantial probability that the United States will prevail on the issue of forfeiture and that failure to enter the order will result in the property being destroyed, removed from the jurisdiction of the court, or otherwise made unavailable for forfeiture; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H8BF29A5C66044D2F93153DF21618D7B7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the need to preserve the availability of the property through the entry of the requested order outweighs the hardship on any party against whom the order is to be entered.</text>
									</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBDE2B7D8435A4DD5998ABDA0CFF4E7F8" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7DA2F8BC336244FC88D585B26189EB51"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon motion of a defendant charged with a violation of section 1962 for which criminal forfeiture is ordered under this section and against whom the order is entered, supported by an affidavit sufficient to demonstrate a genuine need for the defendant to use the property subject to an order entered under subparagraph (A) to retain counsel of choice, the court shall hold a hearing to determine whether to modify or rescind, in whole or in part, the order to allow the defendant to use the property to retain counsel of choice.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3B175FC08A99404FB380E285D6AB6568" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>At the hearing, the court shall consider—</text> <subclause id="H088C1FD9309D4365B796B5A01D78880D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the weight of the evidence against the defendant with respect to the violation of this title or title III for which criminal forfeiture is be ordered under this section;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H0FDDE4BC25F744E6B2026FC9F9036CDC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the weight of the evidence with respect to whether the property will be subject to forfeiture under this section;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA9D38DCDCD7B477793355D2DD0388A27"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the history and characteristics of the defendant; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H90DDE1D14394446F92031AD81652D9EA"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the nature and circumstances of the case.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE1F96E6D950409EA60D1FB1488B70FA" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An order entered pursuant to subparagraph (A)(ii) shall be effective for not more than 90 days, unless—</text>
 <clause id="H52C72B51821948CAA298E20634B6B8B9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>extended by the court for good cause shown; or</text> </clause><clause id="HE6C8AB528FAE4BEB97B63946F1F6AA9B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an indictment or information described in subparagraph (A)(i) has been filed.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA58D64D2B54348A0BDD123DE01BDDC84"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by inserting <quote>that the defendant committed a violation of this title or title III for which criminal forfeiture may be ordered under this section and probable cause to believe</quote> after <quote>believe</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H48A1C69D6111450C9613D2C1D4172D4A"><enum>6.</enum><header>Recovery of attorneys fees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2465(b) of title 28, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H5D68B6CE70D3497C9FC53569C420E706"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>substantially</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF3E4530E4C2C4EF385403A25E6F2C503"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8C589E14C0274F98A4FB0D4E05FBDFBC" style="USC"> <paragraph id="H39DB4ACB796B42CAA5A34D421C35CBC4" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the claim is resolved by a settlement in which the claimant prevails, the claimant is entitled to attorneys fees under this subsection to the same extent that the claimant would be if a judgment were issued in the proceeding for the property recovered under the settlement. The payment of attorneys fees under this subsection may not be waived as a part of any settlement with the claimant. That payment is not subject to any offset or deduction by the United States in connection with any claim the United States may have against the claimant.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H009E9110DCDB47EE84AC3E0DA430D945" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>For the purposes of this subsection, a claimant prevails if the claimant recovers more than 50 percent, by value, of the money or other property that is claimed.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H93E608DBB08B44A895C8508A2D232C43"><enum>7.</enum><header>Annual audit of civil forfeitures</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Inspector General shall annually conduct an audit of a representative sample of Federal civil forfeitures under statutes described in section 983(i) of title 18, United States Code, to ensure those forfeitures are constitutionally sound and consistent with the letter and spirit of the law. The Department of Justice Inspector General shall report the results of the audit to the Attorney General and to Congress. Such report shall also include the fiscal status of the Asset Forfeiture Fund and Treasury Forfeiture Fund, including any projected growth or shrinking of the Funds in future years, and the viability of the Funds.</text>
		</section><section id="HE126165DC4504337B1CDDF0DCC147D83"><enum>8.</enum><header>Publicly available databases</header>
 <subsection id="H82BF41F5105B4666A542D8A0D6BBC7AC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Quarterly updated database on details of forfeitures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall establish and maintain, with updates on a quarterly basis, a publicly available database that describes with respect to seizures for all Federal civil forfeiture containing the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H8681722AE96342EEAE4EB6DBA4979F2D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each such seizure:</text> <subparagraph id="H2FFDFBF04E424905A49AAB0D6C4E9FA3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Unit of an agency responsible for the seizure, and the location, including at a minimum the State, city, and judicial district where and date when the seizure took place.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3479DBA8BEB34DFB955B9901067FD650"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The type of initial seizure (such as during a stop based on probable cause, or pursuant to a Federal warrant).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8B3A96E336D4258AAE1C2C8A69E7FB9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The nature and value of the seized property.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C8602C866FC4611BD9750529942B3EC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>In what manner forfeiture of seized property was conducted (whether by a civil or administrative proceeding, through settlement, or otherwise).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4DB968AEE3054BBF850DD213FE3E5712"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Whether a forfeiture of the seized property was of the entire property, or only a part, and if partial, the proportion of the whole that was forfeited.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HADABDE7DC9D64156BAC6248B05F0EF9C"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The disposition of the seized property, the date of forfeiture, if any, and the date the disposition took place.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD8EA5366690466B9879168EFDB537D7"><enum>(G)</enum><text>What type of criminal activity any forfeited property relates to.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69F5A3D348D147D2AD204304D8AEE7EF"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Whether any forfeited money was returned to the victim of a crime in connection with which the forfeiture occurred, and the amount returned.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3AAE23D391CA4677ABB843C90C9DC06D"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The status of any concurrent or related criminal proceeding against the owner of the property, any pending case under title 11 in which the owner of record of the property is the debtor, and any pending civil case in which a receiver has been ordered to take control of the property.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7DD983E356C04A7B93E800909864B535"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the forfeiture was contested.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3AAEF73D73EB4CACAF5AAB24F2EAEFB4"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the innocent owner made a claim on the property.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B30B27D2DA64D06ADBD6028E5AEDEE6"><enum>(L)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The total expenses associated with the forfeiture.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD3E5093423CB4359AD8E5B71204D56B8"><enum>(M)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The total net proceeds of the forfeiture.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0ED4085B40D948DE87EE39412BC8B383"><enum>(N)</enum><text>Demographic information on the person or persons subject to the seizure.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H72A75E0CF32442FEB7C380F5E2693E15"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A statistical breakdown for each agency of the cases of remission and mitigation, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7134715D10004CAB94CC9F78C98FF265"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the numbers of requests for remission and mitigation that were—</text> <clause id="H90258C594DD64F85AEBA4FEA3F16B436"><enum>(i)</enum><text>fully granted;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD97E9433C2B44476B0D723B614945969"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>partially granted; or</text> </clause><clause id="HD3F8C1378888421BB46687531735E382"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>returned; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5052D06A46AC407C9AA32C9F8CFB25D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to requests that were partially granted—</text> <clause id="HEDBD949F4DDF431FB9AB97506FFF6F36"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the average percentage of the value of seized property that was returned to the owner; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H319DFC6E68DB4204A7283D7A553DDA40"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>what percentage of requests resulted in returned property in each of the following categories:</text> <subclause id="H2ADFA6E5ECF745EA87D0A7BD55686C6A"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">More than zero but less than 25 percent of the property was returned.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD9134D69002A4D929EB2A08A55BA5AEF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>25 percent or more of the property was returned, but less than 50 percent.</text> </subclause><subclause id="HA2C62FC3CD5A45CFAEE60DFF6293F9EA"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">50 percent or more of the property was returned, but less than 75 percent.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE8BC92CBA31044C2BF4BBD0069E73505"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>75 percent or more of the property was returned, but less than 100 percent.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7B64E70FA52B4E6E8474FCEAFC1A0027"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any money given from the Asset Forfeiture Fund or Treasury Forfeiture Fund to State or local law enforcement for Joint Law Enforcement Operations (commonly referred to as <quote>JLEO</quote>) funding, or for any other purpose, and the name of the State or local entity receiving that funding.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H580A214F4081461B87FFAE318F54C32C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Real-Time database To assist persons whose property is seized</header>
 <paragraph id="HF68A2141A69C40B89DA56C49870E13F7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Attorney General shall establish and maintain, with updates on a real-time basis, a database, organized by State and county, with respect to each Federal seizure of real and personal property for Federal civil forfeiture under statutes described in section 983(i) of title 18, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1D471EA040AB4B7B8F8B951E6A33A7EC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Design</header><text>The Attorney General shall design the database to allow any interested party, including any owner, creditor, or lienholder, to determine whether that party has an interest in any such property and to inform that party, and the general public, on the specifics of how to contest each seizure before the forfeiture.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6E85F87BD1A5472C9C713BE5162E8ABE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Heads of agencies To submit information for databases</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less frequently than quarterly, on a schedule determined by the Attorney General, the head of each Federal agency shall submit to the Attorney General a report that provides, in such form as the Attorney General may prescribe, the information the Attorney General is required to include in the databases established under this section.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HA4BE038201334702A273E032395335CA"><enum>9.</enum><header>Standard of proof relating to possibly innocent owners</header>
 <subsection id="H405802CB3ECA449AB44D123BA5EDAA6C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Burden of proof</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (3) of section 983(c) of title 18, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4E309456CB8344618FAC33881FCDECA9" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H527903B3629443CD919D81E460FDE35E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the Government’s theory of forfeiture is that the property was used to commit or facilitate the commission of a criminal offense, or was involved in the commission of a criminal offense, the Government shall establish by clear and convincing evidence that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H43BE22C524074240BF2779429AE6AB37"><enum>(A)</enum><text>there was a substantial connection between the property and the offense; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA5CC6199E994F7B8C499828FC9A08AA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the owner of any interest in the seized property—</text>
 <clause id="H91448B107BB5457B838A7BF6908E9CF1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>intentionally used the property in connection with the offense;</text> </clause><clause id="H0CE9D1EA9FF74BE388E7E8A1AD515C2C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>knowingly consented to the use of the property by another in connection with the offense; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA582397BE3FE4CA2BC98B4B60421F000"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>knew that the property was being used in connection with the offense.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H4664CB3A8A1246AC890EA00A9DA12711"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Innocent owner defense</header> <paragraph id="H9149782DA68F476BB8B3CBDA6AA2CF0D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Section <enum-in-header>983(d)(1)</enum-in-header></header><text>Paragraph (1) of section 983(d) of title 18, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC494A6AD8B424F4CA1272C7569CCEFB2" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H28EA5EF5E0C4498CAEEEE62D95A1903E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An innocent owner’s interest in property shall not be forfeited under any civil forfeiture statute. The Government shall have the burden of proving that the claimant is not an innocent owner by clear and convincing evidence.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8FD8496AC38F4E43B305E010245A427E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Section <enum-in-header>983(d)(2)(A)(i)</enum-in-header></header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (2)(A)(i) of section 983(d) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>or consent to</quote> after <quote>did not know of</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA90A6222909A4846877AAF6DA5312DEE"><enum>10.</enum><header>Proportionality</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 983(g) of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE0CE2ECEDFB545AA9C9C21F36D99950E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>or otherwise disproportional to the gravity of the offense</quote> before the period at the end; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAAFCD2D6DC0D41DA915DDE1098451AE3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by amending paragraph (2) to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H35DC96ED93364E2EAA3022E344136ECA" style="USC">
 <paragraph id="H4DE72F7CA8DE45DBA49E764960229A19"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making this determination, the court shall consider, in addition to the analysis as to whether the forfeiture is constitutionally excessive, the value of the property, the seriousness of the offense, the level of the claimant’s culpability in the offense giving rise to forfeiture, the claimant’s prior record, the claimant’s financial condition, and whether the forfeiture statute is intended to address the type of conduct alleged as the basis for forfeiture.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H5581633B77624784A4E12FAEF4CD7BEE"><enum>11.</enum><header>Search and forfeiture of monetary instruments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5317(c) of title 31, United States Code, is amended by striking paragraph (2) and inserting the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="H6B6DDDFAD8DC41AEBA423ABCA6259B1C" style="OLC">
				<paragraph id="H4275D00DC3AC4EDDACC576BCC93111BA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Civil forfeiture</header>
 <subparagraph id="H6765506FB5F8487FBE2778F4CEEAD572"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any property involved in a violation of section 5313 or 5316, or any conspiracy to commit any such violation, and any property traceable to any such violation or conspiracy, may be seized and forfeited to the United States in accordance with the procedures governing civil forfeitures in money laundering cases pursuant to section 981(a)(1)(A) of title 18.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49DF030EEF7F4078AECAB18595948B97"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Structuring</header><text>Any property involved in a violation of section 5324, or any conspiracy to commit any such violation, and any property traceable to any such violation or conspiracy, may be seized and forfeited to the United States in accordance with the procedures governing civil forfeitures in money laundering cases pursuant to section 981(a)(1)(A) of title 18 only if the property to be seized and forfeited is derived from an illegal source or if the structuring offense was used to conceal violations of other criminal laws.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="H816559EE0B12413593D11011B64A7F0C"><enum>12.</enum><header>The HEART Act</header>
 <subsection id="H2F16E2EB4777458A9C90E3E2467566DF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendment to Section <enum-in-header>983(a)</enum-in-header> of title 18</header><text>Section 983(a)(1) of title 18, United States Code, as amended by this Act, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H33489A7343E440D789B78D8D6FEDE449"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by inserting <quote>and with respect to an animal seized under section 26 of the Animal Welfare Act or section 1955 of this title, that the delay is warranted in light of the criteria in subparagraph (G)</quote> after <quote>if the official determines that the conditions in subparagraph (D) are present,</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H168117CC20794348867B7F42257B96AB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by inserting <quote>and with respect to an animal seized under section 26 of the Animal Welfare Act or section 1955 of this title, that the delay is warranted in light of the criteria in subparagraph (G)</quote> after <quote>that the conditions in subparagraph (D) are present,</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H83C7B20DD6664B88ACF2B6C2BA04EB16"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding after subparagraph (F) the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H68B7451AFF04421599E4AFFAF92FDA03" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H3F0940DCA2BB4D49A633DA5C3C7ABD27" indent="up1"><enum>(G)</enum><text>With respect to animals seized under section 26 of the Animal Welfare Act or section 1955 of this title, the period for sending notice under this paragraph may be extended only after consideration of the following:</text>
 <clause id="HF845DF84D96C473BACD6A408DA8A1123"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The cost to the government of caring and providing shelter for the animal.</text> </clause><clause id="H63EB914BC9E44480BED2DAAE65C75EBC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The psychological and physical health of the animal and the effect the delay will have on its rehabilitation.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEDBF648EEE714930BBC509E0664BF800"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Any increased risk that the delay could necessitate the euthanasia of the animal.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5E2297C8F5E44486A7166F36FE85E6F6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amendment to section <enum-in-header>524</enum-in-header> of title 28</header><text>Section 524(c)(1) of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding after subparagraph (I) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H798C262CAFAD484AAEC83261F5ACB589" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H40586E98A9B8406C82A90036D9129AEA" indent="up1"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">payment for the transportation, shelter, care, veterinary services, and where appropriate, humane euthanasia of an animal seized under section 26 of the Animal Welfare Act or under section 1955 of title 18.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1D7160F64D624F5182657F21F840277D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Amendment to Section <enum-in-header>983(h)</enum-in-header> of title 18</header><text>Section 983(h) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end, the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HDFF8133351E84A698C8A0F746C5D4595" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H3BC605EAC3864DFF941D2C1A41970EC1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any civil forfeiture proceeding in which the Government prevails, the court shall require the claimant to reimburse the United States for any actual and reasonable costs to the Government for the transportation, shelter, care, veterinary services, or where appropriate, humane euthanasia of an animal that was the subject of the proceeding, unless the court determines that the factors in subsection (g) warrant reduction or elimination of the reimbursement. The reimbursement shall be credited to the agency or fund that was used to pay the costs being reimbursed.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section id="H23BDB17081584C8BAA1A7E039206E118"><enum>13.</enum><header>Effective date and applicability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act and the amendments made by this Act shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act and apply only with respect to seizures made on or after that date. Seizures made before that date shall continue to be governed by the law as it existed without regard to this Act or the amendments made by this Act.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


