<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCAEC5AA0A1E64A29899AC50BE6F30F1C" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4382 IH: Free Flow of Information Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4382</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171114">November 14, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="J000289">Mr. Jordan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To maintain the free flow of information to the public by providing conditions for the federally
			 compelled disclosure of information by certain persons connected with the
			 news media.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HEF3361C77FBD461E907E9318919D6142" style="OLC">
 <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDBBD151DD46B4108AF35887CE878E4E9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Free Flow of Information Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H1B3D1F0172C94A0089A2B90E57137754"><enum>2.</enum><header>Compelled disclosure from covered persons</header> <subsection id="H66FA8EBE247D452CA2D8FF1B806ACB5C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Conditions for compelled disclosure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any matter arising under Federal law, a Federal entity may not compel a covered person to provide testimony or produce any document related to information obtained or created by such covered person as part of engaging in journalism, unless a court determines by a preponderance of the evidence, after providing notice and an opportunity to be heard to such covered person—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF5C7B71667F043F9BAF86B4EF4954A71"><enum>(1)</enum><text>that the party seeking to compel production of such testimony or document has exhausted all reasonable alternative sources (other than the covered person) of the testimony or document;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HED6A574FEE7C4990AD39EF2FA8A98F36"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that—</text> <subparagraph id="HD2190F526CF54716856580517E8220A6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in a criminal investigation or prosecution, based on information obtained from a person other than the covered person—</text>
 <clause id="HCA11F645E64749B8ACCFE469FDE09DC0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>there are reasonable grounds to believe that a crime has occurred; and</text> </clause><clause id="HCFE8A935DEC7425288C14425E265DBD8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the testimony or document sought is critical to the investigation or prosecution or to the defense against the prosecution; or</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13DBD3EA18A745A7971DDBB1FD298185"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in a matter other than a criminal investigation or prosecution, based on information obtained from a person other than the covered person, the testimony or document sought is critical to the successful completion of the matter;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE271A69588DE4FBE852F9494EE0F7DDC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in the case that the testimony or document sought could reveal the identity of a source of information or include any information that could reasonably be expected to lead to the discovery of the identity of such a source, that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4BB894C9A65848E1BB19CCB7D697E0DF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disclosure of the identity of such a source is necessary to prevent, or to identify any perpetrator of, an act of terrorism against the United States or its allies or other significant and specified harm to national security with the objective to prevent such harm;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E69B66CE03C4D64ABECF7EEC4D64A2F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disclosure of the identity of such a source is necessary to prevent imminent death or significant bodily harm with the objective to prevent such death or harm, respectively;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H170C5D3C21B844A79DBB86F5FF2129C5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>disclosure of the identity of such a source is necessary to identify a person who has disclosed—</text> <clause id="HC7562600C65342AFA82398E3D682482D"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a trade secret, actionable under section 1831 or 1832 of title 18, United States Code;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB58A6EFE52B343C09FB08F8435E81E46"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">individually identifiable health information, as such term is defined in section 1171(6) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320d">42 U.S.C. 1320d(6)</external-xref>), actionable under Federal law; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAA7CEEEB5D4F4303AB1B42783307CFD8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">nonpublic personal information, as such term is defined in section 509(4) of the Gramm-Leach-Biley Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/6809">15 U.S.C. 6809(4)</external-xref>), of any consumer actionable under Federal law; or</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8851DFADA2F648168E100711494F49DC"><enum>(D)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H19EE59AD831F406A972F230A26EC14D7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>disclosure of the identity of such a source is essential to identify in a criminal investigation or prosecution a person who without authorization disclosed properly classified information and who at the time of such disclosure had authorized access to such information; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1EF3BEAC95954C39BCC07DB759D687A9" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such unauthorized disclosure has caused or will cause significant and articulable harm to the national security; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB400EB33D9184E50B41FA0E259A9B54A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>that the public interest in compelling disclosure of the information or document involved outweighs the public interest in gathering or disseminating news or information.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB783E3F634EC49EC958190E6A289D365"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authority To consider national security interest</header><text>For purposes of making a determination under subsection (a)(4), a court may consider the extent of any harm to national security.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD9DFE1228F584264B9C2221388B7A653"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitations on content of information</header><text>The content of any testimony or document that is compelled under subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph id="HBDDB6A95D4494B7992BCCB5E9941AAE9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not be overbroad, unreasonable, or oppressive and, as appropriate, be limited to the purpose of verifying published information or describing any surrounding circumstances relevant to the accuracy of such published information; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8A2CFCE85DB147DC93405938AE5068BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be narrowly tailored in subject matter and period of time covered so as to avoid compelling production of peripheral, nonessential, or speculative information.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H773E1DFAC7C0475CAF13AA065089BDDA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed as applying to civil defamation, slander, or libel claims or defenses under State law, regardless of whether or not such claims or defenses, respectively, are raised in a State or Federal court.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB844F3B7CC444D97A22C9F5299DC85AB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Exception relating to criminal or tortious conduct</header><text>The provisions of this section shall not prohibit or otherwise limit a Federal entity in any matter arising under Federal law from compelling a covered person to disclose any information, record, document, or item obtained as the result of the eyewitness observation by the covered person of alleged criminal conduct or as the result of the commission of alleged criminal or tortious conduct by the covered person, including any physical evidence or visual or audio recording of the conduct, if a Federal court determines that the party seeking to compel such disclosure has exhausted all other reasonable efforts to obtain the information, record, document, or item, respectively, from alternative sources. The previous sentence shall not apply, and subsections (a) and (b) shall apply, in the case that the alleged criminal conduct observed by the covered person or the alleged criminal or tortious conduct committed by the covered person is the act of transmitting or communicating the information, record, document, or item sought for disclosure.</text>
			</subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H64D94996DBF246D487AD861300486473"><enum>3.</enum><header>Compelled disclosure from communications service providers</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H1433D572EC464DA4AC43F18D7BAAB2C2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Conditions for compelled disclosure</header><text>With respect to testimony or any document consisting of any record, information, or other communication that relates to a business transaction between a communications service provider and a covered person, section 2 shall apply to such testimony or document if sought from the communications service provider in the same manner that such section applies to any testimony or document sought from a covered person.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H24F72DC26897484AB5BB9F7364E42D3B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notice and opportunity provided to covered persons</header><text>A court may compel the testimony or disclosure of a document under this section only after the party seeking such a document provides the covered person who is a party to the business transaction described in subsection (a)—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HDBD492F552974A97827ED5D3E4A85218"><enum>(1)</enum><text>notice of the subpoena or other compulsory request for such testimony or disclosure from the communications service provider not later than the time at which such subpoena or request is issued to the communications service provider; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6624100CBB4243AB82DE1D89ABAE6797"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an opportunity to be heard before the court before the time at which the testimony or disclosure is compelled.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HC8583210813145038E6EDF425CDC94E5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exception to notice requirement</header><text>Notice under subsection (b)(1) may be delayed only if the court involved determines by clear and convincing evidence that such notice would pose a substantial threat to the integrity of a criminal investigation.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H2992FB96A6C74475BDF8B17E3D7B65B1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H455164CB5DE048BEA73D983F00F5EA10"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Communications service provider</header><text>The term <term>communications service provider</term>—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3A08868478E84B9198FC312CEAC19ED2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any person that transmits information of the customer's choosing by electronic means; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB38EBD32A440459BBF9A01FD1143044D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a telecommunications carrier, an information service provider, an interactive computer service provider, and an information content provider (as such terms are defined in sections 3 and 230 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/153">47 U.S.C. 153</external-xref>, 230)).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1C71DC4441E64C46B10E0C2B279DF818"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered person</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered person</term> means a person who regularly gathers, prepares, collects, photographs, records, writes, edits, reports, or publishes news or information that concerns local, national, or international events or other matters of public interest for dissemination to the public for a substantial portion of the person’s livelihood or for substantial financial gain and includes a supervisor, employer, parent, subsidiary, or affiliate of such covered person. Such term shall not include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H43A199457E0549AEA97EDC50FDDE4D54"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any person who is a foreign power or an agent of a foreign power, as such terms are defined in section 101 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1801">50 U.S.C. 1801</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE18474D8DD384BFC981EBF5F52054AD5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any organization designated by the Secretary of State as a foreign terrorist organization in accordance with section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F778BC8B9414A73A129D81E4EA7C4B9"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any person included on the Annex to Executive Order No. 13224, of September 23, 2001, and any other person identified under section 1 of that Executive order whose property and interests in property are blocked by that section;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2ACCFD05EC643D1B6BA871707D5E7EE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any person who is a specially designated terrorist, as that term is defined in section 595.311 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor thereto); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A0FEA4095404EBEB10D1EF2C2A6E0C0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any terrorist organization, as that term is defined in section 212(a)(3)(B)(vi)(II) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(3)(B)(vi)(II)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H95F5374ED9BD4C229D6A57C105276A02"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Document</header><text>The term <term>document</term> means writings, recordings, and photographs, as those terms are defined by Federal Rule of Evidence 1001 (28 U.S.C. App.).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC2A8939E8778472F821146D0BD957739"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Federal entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Federal entity</term> means an entity or employee of the judicial or executive branch or an administrative agency of the Federal Government with the power to issue a subpoena or issue other compulsory process.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5E0B674D455F4893985102FBC5BD2171"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Journalism</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>journalism</term> means the gathering, preparing, collecting, pho­to­graph­ing, recording, writing, editing, reporting, or publishing of news or information that concerns local, national, or international events or other matters of public interest for dissemination to the public.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


