<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H38D3560235674CBB9A4CADB0C20BE40A" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2733 IH: Housing Our Heroes Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2733</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170525">May 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000583">Mr. Thomas J. Rooney of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001185">Mr. Sean Patrick Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a pilot grant program to acquire and
			 renovate abandoned homes for homeless veterans.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H79933DB5F6A04FA7B54CF75263B6E72B" style="OLC">
 <section id="H78FC26B513D8423290F31B85EC1C7B90" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Housing Our Heroes Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H4FE94A1576D0406090684A7B37A8D186" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of pilot grant program for homeless veterans</header> <subsection id="H8B8732BC919649EA9293F72DB244FA85"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall commence a pilot grant program to assess the feasibility and advisability of awarding grants to eligible entities to purchase and renovate abandoned homes for homeless veterans.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HBDF7E3664B484AD49B1DF30F5D1F5C01"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants</header>
 <paragraph id="HB714076477D043FBB58E8062B299C084"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Award</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the pilot program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall award grants to eligible entities to purchase and renovate abandoned homes for homeless veterans.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF3CE321517464598B812D6766CDED1B0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Maximum Amount</header><text>The amount of a single grant awarded under paragraph (1) shall not exceed $1,000,000.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB11323BF98CF471183EAF28DFC938827"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Number</header><text>The Secretary may award to an eligible entity more than one grant under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9028A05588004480B653C8DA5286829B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>The Secretary may award a grant under subsection (b)(1) to any of the following:</text> <paragraph id="H1DC3208DC48F4B4FB89CDA7E42D20F49"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A veterans service agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H86627F78A5294AB691BC9279136B379F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A veterans service organization.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBAD7376AB297458A9B25EACA48C7F1A8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Homeless organizations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4231120AB16B4293B4604B08B7E9626B"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other nongovernmental organization.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5C9F1E127D8C421F93FD9F6501A3A88D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Selection of grant recipients</header> <paragraph id="H667CEA04D70E4A20A1460D21B37FD2CD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any eligible entity seeking a grant under subsection (b)(1) shall submit to the Secretary an application therefore in such form and in such manner as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBF04D91D028D45CFB04ABB8C3260CFDC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The Secretary may only award grants under subsection (b)(1) to an eligible entity that demonstrates, as determined by the Secretary—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0F321595788B4018AFD0D808B7021B39"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a record of financial stability; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H40A78C555C2040C495064FB943A4FAEB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>experience in developing housing for homeless veterans.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H23B73EB72D4340F6B9E68A55AD2C5A1E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Selection Priority</header>
 <subparagraph id="H04B17510BA1C41C1883563E1C8DF59A9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Communities with greatest need</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subparagraph (B), in accordance with regulations the Secretary shall prescribe, the Secretary shall give priority in the awarding of grants under subsection (b)(1) to eligible entities who serve communities that the Secretary determines have the greatest need of homeless services.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H804A3403BE2C43FE93892375BF1C8A6D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Geographic Distribution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may give priority in the awarding of grants under subsection (b)(1) to achieve a fair distribution, as determined by the Secretary, among homeless veterans in different geographical regions.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8413601C356449D2ACE9E53ACC3A6C4A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Other agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding a grant under subsection (b)(1) to an eligible entity in a location determined pursuant to subparagraphs (A) and (B), the Secretary shall give preference to eligible entities that are entered into an agreement with the Secretary under section 2041 of title 38, United States Code.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H14BEAA6181D147D89AA281023CEC5C3C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of grant funds</header>
 <paragraph id="H9CC4375845944C8D959C7FF24E39C1AA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>A grantee may use amounts of a grant awarded to the grantee under subsection (b)(1) to purchase or renovate abandoned homes, including homes that have been foreclosed.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0F9C13D468F04FAE94444248CBFD1F33"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Maximum purchase amount</header><text>The Secretary shall establish maximum amounts, based on geography, for grants awarded under subsection (b)(1) that may be used for the purchase of a single home.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HF96FF0028DEC4EA988F56130B1128D2C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Payment program</header>
 <subparagraph id="HEBBAF2BB4A884B569BE9A16331AB0BFB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States shall not have any ownership interest in a home that is purchased by a grantee using amounts of a grant awarded under subsection (b)(1).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B379D94B2FE4254A36509ED6F416817"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each grantee shall ensure that, beginning one year after the date on which a veteran begins to reside in a home purchased or renovated by the grantee using a grant awarded under subsection (b)(1), the veteran makes monthly payments to the grantee in an amount determined appropriate by the grantee that is not less than 85 percent of the fair market rent for such home.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9783DC859173483BBB2DE9D14E15E203"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each grantee shall determine whether payments made by a veteran under subparagraph (B) shall be treated as rent or as a mortgage for the home for which the veteran is making such payments. The Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, shall determine the requirements for such payments.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HEA66BABEE8CB454DBBDEEEF21ECC8499"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Each grantee shall pay to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs not less than 80 percent of each payment received under subparagraph (B).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61BD5508F8BC49879B9429F9F0710AD6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Secretary may conduct an audit of any grantee to ensure that the grantee carries out this paragraph.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE23D076726D44EF5BCE51D2E5A86E6F8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Veterans Homelessness Grant Fund</header>
 <subparagraph id="HA2301B9178AB48ECABE305D98EF8BFBA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>There is established in the Treasury a fund to be known as the <quote>Veterans Homelessness Grant Fund</quote> (in this paragraph referred to as the <quote>Fund</quote>).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5D732B66C8D4FF5BAA469B131EE7B51"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary shall deposit into the Fund the payments collected by the Secretary under paragraph (3)(D).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0023D8AE780247058425D4D92A2B3CF8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Amounts deposited into the Fund pursuant to subparagraph (B) shall be available to the Secretary to carry out the pilot program under subsection (a) without further appropriation. The Secretary may not use such amounts from the Fund for any other purpose unless pursuant to a specific provision of law.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H041C15BB7FB34FD3A4BF79FB345E9644"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out the pilot program under subsection (a) during the three-year period beginning on the date of the commencement of the pilot program.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H451A03666AD0495E938DD181B920FBF4"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Secretary may consult with nongovernmental entities in developing the pilot program under subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA02EBF0D86E942A1A889816735AD7B88"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During each year in which the Secretary carries out the pilot program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that details, with respect to the year covered by the report, the number of grants awarded, the amounts so awarded, the progress of home purchase and renovation made by eligible entities using such grants, and the number of tenants currently paying rent towards such homes.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H49022B9BA88D43F9B1D435F6ED1A2536"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary a total of $25,000,000 to carry out the pilot program under subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE8E8D84A0C6241BC887B61D8C985D756"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Homeless veteran defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>homeless veteran</term> means any of the following veterans:</text> <paragraph id="HDD4B920D84F945DEBFB91BB2E0126133"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A veteran who is eligible to receive housing, clinical services, and case management assistance under section 8(o)(19) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f(o)(19)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7E68370B6C8F4F6892F89B2BBF4EE3EC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A veteran who is receiving—</text> <subparagraph id="H5207245D84E14AAE8621CC8B5A7623E1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assistance from, or is the beneficiary of a service furnished by, a program that is in receipt of a grant under section 2011 of title 38, United States Code; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA417638817A84CE891DA88CE20C8E9E2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>services for which per diem payment is received under section 2012 of such title.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H76B91878B2174B54B335321D5F0B62F9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A veteran who is—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1E5DBFEF6E554CA0880EFD99BAF1B1ED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a beneficiary of the outreach program carried out under section 2022(e) of such title; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1AE0883E1C414D3B9BE28A6534A74FB5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in receipt of referral or counseling services from the program carried out under section 2023 of such title.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H87C93DB235FD4376B3DF8D3D8474D686"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A veteran who is receiving a service or assistance under section 2031 of such title.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H51A82045845C45CAB1A61F0EB8B18589"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A veteran who is residing in therapeutic housing operated under section 2032 of such title.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7D9489928D7F43C781FF1D558E375F39"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A veteran who is receiving domiciliary services under section 2043 of such title or domiciliary care under section 1710(b) of such title.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC946E7DD4BC9414FA6BFEB5FFD6F7CF9"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A veteran who is receiving supportive services under section 2044 of such title.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

