<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD9A19B7062E748ED851C299CAA81736F" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2079 IH: Young Fishermen’s Development Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2079</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170406">April 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young of Alaska</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To preserve United States fishing heritage through a national program dedicated to training and
			 assisting the next generation of commercial fishermen.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H3364357F7E03412B94BEB2B78A10F235" style="OLC">
 <section id="H5CD5815EFF7044CD9CA3765CFF9275FE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Young Fishermen’s Development Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H9D8C0EC69F2C46F98CE8C3CD80BB400D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; purposes</header> <subsection id="H35CCE7775BEA4D2B96FC9828F5381C2C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H5E232039398C45209BF547C1E80D5173"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the average age of commercial fishermen continues to increase due to fewer new entrants replacing retiring fishermen;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2B9BD8E5FAA94E2598DA9E9E5A0AF881"><enum>(2)</enum><text>there are fewer young or beginning fishermen entering the commercial fisheries for many reasons, including the lack of training, fewer entry level opportunities, lack of capital, and other barriers to entry;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA9BA98A1118041CABF678DA30F79697B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>without well-trained young or beginning fishermen to replace those retiring, fishing businesses and vessels will be lost and fishing communities will suffer;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1AA553ACCB7A4254BF3BC3FC04E35E3B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>for food security and economic reasons, it is in the United States national interest to sustainably harvest United States fishery resources;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF26F2FECEDC647E1B8B8DDA89C283BC5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>United States farmers and ranchers faced similar difficulties and Congress responded by enacting the Beginning Farmers and Ranchers Development Program administered by the Department of Agriculture;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDE84C57B20CD4A5EA97F998F5157AF5D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the Young Fishermen’s Development Grant Program established by this Act is modeled after the successful Department of Agriculture program; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7B409D45A65E4C4DA45E2C67E584DBF3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the training, education, and outreach provided for in the Young Fishermen’s Development Grant Program established by this Act will ensure there is a next generation of commercial fishermen and businesses to harvest the United States rich fishery resources and support our coastal communities.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5FD2F9EFBB2A47D187F31FA8A06E662E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are—</text> <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD344E1FA289F4A2A802629B45815D990"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to establish a national grant program to support the training and education of the United States next generation of commercial fishermen; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4B53549AC804424BB9BBD9905D0153EA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to engage partnerships and collaborations led by or including nongovernmental, community-based fishing organizations, and school-based fisheries, including Sea Grant Institutions, or marine educational organizations with expertise in new fisheries training and outreach, to provide the education and training.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H088DCE5C2F3D44A98CBAC0DBAFAE098C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act—</text> <paragraph id="H29B01DCCE3A34E0A8AB0C700F46BE892"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <quote>young fishermen</quote> means an individual who—</text>
				<subparagraph id="H05C424BDF93846D4852FB68192F651BC"><enum>(A)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HAE3E073343E04460B7AC372995A7001B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>desires to participate in the commercial fisheries of the United States, including the Great Lakes fisheries;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBBB074FB272B4919A7A65922256DA6AB" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has worked as a captain, crew member, deckhand, or other at-sea position on a commercial fishing vessel for not more than 10 years of cumulative service;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H03918D3DB38B437AAC1335517F5E2B8A" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is a beginning commercial fisherman; or</text> </clause><clause id="H50A589C8A9B44407BEF1AEAABCCBDBBF" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>meets such other criteria as the Secretary of Commerce may establish; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F82CD2A2D194CD99E73462B9276F9EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is less than 35 years of age; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5EA397E8FCA4DBCB6317A204F2FC844"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <quote>Sea Grant Institution</quote> means a sea grant college or sea grant institute, as those terms are defined in section 203 of the National Sea Grant College Program Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1122">33 U.S.C. 1122</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HC893B3CAEEE04972AD52F2D4CD82B051"><enum>4.</enum><header>Establishment of program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Commerce, acting through the National Sea Grant Office, shall establish a Young Fishermen’s Development Grant Program to provide training, education, outreach, and technical assistance initiatives for young fishermen.</text>
		</section><section id="HBDDA0C5DD6D2426282D171EB00216D0F"><enum>5.</enum><header>Grants</header>
 <subsection id="H9157418170A840A29460E7FE9970D0E7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out this Act, the Secretary shall make competitive grants to support new and established local and regional training, education, outreach, and technical assistance initiatives for young fishermen, including programs, workshops, and services relating to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H41796980D9EB44E08E94967B20DB2B67"><enum>(1)</enum><text>seamanship, navigation, electronics, and safety;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6F985707A7AB437B9536D7A695D60A07"><enum>(2)</enum><text>vessel and engine care, maintenance, and repair;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF484E87D07D34184814312A685A5C6C2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>innovative conservation fishing gear engineering and technology;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD57100EE476F4418A19FE61FE877855E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>sustainable fishing practices;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0EF153A7B7484174B2ACBCB1ABE910A1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>entrepreneurship and good business practices;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1E91AAA412954C998C0184C036F278B7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>direct marketing, supply chain, and traceability;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H89D317125FC146C4BB40C9CEA4FA8932"><enum>(7)</enum><text>financial and risk management, including vessel, permit, and quota purchasing;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9C67AF1F9A2947758A754BE5837E2EF9"><enum>(8)</enum><text>State and Federal legal requirements for specific fisheries, including reporting, monitoring, licenses, and regulations;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8BB555D81D854CAE9CD585A392A22B69"><enum>(9)</enum><text>State and Federal fisheries policy and management;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H87FD07DE359D4E54B7B5FD76F7AFB656"><enum>(10)</enum><text>mentoring, apprenticeships, or internships; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE0D8AFE0505B4A118ACEDDA501A9E502"><enum>(11)</enum><text>any other activities, opportunities, or programs as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4ADE4966C44F4EC9BEE89EEC62C78876"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header> <paragraph id="HD73B176E502B4A6799CB1A62D2EA9C99"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applicants</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this Act, the recipient must be a collaborative State, Tribal, local, or regionally based network or partnership of public or private entities, which may include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFD88066C89DD4FE98013A204CEDEEF98"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a Sea Grant Institution;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56CEF948E6A64C29AD634EFD64A224AE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a Federal, State, or Tribal agency;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1377817DBB14C8E9CDE39E3B3A64709"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a community-based or non­go­vern­ment­al organization;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B9A6C1397194D559470732FCB24C0E7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>fishermen’s cooperatives or associations, including permit banks and trusts;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C6A1D0E9670487F9B9C819F37415EF3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Alaska Native corporations;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31537EBA238C417C8E1EC66757D1D9ED"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a college or university (including an institution awarding an associate’s degree), or a foundation maintained by a college or university; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H65CFA3616EF3450280BD21132AA4E619"><enum>(G)</enum><text>any other appropriate entity as determined by the Secretary.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H87C2ED8AA5AA41508F327D7EC8BF81C9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Participants</header><text>All young fishermen seeking to participate in the commercial fisheries of the United States and the Great Lakes are eligible to participate in the activities funded through grants provided for in this section, except that participants in such activities shall be selected by each grant recipient.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE5501A4D732A4955921EFE9089F57797"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Maximum term and amount of grant</header>
 <paragraph id="H07C96646F11044C2B6E5AD27CEF0C241"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A grant under this section shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H18927675C609426CBCBFB5D9AFF2B3CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have a term of no more than 3 fiscal years; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE6DBBD2B924C4197BD73E60E796A23AD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be in an amount that is not more than $200,000 for each fiscal year.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5BC280716CC04551A0CCF8FCC1F57180"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consecutive grants</header><text>An eligible recipient may receive consecutive grants under this section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H88AC63C30CE845FEBA274B149DF37D06"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Matching requirement</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, a recipient shall provide a match in the form of cash or in-kind contributions in the amount equal to or greater than 25 percent of the funds provided by the grant.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5C9D5C818F81404A8555658EB2EF116E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regional balance</header><text>In making grants under this section, the Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable, ensure geographic diversity.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H83130225BA7748B188E946AFA888B592"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to partnerships and collaborations that are led by or include nongovernmental fishing community-based organizations and school-based fisheries educational organizations with expertise in fisheries and sustainable fishing training and outreach.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H51A786E097934F8FBA2451E3756A77E5"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Cooperation and evaluation criteria</header><text>In carrying out this section and especially in developing criteria for evaluating grant applications, the Secretary shall cooperate, to the maximum extent practicable, with—</text>
 <paragraph id="H75C5375A58404FB6AAAD23DCDE768089"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Sea Grant Institutions and extension agents of such institutions;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6FAC30D81DC34A51B670E08CEBBF4549"><enum>(2)</enum><text>community-based and nongovernmental fishing organizations;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0A671C7ADD544ED9BCFFAB62D60240DE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Federal and State agencies, including Regional Fishery Management Councils established under the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1851">16 U.S.C. 1851</external-xref> et seq.);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD6A95E27AAC34FAEB1720D47BFC2704C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>colleges and universities with fisheries expertise and programs; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF15E80EF4A4043EB8373163E982BEBA8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>other appropriate partners as determined by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCE86DF4284484E7D8696FF469A6BD674"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>A grant under this section may not be used to purchase any fishing license, permit, quota, or other harvesting right.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H4E9919B1E4114973984B6EEE5FFB8E15"><enum>6.</enum><header>Funding</header>
 <subsection id="H6C7CF4417F6741FD909BABBC5E62A57A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Of the amount made available to the Secretary of Commerce under section 311(e) of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1861">16 U.S.C. 1861(e)</external-xref>) for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022, the Secretary shall use $2,000,000 to carry out section 5 of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCC636A5E35CF41D58356983510C9ACC1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Proportional allocation</header><text>The amount obligated under this section each fiscal year for activities in each fishery management region shall be in the same proportion as the portion of the total amount obligated under this section for that fiscal year that was collected in that region.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


