<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H8C28388CEEEC4D2C95BC7663BF41D907" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2075 IH: Crooked River Ranch Fire Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2075</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170406">April 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000791">Mr. Walden</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To adjust the eastern boundary of the Deschutes Canyon-Steelhead Falls Wilderness Study Area in the
			 State of Oregon to facilitate fire prevention and response activities in
			 order to protect adjacent private property, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H3CB32AA541BE473F8DC629B8D99696F5" style="OLC">
 <section id="H0383F36C5EA1464E82EDEF7FA111AEE8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Crooked River Ranch Fire Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H74EDDD205A1E4F8FA998CC1A2E9CD9D1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HC15214380C77461C968928417A77D738"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Crooked River Ranch is an unincorporated community with a population of 5,000 residents.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA14837B97EDC4C7084FD7CEDA3683E99"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The current lands located adjacent to Crooked River Ranch are managed by the Bureau of Land Management and are classified as a Wilderness Study Area.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H71F6D2071887453FB742428C2D3216FB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>There is currently only one entrance/exit to the Crooked River Ranch.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H441FD760EFD54D1CBC20A2CB14A55F32"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Jefferson County and Crooked River Ranch have determined that the Wilderness Study Area lands are in the highest risk category for exposure to devastating wildfire due to overstocked juniper stands under the federally mandated and locally promulgated Jefferson County Community Wildfire Protection Plan (CWPP).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0CA9297D334848FE8BBF07FD094B16AF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The current Wilderness Study Area classification prevents mechanical fire prevention activities within the overstocked juniper stands.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H43284F0061B8441BAF8B47E905025C3B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Advancing this proposed legislation will greatly enhance the life and safety of people and property by reducing the extreme fire threat to these lands.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H3B8F61CEAEB3447BAA11E07994CE5DBC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Boundary adjustment, Deschutes Canyon-Steelhead Falls Wilderness Study Area, Oregon</header>
 <subsection id="H4D659F3744274D53B4B098DD036F9D9F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Boundary adjustment required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior shall adjust the eastern boundary of the Deschutes Canyon-Steelhead Falls Wilderness Study Area in the State of Oregon to exclude approximately 832 acres, as depicted on the map entitled <quote>Deschutes Canyon-Steelhead Falls Wilderness Study Area</quote> and dated April 6, 2017, in order to facilitate fire prevention and response activities on the excluded public lands and adjacent private property.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC88860346AB64B42813F86BD4A23E88A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effect of exclusion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective on the date of the enactment of this Act, the public lands to be excluded from the Deschutes Canyon-Steelhead Falls Wilderness Study Area pursuant to subsection (a) are no longer subject to section 603(c) of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1782">43 U.S.C. 1782(c)</external-xref>).</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


