<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC5164108DAB3440588ED3AEDC2B41C35" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 931 EH: Firefighter Cancer Registry Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 931</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to develop a voluntary registry to collect data on cancer incidence among firefighters.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H6D5FA688E793410C81BD871F2B754680" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H927633CDCC6A485D9B053A110077EFB5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Firefighter Cancer Registry Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H960F0996D9BE4777821C16DA4DFE8A08"><enum>2.</enum><header>Population-based registry for firefighter cancer incidence</header> <subsection id="HDA7E0C5DC6A249AE81DCD92FDA688F5A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall develop and maintain, directly or through a grant or cooperative agreement, a voluntary registry of firefighters (referred to in this section as the <quote>Firefighter Registry</quote>) to collect relevant history and occupational information of such firefighters that can be linked to available cancer registry data collected by existing State cancer registries.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H42E85A0ECFFD4FFB8B557B3E4DD62B75"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of Firefighter Registry</header><text>The Firefighter Registry shall be used for the following purposes:</text> <paragraph id="H2F1C43ED0D3F487DBC79AA0C11B96FF6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To establish and improve collection infrastructure and activities related to the nationwide monitoring of the incidence of cancer among firefighters.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2C306E931B2F4370B6F503A1F243193A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To collect, consolidate, store, and make publicly available epidemiological information related to cancer incidence and trends among firefighters.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H0B1BE3514D56465A88B0B645E824A4AE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Relevant data</header> <paragraph id="HACA4ED77A9BA4948AB56CC95D59D53D8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the voluntary data collection for purposes of inclusion under the Firefighter Registry, the Secretary should seek to include the following information:</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H3AF4811577DA42078E057F7760E01DB2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identifiable information from a representative sample size, as determined by the Secretary under subsection (d)(2)(A), of volunteer, paid-on-call, and career firefighters, independent of cancer status or diagnosis.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HF319C62073604BD8A7C426E5E2D03CDF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>With respect to individual risk factors and work history of firefighters, available information on—</text> 
<clause commented="no" id="H52044F158CA94FBC8C19193127C0E746"><enum>(i)</enum><text>basic demographic information, including the age of the firefighter involved;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H1F5FDCDB6C78407A93BE32B6616A412D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a listing of status of the firefighter as either volunteer, paid-on-call, or career firefighter;</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H6AB1AEAA88204E65A50365BE419F0B82"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of years on the job and a detailing of additional employment experience that was either performed concurrently alongside firefighting service, before, or anytime thereafter;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H311DF41D1D7B4D3DBC233B8130ABED10"><enum>(iv)</enum> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H3B2676748ED341B1955507FABF18CCEF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a measure of the number of fire incidents attended as well as the type of fire incidents (such as residential house fire or commercial fire); or</text></subclause> 
<subclause commented="no" id="HD5A40E739B1D4F578B9A5579CEBDB20D" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a firefighter for whom information on such number and type is not available, an estimate of such number and type based on the method developed under subsection (d)(2);</text></subclause></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H8FD69BB825724BEAB6BD64BD2215E2E5"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a list of additional risk factors, including smoking or drug use, as determined relevant by the Secretary; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3770037405D7438F88BB3D7D016B9D9F"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>other physical examination and medical history information relevant to a cancer incidence study or general health of firefighters not available in existing cancer registries.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H440BDE93DF8040D1A878A52E4027E8FF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any additional information that is deemed necessary by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB7C53553900B48748D32916A7034C6FA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Diagnoses and treatment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the data collection for purposes of inclusion under the Firefighter Registry, with respect to diagnoses and treatment of firefighters diagnosed with cancer, the Secretary shall enable the Firefighter Registry to link to State-based cancer registries, for a purpose described by clause (vi) or (vii) of section 399B(c)(2)(D) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280e">42 U.S.C. 280e(c)(2)(D)</external-xref>), to obtain information on—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HE42423264B9846DFB0D6274FF71AC864"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">administrative information, including date of diagnoses and source of information; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3D85DD5DB1D7436693DD231F122CAB4A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">pathological data characterizing the cancer, including cancer site, state of disease (pursuant to Staging Guide), incidence, and type of treatment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0427007E1596488E82C3B048ACB6A125"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Methods</header> <paragraph id="HD1662177C36247CE97DEB0E0C48BF214"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes described in subsection (b), the Secretary is authorized to incorporate questions into public health surveys, questionnaires, and other databases.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD56D159E5E5F4522A02AAF633CC925FE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Required strategy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall develop a strategy, working in consultation with the stakeholders identified in subsection (e), to maximize participation in the Firefighter Registry established under this Act. At minimum, the strategy shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HCB3E460CEF394975B1649B930064A864"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Identified minimum participation targets for volunteer, paid-on-call, and career firefighters.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H74386767882E4049B7D45389D67C9EF0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A strategy for increasing awareness of the Firefighter Registry and maximizing participation among volunteer, paid-on-call, and career firefighters to meet minimum participation targets.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAA4E194FD27E49E68613E4AA1BA05504"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Additional steps that may be required to ensure the equitable representation of groups identified in paragraph (5).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD939883EABEC4FFEAFC1B3B85C9E30C6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Information on how the Secretary will store data described in subsection (c)(1) and provide links to relevant health information described in subsection (c)(2).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3903ACB085034B22A2781CF2CDC3632E"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Working in consultation with the experts described in subsection (e), a reliable and standardized method for estimating the number of fire incidents attended by a firefighter as well as the type of fire incident so attended in the case such firefighter is unable to provide such information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H42F37BE451234EEAA206A89C5286D664"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall submit the strategy described in paragraph (2) to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate not later than 30 days after the date of the completion of the strategy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1A283B22FDE54DBAABB24D1759111D05"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Guidance for inclusion and maintenance of data on firefighters</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall develop, in consultation with the stakeholders identified in subsection (e), State health agencies, State departments of homeland security, and volunteer, paid-on-call, combination, and career firefighting agencies, a strategy for inclusion of firefighters in the registry that are representative of the general population of firefighters, that outlines the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5301F1AF41634E5FB3FEE4AC4AC682D7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">How new information about firefighters will be submitted to the Firefighter Registry for inclusion.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2A84AB87E5084ADAB9B0FF4613EBFA23"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">How information about firefighters will be maintained and updated in the Firefighter Registry over time.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAD81E15E3288476BAC54276FE37CCDB9"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A method for estimating the number of fire incidents attended by a firefighter as well as the type of fire incident so attended in the case such firefighter is unable to provide such information.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7BB2FB5C0AB542F0979935C3439410A8"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Further information, as deemed necessary by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H55AB3A6D31B546A1A4DF3F0B9D804A55"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Ensuring representation of underrepresented groups in registry</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall take such measures as the Secretary deems appropriate to encourage the inclusion of data on minority, female, and volunteer firefighters in the Firefighter Registry established under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H3CA305D5FFAE420689A56B9B003153C9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Secretary shall, on a regular basis, seek feedback regarding the utility of the Firefighter Registry established under this section and ways the Firefighter Registry can be improved from non-Federal experts in the following areas:</text> 
<paragraph id="HB12D4CF2F08D44CEA53FC0845F2DF7B8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Public health experts with experience in developing and maintaining cancer registries.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H297BE64DF53D4562A4F8AC345054A78F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Epidemiologists with experience in studying cancer incidence.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFCCA4C987D7C4FB1934AF06E09FFF342"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Clinicians with experience in diagnosing and treating cancer incidence.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAB18E1435FDE44B389E5AA6458BFBE79"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Active and retired volunteer, paid-on-call, and career firefighters as well as relevant national fire and emergency response organizations.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC8D8E913C7D4421EAC31A62F10F7B419"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Research availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall develop and make public a process for de-identifying data from the Firefighter Registry and making such data available without a fee for research or other purposes. Such process shall provide that such data shall be made available for such research purposes only if there is an agreement to make findings, journal articles, or other print or web-based publications derived from such research public or available to the relevant stakeholders identified in subsection (e).</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="HD8135BAF6B4F4EB78586E69F211658BD"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Privacy</header><text>In carrying out this Act, the Secretary shall apply to the Firefighter Registry developed under subsection (a) data security provisions and privacy standards that comply with the best practices of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and provide for data privacy and security standards similar to those in the HIPAA privacy regulation, as defined in section 1180(b)(3) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320d-9">42 U.S.C. 1320d–9(b)(3)</external-xref>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3AD7041A8EC94150A46BA5D87406B7FC"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of funds</header><text>To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $2,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2018 through 2022.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H9F86F006ED60481AAB3B8A41517E8A33"><enum>3.</enum><header>Cut-Go Compliance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subsection (f) of section 319D of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247d-4">42 U.S.C. 247d–4</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>through 2018</quote> and inserting <quote>through 2017, and $128,300,000 for fiscal year 2018</quote>.</text> </section> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20170912" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives September 12, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement>
</bill> 


