<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H977B4BBD6A3345C1BF47365FDA04991D" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 828 IH: Investing in Opportunity Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 828</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170202">February 2, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000462">Mr. Tiberi</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001181">Mr. Meehan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000015">Mr. Neal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000586">Mr. Renacci</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000371">Mr. Aguilar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001195">Mr. Smith of Missouri</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000594">Mr. Paulsen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000578">Mr. Reichert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000754">Mr. Cooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000290">Ms. Jenkins of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001187">Mr. Stivers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000567">Mr. Lance</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000244">Mr. Sensenbrenner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000619">Mr. Rodney Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000063">Mr. Yoder</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001158">Mr. Marchant</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="U000031">Mr. Upton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001092">Mr. Collins of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000171">Mr. O'Halleran</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for the deferral of inclusion in gross income
			 for capital gains reinvested in opportunity zones.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H7144AC6268A54B72A6341922D439630A" style="OLC">
 <section id="H5541E08770254B8D8EA19EAE6B48F7E9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Investing in Opportunity Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HD40D9795745F4865B7E322BEA7CFAA33"><enum>2.</enum><header>Opportunity zones</header> <subsection id="HFAAC0FB8469F4C6CBAE299D1C3D369F9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">Chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB1C66B8937A243A8846AC220B95F72EA" style="OLC">
					<subchapter id="HAA61B52D79D14CB68664BBD7675E88D3"><enum>Z</enum><header>Opportunity Zones</header>
						<toc container-level="subchapter-container" idref="HAA61B52D79D14CB68664BBD7675E88D3" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
							<toc-entry idref="H789236D9879C45D885565F9A0E8B7D2B" level="section">Sec. 1400Z–1. Designation.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H2CE36B67ACCC4F89BD0B2571450C0176" level="section">Sec. 1400Z–2. Deferral for capital gains invested in opportunity zones.</toc-entry></toc>
						<section id="H789236D9879C45D885565F9A0E8B7D2B"><enum>1400Z–1.</enum><header>Designation</header>
 <subsection id="H3614A6F97EBE44BAA9E7DC8263D507FF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Qualified opportunity zone defined</header><text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term <term>qualified opportunity zone</term> means a population census tract that is a low-income community that is designated as a qualified opportunity zone.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="H2DB14BC9BE614DEBA6C1A7F0E827DB2A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designation</header>
								<paragraph id="H4214F74736934C97BEB04EB35B3CA85C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Governor</header>
 <subparagraph id="HB6BE7548B7494B679A8E34404ACA9472"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a), a population census tract that is a low-income community is designated as a qualified opportunity zone if—</text>
 <clause id="H176E56DE3237431D921E998D98282E70"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not later than the end of the determination period, the governor of the State in which the tract is located—</text>
 <subclause id="HEEE9CDC5BB42423785310C176F23148B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>nominates the tract for designation as a qualified opportunity zone, and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H2D8F5024FBC649AF80A04D1CBFAD3BC4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>notifies the Secretary in writing of such nomination, and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H283ADE34AF5D40A4B7A9F49BB62A9280"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Secretary certifies such nomination and designates such tract as a qualified opportunity zone before the end of the consideration period.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H644D278617354782ABE71F0391D4995B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Extension of periods</header><text>A governor may request that the Secretary extend either the determination or consideration period, or both (determined without regard to this subparagraph), for an additional 30 days.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C75BCFA335E4C918004293A82629FF1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Deemed designation if Secretary fails to act</header><text>Unless the tracts are ineligible for designation, if the Secretary declines in writing to make such certification and designation or fails to act before the end of the consideration period, such nomination shall be deemed to be certified and designated, effective on the day after the last day of the consideration period.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFDFD84556320452FA8FAEDE99319F0C4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a governor fails to make the nominations and notifications by the end of the periods referred to in paragraphs (1)(A) and (1)(B), the Secretary shall designate and certify population census tracts that are low-income communities as qualified opportunity zones, as permitted by subsection (e).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H511F674245DF4BC2AF304D1830089D7A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Other definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection—</text> <paragraph id="HA4CE41C04ED44C1A8583F166807C0473"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Low-income communities</header><text>The term <term>low-income community</term> has the same meaning as when used in section 45D(e).</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="H5B78A7C81DA9401BB7B7A0749EA2809F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definition of periods</header>
 <subparagraph id="H7429FD7C127A40E7AA67D46006A7DD20"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Consideration period</header><text>The term <term>consideration period</term> means the 30-day period beginning on the date on which the Secretary receives notice under subsection (b)(1)(A)(i)(II), as extended under subsection (b)(1)(B).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3C33DD9B0D94293A5AAB9C7CBA95789"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Determination period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>determination period</term> means the 90-day period beginning on the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Investing in Opportunity Act</short-title>, as extended under subsection (b)(1)(B).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBDD6F1444D6C46C58E4C236B43F01F56"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Guidance for opportunity zone nominations</header><text>When considering the nomination of qualified opportunity zones, governors should strive for the creation of qualified opportunity zones that are geographically concentrated and contiguous clusters of population census tracts and should give particular consideration to areas that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HCB37419473134B6ABE0DEB1EB86B1A73"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are currently the focus of mutually reinforcing State, local, or private economic development initiatives to attract investment and foster startup activity,</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H66906ACA42374F899E923B97FF799AD0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>have demonstrated success in geographically targeted development programs, such as promise zones, new market tax credit, empowerment zones, and renewal communities, and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H096D3586FDA74E3F9B3CF156F458D5A1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>have recently experienced significant layoffs due to business closures or relocations.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4E02F530999940F8B9CD3D167193BA73"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Number of designations</header> <paragraph id="HA6DA223480A14AEEAB671BE06D3F41F7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided by paragraph (2), the number of population census tracts in a State that may be designated as qualified opportunity zones under this section may not exceed 25 percent of the number of low-income communities in the State.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9A57050A91D749BC96D7C9223586FA2E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>If the number of low-income communities in a State is less than 100, then a total of 25 of such tracts may be designated as qualified opportunity zones.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H805C2783D0DA4C8F8BC9FA3050661D59"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Designation of tracts contiguous with low-Income communities</header>
 <paragraph id="HBF66B081727649398A84DC9DE1151D9C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A population census tract that is not a low-income community may be designated as a qualified opportunity zone under this section if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1DD1662465174084877BCDC74136B865"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the tract is contiguous with the low-income community that is designated as a qualified opportunity zone, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89B1272130F849CF8AB9F7E12EA78235"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the median family income of the tract does not exceed 125 percent of the median family income of the low-income community with which the tract is contiguous.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C5E3621E6454178BBA1313AF77DADFE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Not more than 5 percent of the population census tracts designated in a State as a qualified opportunity zone may be designated under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H815F4C3AF66143BD99C6F0510EC5C9C0"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Period for which designation is in effect</header><text>A designation as a qualified opportunity zone shall remain in effect for the period beginning on the date of the designation and ending at the close of the 10th calendar year beginning on or after such date of designation.</text>
							</subsection></section><section id="H2CE36B67ACCC4F89BD0B2571450C0176"><enum>1400Z–2.</enum><header>Deferral for capital gains invested in opportunity zones</header>
							<subsection id="HC5B3205394624938933CB8058657B74C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Special rules when gain from sale of property invested in opportunity zone property</header>
 <paragraph id="H3FCCF7CD40E143939354F62B9493822B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exclusion of gain invested in opportunity zone property</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of gain from the sale to, or exchange with, an unrelated person of any property held by the taxpayer, at the election of the taxpayer—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3E3949A695C44842965F49579377DC4A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>gross income for the taxable year shall not include so much of such gain as does not exceed the aggregate cost of all qualified opportunity zone property acquired by the taxpayer during the 180-day period beginning on the date of such sale or exchange, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBD1D5BA38D748079390D9F706CF92B8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of gain excluded by subparagraph (A) shall be included in gross income as provided by paragraph (2).</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE68A0C61ED764620BE3AB28E8FA85B1C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deferral of gain invested in opportunity zone property</header>
 <subparagraph id="HA672B6394B654982A6252692C7B2898D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Year of inclusion</header><text>Except as provided by subparagraph (C), gain to which paragraph (1)(B) applies shall be included in income in the taxable year in which the qualified opportunity zone property related to such gain is sold or exchanged in the amount determined under subparagraph (B).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A2B8523C1CE435092AB2A0B1602E08F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Amount includible</header><text>The amount of gain determined under this clause shall be—</text> <clause id="H43A25408D32841C68920EAB6B23906D9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>100 percent of such gain in the case of the sale or exchange of the qualified opportunity zone property with respect to which gain is deferred under paragraph (1) that is held for less than 5 years,</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE8093E76D91F47C9B5DCAE413CDD0CBE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">90 percent of such gain in the case of the sale or exchange of the qualified opportunity zone property with respect to which gain is deferred under paragraph (1) that is held for at least 5 years but less than 7 years, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5DFC5F1B7F2940F8BFDB1E3D0E4976E0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">85 percent of such gain in the case of the sale or exchange of the qualified opportunity zone property with respect to which gain is deferred under paragraph (1) that is held for at least 7 years.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H263F8EA6A39B457DB224A30BF4B0BED7"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Property held after 2026 treated as sold</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subparagraph (A), any qualified opportunity zone property that has not been sold or exchanged on or before December 31, 2026, shall be treated as sold on December 31, 2026.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H295389214EBF452992F3DD7A50BDF3D7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exclusion of gain on qualified opportunity zone property held for at least 10 years</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), in the case of the sale or exchange of qualified opportunity zone property, or an investment in a qualified opportunity fund, held for at least 10 years, gross income for the taxable year shall not include any gain from the sale or exchange of such property or investment.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB8C1B98F37804AFFBA450022E96BC3D3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>One election per property</header><text>No election may be made under paragraph (1) with respect to a sale or exchange if an election previously made with respect to such sale or exchange is in effect.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3F22BE84D2F9494A828CFAAB07BF63ED"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Basis rules relating to qualified opportunity zone property</header>
 <paragraph id="H783E3BDDE8D84D388E7D4C1021D318FE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reduced by gain deferred under subsection <enum-in-header>(a)(1)</enum-in-header></header><text>The basis of a qualified opportunity zone property immediately after its acquisition under subsection (a) shall be reduced by the amount of gain deferred by reason of subsection (a)(1)(A) with respect to such property.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5F9205E846394E8CBEA10008209FA3E1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Increase for gain recognized under subsection <enum-in-header>(a)(2)</enum-in-header></header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The basis of qualified opportunity zone property shall be increased by the amount of gain recognized by reason of subsection (a)(2) with respect to such property.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H782217EF24D34E5796C214C0E3BD0722"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Subsequent increase in basis for property held for at least 5 years but less than 10 years</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of qualified opportunity zone property held for at least 5 years but less than 10 years—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H179AEF3B12284424BAD551945F8F6141"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Property held for 5 years</header><text>For qualified opportunity zone property held for at least 5 years, the basis of such property shall be increased by an amount equal to 10 percent of the amount of gain deferred by reason of subsection (a)(1)(A) with respect to such property.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62DD622E6A694CEFBDFBE72516CD20FA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Property held for 7 years</header><text>For qualified opportunity zone property held for at least 7 years, the basis of such property shall be increased by an amount equal to 5 percent of the amount of gain deferred by reason of subsection (a)(1)(A) with respect to such property.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8AAC0C4DD17B443697D2F4E093C8FDB8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Qualified opportunity zone property</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text> <paragraph id="H7AD3C6D7EEDD4D8EB58CD535C6387407"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>qualified opportunity zone property</term> means property which is—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1AB71DBE1C4E4FC892F17F813E886616"><enum>(A)</enum><text>qualified opportunity zone stock,</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6BB3202018F4388BA95B29F2B41B516"><enum>(B)</enum><text>qualified opportunity zone partnership interest,</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4901727818B84522A25C14E208251486"><enum>(C)</enum><text>qualified opportunity zone business property, or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H152BD635C4894B66B29490983D587346"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an interest in a qualified investment fund.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCDD1AABF74E04E18A98D403D500D3B1A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified opportunity zone stock</header>
 <subparagraph id="H0BF0A5274877484EBAB5E16DF3A42131"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term <term>qualified opportunity zone stock</term> means any stock in a domestic corporation if—</text> <clause id="HD661F1E142E847F29A8401CCFA6B14A3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such stock is acquired by the taxpayer after December 31, 2017, at its original issue (directly or through an underwriter) from the corporation solely in exchange for cash,</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB9EAF41E70314D9A9E624A65BD39295B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>as of the time such stock was issued, such corporation was a qualified opportunity zone business (or, in the case of a new corporation, such corporation was being organized for purposes of being a qualified opportunity zone business), and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6779BA4FC0544D88AF32B427C6E0A692"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>during substantially all of the taxpayer’s holding period for such stock, such corporation qualified as a qualified opportunity zone business.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE369C36B1B9444D8E4A12146F2ACA25"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Redemptions</header><text>A rule similar to the rule of section 1202(c)(3) shall apply for purposes of this paragraph.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H21167DEC43EA408987A10DA5EDE80DDC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified opportunity zone partnership interest</header><text>The term <term>qualified opportunity zone partnership interest</term> means any capital or profits interest in a domestic partnership if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H61BB6B6B3451483FB73DC51C825B7085"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such interest is acquired by the taxpayer after December 31, 2017, from the partnership solely in exchange for cash,</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3309C60F50664D3B8BC55811819B6113"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as of the time such interest was acquired, such partnership was a qualified opportunity zone business (or, in the case of a new partnership, such partnership was being organized for purposes of being a qualified opportunity zone business), and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E0EB7C65C9B418EAD6564A32FEE1FE2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>during substantially all of the taxpayer’s holding period for such interest, such partnership qualified as a qualified opportunity zone business.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF6BECFC8DF0E4DA080DF045B996CE42B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Qualified opportunity zone business property</header>
 <subparagraph id="H0F1DEFAF9E194A18995539132806B937"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>qualified opportunity zone business property</term> means tangible property used in a trade or business of the taxpayer if—</text> <clause id="H319952C1E1394D8DADD624A8206D85E3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such property was acquired by the taxpayer by purchase (as defined in section 179(d)(2)) after December 31, 2017,</text>
 </clause><clause id="H87F3EF9E4A304FF3B0D421BB30AC37EF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the original use of such property in the qualified opportunity zone commences with the taxpayer or the taxpayer substantially improves the property, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H816FA537C1F04E9A9774C073D93999DF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>during substantially all of the taxpayer’s holding period for such property, substantially all of the use of such property was in a qualified opportunity zone.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA48D11A7E5814632B5B03DF26F4C3B75"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Substantial improvement</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A)(ii), property shall be treated as substantially improved by the taxpayer only if, during any 30-month period beginning after the date of acquisition of such property, additions to basis with respect to such property in the hands of the taxpayer exceed an amount equal to the adjusted basis of such property at the beginning of such 30-month period in the hands of the taxpayer.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CBDFDF7F64A46D8AB5F82D4CF867B07"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Related party</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A)(i), the related person rule of section 179(d)(2) shall be applied pursuant to paragraph (8) of this subsection in lieu of the application of such rule in section 179(d)(2)(A).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C238E4ACC174A3F9FA2756FA89B823F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Qualified opportunity fund</header><text>The term <term>qualified opportunity fund</term> means any investment vehicle organized as a corporation or a partnership for the purpose of investing in qualified opportunity zone property (other than another qualified opportunity fund) that holds at least 90 percent of its assets in qualified opportunity zone property, determined—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H52B30658302D46DE93F134283B6A263F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on the last day of the first 6-month period of the taxable year of the fund, and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H26BA883EA959404299A1B495833DF1D5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>on the last day of the taxable year of the fund.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7CDE6EA25FA645D6B88812CF0168BA5F"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Qualified opportunity zone business</header>
 <subparagraph id="H57B00C5587CE4FE2BC6161CB1B86D7D2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>qualified opportunity zone business</term> means a trade or business—</text> <clause id="HD66C3976B9EF4F42AF77581F653A7A50"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in which substantially all of the tangible property owned or leased by the taxpayer is qualified opportunity zone business property,</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAE8CE4A4D8254C32AC97A9810C5E8899"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>which satisfies the requirements of paragraphs (2), (4), and (8) of section 1397C(b), and</text> </clause><clause id="H93A26D1AA4304319BFD4B30BBCA19D29"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>which is not described in section 144(c)(6)(B).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F6B1A9AF1D241F48B0C2C2708B83C91"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subparagraph (A), tangible property that ceases to be a qualified opportunity zone business property shall continue to be treated as a qualified opportunity zone business property for the lesser of—</text>
 <clause id="H5600A1DBE2A34D648C8BF33FA4AA372F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>5 years after the date on which such tangible property ceases to be so qualified, or</text> </clause><clause id="HD0F3320AEFB64E67A58E893040B60433"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the date on which such tangible property is no longer held by the qualified opportunity zone business.</text>
										</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4AC2607D7AB4435A96A5BF523273DEBD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applicable rules</header>
 <paragraph id="HA664AC1CC5F543AA8E973CC17E442876"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this section and except as otherwise provided in this section, rules similar to the rules applicable to deferred like kind exchanges under section 1031 shall apply except that reinvestment in opportunity zone property need not require an intermediary party.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H16D5E26EAF354A7A971B142DE9AA6ACC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Related persons</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, persons are related to each other if such persons are described in section 267(b) or 707(b)(1), determined by substituting <quote>20 percent</quote> for <quote>50 percent</quote> each place it occurs in such sections.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H453CFEBE82A640ADAB8D3CD6EB4DE5BB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Decedents</header><text>In the case of a decedent, amounts recognized under this section shall, if not properly includible in the gross income of the decedent, be includible in gross income as provided by section 691.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H83801B0EB16F42C7AB883209F3F28252"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8CC1C633BC734C3D9F74B7463E3B893A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>rules providing for proportionate inclusion in income and increases in basis for purposes of subsections (a) and (b) in cases in which a sale or exchange of any qualified opportunity zone property with respect to which gain is deferred under subsection (a)(1)(A) is less than all of such property,</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA85461C9F08541E0A9EC44C226DBF3C2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>rules requiring taxpayers to provide such information as the Secretary determines to be necessary or appropriate for the identification of both the assets sold (including basis and sale price) and the assets acquired and investments made, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64F17EF2753D4B76AFD876FEF13F8729"><enum>(C)</enum><text>rules to prevent abuse.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFB1F6032020D4E12A5088E5B42A7A3D6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Failure of qualified opportunity fund To maintain investment standard</header> <paragraph id="H45EC8C6881A14562A9FBFF5038DC342A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a qualified opportunity fund fails to meet the 90-percent requirement of subsection (c)(5), the qualified opportunity fund shall pay a penalty for each month it fails to meet the requirement in an amount equal to the product of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5616CB75AD6041318E42392E5AF9BD2F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the excess of—</text> <clause id="HC4BB9D33D0E5481BABA014D3AE5BB988"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount equal to 90 percent of its aggregate assets, over</text>
 </clause><clause id="H20B75DB38A654768A53444BDBD3EC098"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the aggregate amount of qualified opportunity zone property held by the fund, multiplied by</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCAD8C726A0FD4DBD9D19C28BDE13C2B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the underpayment rate established under section 6621(a)(2) for such month.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFFDD2FC783744BC7857C34816625BABD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rule for partnerships</header><text>In the case that the qualified opportunity fund is a partnership, the penalty imposed by paragraph (1) shall be taken into account proportionately as part of the distributive share of each partner of the partnership.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5E1A5D42FD3846C38CDE4E298E8F7FBB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reasonable cause exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No penalty shall be imposed under this subsection with respect to any failure if it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></subchapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC918FB5B5E764DC998F5DAB632EFD537"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Basis adjustments</header><text>Section 1016(a) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (36), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (37) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and by inserting after paragraph (37) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA8B930415EE047DE9313F0CFC43202E5" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HE9E5C507099D4D36AD2280BE09467544"><enum>(38)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the extent provided in section 1400Z–2(b).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF663EEE6C1E24F8AA028249E17338F04"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury, or the Secretary’s delegate, shall submit a report to Congress on the opportunity zone incentives enacted by this section beginning 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act and annually thereafter. The report shall include an assessment of investments held by qualified opportunity funds nationally and at the State level. To the extent such information is available, the report shall include the number of qualified opportunity funds, the amount of assets held in qualified opportunity funds, the composition of qualified opportunity fund investments by asset class, the percentage of qualified opportunity zone census tracts designated under subchapter Z of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (as added by this section) that have received qualified opportunity fund investments. The report shall also include an assessment of the impacts and outcomes of the investments in those areas on economic indicators including job creation, poverty reduction, and new business starts, and other metrics as determined by the Secretary.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCDEA20909D114705BD834C1D09D37CC7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of subchapters for chapter 1 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA8249EB965004D8C8F59D400F7ACB366" style="OLC">
					<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="HB1C66B8937A243A8846AC220B95F72EA" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
						<toc-entry idref="HAA61B52D79D14CB68664BBD7675E88D3" level="subchapter">Subchapter Z. Opportunity zones</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB9B12E8A28C3439D9854376C077536ED"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text> </subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

