<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HADCB647A074B4716A9E9538D981979EF" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4271 IH: To block the implementation of certain presidential actions that restrict individuals from certain countries from entering the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4271</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171107">November 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001050">Ms. Hanabusa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Intelligence (Permanent Select)</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To block the implementation of certain presidential actions that restrict individuals from certain
			 countries from entering the United States.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H830F0D23171D4597BCFB5095995E76B1" style="OLC">
 <section id="HF2990DBDE3F44FEABD705924B0F95472" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that Executive Order 13780 and the presidential proclamation issued on September 24, 2017—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2ABC30B98D974160B6FD84F92DD17EAE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">violate the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref> et seq.), which states that no person can be discriminated against in the issuance of an immigrant visa because of the person’s race, sex, nationality, place of birth, or place of residence; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB26C5EF1DB4849AEAE595A6190AAAA09"><enum>(2)</enum><text>violate the Establishment Clause of the First Amendment to the United States Constitution and the equal protection component of the Due Process Clause of the Fifth Amendment to the United States Constitution.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HC031D110F7C44BEB851AD5FD85A5CFF3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition against use of funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No funds, resources, or fees made available to the Secretary of Homeland Security, or to any other official of a Federal agency, by this Act or any other Act for any fiscal year, may be used to implement or enforce Executive Order 13780, signed on March 6, 2017, or the presidential proclamation issued on September 24, 2017.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


