<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H3FE76552D76C4D77A3F4BBEA3D108BD0" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4047 IH: Saving Federal Dollars Through Better Use of Government Purchase and Travel Cards Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4047</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171012">October 12, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001286">Mrs. Bustos</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the identification and prevention of improper payments and the identification of
			 strategic sourcing opportunities by reviewing and analyzing the use of
			 Federal agency charge cards.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H958BDA428C534A4592030B917A145484" style="OLC">
 <section id="HD3F289DB85344B0595E91065344FFC69" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Saving Federal Dollars Through Better Use of Government Purchase and Travel Cards Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4DB79B99A38F4888B7AF9DBF15702EEC" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H56C39705746E4BE4AC6F09BD7CCD1A1F"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Improper payment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>improper payment</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2 of the Improper Payments Information Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/3321">31 U.S.C. 3321</external-xref> note).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H09EEAB9E0586400E8491DA858AD16D5E"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Questionable transaction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>questionable transaction</term> means a charge card transaction that from initial card data appears to be high risk and may therefore be improper due to non-compliance with applicable law, regulation or policy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H920C84293251405296AC032D45F42E00"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Strategic sourcing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>strategic sourcing</term> means analyzing and modifying a Federal agency’s spending patterns to better leverage its purchasing power, reduce costs, and improve overall performance.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA23280B0124D4E34B099E6AEA923D430" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Expanded use of data analytics</header>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2EA2AB00034746528EF61DBA1C18B51E"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Strategy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in consultation with the Administrator for General Services, shall develop a strategy to expand the use of data analytics in managing government purchase and travel charge card programs. These analytics may employ existing General Services Administration capabilities, and may be in conjunction with agencies’ capabilities, for the purpose of—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC6C06BE65BBD443E847AFABCBDBD1A88"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifying examples or patterns of questionable transactions and developing enhanced tools and methods for agency use in—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9DCFBA7126D049D0AE822A0C9902BF5F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifying questionable purchase and travel card transactions; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6187A484B56A4402A56D08F21D102DF7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recovering improper payments made with purchase and travel cards;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF6FF461BA7944DE1A984F6FDA081CF50"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifying potential opportunities for agencies to further leverage administrative process stream­lining and cost reduction from purchase and travel card use, including additional agency opportunities for card-based strategic sourcing;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0472B48C2F0A49DC89A06D95F2A05778"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">developing a set of purchase and travel card metrics and benchmarks for high-risk activities, which shall assist agencies in identifying potential emphasis areas for their purchase and travel card management and oversight activities, including those required by the Government Charge Card Abuse Prevention Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/194">Public Law 112–194</external-xref>); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H02774DC2E87048EC873EF3681A26C131"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">developing a plan, which may be based on existing capabilities, to create a library of analytics tools and data sources for use by Federal agencies (including inspectors general of those agencies).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H057E2FC5721F4C3CB6B7889987FADF92" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Guidance on improving information sharing to curb improper payments</header>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2B600D8D844249E88413DB4E5FDD0DAE"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in consultation with the Administrator of General Services and the interagency charge card data management group established under section 5, shall issue guidance on improving information sharing by government agencies for the purposes of section 3(a)(1).</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5800DA8A89E94BCC9F58F730CD8BFAC3"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The guidance issued under subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCDBECAE08C7C4F2DAF59F994D8E2B5C3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require relevant officials at Federal agencies to identify high-risk activities and communicate that information to the appropriate management levels within the agencies;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H32E1FF668B4A46B698981B0DDB4E8370"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require that appropriate officials at Federal agencies review the reports issued by charge card-issuing banks on questionable transaction activity (such as purchase and travel card pre-suspension and suspension reports, delinquency reports, and exception reports), including transactions that occur with high-risk activities, and suspicious timing or amounts of cash withdrawals or advances;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4A2AAAF2A652474B88E74D6B728754AB"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide for the appropriate sharing of information related to potential questionable transactions, fraud schemes, and high-risk activities with the General Services Administration and the appropriate officials in Federal agencies;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H77478D9658A04BDBA11806A2EE68214C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>consider the recommendations made by Inspectors General or the best practices Inspectors General have identified; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H122D8338F23D47EF94C4FBA2F3F249BF"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include other requirements determined appropriate by the Director for the purposes of carrying out this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD867D2C51457452BBA7D03BC2093AC02" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Interagency Charge Card Data Management Group</header>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEAAE96F46B4B4AE8AD82CD2040327D81"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of General Services and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall establish a purchase and travel charge card data management group to develop and share best practices for the purposes described in section 3(a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE60A3C4DAB494E02B210954C561EAC87"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The best practices developed under subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0763CD5BF4714851ACE3F596757661DC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">cover rules, edits, and task order or contract modifications related to charge card-issuing banks;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6E3ACFC3E28D41D7BCB3FED1C2491B35"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include the review of accounts payable information and purchase and travel card transaction data of agencies for the purpose of identifying potential strategic sourcing and other additional opportunities (such as recurring payments, utility payments, and grant payments) for which the charge cards or related payment products could be used as a payment method; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC29ED1B2BA054A2689A43A7CE930775C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include other best practices as determined by the Administrator and Director.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE466C5B2F1E74BD3B090D57422195CA1"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Membership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purchase and travel charge card data management group shall meet regularly as determined by the co-chairs, for a duration of three years, and include those agencies as described in section 2 of the Government Charge Card Abuse Prevention Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/194">Public Law 112–194</external-xref>) and others identified by the Administrator and Director.</text>
			</subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBA885134BADA4EDFB48978DD2E793948" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>6.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reporting requirements</header>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H52046AC26CA544B08055F748380FA0AF"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">General Services Administration report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator for General Services shall submit a report to Congress on the implementation of this Act, including the metrics used in determining whether the analytic and benchmarking efforts have reduced, or contributed to the reduction of, questionable or improper payments as well as improved utilization of card-based payment products.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE4AED26FDE7F4F5E953FEF4F95888A3A"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Agency reports and consolidated report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the head of each Federal agency described in section 2 of the Government Charge Card Abuse Prevention Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/194">Public Law 112–194</external-xref>) shall submit a report to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget on that agency’s activities to implement this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2309BEE577514AF88A28D9C3C678886B"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Office of Management and Budget report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall submit to Congress a consolidated report of agency activities to implement this Act, which may be included as part of another report submitted to Congress by the Director.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE2FCF78313774B14BB471CDF9CC78CF1"><enum>(d)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Report on additional savings opportunities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of General Services shall submit a report to Congress identifying and exploring further potential savings opportunities for government agencies under the Federal charge card programs. This report may be combined with the report required under subsection (a).</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


