<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE162F3DA8FB84E8D86F5C1F89C771A36" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4064 IH: To impose restrictions on the sale of binary explosives, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4064</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171012">October 12, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To impose restrictions on the sale of binary explosives, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H310848D14E164655A71BD7215B2A5BB4" style="OLC">
		<section id="H03970451CB9E415390A083112BDA7D66" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Licensing of retailers of binary explosives</header>
 <subsection id="H1A523572F41E4A30819F78D950B48A2B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibited acts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 842(a) of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H7FBFF731EBA449A2819220AE9ABB5B0C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(B), by striking <quote>or</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD4ACC33447B74F0EA8716558DFFF943C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)(B), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H362C4D08C3F54B37BA63D7E0FEEE1F14"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8E24EF8BA55E465FBCA194EF615EA5C7" style="USC">
 <paragraph id="HD66FAEE428ED41A093D704E8C549D531"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to engage in the business of selling a binary explosive to an individual without a license issued under this chapter;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HADD2C3BC85434D4C9B0E8074F2726CEE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to knowingly sell a binary explosive to an individual without complying with subsection (q); or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H14BA7DF5DD36487F8B7DBAC498B63CB4"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to knowingly purchase a binary explosive in excess of the monthly amount described in subsection (q)(1).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB2E5A1BFF2FE4348B23A8DCF5F7766C0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment of binary explosives</header>
 <paragraph id="H99B7959FD04F4834B27AECB24D1DB3EF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Treatment with respect to licenses</header><text>Section 843 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H5F209BF3C87D43F987ABC543439D9E2F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>deal in explosive materials</quote> and inserting <quote>deal in explosive materials, or to sell a binary explosive to an individual,</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13C8302FE1FD4B9D8CAE2D0FBC47C02F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>to possess explosive materials</quote> and inserting <quote>to possess explosive materials or a binary explosive</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F874699048545C2B2F392F0DDA4456A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(4)(A), by striking <quote>storage for explosive materials</quote> and inserting <quote>storage for explosive materials or a binary explosive</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23D19DF36F1D43F9834296D04383C068"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subsection (f), by adding at the end: <quote>A reference in this subsection to <quote>explosive materials</quote> shall also include a binary explosive.</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F668DEFEDE2458DAE970D9BCBD07DFB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment with respect to penalties</header><text>Section 844 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3E155BAF3160454484E4000AB533B06F" style="USC">
 <subsection id="H21B02DCE6AF34E02BBA9C8DEC5857C14"><enum>(q)</enum><header>Treatment of binary explosives</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A reference in this section to <quote>explosive materials</quote> shall also include a binary explosive.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFA2D08D55AB5420A939D90C2CB25814C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H29335982559B42C281F20F21503B9335"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of maximum purchase amounts for binary explosives</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 842 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H01235469D04B4823A07AF1C2676A0999" style="USC"> <subsection id="HEDC292515F8640829E482384C9CBBF16"><enum>(q)</enum><header>Establishment of maximum purchase amounts for binary explosives</header> <paragraph id="H9F6AD1423073426EB7D13BF07D8D8C5B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Maximum monthly purchase amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Attorney General shall establish the maximum amount of a binary explosive (or a combination thereof) that may be purchased by one individual in a calendar month, based on a recommendation from the Director of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="HA2A31D05312040D18DEBEAC44B3F3FAD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Establishment of national binary explosive check system</header>
 <subparagraph id="H1EED012699DD49A184125801B9FD2927"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Attorney General shall establish a national binary explosive check system.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H610A5A488E1E449F87544A8A2C245176"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Operation of system</header><text>The system shall—</text> <clause id="HC6FEC567BD9C4ACDABBDBE55F923526D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be electronic and accessible through an Internet website;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1221D882B4B3413A86FC9AF4E8355D4D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">compile records of sales of all binary explosives to named individuals;</text> </clause><clause id="H313E5BD8EC994C57B3DA4B0B93FD4A1E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be capable of identifying a named individual by entry of information from a valid identification document (as defined in section 1028(d)) issued to such individual;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8D4694289248431EBE0111F79EBC7033"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be capable of receiving inquiries from a seller about whether the amount of a binary explosive sought to be purchased by a prospective purchaser would exceed the amount described in paragraph (1);</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF358CF44F6C9411C8D4DD9EAD78C5932"><enum>(v)</enum><text>be capable of responding to a seller with an indication whether the amount of a binary explosive sought to be purchased by a prospective purchaser would exceed the amount described in paragraph (1);</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCE2A048B2CFE4C63AD73B715CDA9D542"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>be able to respond to all inquiries in a reasonable amount of time; and</text> </clause><clause id="HDD325C01B1B545AFB901BD0183D204F2"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">only be accessible to dealers of binary explosives that have a valid license issued under this chapter.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F1A6DE2911141D3992583D3EA0283FA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Behind-the-counter access and sales form requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of this subsection, a seller of binary explosives to an individual shall ensure that sales by such seller of a binary explosive are made in accordance with the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2D1E2D257A844919AF99A1754459B771"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The seller offers the product for sale only at a retail location.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8BBC3341439946719B687F641DE63F17"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In offering the product for sale, the seller places the product behind the counter.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86B756F82483405A8ADB90FC57E17EFA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The seller delivers the product directly into the custody of the purchaser.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90120F3EEE0D48B8B843C25E9D197810"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The seller does not sell such a product unless the prospective purchaser—</text>
 <clause id="H9A61E26C8D7F4F4A9F1A19FAA6143660"><enum>(i)</enum><text>presents a valid identification document (as defined in section 1028(d)) of such purchaser containing a photograph of such purchaser; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H447AA6D27A0547E9BE20A7DF3C8FE576"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>fills out the sales form with the name and address of such purchaser and the amount of binary explosive being purchased.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD3AD06F9A48F4E0885B7E48EFC4461D2"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The seller does not sell such a product to a prospective purchaser unless the seller—</text> <clause id="HB5FCDCC7075147E5AE657BA6F920FE7A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determines that the name entered by such prospective purchaser on the sales form is the same as the name provided on the identification document;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2169691F42C44D1F893DB99A4F7F7389"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>transmits to the national binary explosive check system the name of the product, the quantity to be sold, and the name and address of such prospective purchaser; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7CADB12DF8AC48F1A5001FB1496AB04C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">receives from the system a statement that the amount of a binary explosive sought to be purchased by a prospective purchaser would not exceed the amount described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F550B701DE64E53B927E8303A19269F"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The sales form includes a notice to purchasers that entering false statements or misrepresentations on the sales form may subject the purchasers to criminal penalties under section 1001, which notice specifies the maximum fine and term of imprisonment under such section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82DF7D7A3F0549CBA6E599A9322A8B5D"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The seller maintains the sales form for not fewer than two years after the date on which the sale is consummated.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F7AC87730B34A5F9428532A0BF82820"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Safe harbor rule</header>
 <subparagraph id="H2AB808E44FC840A68F3020FCB5DB60DE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A seller who knows, should know, or has reason to believe that the purchase of an amount of a binary explosive by a prospective purchaser would result in a violation of paragraph (1) may sell such amount to such purchaser if such seller is notified by the national binary explosive check system that the purchase of such amount would not result in a violation of paragraph (1).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE12FA81305742ADBAE2CB9F382A8085"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Required procedure</header><text>If a seller sells a binary explosive to a prospective purchaser pursuant to subparagraph (A), such seller, promptly after the sale, shall notify the Attorney General of—</text>
 <clause id="H239AA46D486744728F3C4E313CBF8753"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the name and address of the purchaser;</text> </clause><clause id="H3AF53D877751491A8E2DC588C51CE310"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount sold; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBCFBFE5C24CA427FB1A4007E302DEDB6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the factual basis, if any, for the knowledge or belief that such a sale resulted in a violation of paragraph (1).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8AFC86194E1A434B883F0C443C0481F5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <subparagraph id="H34BB19347CA34AD9A238CD516803D83C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>behind the counter</quote> means, with respect to a binary explosive, that customers do not have direct access to the product before the sale is made at a retail location.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD32AB067D4947BCA1F69775ABF504A5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term <quote>retail location</quote> means a location at which a seller sells a binary explosive in limited, small quantities or amounts, and not in gross.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6860A8559F0D4402AF2EE72A5D3902C1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>sales form</quote> means the form the prospective purchase of a binary explosive fills out with the name and address of such purchaser and the amount of binary explosive being purchased.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="HE9302DCBF23448DFBF1C6D0BFEE1E349"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 841 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF4EB23F0D8B14009A97223E08472BF55" style="USC"> <subsection id="H188C13A6267D4E28AEEC146D541473AD"><enum>(u)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><quote>Binary explosive</quote> means a substance that, when combined with another substance—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8F9127D878BB490EA9D784E30123C305"><enum>(1)</enum><text>results in explosive material; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3CCDF03D1040481BBDEC10DF5D0A79E2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has as its primary or common purpose to function by explosion through target practice using a firearm.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


