<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H87B1F80201174A758F79BBD61B573684" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 554 IH: Make State Governments More Open, Honest, and Transparent Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 554</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170113">January 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000380">Mr. Kildee</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To suspend the authority of a State to administer funds under Federal block grant programs if the
			 State does not enact certain conflict of interest protections, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H84FA0C9A45FB48E1821FA020DD2A0D7F" style="OLC">
 <section id="HBF44CFD114B144AEA363E68B291D22F7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Make State Governments More Open, Honest, and Transparent Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HB99F726B7C60431A812588A2B5479FFE"><enum>2.</enum><header>National standards relating to State conflict of interest protections</header> <subsection id="HE4AF88F07576456AB1E0BFF792742557"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of a Federal agency that administers a Federal block grant program in a fiscal year shall take the following actions with respect to a State that is in noncompliance as described in subsection (b) on the first day of the fiscal year:</text>
 <paragraph id="H84B6CCF33AF847D98C1BE6AB224A6365"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Suspend the authority of the State or any political subdivision of the State to administer funds made available to the State or subdivision under the Federal block grant program in that fiscal year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0F8D4B053EBF4B90AC8EDEEA87B0DB3C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Exercise the authority of the State described in paragraph (1) in that fiscal year, including the selection of the projects to be carried out in the State or subdivision under the Federal block grant program.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDAF2CA6B59204A37959E4DFA2B48F38E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State shall be treated as being in noncompliance as described in this subsection with respect to a fiscal year if the Director of the Office of Government Ethics determines that the State has not enacted or is not enforcing one or more of the following laws on the first day of the fiscal year:</text>
 <paragraph id="H55C2198F4ECB4EFB95B656C3E0943D8C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A law that requires an individual serving as a member of the legislature of the State to prepare and make available to the public an annual report disclosing the financial interests of the individual during the preceding year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H479099DA35044F5DBFC52FC3447C8E42"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A law that prohibits an individual serving as a member of the legislature of the State to solicit or require, either directly or indirectly, an employee of the individual to make a financial or in-kind contribution to a political party or a political campaign.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8B06EF1F09E7479E984A34E493A8BBD1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A law that makes it unlawful for any person—</text> <subparagraph id="H439ACC630CC247F183EBA679FCC28139"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who enters into any contract with the State (including any department or agency of the State) either for the rendition of personal services or furnishing any material, supplies, or equipment to the State or for selling any land or building to the State, if payment for the performance of such contract or payment for such material, supplies, equipment, land, or building is to be made in whole or in part from funds appropriated by the State, at any time between the commencement of negotiations for and the later of (i) the completion of performance under, or (ii) the termination of negotiations for, such contract or furnishing of material, supplies, equipment, land, or buildings, directly or indirectly to make any contribution of money or other things of value, or to promise expressly or impliedly to make any such contribution to any political party, committee, or candidate for State public office or to any person for any political purpose or use; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A56D453F1AF49028BF2968173A2A25F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">knowingly to solicit any such contribution from any such person for any such purpose during any such period.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB7FF7F88029B49C789E614B2D6D3489E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the following definitions apply:</text> <paragraph id="HBF556271F10F4F12B6880A70AC3DA9C3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal block grant program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Federal block grant program</quote> means each of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3AFA68C1298A4C53ACA712DBEF9BC117"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Innovative Education Program Strategies Block Grant program of the Department of Education.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H30C4F57D643044BC83D5A4CF3E152B99"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Energy Efficiency and Conservation Block Grant program of the Department of Energy.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7902AAA5367844E19F212D23762539E0"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following programs of the Department of Health and Human Services:</text> <clause id="H31A287D56B2A450E910B7F7471FD9486"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Child Care and Development Block Grant program.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD68D78E1ECE248D4B56F33A45A7AD1C8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Community Mental Health Services Block Grant program.</text> </clause><clause id="HBF666622EC554B6B9D019F7E84FA9F77"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Community Services Block Grant program.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7D6F0C755BEC4BCAAD1E65CB076AD8FE"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Low Income Home Energy Assistance Block Grant program.</text> </clause><clause id="H185FAC0F03C2487EB171B8A549384EB8"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Maternal and Child Health Services Block Grant program.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3F9802CFECC9420A86327C59D7711D9F"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Preventive Health and Health Services Block Grant program.</text> </clause><clause id="HF2CAB5ED43AF42D0A5D3D19364969A95"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Social Services Block Grant program.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB39194DC15A94FDDAFEDCCF53C9CB4D8"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Substance Abuse Prevention and Treatment Block Grant program.</text> </clause><clause id="H9D668CC72D7546BEA7101289BBEE5EB9"><enum>(ix)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Temporary Assistance to Needy Families program.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H13688CD433F04498B976780116A8C8C3"><enum>(x)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Title V Abstinence Education Block Grant program.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDB9F174C61242B895AE452014C749DE"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Homeland Security Grant Programs (State Homeland Security Programs, Urban Area Security Initiative Grant, and Operation Stonegarden) of the Department of Homeland Security.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E84A9ABCC394B239984292D85763F20"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following programs of the Department of Housing and Urban Development:</text> <clause id="HAEA6A8C0B45147718C903658DAED2848"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Community Development Block Grant program.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H202171DE09EC464DB741C86A606C8CDE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Indian Community Development Block Grant program.</text> </clause><clause id="H461A389FB73A4D669ED97E5E5648C5B2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The Emergency Solutions Grant Program.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB3BE403764CC4EDBA0A15A92DEC25EBC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The HOME Investment Partnerships Program.</text> </clause><clause id="H5E67077D640D47D19DBCDBC5C111DCC5"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The Indian Housing Block Grant program.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7C4E44FD81BA4D83947FA01350D1C8E1"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The Native Hawaiian Housing Block Grant program.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD26B7D02464D4D8E86FFD1FF8FB8CFBA"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant program of the Department of Justice.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2309716D34E471B9C368AB71EF00B18"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Workforce Investment Act (Youth, Adult, and Dislocated Workers) program of the Department of Labor.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE9C04E2788A4F1FA694756EEC2EFC8B"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following programs of the Department of Transportation:</text> <clause id="H93A59664E71A40F8AFE24DCEFC9B49B8"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Aviation Administration Airport Improvement State Block Grant Program.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9BA102452D0B42C6AB75EF1287D360C9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Surface Transportation Block Grant Program.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA59917C8043A4BE286FA6595A5545A8A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>State</quote> means any of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, or Puerto Rico.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


