<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H694FC91C9E7240D9A5A035980827D62E" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2142 IH: International Narcotics Trafficking Emergency Response by Detecting Incoming Contraband with Technology Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2142</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170425">April 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000465">Ms. Tsongas</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve the ability of U.S. Customs and Border Protection to interdict fentanyl, other synthetic
			 opioids, and other narcotics and psychoactive substances that are
			 illegally imported into the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H7C07F335ED164B7182F1D7018E8E121C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H0992554D7DB540C9B323489B7D3C68C5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>International Narcotics Trafficking Emergency Response by Detecting Incoming Contraband with Technology Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>INTERDICT Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="H89A05A29C0014258961C734FEC174654"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB40663A95EF1456090142F8CB2917BA7"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chemical screening device</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>chemical screening device</term> means an infrared spectrophotometer, mass spectrometer, nuclear magnetic resonance spectrometer, Raman spectrophotometer, or other scientific instrumentation able to collect data that can be interpreted to determine the presence of fentanyl, other synthetic opioids, and other narcotics and psychoactive substances.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6049694278724CB6A047E4E2FA293860"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Express consignment operator or carrier</header><text>The term <term>express consignment operator or carrier</term> has the meaning given that term in section 128.1 of title 19, Code of Federal Regulations (or any similar successor regulation).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6DAA147D1A95473D96E211EF89CD6073"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H5AE3DB4F4E4647A5A42C3061DB218EA8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Interdiction of fentanyl, other synthetic opioids, and other narcotics and psychoactive substances</header> <subsection commented="no" id="HF4A73DE6705943EB9C1D0128093AFE25"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Chemical screening devices</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HCC131C3813174462905CF147F4B5213B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>increase the number of chemical screening devices available to U.S. Customs and Border Protection over the number of such devices that are available on the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H288D13FC9B2446FFA223825C4FD10D29"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make such additional chemical screening devices available to U.S. Customs and Border Protection as the Secretary determines are necessary for U.S. Customs and Border Protection to carry out activities to interdict fentanyl, other synthetic opioids, and other narcotics and psychoactive substances that are illegally imported into the United States, including such substances that are imported through the mail or by an express consignment operator or carrier.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HC8118636A3A144BB8EFA88DF599D4475"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Personnel To interpret data</header><text>The Secretary shall dedicate the appropriate number of personnel, including scientists, to U.S. Customs and Border Protection so that personnel are available during all operational hours to interpret data collected by chemical screening devices.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HB74D314B295C41379C34342FB039A9BD"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $15,000,000 to ensure that U.S. Customs and Border Protection—</text>
 <paragraph id="H661C72E92AD44498B0F2AE85FD7EF06B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has sufficient resources and personnel, including scientists, available during all operational hours to prevent the unlawful importation of fentanyl, other synthetic opioids, and other narcotics and psychoactive substances; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8D647EA36BC94F21BD91774BBA1D7D6D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is provided with sufficient chemical screening devices to facilitate the effective and efficient detection and identification of such substances.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


