<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H7D902871FE0648ADACC75A60C8341DD1" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 612 EH: United States-Israel Cybersecurity Cooperation Enhancement Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 612</legis-num>
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To establish a grant program at the Department of Homeland Security to promote cooperative research and development between the United States and Israel on cybersecurity.</official-title>
</form> 
<legis-body id="HCC058C16A1A845E1B124C312B969058A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1DA185BE846044BEB2DE35125D9975D5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>United States-Israel Cybersecurity Cooperation Enhancement Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="HE3BBCF02DDBB49CDB28045849C80D688"><enum>2.</enum><header>United States-Israel cybersecurity cooperation</header> <subsection id="H23D536728C9441F7AA106CABC510ECE8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grant program</header> <paragraph id="HFBB09385624445348ED68D5518F2ACA9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary, in accordance with the agreement entitled the <quote>Agreement between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of the State of Israel on Cooperation in Science and Technology for Homeland Security Matters</quote>, dated May 29, 2008 (or successor agreement), and the requirements specified in paragraph (2), shall establish a grant program at the Department to support—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDB00037A791D4E80A026BD0614512003"><enum>(A)</enum><text>cybersecurity research and development; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5BE277D7054F4F7FA4CC695D608A5516"><enum>(B)</enum><text>demonstration and commercialization of cybersecurity technology.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H43BDB59836374115A0309DE8E446207B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header> 
<subparagraph id="H5CDF7726047F495783345B7139EB1B91"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in carrying out a research, development, demonstration, or commercial application program or activity that is authorized under this section, the Secretary shall require cost sharing in accordance with this paragraph.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7059EC8DCEB4458A8B7F053A8E611D9F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Research and development</header> <clause id="H5C33A788AEAA48F682A66E2C7F6A28B6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (ii), the Secretary shall require not less than 50 percent of the cost of a research, development, demonstration, or commercial application program or activity described in subparagraph (A) to be provided by a non-Federal source.</text> </clause>
<clause id="H08C72676D9C24896A8462F7CDB27EEEB"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Reduction</header><text>The Secretary may reduce or eliminate, on a case-by-case basis, the percentage requirement specified in clause (i) if the Secretary determines that such reduction or elimination is necessary and appropriate.</text> </clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA7EAB28FE1A74BC7AA97E1480836C053"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Merit review</header><text>In carrying out a research, development, demonstration, or commercial application program or activity that is authorized under this section, awards shall be made only after an impartial review of the scientific and technical merit of the proposals for such awards has been carried out by or for the Department.</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE8D29093914D4C49ACCD587EED2854B7"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Review processes</header><text>In carrying out a review under subparagraph (C), the Secretary may use merit review processes developed under section 302(14) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/182">6 U.S.C. 182(14)</external-xref>).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H579552486FCD4798AB13FE4BB493C8F9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible applicants</header><text>An applicant shall be eligible to receive a grant under this subsection if the project of such applicant—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H914493CED6F344F791E09A135EB9827D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>addresses a requirement in the area of cybersecurity research or cybersecurity technology, as determined by the Secretary; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD1A13E24485641BA9D76A66B69C4F369"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is a joint venture between—</text> 
<clause id="H380B8DE3AF814D4E85E7E6E53FBE68C5"><enum>(i)</enum> 
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H4950E1ACDA2140CA8724E160D48207B0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a for-profit business entity, academic institution, National Laboratory (as defined in section 2 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15801">42 U.S.C. 15801</external-xref>)), or nonprofit entity in the United States; and</text> </subclause> <subclause id="H5E51DC4652FA41B6ABCDCB4D0D4CB0A3" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a for-profit business entity, academic institution, or nonprofit entity in Israel; or</text> </subclause></clause>
<clause id="HDEE067D009074526B80B4EABC0D56C2D"><enum>(ii)</enum> 
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H46A3E44E4EA14822881A4BB4148AF02A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Federal Government; and</text> </subclause> <subclause id="HBA44547D055146D28EB84315BF644200" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Government of Israel.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9543572517064CC294F1CAFA458B9FE5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this subsection, an applicant shall submit to the Secretary an application for such grant in accordance with procedures established by the Secretary, in consultation with the advisory board established under paragraph (5).</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HA689022577AB4396964EA9170D5972DE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Advisory board</header> <subparagraph id="HEC088C03DF8C41F09CE20F862669E9C8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary shall establish an advisory board to—</text> 
<clause id="H67275A24C74E49D6B2A233F8A8F73594"><enum>(i)</enum><text>monitor the method by which grants are awarded under this subsection; and</text> </clause> <clause id="H17F76EEB11F048408CD2336D4B33C6EC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide to the Secretary periodic performance reviews of actions taken to carry out this subsection.</text> </clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7EFEF286DCDC488FAA7C3CD19E5A0A8D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The advisory board established under subparagraph (A) shall be composed of three members, to be appointed by the Secretary, of whom—</text> <clause id="H6B89D6C085464652A0A6617CD6C232AD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>one shall be a representative of the Federal Government;</text> </clause>
<clause id="H905B57B05A4E423A9EEF4A831903A0D3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>one shall be selected from a list of nominees provided by the United States-Israel Binational Science Foundation; and</text> </clause> <clause id="HD8E0367DF46E46AC8709BAB9B8C5629E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>one shall be selected from a list of nominees provided by the United States-Israel Binational Industrial Research and Development Foundation.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3A4C609A2B5E4829860D4BC082F0263C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Contributed funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may accept or retain funds contributed by any person, government entity, or organization for purposes of carrying out this subsection. Such funds shall be available, subject to appropriation, without fiscal year limitation.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HE0DE3F0E96904E489431CB459873E4A8"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of completion of a project for which a grant is provided under this subsection, the grant recipient shall submit to the Secretary a report that contains—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H37DD9CE540A54257B037E725FCC44508"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of how the grant funds were used by the recipient; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE0C9A5AFD0C84C0B9E2C2FC740625AFA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an evaluation of the level of success of each project funded by the grant.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H24078D69592141DBA9AC047A2783BCF8"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Classification</header><text>Grants shall be awarded under this subsection only for projects that are considered to be unclassified by both the United States and Israel.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFBB27DA0B093487D9A196C6F21CDA596"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The grant program and the advisory board established under this section terminate on the date that is 7 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H3D99F63F762F48D78A85777682630718"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No additional funds authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to carry out the requirements of this Act. Such requirements shall be carried out using amounts otherwise authorized.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H9150679163214BE6A68B106653594E32"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD329CFD0DB9040F0BE9C0396F5945134"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <quote>cybersecurity research</quote> means research, including social science research, into ways to identify, protect against, detect, respond to, and recover from cybersecurity threats;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HF364BFA0330E48EF925FEC52C13CD667"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <quote>cybersecurity technology</quote> means technology intended to identify, protect against, detect, respond to, and recover from cybersecurity threats;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC9BD0BB320294856B78274310DA31716"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <quote>cybersecurity threat</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 102 of the Cybersecurity Information Sharing Act of 2015 (enacted as title I of the Cybersecurity Act of 2015 (division N of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/113">Public Law 114–113</external-xref>)));</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H487BEB797E27489287D085535AF325D8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <quote>Department</quote> means the Department of Homeland Security; and</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFBBDF3A11F814BA8A2522827F6D49287"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20170131" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives January 31, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> <endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> </bill> 

