<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H27F0DFE10CCF447AA850042181D6A669" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1407 IH: METALS Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1407</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170307">March 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001048">Mr. Hunter</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a strategic materials investment fund, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HC599B1590DEC40908E0B6A15C7D44C10" style="OLC">
 <section id="HBB7624B89023426D986BC9DE8B42FE49" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Materials Essential To American Leadership and Security Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote>METALS Act</quote>.</text> </section><section id="H0766337DD62A4601AE7F942805DE1A61"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress on domestic production of rare earth elements</header> <subsection id="H3212305CDE6D4FF38ADBCE1B1C5F7526"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H5AFE7501DA2746A39CD5095BABABF242"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In the wake of increased tension between the People’s Republic of China and the nation of Japan in 2010, the People’s Republic of China enacted a de facto embargo of all rare earth elements which placed the Department of Defense at risk of losing access to materials used in the manufacture of key components of numerous major weapons systems. The potential for the People’s Republic of China to suspend exports of rare earth elements to the United States still exists today.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF9BE96575DCC41E69E06AB86891093C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In 2015, a major United States corporation, the only major domestic producer of certain rare earth products, filed for bankruptcy after compiling $1.4 billion in debt. Assets from the company were sold to operators in the People’s Republic of China to pay off creditors while the domestic mine and processing plant were shuttered and disassembled.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1C784D49D4894B91B6EDAB08641B656E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The People’s Republic of China currently dominates the supply chain for the production of rare earth elements controlling more than 90 percent of the world’s production.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF23FAD5234D64004A5F37904C0B5A77E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Rare earth elements are used in a host of advanced defense applications and technologies which would largely be rendered ineffective without these materials.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6A9FFB03DC544476B234FC1F56D7573C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="H0A868A55C71B44919C1036C600C63511"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the interest of national security the United States must develop a domestic industrial base for the production of strategic and critical materials;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3E340C2924114C8EAAAABD9B44B9B65E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>considering the host of defense-related applications that would be rendered ineffective if United States access to foreign strategic and critical materials was restricted, the United States must ensure a safe and secure supply chain for strategic and critical materials for defense purposes;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBA1CC1D02E814842839535F2CB176EFB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>given the current supply chain for strategic and critical materials the United States, and specifically the Department of Defense, is at considerable risk for a supply interruption;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC881A45288F14843AF14CAB415C8D056"><enum>(4)</enum><text>if it is to divest itself from a dependence on foreign-produced strategic and critical materials, the United States must be willing to accept some risk in the form of aiding domestic investment opportunities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3EB85477B68942DB9115F75AE0F28D8C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the United States must support the domestic production of strategic and critical materials by creating a fund which uses a small percentage, 1 percent, of the internal programmatic administration costs of major aircraft and missile weapons systems to promote investment in domestic production of strategic and critical materials;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA9B4D6379C6743CE8E263C04F94BDDAD"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the fund should only leverage those funds used by the Department of Defense for internal programmatic administration costs and should not decrease quantities to be procured by the Department of Defense;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H257081E49668409A81B25B0B0397327F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the fund should be managed by the Defense Logistics Agency Strategic Materials;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H78496C77CC834B3A975E0728B0FBFD1E"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the purpose of the fund should be to provide 5-year, interest-free loans to domestic producers of strategic and critical materials in an attempt to reduce American dependence on foreign sources of these materials and the loans should be paid back to the fund at the termination of the loan period; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H5AC86E5F2EC04F71B08C70A4C7A8550D"><enum>(9)</enum><text>in those cases where domestic materials are more expensive than materials available from international sources, often owing to unfair trade and labor practices in foreign countries, the fund should reimburse weapons systems programs for cost increases as a result of procuring strategic and critical materials from domestic sources.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H93EC8C0E94334F8FAFEB376FCB2680C4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Strategic materials investment fund</header>
 <subsection id="HA7B5A21929D34E1C934D7442B457E24A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established in the Treasury of the United States a separate fund to be known as the <quote>Strategic Materials Investment Fund</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Fund</quote>). The Fund shall consist of amounts deposited to it under subsection (e).</text> </subsection><subsection id="H63E4641E3D3047F882FE6D9970837F8C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Fund operations</header><text>The Secretary of Defense, acting through the Administrator of the Defense Logistics Agency Strategic Materials, may make expenditures from the Fund to develop the domestic strategic and critical materials industrial base, including by—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD6B52AA063BF409A8824AA8F02D2DA59"><enum>(1)</enum><text>making loans to domestic producers of strategic and critical materials in accordance with subsection (c) for the purposes of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7805CFF2D8C34A7E80BF0A80C43A44B8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>constructing, upgrading, and operating facilities inside the United States for the smelting, sintering, leaching, processing, separation, beneficiation, or production of strategic and critical materials; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC533457BFA5A445BA7735F290A141A97"><enum>(B)</enum><text>developing new technologies for the more efficient smelting, sintering, leaching, processing, separation, beneficiation, or production of strategic and critical materials; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F0FC8D1F4194665A76844C7E7BEC75B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reimbursing original equipment manufacturers in accordance with subsection (d).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H22AA1940FF28423981DBC82080551EB2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Loans to domestic producers</header> <paragraph id="HAB5E33562FF84CC98AE3F5F9FFDF5520"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts from the Fund may be used to make loans to domestic producers of strategic and critical materials for the purposes described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (b)(1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H26E27292620840E88F063AEC2D27BDF0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A domestic producer of strategic and critical materials shall not be eligible to receive a loan from the Fund if such producer—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H491EF3FCADCD4C85944FDBAF50C6B930"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is carrying out an activity described in subsection (f);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB121E11105B40E28524B3D7BD9C6C7C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has a history of financial insolvency or bankruptcy; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E35B07BDB424F169437500825DE4446"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is controlled by or acting on behalf of the People’s Republic of China or the Russian Federation.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6E0CE0E7BA047F7BB223986BF40F530"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Loan terms</header> <subparagraph id="H9DA73CF18F9143A79A3F74D719FF12D2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Interest</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Interest shall not accrue on any loan made under paragraph (1).</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H090F25EE151A4242BD44132DFD4BE91D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Repayment</header>
 <clause id="HFBE6B885871343E680313C76D07E867E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Repayment required</header><text>Not later than 5 years after receiving a loan under paragraph (1), the recipient of the loan shall repay the full amount of the loan—</text>
 <subclause id="H600B3372221E4B2A89788130C10037C6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to the Fund; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="H75E1D0176F0148EAB4ED0AFCD792EE58"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if the Fund has terminated under subsection (h), to the Treasury of the United States</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HAD659F56EE4F4CE38E0A521BB7F1B98F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>If a recipient does not repay the full amount of the loan in the time period described in clause (i), the recipient—</text>
 <subclause id="H5A9D181D84BB4B1AB197719FB37DCE1D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall not be eligible to receive additional disbursements from the Fund; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HFF0C147B0FD546829D5F35D9C8A1DE17"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall be liable to the United States for the full amount of the loan plus a penalty in an amount equal to 50 percent of the amount of the loan.</text>
							</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7EFD16837B7D40239EE94C1C8A35F173"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Prohibition on transfer to foreign entity</header>
 <clause id="HE8C50EF666874568927481016ADF3AA2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Prohibition on transfer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A recipient of a loan from the Fund shall not transfer to a foreign government or an entity controlled by or acting on behalf of a foreign government, any interest in—</text>
 <subclause id="H2429F043F6A54A84A2B9EC4619F3AF4D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any facilities constructed, upgraded, or operated by the recipient; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="HFCCC04EBD3DC447AA3CDF70F9751C5C3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any new technologies developed by the recipient for the more efficient smelting, sintering, leaching, processing, separation, benefaction, or production of strategic and critical materials.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HD19DE0D7E689432AAC8B76FD8E3B5C3E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>If the recipient of a loan from the Fund makes a transfer prohibited under clause (i), the recipient shall be liable to the United States for the full amount of the loan plus a penalty in an amount equal to 500 percent of the amount of the loan.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC9B6A88283B24333AFE4A47514061929"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reimbursement of original equipment manufacturers</header>
 <paragraph id="HDF617B0059744EB5A5EB4217A932D21B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (2), amounts from the Fund may be used to reimburse original equipment manufacturers for the increased costs that result from such manufacturers purchasing strategic and critical materials produced in the United States from producers that have received disbursements from the Fund.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HBD9F7F4CAB3844C480530C5CA2BE7190"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitations</header>
 <subparagraph id="HCBCAC28ECFDD48F6979212BDAD6D7FAE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Limitation on amounts available for reimbursement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not more than 50 percent of the amounts deposited in the Fund for a fiscal year shall be available for reimbursing original equipment manufacturers under paragraph (1) in such fiscal year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H52721C3426E2464E89AF82C86D3E7170"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation on reimbursement of excessive costs</header><text>Excessive costs, as determined by the senior acquisition executive for the program concerned, shall not be reimbursed under paragraph (1).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4577685756B248F99CBF2285FFF841C7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Deposits to Fund</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HB5FC2569BF89454D89EE7CC91B2F037F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2023, one tenth of one percent of the amounts appropriated for covered programs shall be deposited to the Fund. Such deposits shall be taken from amounts allocated for the internal administration of the covered programs and shall not reduce the quantities of items procured under the programs.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H436294DFF63D4820A95CC5E505F83835"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header>
 <subparagraph id="H78EE3BEFC3514BC8838F15CD4AA09A0B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>The requirement under paragraph (1) shall not apply to a covered program if the prime contractor for such program certifies to the senior acquisition executive concerned that no strategic or critical materials from the People’s Republic of China or the Russian Federation are included in the final item delivered to the Government or in any component thereof.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF9337C931C594F17B36F9CE3CBA13064"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Supporting documents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after a prime contractor makes a certification under subparagraph (A), the senior acquisition executive concerned may require the prime contractor to provide supporting documents verifying that the final item delivered to the Government meets the requirements of such subparagraph.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5012B7F4D3894C7EB9BBAA04990BDA59"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Civil penalty</header><text>A prime contractor who makes a false certification under this paragraph shall be subject to a civil fine of not more than 1 percent of the value of the contract concerned.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H76E1CCE306C44BD18A00DBE0D736B7AF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Prohibited uses of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No amount may be expended from the Fund—</text> <paragraph id="HFF9483DC70214455A70D004CEFBE4A21"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to develop technologies that would decrease the capacity of the domestic industrial base for strategic and critical materials; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC75C5EBEEC9B4197B23350F1A98C6ED2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to redesign technologies to reduce the use of strategic and critical materials in such technologies.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5021E5B6E1754C79996865DC9E9EA18B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HD336042024E24D58BA4819F87AFCB182"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered programs</term> means all major defense acquisition programs (as that term is defined in section 2430 of title 10, United States Code) for the development or procurement of aircraft or missiles.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HADD769D1A67947E7B1A3402676170145"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Original equipment manufacturer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>original equipment manufacturer</term> means a contractor or subcontractor in the supply chain that integrates strategic and critical materials into a component used in a product that is sold to the Federal Government.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB2BEDCAD465C4961B72561A4300CA4D7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Strategic and critical materials</header><text>The term <term>strategic and critical materials</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HB9318F0C73CB45CD8C50A1E83D9B2061"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the lanthanide elements, yttrium, and scandium;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEFDDC08930604C579A111DB1FE343A85"><enum>(B)</enum><text>titanium and titanium alloys;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34181E789ADB4330A204C09C7E550CF1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>magnesium;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD3C18C38772E4651AB6696966037C41C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>antimony;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5DF8B6CFB344D30964791012569BD96"><enum>(E)</enum><text>tungsten;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H595AC86ABB264673B51F2AC80677DEF1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>uranium;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57E238F5A57546959DCDA365041F8234"><enum>(G)</enum><text>tantalum;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB10C3DC742EB4A7DB09BCAC3595E2DB0"><enum>(H)</enum><text>fluorspar;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBED1034912CA43E28E826E8AD24CA18E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>lithium;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA65720193E914110BA3178C8CD903A7D"><enum>(J)</enum><text>strontium;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4208E468E3074381802DFE431F65ECF3"><enum>(K)</enum><text>vanadium;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB74F2F71AAA4FDFA81A694C167D2052"><enum>(L)</enum><text>steel—</text> <clause id="HE5A946A7343245D99ADCC489266A28E4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with a maximum alloy content exceeding one or more of the following limits:</text>
 <subclause id="H5B59074B66D84DBABA32A6508E0966BD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>manganese, 1.65 percent;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HDDD8A155B8514D59A2254C7BB0B8DAE0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>silicon, 0.60 percent; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H22BBC96F7DFF4551BF7123CFD03E1F0E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>copper, 0.60 percent; or</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H1951509E4A3E4471BE7CBB18EDB9755B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>containing more than 0.25 percent of any of the following elements: aluminum, chromium, cobalt, columbium, molybdenum, nickel, titanium, tungsten, or vanadium;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5022D9D931F8489B9471DDF82928646F"><enum>(M)</enum><text>zirconium and zirconium base alloys;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A6A785CFBC6484FA11278ACE2D523A5"><enum>(N)</enum><text>metal alloys consisting of nickel, iron-nickel, and cobalt base alloys containing a total of other alloying metals (except iron) in excess of 10 percent;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDFD1D8F1341F4AB0853F6381453F2176"><enum>(O)</enum><text>thorium; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68100E5335044DFF91C35E47D9049B1E"><enum>(P)</enum><text>any other materials determined to be materials critical to national security by the Strategic Materials Protection Board established under section 187 of title 10, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H370738EBEF2043DD832BF964169F34D2"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The Fund shall terminate on September 30, 2023, and any amounts remaining in the Fund on such date shall be deposited in the Treasury of the United States.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HA9C42C9ACA80425E93AB43476ACC363C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Nuclear reactors assessment</header>
 <subsection id="H667A59B6E2B64F50BEBE864F53BDAD41"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Finding</header><text>Congress finds that section 1012 of the National Defense Authorization Act for 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/181">Public Law 110–181</external-xref>; 122 Stat. 303) required that the United States construct all major combatant vessels of the strike forces of the Navy with integrated nuclear power systems.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H60E3047B47B14221953B0E459F8E1914"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text>The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, shall assess the ability of thorium-fueled nuclear reactors to meet the power generation needs of the Navy.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H33B8B65761024D129AB7280FD8706BB3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The assessment under subsection (b) shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H6FA086CC226C41989F0F4B5C69C5A6C7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an identification of the benefits to naval operations of incorporating thorium-liquid-fueled nuclear reactors or uranium reactors into a range of naval vessels (including major surface combatants and conventionally fueled ships), including identification of any such benefits with respect to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7E665B0268E4433795C4658C13F0AF3E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>fuel cycle, from mining of fuel to disposal of fuel waste;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49EC3682807A4CBEABC43C583EAF348F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>security of the fuel supply;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1573EBB44FEF4274B43987A0959D1132"><enum>(C)</enum><text>power needs for advanced weapons and sensors;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H870A79A03B3C4811901D5D359D55D7AC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>safety and operations, waste handling and disposal, and proliferation issues compared to uranium reactors;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7135415B1AA4C5386527D5E4B052C6D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>refueling and logistics;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D7FA8701C4F4AFC8901DC0897FEB536"><enum>(F)</enum><text>ship upgrades and retrofitting;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F1ADB8784A84FBA830FCA3F14A9CB63"><enum>(G)</enum><text>manning levels;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4AE32049475B44A2844D104E0AB12435"><enum>(H)</enum><text>global range at flank speed, greater forward presence, and extended combat operations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H209D89FF8E584DB2B4C1477226BC244D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>power for advanced sensors and weapons, including electromagnetic guns and lasers;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H362DA6F7AE634BB7AA2BA32950E2FD52"><enum>(J)</enum><text>survivability due to increased performance and reduced signatures;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F8ED0681D884416958D8BBD1943E586"><enum>(K)</enum><text>high-power density propulsion;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7F5902D05FC4DC6BDCB2C77725AAB56"><enum>(L)</enum><text>operational tempo;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC993C53412B44F38832BF7FE64C748BC"><enum>(M)</enum><text>operational effectiveness; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0686F81AD9B4D149490E580955B74AD"><enum>(N)</enum><text>estimated cost effectiveness; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H44CEFAD4EAD545AF95E542FC21344201"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an analysis of the domestic supply chain of thorium, including a description of—</text> <subparagraph id="HD22806E294674B9798265939FFBB78AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>domestic reserves;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6292C00368AB49568D994088D6F81826"><enum>(B)</enum><text>operational mines;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3C2198D3E814977A5244DC89DFDDBA7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>separation and refinement capabilities; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H428F16143EC243FCB99184B602E4A954"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the ability for the domestic supply chain to meet the requirements of the Department of Defense for thorium.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H23EA32FA737043E09FF164C48AA83BDA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Submission to Congress</header><text>Not later than December 31, 2020, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the results of the assessment under subsection (b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H627C52C5A0344E8D97CCFBADE0498A27"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Congressional defense committees defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>congressional defense committees</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101(a)(16) of title 10, United States Code.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H6A999F34EDE442F2A32D5BA19EF13BB0"><enum>5.</enum><header>Limitation on ammonium perchlorate from foreign sources</header> <subsection id="H72DFE565D4334969BFFCCCC38A19748B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Beginning not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall ensure that any covered ammonium perchlorate is obtained from sources inside the United States.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HDA8AAE3FA823443B92DE64C54A30F092"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered ammonium perchlorate</header>
 <paragraph id="HB2E9E3DAA66A453E9B37FE4CF96E2F7C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the term <term>covered ammonium perchlorate</term> means any ammonium perchlorate (or any sodium perchlorate used as a precursor to ammonium perchlorate) that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCC484C2C2AED42DF8767E1D3E6948295"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is incorporated into any item procured by the Department of Defense; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6871F33F6394422D9A6CB9CDF11B496B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is used to launch a national security payload into space.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CDAA4EB65D44195BD7CF92FB80811C6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term does not include ammonium perchlorate obtained from sources outside the United States for use in an air-to-air missile program and qualified for such use as of the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA4C747CF3DAD496E9A8CF4DB0F49FE07"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The Secretary of Defense may waive the limitation in subsection (a) if the Secretary makes a determination in writing that obtaining covered ammonium perchlorate from sources outside the United States is in the national security interests of the United States.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H6F866F3B7356458FBB2519C579C94FFC"><enum>6.</enum><header>Prohibition on sale of domestic rare earth mines</header>
 <subsection id="H1ADEEEE930BB44D190CF45ABF1E197F1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States shall not approve any foreign government-controlled transaction relating to a domestic rare earth facility if a party to such transaction is controlled by or acting on behalf of—</text>
 <paragraph id="H37DFD382E0C64DF08367639E30861DBC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the People’s Republic of China; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H188D600E126E4EE884ED2CED79D6BEFC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Russian Federation.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCBBB4E0EAD1D45F0BB2F5F94396470E8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before approving a foreign government-controlled transaction relating to a domestic rare earth facility, the Committee shall submit to Congress a written certification that the transaction—</text>
 <paragraph id="H159F998E41C9459791B6B6C5A7753F85"><enum>(1)</enum><text>does not violate the prohibition under subsection (a); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA356D43A2BB948FAB17EB90118ADB001"><enum>(2)</enum><text>will not compromise the national security of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4DC1816968474216B85AF7E9A65A02C7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H1027647F24DD4F06A39A42C56C38017A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States</term> means the committee established under section 721(k) of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4565">50 U.S.C. 4565(k)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6C6E162E284F49BA9C12DFA54BFD3C04"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>domestic rare earth facility</term> means any facility inside the United States at which rare earth elements are mined, produced, or processed, regardless of whether such facility is operational.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE7BAB39EFE1548029D457B94CCAF3DFA"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>foreign government-controlled transaction</term> has the meaning given the term in section 721(a) of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4565">50 U.S.C. 4565(a)</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


