<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H45E04FF45CCC4648AEC1B142DB43276F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><form><distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1152</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170216">February 16, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000576">Mr. Ruppersberger</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To eliminate the sunset date for the Veterans Choice Program of the Department of Veterans Affairs, to expand eligibility for such program, and to extend certain operating hours for pharmacies and medical facilities of the Department, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1561AE0BD85342A4819D8E19EC65087E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H05EC15E21B244FD8AA4F967589D05B75" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Care Veterans Deserve Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HBD191747F880490A9ED09C220EE802D8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Expansion of Veterans Choice Program</header> <subsection id="HAF461991A5FB466A8F70AB46FD231501"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Elimination of sunset</header> <paragraph id="H5A7D4035A2B1434FB90AC0911762007B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 101 of the Veterans Access, Choice, and Accountability Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/146">Public Law 113–146</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/1701">38 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
<subparagraph id="HB6D49008106342D1B7C9F93C5991E15C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking subsection (p); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5257328B967B4B098CC4F9A2AC5F8DFF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (q), (r), (s), and (t) as subsections (p), (q), (r), and (s), respectively.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H34A870BC64A249C3B095B02A97EE3D86"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Such section is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HB0244EB9C8E140CF81BC661298FE737E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (i)(2), by striking <quote>during the period in which the Secretary is authorized to carry out this section pursuant to subsection (p)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4D75047E1E394DAF96E83C2D44B2A3D3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (p)(2), as redesignated by paragraph (1)(B), by striking subparagraph (F).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE64EFD2CE0484F3E8627CF9483D49FB2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Expansion of eligibility for program</header> <paragraph id="H5DE67E6D28174075B9A9D9C3C4F6934D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subsection (b)(2) of such section is amended—</text>
<subparagraph id="H3C1E910986D6484B928180B2053F1F0F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)(ii), by striking <quote>or</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H26B5680D9ADB43148AE580A4815B7AF2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D)(ii)(II), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H023C2CDDAFBF45089E9F5D462024B2D8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block id="H68709D797CFC468B909A8BE18E8705D6" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HF3D0B21724834A9097836ADF7DB22193"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has a service-connected disability rated at 50 percent or more.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE65F295B9202462086ED881ADE4F815C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Subsection (g)(3) of such section is amended by striking <quote>or (D)</quote> and inserting <quote>, (D), or (E)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H807979FB661240A0BC53BB078D8AEA46"><enum>3.</enum><header>Access of veterans to walk-in clinics</header> <subsection id="H3FA90DD740A54BBDBD81B39597BAC339"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/17">chapter 17</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/1703">section 1703</external-xref> the following new section:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H40517AC02BBF41B7BE4BEEE58664DF16" style="USC">
<section id="HF38A44D4EA0545BA95498A0B7CA3A6FF"><enum>1703A.</enum><header>Hospital care and medical services at walk-in clinics</header>
<subsection id="H5CE4327E78DC4001A522AAA832BEE87B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall enter into a contract with a national chain of walk-in clinics to provide the hospital care and medical services offered in such clinics to veterans enrolled in the system of annual patient enrollment established and operated under section 1705 of this title.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5AB5880A37624F12B1200B6321F420F5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No authorization or copayment required</header><text>In receiving hospital care or medical services at a walk-in clinic under subsection (a), a veteran is not required—</text>
<paragraph id="H32E48ABA85034B1D8A3F0D60667AA129"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to obtain authorization before receiving such care or services at the clinic; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFB7D93268CEA443C8E3D8A07184BFDC6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to pay a copayment to the clinic or the Department in connection with the receipt of such care or services.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H7B2B3D5201AA452DA2C49C7A5BF1AB44"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Locations</header><text>The Secretary may not require a national chain of walk-in clinics to expand their locations as a condition of a contract entered into under subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE433ABC8EA5B40B9B343A0CF609BF457"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Transmittal of information</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE54EC2DC439645A69E2A220361ED03D7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The national chain of walk-in clinics with which the Secretary has entered into a contract under subsection (a) shall establish an automated system that transmits to the Secretary on a weekly basis information regarding the hospital care or medical services provided to veterans under this section during such week.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2F4D8D417EA0479A8DE630A58DD20902" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The automated system under paragraph (1) shall be established in a manner that allows the system to securely transmit information to the electronic health record of a veteran regarding the hospital care and medical services provided to the veteran under this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1ED1F5B0F64C4A338A772C9A76A15E33" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Transmittal of information under paragraph (1) may not be required as a condition of payment for hospital care or medical services provided under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="H3C1A26B728134A75AF11B0154E324E27"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 17 of such title is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 1703 the following new item:</text> <quoted-block id="HCBDC4AB5E4904F48A10187F883558287" style="USC"> <toc> <toc-entry idref="HF38A44D4EA0545BA95498A0B7CA3A6FF" level="section">1703A. Hospital care and medical services at walk-in clinics.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="HA1CCB1EB1049480C9872427ED4F4AAD3"><enum>4.</enum><header>Licensure of health care professionals of the Department of Veterans Affairs providing treatment via telemedicine</header> <subsection id="H8E3BE785F1394C348BC3D037E61BBDCD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/17">chapter 17</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/1730A">section 1730A</external-xref> the following new section:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H32525DD41DB94C698A86486539500CC1" style="USC">
<section id="H82E14575F2C94E05BF8D3133B1417CAA"><enum>1730B.</enum><header>Licensure of health care professionals providing treatment via telemedicine</header>
<subsection id="H8356208AC0E44C2AA24529E6A85BE02C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any provision of law regarding the licensure of health care professionals, a covered health care professional may practice the health care profession of the health care professional at any location in any State, regardless of where such health care professional or the patient is located, if the health care professional is using telemedicine to provide treatment to an individual under this chapter.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H252D72DF5BDF496690FC7EB7F4C317BB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Location of care</header><text>Subsection (a) shall apply to a covered health care professional providing treatment to a patient regardless of whether such health care professional or patient is located in a facility owned by the Federal Government during such treatment.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8F137ACE7AAC4C449CA5288448CB2E79"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section may be construed to remove, limit, or otherwise affect any obligation of a covered health care professional under the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/801">21 U.S.C. 801</external-xref> et seq.).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H029E07E94CCE4442A493203C614F8388"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="H900DA538D82547E7B97A8D31E8467E9D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>covered health care professional</term> means a health care professional who is—</text> <subparagraph id="HEEBDAFE41FA24CABBFC7FBFCD0AECF79"><enum>(A)</enum><text>authorized by the Secretary to provide health care under this chapter, including a private health care professional who provides such care under a contract or agreement entered into with the Secretary, including a contract entered into under section 1703 of this title; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDD04D2806A5143D996E1A5F67AA3B645"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">licensed, registered, or certified in a State to practice the health care profession of the health care professional.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE27C4A6B6C0042239B649808E5D3FADD"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>telemedicine</term> means the use of telecommunication technology and information technology to provide health care or support the provision of health care in situations in which the patient and health care professional are separated by geographic distance.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="H6726E30CAC314A539D2B12A053100456"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 17 of such title is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 1730A the following new item:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H888BC71030F745C39D36075FDC7AF2E5" style="USC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">1730B. Licensure of health care professionals providing treatment via telemedicine.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H51B6D03C40B34351968B5D484FA622C0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report on telemedicine</header> <paragraph id="HB3ABBC78260744E4A84E7095152D1E77"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the effectiveness of the use of telemedicine by the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6CC49D331EFD42A4AC6AB7D59FF14579"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall include an assessment of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H35F03C3DC6574EFDAB4BBCF6C75F73D1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The satisfaction of veterans with telemedicine furnished by the Department.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8E51420F525E4375B942D83842F53710"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The satisfaction of health care providers in providing telemedicine furnished by the Department.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCE56CA7CBB3B427C9C73EC684C9A5CB6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The effect of telemedicine furnished by the Department on the following:</text>
<clause id="H9B2F9F52CBC8490FBD86B4F40A38DF20"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The ability of veterans to access health care, whether from the Department or from non-Department health care providers.</text></clause> <clause id="H122CFCE2091B48B2BA0D03ADD72B42BB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The frequency of use by veterans of telemedicine.</text></clause>
<clause id="H20FA3830ED2C4B1DAD661FDC6E78A322"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The productivity of health care providers.</text></clause> <clause id="H76DBB4865A18485BA8793E12E81934B2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Wait times for an appointment for the receipt of health care from the Department.</text></clause>
<clause id="H39CDDBBCFD3A45FFA046F689478CCC8B"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The reduction, if any, in the use by veterans of services at Department facilities and non-Department facilities.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6EA7FC318DB1499D91D5EF966C469AD7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The types of appointments for the receipt of telemedicine furnished by the Department that were provided during the one-year period preceding the submittal of the report.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H750B210A5527463B860293BEDC78E9F0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The number of appointments for the receipt of telemedicine furnished by the Department that were requested during such period, disaggregated by Veterans Integrated Service Network.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD79939440480402F93FB54B38F54AA82"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Savings by the Department, if any, including travel costs, of furnishing health care through the use of telemedicine during such period.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB13A35BCB9B94BD5B870932752110139"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Telemedicine defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>telemedicine</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1730B(d)(2) of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H8CBC5CC22B414A618AC8D7E5DBD88D8B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Extension of operating hours for pharmacies and medical facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs</header> <subsection id="HF5F19EE12BC54DF4801DB4E9CA9646E7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Extension of operating hours for pharmacies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall extend the operating hours for each pharmacy of the Department of Veterans Affairs during which the pharmacy offers services comparable to retail pharmacies to include—</text>
<paragraph id="H7890D9AD36524A749D242D02526F27DF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>operation on Saturday, Sunday, and Federal holidays; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H596BD32F882C410B94EE4E5FB9910B84"><enum>(2)</enum><text>operation until 8:00 p.m. on weekdays that are not Federal holidays.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H3684C383DA7944228E1FB58D55D0B92B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contracts with providers during nights and weekends</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall enter into contracts, including through locum tenens arrangements, with physicians and nurses that meet qualifications set forth by the Secretary for purposes of this section under which such physicians and nurses work at medical facilities of the Department during nights and weekends.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8D99E07C821346C28BBE6265C01D1068"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Support staff</header><text>The Secretary may obtain additional support staff as necessary to carry out this section, including by hiring employees or contracting for services.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H3926BA49225941958B7E2F80835E9102"><enum>6.</enum><header>Conduct of best-practices peer review of each medical center of the Department of Veterans Affairs</header>
<subsection id="HA4F6AB3193404B6BB2FA60C7BC86CE76"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs may provide for the conduct by a nongovernmental hospital organization of a best-practices peer review of each medical center of the Department of Veterans Affairs to evaluate the efficacy of health care delivered at each such medical center.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H376849CFA5834A92B21CF4AD8F345437"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>The Secretary shall give priority for peer review conducted under subsection (a) to the medical centers of the Department with the longest wait times for an appointment or the worst health outcomes, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

