<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD2AF238732C4464A9F2B570276D6416C" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2921 RH: National Forest System Vegetation Management Pilot Program Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
		<calendar display="yes">Union  Calendar No. 261</calendar>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2921</legis-num>
		<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 115–357, Part I]</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20170615">June 15, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001096">Mr. Cramer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001077">Mr. Coffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000258">Mr. Peterson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001297">Mr. Buck</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000593">Mr. Perlmutter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000470">Mr. Tipton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name>, and in addition to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<action><action-date>October 19, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsor: <cosponsor name-id="W000799">Mr. Walz</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action>
			<action-date>October 19, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<action><action-date>October 19, 2017</action-date><action-desc>The <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to
			 be printed</action-desc></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To establish a vegetation management pilot program on National Forest System land to better protect
			 utility infrastructure from passing wildfire, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HAB27A3DD0B334953A470463E25B6CB4E" style="OLC">
 <section id="HC16817C35DB14D378A87A10E12BA6B37" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Forest System Vegetation Management Pilot Program Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H9EEDB0A2A78B47BE8E5AB22795A4D5AF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Utility infrastructure rights-of-way vegetation management pilot program</header> <subsection id="H4B856B4820A8428784DAA70A76E895CD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Pilot program required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To encourage owners or operators of rights-of-way on National Forest System land to partner with the Forest Service to voluntarily perform vegetation management on a proactive basis to better protect utility infrastructure from potential passing wildfires, the Secretary shall conduct a limited, voluntary pilot program, in the manner described in this section, to permit vegetation management projects on National Forest System land adjacent to or near such rights-of-way.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB592FA76E57A4FF9BBA934096B5367FB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible participants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A participant in the pilot program must have a right-of-way on National Forest System land. In selecting participants, the Secretary shall give priority to holders of a right-of-way who have worked with Forest Service fire scientists and used technologies, such as Light Detection and Ranging surveys, to improve utility infrastructure protection prescriptions.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF0CED7819FC04C199D7CD4310EBE65E5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Project elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A vegetation management project under the pilot program involves limited and selective vegetation management activities, which—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB0398ED016C647588A8F66CA44C4A1F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall create the least amount of disturbance reasonably necessary to protect utility infrastructure from passing wildfires based on applicable models, including Forest Service fuel models;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H157E193A42FF49E0A351F9643F69FD75"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may include thinning, fuel reduction, creation and treatment of shaded fuel breaks, and other measures as appropriate;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE51D22FF5AAD400AAE9131C7121BDA01"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall only take place adjacent to the participant’s right-of-way or within 75 feet of the participant’s right-of-way;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H02C77A6ADCE040BCB04735A582C76B7C"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall not take place in any designated wilderness area, wilderness study area, or inventoried roadless area; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H59556F1245A14E04A95A8A4FBDBC1782"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be subject to approval by the Forest Service in accordance with this Act.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF6F06F543D744FFDB2304037DC055930"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Project costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A participant in the pilot program shall be responsible for all costs, as determined by the Secretary, incurred in participating in the pilot program, unless the Secretary determines that it is in the public interest for the Forest Service to contribute funds for a vegetation management project conducted under the pilot program.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H54F66131C90B4A65ADE56874E948DA08"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Liability</header>
 <paragraph id="H39187E44E64647E79806FC45AEEBDA45"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Participation in the pilot program does not affect any existing legal obligations or liability standards that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB3396CAA88BB46179EB5EFF452E06C58"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">arise under the right-of-way for activities in the right-of-way; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE21BDC5A5F0F42CBA5595F846A770E33"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">apply to fires resulting from causes other than activities conducted pursuant to an approved vegetation management project.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1728D190B58244C0BFE1990660DAEBAF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Project work</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A participant shall not be liable to the United States for damage proximately caused by activities conducted pursuant to an approved vegetation management project unless—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF22B3C04C8AA4AE7AEC232823A2E381D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such activities were carried out in a manner that was grossly negligent or that violated criminal law; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF38B13D18314E3DA029FA56496CB49C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the damage was caused by the failure of the participant to comply with specific safety requirements expressly imposed by the Forest Service as a condition of participating in the pilot program.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1E29A058E171448789249769224560B2"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall utilize existing laws and regulations in the conduct of the pilot program and, in order to implement the pilot program in an efficient and expeditious manner, may waive or modify specific provisions of the Federal Acquisition Regulation, including modifications to allow for formation of contracts or agreements on a noncompetitive basis.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF4EC95ECAB1C43388A05D2A3B27953E9"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Treatment of proceeds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may—</text> <paragraph id="H0C2AFF65856E4910A2BD0B9A881382F1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">retain any funds provided to the Forest Service by a participant in the pilot program; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4BF3B974E44F4214804D8ECC5DD44623"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use such funds, in such amounts as may be appropriated, in the conduct of the pilot program.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H50BB06441F304189A64AAF45475EACCA"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
 <paragraph id="H939EA920FE3B47678AE8C5136AEF06BF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>National Forest System land</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>National Forest System land</quote> means land within the National Forest System, as defined in section 11(a) of the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1609">16 U.S.C. 1609(a)</external-xref>) exclusive of the National Grasslands and land utilization projects designated as National Grasslands administered pursuant to the Act of July 22, 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1010">7 U.S.C. 1010–1012</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF98F36E503234F199BA2751810EB6CA9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Passing wildfire</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>passing wildfire</quote> means a wildfire that originates outside the right-of-way.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3C11FA7DD34F484DBA67E7B3C291D48A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Right-of-way</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>right-of-way</quote> means a special use authorization issued by the Forest Service allowing the placement of utility infrastructure.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4BC8DA8D7DE14718AD28EAC9B4BB59C1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Agriculture.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2B788EA66C77411580B284F891D3DFE7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Utility infrastructure</header><text>The term <quote>utility infrastructure</quote> means electric transmission lines, natural gas infrastructure, or related structures.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2CCC048F1844482A87DB4F84DE893EE7"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Duration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority to conduct the pilot program, and any vegetation management project under the pilot program, expires December 21, 2027.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF27B78D91EDF4204A0762B8F7D9B3F6A"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than December 31, 2019, and every two years thereafter, the Secretary shall issue a report to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate, the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate, the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives on the status of the program and any projects established under this section.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
	<endorsement display="yes">
		<action-date>October 19, 2017</action-date>
		<action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc><action-date>October 19, 2017</action-date><action-desc>The <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to
			 be printed</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill>


