<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC86E69C946694E3389D2B4B969C0C64F" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3602 IH: Real Education for Healthy Youth Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3602</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170728">July 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001166">Mr. McNerney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000602">Miss Rice of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000371">Mr. Aguilar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000486">Ms. Roybal-Allard</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000390">Mr. Kihuen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000523">Mr. Price of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001150">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001050">Ms. Hanabusa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000287">Mr. Lewis of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000248">Mr. Serrano</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the overall health and well-being of young people, including the promotion of
			 lifelong sexual health and healthy relationships, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H53BB87C20353447B818F21429EB89B8B" style="OLC">
 <section id="H5F79E6736BE249409B30781EEFE40A7C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Real Education for Healthy Youth Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H35077236FFD34A1C9F36D71E7952FD48"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purposes; finding; sense of Congress</header> <subsection id="HECFB16A4F23E4B2D8FFA20411D9947A4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this Act are to provide young people with comprehensive sex education programs that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H3DE05688127E4726B4500606DBF7108A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promote and uphold the rights of young people to information in order to make healthy decisions about their sexual health;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H41C62E4539384EDE863E1D1A758FEA2D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide the information and skills all young people need to make informed, responsible, and healthy decisions in order to become sexually healthy adults and have healthy relationships;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4D4E44CAFF3A4EC29A042741FD080409"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide information about the prevention of unintended pregnancy, sexually transmitted infections, including HIV, dating violence, sexual assault, bullying, and harassment; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE706DA4038EB49F3B8ED7B66352048BB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide resources and information on topics ranging from gender stereotyping and gender roles and stigma and socio-cultural influences surrounding sex and sexuality.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1DF2E44C0A0246129A8062725B5E1368"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Finding on required resources</header><text>In order to provide the comprehensive sex education described in subsection (a), Congress finds that increased resources are required for sex education programs that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7F35931A3B63455F861B68B5825B46BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>substantially incorporate elements of evidence-based programs or characteristics of effective programs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H233772A8CC2641C68765613B2A1B0651"><enum>(2)</enum><text>cover a broad range of topics, including medically accurate and complete information that is age and developmentally appropriate about all the aspects of sex, sexual health, and sexuality;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8E3A78FF49C94986B66DBDEAC1E6DAEB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>are gender and gender identity-sensitive, emphasizing the importance of equality and the social environment for achieving sexual and reproductive health and overall well-being;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAA327BACAD3D4845B1352F460CE1161A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>promote educational achievement, critical thinking, decisionmaking, self-esteem, and self-efficacy;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H11D86A4C05034D62AA072930D6E6FE22"><enum>(5)</enum><text>help develop healthy attitudes and insights necessary for understanding relationships between oneself and others and society;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE22C72C0A30C4BF6B213B375AD57577C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>foster leadership skills and community engagement by—</text> <subparagraph id="H1042BCE7F3D9420A97686D2323A9D195"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promoting principles of fairness, human dignity, and respect; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE99CC98E93B74C27B4E7ED6549316BD0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>engaging young people as partners in their communities; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D18D4FDFD02462690D91CCC846D261F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>are culturally and linguistically appropriate, reflecting the diverse circumstances and realities of young people.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE408CFD358C34EE49711B9269CE1B5A8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="HBE41D6EB08BD49ACBB83F5D90F0F7E8B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>federally funded sex education programs should aim to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7A54B797A9B849DCB997543B89856676"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide information about a range of human sexuality topics, including—</text> <clause id="HA7027A0141FD4002A01CC84D54996E37"><enum>(i)</enum><text>human development, healthy relationships, personal skills;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA08250CAF628423DA19DF97D6C26E059"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>sexual behavior including abstinence;</text> </clause><clause id="H13EDDCBE80DC40C8B07CFD1EC88AA7E4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>sexual health including preventing unintended pregnancy;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8656CD3CC72D4F9FAD61DA919878E953"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>sexually transmitted infections including HIV; and</text> </clause><clause id="HE8B7E4B4F53A4C00B38834EBA5B3AD33"><enum>(v)</enum><text>society and culture;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D6A069A673B4A3EB677449C66BBA296"><enum>(B)</enum><text>promote safe and healthy relationships;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HACAFC25F1D7940149568B7F8159E02C4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>promote gender equity;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6271F4BD00E84EC7B158A25D45321B49"><enum>(D)</enum><text>use, and be informed by, the best scientific information available;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D158A2A5B2D41F8AB2A920D3E07E3EB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>be culturally appropriate and inclusive of youth with varying gender identities, gender expressions, and sexual orientations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H839EBBE609A644CA82F27FF523BE138A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>be built on characteristics of effective programs;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H361FA0D8979D44ADB80CEDFB3A7644C3"><enum>(G)</enum><text>expand the existing body of research on comprehensive sex education programs through program evaluation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A7FB78CE9704A45B8A1D98C95FE0FFF"><enum>(H)</enum><text>expand training programs for teachers of comprehensive sex education;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H320D0971E8134E30A33E0F03C970D597"><enum>(I)</enum><text>build on programs funded under section 513 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/713">42 U.S.C. 713</external-xref>) and the Office of Adolescent Health’s Teen Pregnancy Prevention Program, funded under title II of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/117">Public Law 111–117</external-xref>; 123 Stat. 3253), and on programs supported through the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6FE91AF3C2294EEE82B5A159FB00EBB0"><enum>(J)</enum><text>promote and uphold the rights of young people to information in order to make healthy and autonomous decisions about their sexual health; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9AF1568E3FA342D69FB6FEDC0B3C494F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>no Federal funds should be used for health education programs that—</text> <subparagraph id="HA31419AFA377423883EDF79BDC3BCDB8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>withhold health-promoting or life-saving information about sexuality-related topics, including HIV;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4DE708635CF461A9D30EC2100817FB8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are medically inaccurate or have been scientifically shown to be ineffective;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A5EB79974984BDB993613C259C2A276"><enum>(C)</enum><text>promote gender or racial stereotypes;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H212740575DD6498FB961187731397C2F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>are insensitive and unresponsive to the needs of sexually active young people;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H200A2536A40141B7BDE29F49E6F5A849"><enum>(E)</enum><text>are insensitive and unresponsive to the needs of survivors of sexual violence;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66258F6966E149EEABA91F2D0B680998"><enum>(F)</enum><text>are insensitive and unresponsive to the needs of youth of all physical, developmental, and mental abilities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8186B9F099FC4BD8BE84AAD9D3B557C0"><enum>(G)</enum><text>are insensitive and unresponsive to the needs of youth with varying gender identities, gender expressions, and sexual orientations; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BFEDFA658AC4341948D69E3E3C344F7"><enum>(H)</enum><text>are inconsistent with the ethical imperatives of medicine and public health.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8F366E82EA0249CC9CE91B72288D3C89"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grants for comprehensive sex education for adolescents</header> <subsection id="HACE344A16D7A48A690B20D357744BD7E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program authorized</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Associate Commissioner of the Family and Youth Services Bureau of the Administration on Children, Youth, and Families of the Department of Health and Human Services, the Director of the Office of Adolescent Health, the Director of the Division of Adolescent and School Health within the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and the Secretary of Education, shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities to enable such eligible entities to carry out programs that provide adolescents with comprehensive sex education, as described in subsection (f).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8027D6565128484784D376B4E6EB6D0A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>Grants awarded under this section shall be for a period of 5 years.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HC6ADFDD536394512945F59FB4B8AD9E6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>eligible entity</quote> means a public or private entity that focuses on adolescent health and education or has experience working with adolescents.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4F22DE59D09944E5AA661A1D662C4F11"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>An eligible entity desiring a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including an assurance to participate in the evaluation described in section 6.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD7AA9711392F40438D1231B79B7FE7AC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities that—</text> <paragraph id="HA72DF48C6FF14FBF9A32D952A2C1C4FE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are State or local public entities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H247036D52FB64E6E8CBDBDBD789A4ACB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>are entities not currently receiving funds under—</text> <subparagraph id="HA42848BB32B34B26BF23DA5625F6B256"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 513 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/713">42 U.S.C. 713</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6883C503C4424672B7A80C1B0752BE6B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Office of Adolescent Health’s Teen Pregnancy Prevention Program, funded under title II of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/117">Public Law 111–117</external-xref>; 123 Stat. 3253), or any substantially similar successive program; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC4C65BFF781448D9282F5A1F1A23992"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention’s Division of Adolescent and School Health; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2932D9354016495E8B9A9018F768DE85"><enum>(3)</enum><text>address health inequities among young people that face systemic barriers resulting in disproportionate rates of not less than one of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8709455F4C1C41D386A719B3BBEFEABA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Unintended pregnancies.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4CB4A8AFFC849258BA811E39AEAB0CD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Sexually transmitted infections, including HIV.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0D1256193E5467EADF5847C1FB1349A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Dating violence and sexual violence.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF360366C1A14474A8EF5CEB07813C8BE"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Use of funds</header> <paragraph id="HC16F7560EBC247C48287C4465CA22D3B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall use the grant funds to carry out an education program that provides adolescents with comprehensive sex education that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBE3D3A281C0544B98A25F40FF4715952"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is age and developmentally appropriate;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H766978B834784FEC9CECD70449DD6EB3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is medically accurate and complete;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2229BC60A4894BD4807EBF2A86257A29"><enum>(C)</enum><text>substantially incorporates elements of evidence-based sex education instruction; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2596E9AC84604D9FA3070E69A4072B07"><enum>(D)</enum><text>creates a demonstration project based on characteristics of effective programs.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7CDCC93D523B4E3F840C84E3F6C84C6E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents of comprehensive sex education programs</header><text>The comprehensive sex education programs funded under this section shall include instruction and materials that address—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB7B717661C3E470AA0D175EA6D9FE202"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the physical, social, and emotional changes of human development including, human anatomy, reproduction, and sexual development;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5662FC75D2D14AE1B466A07C5CB606F4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>healthy relationships, including friendships, within families, and society, that are based on mutual respect, and the ability to distinguish between healthy and unhealthy relationships, including—</text>
 <clause id="HDD04ECA9E04A4A8E86EB1AF0EFE1A275"><enum>(i)</enum><text>effective communication, negotiation and refusal skills, including the skills to recognize and report inappropriate or abusive sexual advances;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H73451F24323843CBBA4A96BE5D61BD8D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>bodily autonomy, setting and respecting personal boundaries, practicing personal safety, and consent; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD742D5BD114C47BDA1ECD7D7F3A00E2B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the limitations and harm of gender-role stereotypes, violence, coercion, bullying, harassment, and intimidation in relationships;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H116CF4568FAA4D3BB83D7259C11C24BE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>healthy decisionmaking skills about sexuality and relationships that include—</text> <clause id="HCAED5176CB854E7090E08171D9CC416C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>critical thinking, problem solving, self-efficacy, stress-management, self-care, and decisionmaking;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA3121EC0170D48C7A564BC0F04707BF0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>individual values and attitudes;</text> </clause><clause id="H9258C1156EB349A1B4CD06395D3655F8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the promotion of positive body images;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8484D2842BFA4A73BF3DFC850F7DE46F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>developing an understanding that there are a range of body types and encouraging positive feeling about students’ own body types;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9038841A3E394D14A76EDA1402FCA795"><enum>(v)</enum><text>information on how to respect others and ensure safety on the internet and when using other forms of digital communication;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H31FFFDD45BB64C5FAE6FF3BF9E4E2864"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>information on local services and resources where students can obtain additional information related to bullying, harassment, dating violence and sexual assault, suicide prevention, and other related care;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H88F5737D796A4630B809340300BF3E24"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>encouragement for youth to communicate with their parents or guardians, health and social service professionals, and other trusted adults about sexuality and intimate relationships;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0C480E2465A4412D9DF57F1B6D742A05"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>information on how to create a safe environment for all students and others in society;</text> </clause><clause id="H110B065B454048B7A159140E130E9C6D"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>examples of varying types of relationships, couples, and family structures; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC4C5081AA0844B62BF25C2A80F3BF3CA"><enum>(x)</enum><text>affirmative representation of varying gender identities, gender expressions, and sexual orientations, including individuals and relationships between same sex couples and their families;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2320A997C0EC4308A8571C5286CEF01F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>abstinence, delaying age of first sexual activity, the use of condoms, preventive medication, vaccination, birth control, and other sexually transmitted infection prevention measures, and the options for pregnancy, including parenting, adoption, and abortion, including—</text>
 <clause id="H02B597ACFBB140918CCD1CD51E7D5949"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the importance of effectively using condoms, preventive medication, and applicable vaccinations to protect against sexually transmitted infections, including HIV;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5EE7D53AFE6A4804932C040C3B8E950C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the benefits of effective contraceptive and condom use in avoiding unintended pregnancy;</text> </clause><clause id="HDA971E11E0C2487F9C0DC735B95A7B91"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the relationship between substance use and sexual health and behaviors; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAF329312A00E4F918F0DF4F68611C578"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>information about local health services where students can obtain additional information and services related to sexual and reproductive health and other related care;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC46CC00B34FA4F16B0D23AB42D857BBD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>through affirmative recognition, the roles that traditions, values, religion, norms, gender roles, acculturation, family structure, health beliefs, and political power play in how students make decisions that affect their sexual health, using examples of various types of races, ethnicities, cultures, and families, including single-parent households and young families;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB56032D358514514ABF89CE0BE2F15A6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>information about gender identity, gender expression, and sexual orientation for all students, including—</text>
 <clause id="H7F52BC69625744EEA60FEE24DA0CA88D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>affirmative recognition that people have different gender identities, gender expressions, and sexual orientations; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE41F9AF1B07548C386D68B2D179C25CB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>community resources that can provide additional support for individuals with varying gender identities, gender expressions, and sexual orientations; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1AD062DDF5746F1AACDB1A421EF7513"><enum>(G)</enum><text>opportunities to explore the roles that race, ethnicity, immigration status, disability status, economic status, homelessness, foster care status, and language within different communities affect sexual attitudes in society and culture and how this may impact student sexual health.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB0F7A2E8F8F74C2FAA9A460371EB3094"><enum>4.</enum><header>Grants for comprehensive sex education at institutions of higher education</header>
 <subsection id="HDD0BB79AE397495A98FE2970AD4206EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program authorized</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Education, shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to institutions of higher education or consortia of such institutions to enable such institutions to provide young people with comprehensive sex education, described in subsection (e)(2).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H98C798AD0E0D4C279F65881D88815B9B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>Grants awarded under this section shall be for a period of 5 years.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H3218536A536F46D988179974D74E7651"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>An institution of higher education or consortia of such institutions desiring a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including an assurance to participate in the evaluation described in section 6.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC4DC73B4560740CFA1E0F2E933B1A43C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to an institution of higher education that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H109F7679EDBD48DDA10E3411D8ED0846"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has an enrollment of needy students as defined in section 318(b) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059e">20 U.S.C. 1059e(b)</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE955C81658DA457799FFE2DE5A419215"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is a Hispanic-serving institution, as defined in section 502(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1101a">20 U.S.C. 1101a(a)</external-xref>);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA6F4E6E4D7B44C92B355FFC9E67022A8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is a Tribal College or University, as defined in section 316(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059c">20 U.S.C. 1059c(b)</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H24F9EE318AA74FE79EC27D4F098AA00C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>is an Alaska Native-serving institution, as defined in section 317(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059d">20 U.S.C. 1059d(b)</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA42AE3B3FF3B4553B994AE205E00A813"><enum>(5)</enum><text>is a Native Hawaiian-serving institution, as defined in section 317(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059d">20 U.S.C. 1059d(b)</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H807B1B2A88BE47BD81042FEE09FBBEC1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>is a Predominately Black Institution, as defined in section 318(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059e">20 U.S.C. 1059e(b)</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H95339708D0474B80BA24CAD7DFBE69C6"><enum>(7)</enum><text>is a Native American-serving, nontribal institution, as defined in section 319(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059f">20 U.S.C. 1059f(b)</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2B1E6CFC095146018626DB4D7BA32CB8"><enum>(8)</enum><text>is an Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institution, as defined in section 320(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059g">20 U.S.C. 1059g(b)</external-xref>); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA9F738837B004266BC5A702D05039D1C"><enum>(9)</enum><text>is a minority institution, as defined in section 365 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1067k">20 U.S.C. 1067k</external-xref>), with an enrollment of needy students, as defined in section 312 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1058">20 U.S.C. 1058</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCA66CE94B44D4ED8BFC3D8D99BF695A4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Uses of funds</header>
 <paragraph id="HD016AB74611A409888DC2A4B026C01D9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An institution of higher education receiving a grant under this section shall use grant funds to integrate issues relating to comprehensive sex education into institution of higher education in order to reach a large number of students, by carrying out one or more of the following activities:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H327A7EFD25C146329742333134727386"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Developing or adopting educational content for issues relating to comprehensive sex education that will be incorporated into student orientation, general education, or core courses.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8F088CBE7AB4382BB91001D48A5110C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Developing or adopting, and implementing schoolwide educational programming outside of class that delivers elements of comprehensive sex education programs to students, faculty, and staff.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8DF2A08D007467C948BB062D6900F56"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Developing or adopting innovative technology-based approaches to deliver sex education to students, faculty, and staff.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB42E218664BA4E1C9187B986CFE05C96"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Developing or adopting, and implementing peer-outreach and education programs to generate discussion, educate, and raise awareness among students about issues relating to comprehensive sex education.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E1C90863A5547C1B3B46F42ED7139D4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents of sex education programs</header><text>Each institution of higher education’s program of comprehensive sex education funded under this section shall include instruction and materials that address the requirements under section 3(f).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H15444A3A04C34E72A77901EC3EFE816F"><enum>5.</enum><header>Grants for pre-service and in-service teacher training</header>
 <subsection id="HFDB2CD61B3824289816C19CD4D02A4B0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program authorized</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and the Secretary of Education, shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities to enable such eligible entities to carry out the activities described in subsection (e).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDEA7A18BA57A47FCA61FF53698597166"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>Grants awarded under this section shall be for a period of 5 years.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HFD380AB1277C4C3F86A64DCC0D5BBE70"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>eligible entity</quote> means—</text>
 <paragraph id="H569784721F2E44A983936FF6ABDEBFFC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a State educational agency;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF98A0C18A4924E5D92A4CD99EBF4E271"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a local educational agency;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H20F2FA2A7A684AC8BD92F32B9EFA5E91"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a tribe or tribal organization, as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H825752545D8744E5A6A14407370FC2DE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a State or local department of health;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H85DD856B729B4467832AAFB139A431E0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a State or local department of education;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2EB14CBC4DD241B6B5C7F45025F01E12"><enum>(6)</enum><text>an educational service agency;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H842466FA511242CE95F48DD006B72BFF"><enum>(7)</enum><text>a nonprofit institution of higher education;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1391858638A34DC0844C1CC50B9A8825"><enum>(8)</enum><text>a national or statewide nonprofit organization that has as its primary purpose the improvement of provision of comprehensive sex education through training and effective teaching of comprehensive sex education; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5CA242B71284409499BD84E3B749BCD2"><enum>(9)</enum><text>a consortium of nonprofit organizations that has as its primary purpose the improvement of provision of comprehensive sex education through training and effective teaching of comprehensive sex education.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAC5E775B9D074517B6797B590862A8A5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An eligible entity desiring a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including an assurance to participate in the evaluation described in section 6.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HDA7805E0A58B42DD9887F877178FA744"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorized activities</header>
 <paragraph id="H5847E4B563A84DA69633756947251529"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Required activity</header><text>Each eligible entity receiving a grant under this section shall use grant funds for professional development and training of relevant faculty, school administrators, teachers, and staff, in order to increase effective teaching of comprehensive sex education students.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H031F8197CA6B4890A7F11910F521798F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Permissible activities</header><text>Each eligible entity receiving a grant under this section may use grant funds to—</text> <subparagraph id="H9ECB7696B8374FE8A8E6596B3BA0EFFD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide research-based training of teachers for comprehensive sex education for adolescents as a means of broadening student knowledge about issues related to human development, healthy relationships, personal skills, and sexual behavior, including abstinence, sexual health, and society and culture;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75D576B0B6CC41F0A15CFE5360CA9BA1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>support the dissemination of information on effective practices and research findings concerning the teaching of comprehensive sex education;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB952BE6C853D4E14937F34960B4D04F0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>support research on—</text> <clause id="H412EAE63E377494EB4B8A273FDDC931B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>effective comprehensive sex education teaching practices; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6F39A0CC540F4632AD2308D10D39AD6F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the development of assessment instruments and strategies to document—</text> <subclause id="H2326406841FC400899881D2453CF12AD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>student understanding of comprehensive sex education; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD64287541ED348D39493B583439AF4EB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the effects of comprehensive sex education;</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0EB9BE3680C24BF79166F70BBD82F9CE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>convene national conferences on comprehensive sex education, in order to effectively train teachers in the provision of comprehensive sex education; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49724E20B9404983A1663AFA742DBF9C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>develop and disseminate appropriate research-based materials to foster comprehensive sex education.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H774B48D7C96A4FC084ED4A8B71BC9D9B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Subgrants</header><text>Each eligible entity receiving a grant under this section may award subgrants to nonprofit organizations that possess a demonstrated record of providing training to faculty, school administrators, teachers, and staff on comprehensive sex education to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H94C3FD631F3E425C9D84D35B2906F9AA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>train teachers in comprehensive sex education;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H673BC699AD104E1DBE5A40EE828A38D8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>support Internet or distance learning related to comprehensive sex education;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF70E55EF25E9427FB6E8D13CF729951A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>promote rigorous academic standards and assessment techniques to guide and measure student performance in comprehensive sex education;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD7D4913FCB2849C3A427D6ECCF2B8A66"><enum>(D)</enum><text>encourage replication of best practices and model programs to promote comprehensive sex education;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF9665FCCCC9843C18CBB8623F497C133"><enum>(E)</enum><text>develop and disseminate effective, research-based comprehensive sex education learning materials;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFE878E8FCFD461DB19B0101A865B29A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>develop academic courses on the pedagogy of sex education at institutions of higher education; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H07DFFB18A49248D78A905DE178F250D4"><enum>(G)</enum><text>convene State-based conferences to train teachers in comprehensive sex education and to identify strategies for improvement.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE58A5170CD33419AA71346F04322F0EF"><enum>6.</enum><header>Impact evaluation and reporting</header>
			<subsection id="H9AD750A75BF44AD7A37D149D85C6BAEF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Multi-Year evaluation</header>
 <paragraph id="HDCEEF33ACD0A4A36918C6A311312416A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall enter into a contract with a nonprofit organization with experience in conducting impact evaluations, to conduct a multi-year evaluation on the impact of the grants under sections 3, 4, and 5, and to report to Congress and the Secretary on the findings of such evaluation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA6B4DB95ED6748EC88BF08BE3651761E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>The evaluation conducted under this subsection shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H5CAD7E2D83D94EB3B89AB1FAFFF081F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be conducted in a manner consistent with relevant, nationally recognized professional and technical evaluation standards;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H468E4EB590A14787B5340106881B33C2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>use sound statistical methods and techniques relating to the behavioral sciences, including quasi-experimental designs, inferential statistics, and other methodologies and techniques that allow for conclusions to be reached;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H76714B39D84141BE94FC3549FB4D9554"><enum>(C)</enum><text>be carried out by an independent organization that has not received a grant under section 3, 4, or 5; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C0CA8EF26094E3FBA55A6565A576DCA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>be designed to provide information on—</text> <clause id="H5207EFA7AD2249EEB260F47FAEDD2A8C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>output measures, such as the number of individuals served under the grant and the number of hours of instruction;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFACCCAA564CF426BBE3C880E6469A8D9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>outcome measures, including measures relating to—</text> <subclause id="H7DF60115FB0A49F2B7C1BDEB2AC5C20C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the knowledge that individuals participating in the grant program have gained in each of the following age and developmentally appropriate areas—</text>
 <item id="H622206A451EA449D863CCE8FE5EF0425"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>growth and development;</text> </item><item id="HE3A6673C97E740F9A2B446441CEF0A0C"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>relationship dynamics;</text>
 </item><item id="HDD03873C22694853B74839CA51DC7123"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>ways to prevent unintended pregnancy and sexually transmitted infections, including HIV; and</text> </item><item id="HFBD4DB526CB94A6B8A8FD2BB030F4C79"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>sexual health;</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H322E386AAADE44E4A6B82918DF435972"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the age and developmentally appropriate skills that individuals participating in the grant program have gained regarding—</text>
 <item id="H2C0B2CAD63DA4B0EAE1041923B8F728F"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>negotiation and communication;</text> </item><item id="HA4B96E8FFA254631B4842F04E87CB613"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>decisionmaking and goal-setting;</text>
 </item><item id="HEDEE61269E2144C9895B52AF8972B568"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>interpersonal skills and healthy relationships; and</text> </item><item id="HB369F63D8B9646A3BD035AB14DF7D054"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>condom use; and</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H13348CA4DCD04B4DA4C0C82F43FEC14B"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the behaviors of adolescents participating in the grant program, including data about—</text> <item id="H5EB683599547430FB07E97A34C2A7ABF"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>age of first intercourse;</text>
 </item><item id="H2E415B27AEF342F1AF3700D15190CD48"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>condom and contraceptive use at first intercourse;</text> </item><item id="H07DCF119F69B434EA1B2306087EB5B70"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>recent condom and contraceptive use;</text>
 </item><item id="H51D855BE3F2E486CB8F4F3406CC325DD"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>substance use;</text> </item><item id="HD9D91EE8A1B147E0A2DA14C527E8BD8A"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>dating abuse and lifetime history of sexual assault, dating violence, bullying, harassment, stalking; and</text>
 </item><item id="H32A0A876C0F94265864B7DB5FD8170B3"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>academic performance; and</text> </item></subclause></clause><clause id="H929229B7070644C799AD10D9786CD171"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>other measures necessary to evaluate the impact of the grant program.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD26DDEC5765B432B9781BC2F03E83AB9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 6 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the organization conducting the evaluation under this subsection shall prepare and submit to the appropriate committees of Congress and the Secretary an evaluation report. Such report shall be made publicly available, including on the website of the Department of Health and Human Services.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB72BDCDE88264E0B9EADFED897E8783B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Secretary’s report to congress</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for a period of 5 years, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the activities to provide adolescents and young people with comprehensive sex education and pre-service and in-service teacher training funded under this Act. The Secretary’s report to Congress shall include—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB675BC74ADE34ACA8F6A5193A3672257"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a statement of how grants awarded by the Secretary meet the purposes described in section 2(a); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB04F1C885A164420ADAEE38FC59003F8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>information about—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB3791BA4E0FF48D4B3F67F5DD165D5A2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of eligible entities and institutions of higher education that are receiving grant funds under sections 3, 4, and 5;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28757BDC51784A15AF3FCBC00EB0A7D5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the specific activities supported by grant funds awarded under sections 3, 4, and 5;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B7B2AD50DE149098D4ECB0FC6B7F52A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number of adolescents served by grant programs funded under section 3;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9EF78B70B8724AC09F975816BD67B228"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the number of young people served by grant programs funded under section 4;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H44A97537287340389430CFA7DC9B46D3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the number of faculty, school administrators, teachers, and staff trained under section 5; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H497B5AF7289A4E9DB8C4755F6143BEEA"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the status of the evaluation required under subsection (a).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2062204AA0044F8EB7F39831AE29A49A"><enum>7.</enum><header>Nondiscrimination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Programs funded under this Act shall not discriminate on the basis of actual or perceived sex, race, color, ethnicity, national origin, disability, sexual orientation, gender identity, or religion. Nothing in this Act shall be construed to invalidate or limit rights, remedies, procedures, or legal standards available under any other Federal law or any law of a State or a political subdivision of a State, including the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000a">42 U.S.C. 2000a</external-xref> et seq.), title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681</external-xref> et seq.), section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>), the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101</external-xref> et seq.), and section 1557 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18116">42 U.S.C. 18116</external-xref>).</text>
 </section><section id="H16F3265C21B3421798C5E147DAC8B2C9"><enum>8.</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No Federal funds provided under this Act may be used for health education programs that—</text> <paragraph id="H820610C9127F47AFB0EA266EA2DD24E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>withhold health-promoting or life-saving information about sexuality-related topics, including HIV;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD2F58806CA024B2B9DF2B1430D7D0997"><enum>(2)</enum><text>are medically inaccurate or have been scientifically shown to be ineffective;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H08311356B10342B7AA8B16F4DAEEAEB0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>promote gender or racial stereotypes;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H38A0CBF644114EB489B9206645EE554B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>are insensitive and unresponsive to the needs of sexually active young people;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H56FD551DDC594B3596E095EC730F3470"><enum>(5)</enum><text>are insensitive and unresponsive to the needs of pregnant or parenting young people;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H45FA1C1C356A4F1393EED4A11FED14E5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>are insensitive and unresponsive to the needs of survivors of sexual abuse or assault;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H10F85F1757FE498BB1584D023DB28520"><enum>(7)</enum><text>are insensitive and unresponsive to the needs of youth of all physical, developmental, or mental abilities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF0C66CCCF62C40C99A66D151DB6CA4D2"><enum>(8)</enum><text>are insensitive and unresponsive to individuals with varying gender identities, gender expressions, and sexual orientations; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE7B862A896724C8D9DBBB06A3DB2374E"><enum>(9)</enum><text>are inconsistent with the ethical imperatives of medicine and public health.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="HA432238C1D0E428DB5C4D0CB4DDC0754"><enum>9.</enum><header>Amendments to other laws</header> <subsection id="H165DCF428A4E46D68A63ECEA6E5B8159"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendment to the public health service act</header><text>Section 2500 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300ee">42 U.S.C. 300ee</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsections (b) through (d) and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H8654CE66934B4947A79FE3DEBEF7C659" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H4444865D1CB4435ABDEF5BC72AF2FEC8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents of programs</header><text>All programs of education and information receiving funds under this subchapter shall include information about the potential effects of intravenous substance abuse.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2CFF0DC8C06D4AFBB30176A5EE05BF79"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amendments to the elementary and secondary education act of 1965</header><text>Section 8526 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7906">20 U.S.C. 7906</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H8D0C10810A704886931527B90B8D019A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (3);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCAB2E0E4D79941288B53B504BC825F19"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (4) and (5) as paragraphs (3) and (4), respectively;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H36C6BB1A9E434C108D673B1D41BEC55C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by inserting <quote>or</quote> after the semicolon;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5C8D1F14BD4F4E87B603460ADFE4D16B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking <quote>; or</quote> and inserting a period; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD1809FC007D24914A166942DF6D79B1D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (6).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H012FADC22E674070A41A152B9B65F1C1"><enum>10.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HCD2E258A12544C71A8775E6347C687A3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Adolescents</header><text>The term <quote>adolescents</quote> means individuals who are ages 10 through 19 at the time of commencement of participation in a program supported under this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6E4417BF2F37490D8A208AE57A424C0E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Age and developmentally appropriate</header><text>The term <quote>age and developmentally appropriate</quote> means topics, messages, and teaching methods suitable to particular age, age group of children and adolescents, or developmental levels, based on cognitive, emotional, social, and behavioral capacity of most students at that age level.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H806FC544D51346F7A6D85BDF11DB59F7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of congress</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate committees of Congress</quote> means the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA59F516E68E541E99935B1AA6B73E109"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Characteristics of effective programs</header><text>The term <quote>characteristics of effective programs</quote> means the aspects of evidence-based programs, including development, content, and implementation of such programs, that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0B060EA720C347E796186A5EDF2B1A46"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have been shown to be effective in terms of increasing knowledge, clarifying values and attitudes, increasing skills, and impacting upon behavior; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA89E2589967B4D37B1E381429EBEB53F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are widely recognized by leading medical and public health agencies to be effective in changing sexual behaviors that lead to sexually transmitted infections, including HIV, unintended pregnancy, and dating violence and sexual assault among young people.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8E4E062529B4C2ABE4CD67015923AC6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Comprehensive sex education</header><text>The term <quote>comprehensive sex education</quote> means instructional part of a comprehensive school health education approach which addresses the physical, mental, emotional, and social dimensions of human sexuality; designed to motivate and assist students to maintain and improve their sexual health, prevent disease and reduce sexual health-related risk behaviors; and enable and empower students to develop and demonstrate age and developmentally appropriate sexuality and sexual health-related knowledge, attitudes, skills, and practices.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5974481EC94040A5B752A283C56918A0"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Consent</header><text>The term <quote>consent</quote> means affirmative, conscious, and voluntary agreement to engage in interpersonal, physical, or sexual activity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB434CAB63C2247548837137B87DAF6B0"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Culturally appropriate</header><text>The term <quote>culturally appropriate</quote> means materials and instruction that respond to culturally diverse individuals, families and communities in an inclusive, respectful and effective manner; including materials and instruction that are inclusive of race, ethnicity, languages, cultural background, religion, sex, gender identity, sexual orientation, and different abilities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2A95A3FC53E4475AB5FFE9648715836F"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Evidence-based</header><text>The term <quote>evidence-based</quote>, when used with respect to sex education instruction means a sex education program that has been proven through rigorous evaluation to be effective in changing sexual behavior or incorporates elements of other programs that have been proven to be effective in changing sexual behavior.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H322D2D9E6993430488D5ADC887FBB4F0"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Gender expression</header><text>The term <quote>gender expression</quote>, when used with respect to a sex education program, means the expression of one’s gender, such as through behavior, clothing, haircut, or voice, and which may or may not conform to socially defined behaviors and characteristics typically associated with being either masculine or feminine.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA3C4CE145B3A4FB5B4BE0510C6DF6F42"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Gender identity</header><text>Except with respect to section 7, the term <quote>gender identity</quote>, when used with respect to a sex education program, means the gender-related identity, appearance, mannerisms, or other gender-related characteristics of an individual, regardless of the individual’s designated sex at birth including a person’s deeply held sense or knowledge of their own gender; such as male, female, both or neither.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAA4F3A2EE75448558A142C5FDC9483C1"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Inclusive</header><text>The term <quote>inclusive</quote>, when used with respect to a sex education program, means curriculum that ensures that students from historically marginalized communities are reflected in classroom materials and lessons.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA72951F1DA584324AB11DA4E56FD7CCD"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <quote>institution of higher education</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4B1C044F79244F7E9193A632E07A16CA"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Medically accurate and complete</header><text>The term <quote>medically accurate and complete</quote>, when used with respect to a sex education program, means that—</text> <subparagraph id="HCC477E8B753046E389024ED69931EEF9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the information provided through the program is verified or supported by the weight of research conducted in compliance with accepted scientific methods and is published in peer-reviewed journals, where applicable; or</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9D7A9D4AC854FA9B53DF2BBB41FE57E"><enum>(B)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H180ECE38EA64487EA18316DB68415EB6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the program contains information that leading professional organizations and agencies with relevant expertise in the field recognize as accurate, objective, and complete; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7E9B5CE7D0C84DDB90DF32C515DAC749" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the program does not withhold information about the effectiveness and benefits of correct and consistent use of condoms and other contraceptives.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BABC4B75FDE4EC7A056F5A87739B64E"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC875A0124C244FEEA6B55F16E0CE089B"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Sexual development</header><text>The term <quote>sexual development</quote> means the lifelong process of physical, behavioral, cognitive, and emotional growth and change as it relates to an individual’s sexuality and sexual maturation, including puberty, identity development, socio-cultural influences, and sexual behaviors.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H17F5A8B9F39C4D0395346DD09DD5412F"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Sexual orientation</header><text>Except with respect to section 7, the term <quote>sexual orientation</quote>, when used with respect to a sex education program, means an individual’s attraction, including physical or emotional, to the same or different gender.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9F5F437DCD114A2680CF1BE1BF60DF69"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Young people</header><text>The term <quote>young people</quote> means individuals who are ages 10 through 24 at the time of commencement of participation in a program supported under this Act.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H1D737FC09A414368B439295CBDBE5503"><enum>11.</enum><header>Funding</header>
 <subsection id="H9BD136DCDCFC40C097841A5AE6B49EF8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Appropriation</header><text>For the purpose of carrying out this Act, there is appropriated $75,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2022. Amounts appropriated under this subsection shall remain available until expended.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HD635BD09AC044745859FCED65042B2FE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reservations of funds</header>
 <paragraph id="H7897D46281B145FD80067833287994A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary shall reserve 50 percent of the amount appropriated under subsection (a) for the purposes of awarding grants for comprehensive sex education for adolescents under section 3.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H943C299FBE8E47E19084A54BD4C2EE49"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary shall reserve 25 percent of the amount appropriated under subsection (a) for the purposes of awarding grants for comprehensive sex education at institutes of higher education under section 4.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7DC25550A6AE4560A26A85A12B12DC00"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Secretary shall reserve 20 percent of the amount appropriated under subsection (a) for the purposes of awarding grants for pre-service and in-service teacher training under section 5.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF41596B97DDC46518E6E2041131EF604"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Secretary shall reserve 2 percent of the amount appropriated under subsection (a) for the purpose of carrying out the impact evaluation and reporting required under section 6(a).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC7D5C5E946664AFEB08356CE101B9046"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Secretarial responsibilities</header><text>The Secretary shall reserve 3 percent of the amount appropriated under subsection (a) for each fiscal year for expenditures by the Secretary to provide, directly or through a competitive grant process, research, training, and technical assistance, including dissemination of research and information regarding effective and promising practices, providing consultation and resources, and developing resources and materials to support the activities of recipients of grants. In carrying out such functions, the Secretary shall collaborate with a variety of entities that have expertise in adolescent sexual health development, education, and promotion.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0362A254C84A4E6E9C306EF68DEE2DE5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reprogramming of abstinence only until marriage program funding</header><text>The unobligated balance of funds made available to carry out section 510 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/710">42 U.S.C. 710</external-xref>) (as in effect on the day before the date of enactment of this Act) are hereby transferred and shall be used by the Secretary to carry out this Act. The amounts transferred and made available to carry out this Act shall remain available until expended.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBD579AD4EE9346E9A07A61B9FF144AB6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Repeal of abstinence only until marriage program</header><text>Section 510 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/710">42 U.S.C. 710</external-xref> et seq.) is repealed.</text> </subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

