<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H533ECEE943F44829A34A8BED4AB4E5E1" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 164 IH: Increasing Access to Voluntary Screening for HIV/AIDS and STIs Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 164</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170103">January 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for an evidence-based strategy for voluntary screening for HIV/AIDS and other common
			 sexually transmitted infections, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H4386E2A3C2A740E0BF451658DE36FF0F" style="OLC">
		<section id="H0AC2DBD82D5B49A6B743BFCACD64147D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="H29C50710B6094485B4508E10C8FFE756"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Increasing Access to Voluntary Screening for HIV/AIDS and STIs Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HA3BFE2177FCE4EA9B6CD78990F62968C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
					<toc-entry idref="H0AC2DBD82D5B49A6B743BFCACD64147D" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H68636AF5F67743DEB278EA9A399FBC9E" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H553E529CDEAA4D169822DB46201E03B0" level="section">Sec. 3. Purpose.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H802818FA302946E98C198085DA98BAF1" level="section">Sec. 4. Definitions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HB968B9F29A454BEDA13D948313BE7F8F" level="title">Title I—Coverage of HIV/AIDS and STI screening under public health care programs and group health
			 plans; Coverage of care under Medicaid.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HF5B4DD90E78E4885AF0C31EB8559DB4B" level="section">Sec. 101. Coverage of routine HIV/AIDS and STI screening tests under Medicaid.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HA00475CDD90E43BE94C03560E4D69432" level="section">Sec. 102. Coverage of HIV/AIDS and STI screening tests under Medicare.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H266E91804FF84D418EECB3A528657ED6" level="section">Sec. 103. Coverage for routine HIV/AIDS and STI screening under group health plans.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H80271836685442459AA342132041E231" level="section">Sec. 104. Optional Medicaid coverage of low-income HIV/AIDS infected individuals.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H260FAECFA50D4E40A78EF37D4302BC3C" level="title">Title II—Increased data collection and education for historically underrepresented populations</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H25E9FC3ABA9245AB8B67E469D75010B5" level="section">Sec. 201. People living with disabilities.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H0B18D21F30554DE99B0E6DBF786CDD7D" level="section">Sec. 202. Women who have sex with women.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H5D4BE9F80F4C470081D58213427ED9A4" level="section">Sec. 203. Transgender community.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HE5A65768491549099A17E4E5B2BFEE0E" level="section">Sec. 204. Report.</toc-entry></toc>
 </subsection></section><section id="H68636AF5F67743DEB278EA9A399FBC9E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="HCCAEBA866C0B40D6BC6FF994A61F8D59"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The CDC estimates 20,000,000 new sexually transmitted infections (STIs) occur each year in the United States, and 50 percent of sexually active Americans will contract a STI at some point in their lives, the majority of which may be asymptomatic for an extended amount of time.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF296D1805BAC45F6B28E68827DF64BB2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Over 1,200,000 people in the United States are living with HIV, and someone is infected with HIV in the United States every 9.5 minutes.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H789FE562C23942D7AF25F103BCAF0344"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">HIV/AIDS and STIs are syndemics. HIV infection can increase a person’s risk for acquiring certain STIs, as well as affect their frequency, severity, and healing time, while STIs increase the risk of HIV transmission, impaired fertility, reproductive tract cancer, and adverse pregnancy outcomes.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3B881788996F4004902AAC0A2EC7D5FE"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Many common long-term and initially asymptomatic STIs such as chlamydia, gonorrhea, herpes, syphilis, inflammatory pelvic disease, viral hepatitis, and HIV/AIDS remain undiagnosed, or diagnosed at later stages, leading to increased rates of mortality, morbidity, disability, and transmission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3EAED09D3AE84CAC873AC309E178B08B"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In fact, the CDC estimates over 3.6 million Americans are living with chronic hepatitis and most do not know they are infected. Chronic hepatitis B can remain asymptomatic for years and, left undiagnosed and untreated, can lead to serious complications. Additionally, individuals infected with hepatitis C virus (HCV) are at risk for chronic liver disease or other HCV-related chronic diseases decades after infection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE939A98649E04300872FDD54DFFCF9F2"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Stigma, culture, language, lack of education, lack of insurance, limited time, cost and resources in medical settings, and an inaccurate perception of risk among communities and providers all contribute to insufficient rates of screening for HIV/AIDS and STIs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCC7B2099B1D0479C8A2DE20E69219530"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and the United States Preventive Services Task Force recognize screening as an effective public health tool that allows providers to administer treatment before symptoms develop and implement interventions that will reduce the likelihood of HIV/AIDS and STI transmission and reduce the development of adverse outcomes.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1D2B14527F934CFB971E21998FC751F2"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The CDC recommends that voluntary screening for HIV/AIDS be integrated into routine clinical care while preserving patient confidentiality and the right of the patient to decline testing and screening.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE004D1395F7443898452D9772A3F6FD9"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The CDC also recommends that all unvaccinated, uninfected persons being evaluated for a STI should receive hepatitis B vaccination. Furthermore, anti-HCV testing is recommended for routine screening of asymptomatic persons based on their risk for infection or based on a recognized exposure.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA575C3A1CBFD4A05B78D648DAD5F4743"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Inaccurate perceptions of risk among health care providers and patients, misdiagnosis, ageism, generational mind-sets, and biological factors have contributed to increased rates in transmission and late detection of HIV/AIDS and STIs over the past decade.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H40011603F1AE4416A7B278BDE927A069"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Health equity and disparities remain a significant public health challenge, with the burden of HIV/AIDS and STIs falling disproportionately on different populations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H83367E365BB84F2E8D41C0765AE3DB0D"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Although African-Americans account for about 13 percent of the United States population, they account for nearly half of all HIV/AIDS cases and infections and have higher instances of mortality and morbidity for most STIs and HIV/AIDS. Also, African-American women who have sex with men account for the majority of HIV/AIDS infections among all women in the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAA31F34113D94945B38A251B39DFBC38"><enum>(13)</enum><text>HIV/AIDS continues to be most prevalent among men who have sex with men (MSM). Continued support and increased funding for community-based programs and behavioral interventions that are culturally competent are key to reaching MSM, especially young MSM of color.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9B633EB16C8E430FB1E0C39435F0CA80"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Transgender persons are particularly vulnerable to contracting HIV/AIDS and STIs due to high rates of survival sex among trans-females, discrimination in education, employment, and housing, and the absence of education and prevention methods culturally relevant to the transgender community.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6FC466A9C6554ED590CBD04D0A60CC1E"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Health care providers must be properly educated to treat groups, such as MSM, transgender persons, African-Americans, and Latinos who are disproportionately affected by HIV/AIDS and other STIs, and also improve interventions for groups that have been historically underrepresented in health interventions for STIs, such as women who have sex with women, individuals over the age of 50, Asian and Pacific Islander Americans, Native Americans, and persons living with disabilities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDDB0A9DD0A92444EBB82C9B48393B94C"><enum>(16)</enum><text>Women living with mobility impairments often lack access to screening for STIs and other women’s health services such as pelvic examinations and mammograms due to, among other factors, the lack of provider awareness, experience, and access to equipment.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H109D8F46C6374281A5DF248C90535CC4"><enum>(17)</enum><text>All individuals engaging in oral, anal, or genital sexual contact must have access to voluntary screening for HIV/AIDS and other STIs. Screening must be confidential, rapid, accurate, and medically appropriate. Screening must be offered regardless of age, race, class, sexual behavior, sexual orientation, gender identity, or disability.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2CAF57764B474DA0A13A09360892405C"><enum>(18)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Congress supports the goals of the National HIV/AIDS Strategy and, in particular, the goal of 90 percent of individuals knowing their HIV/AIDS status.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H553E529CDEAA4D169822DB46201E03B0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are as follows:</text> <paragraph id="H6236153B86D24A7BB31CDC528C2BEC52"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Increase access, quality, and affordability for voluntary and medically appropriate screening for HIV/AIDS and other STIs, including chlamydia, gonorrhea, syphilis, viral hepatitis, and human papillomavirus, for all persons engaging in various forms of sexual activity, including oral, genital, or anal sex.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7DB725E207E34F5D9E656F115558B250"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Reduce the spread, morbidity, and mortality of HIV/AIDS and other STIs.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H26EEACCA82E74ACE9F5E9A03D33B8556"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Reduce the disproportionate incidence of HIV/AIDS and other STIs in certain groups through early detection and treatment and comprehensive education for health care providers, centers, and communities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H69F1D3CE76C2438C90DC37E9EFC3E795"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Support the execution of other scientifically based interventions that are culturally competent and age appropriate and are proven to reduce the incidence of HIV/AIDS and other STIs.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H802818FA302946E98C198085DA98BAF1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H17BA094DE0C741DD8F280FE19A72FC7C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>CDC</header><text>The term <term>CDC</term> means the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC0DF4D94CDBB4A47B026D4CB6913C5C7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>CMS</header><text>The term <term>CMS</term> means the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA07A05994877405DA012C840AD478AC0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H59EF9287BA2F46A99D48B65DEC377838"><enum>(4)</enum><header>HIV/AIDS</header><text>The term <term>HIV/AIDS</term> means infection with the human immunodeficiency virus and includes acquired immune deficiency syndrome and any condition arising from such syndrome.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0675F2ED930148CFB85EA9C57BCD7333"><enum>(5)</enum><header>MSM</header><text>The term <term>MSM</term> means men who have sex with men.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6812FC759BD9404E9C644B67E724377F"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H240CBBFAD1FC49DAAA6F16998AD1BFB7"><enum>(7)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, the United States Virgin Islands, Guam, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and American Samoa.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H79AE03A0E014400C9D5E6DE0E7C320C5"><enum>(8)</enum><header>STI</header><text>The term <term>STI</term> means a sexually transmitted infection that is recognized by the CDC, including chlamydia, gonorrhea, syphilis, viral hepatitis, and human papillomavirus.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF6AC047D8B9A4E74946500942B17A134"><enum>(9)</enum><header>WSW</header><text>The term <term>WSW</term> means women who have sex with women.</text> </paragraph></section><title id="HB968B9F29A454BEDA13D948313BE7F8F"><enum>I</enum><header>Coverage of HIV/AIDS and STI screening under public health care programs and group health plans; Coverage of care under Medicaid.</header> <section commented="no" id="HF5B4DD90E78E4885AF0C31EB8559DB4B"><enum>101.</enum><header>Coverage of routine HIV/AIDS and STI screening tests under Medicaid</header> <subsection id="HBBE4D4AE28074BAD86238AF2FD62DC81"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Inclusion in State plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1902(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)</external-xref>) is amended in paragraph (10)(A), in the matter before clause (i), by striking <quote>and (28)</quote> and inserting <quote>(28), and (29)</quote>.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="HA4F79D6D576B4535B715A5973679FE08"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inclusion in medical assistance</header>
 <paragraph id="HA1E8782B0AFD45719364C0BFCDBE7D7F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1905(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HA5408DE03158445FB920743B6823BFC9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (28), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD25DF2594DC4C4A84897CEC418C610E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (29) as paragraph (30); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF0E69EFF27F042BC9900D0B7280B4C72"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (28) the following:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H961AF69A1318436B8C6589C6608731E6" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H6FC9599CFBD54E439B3C4C10CFD9CF89"><enum>(29)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">routine HIV/AIDS and STI screening services (as defined in subsection (ee)).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H135CBADC200343598CA03CA1734E4AE3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definition of services</header><text>Section 1905 of such Act is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCCEDA0CE00FA4A0194FEA90005D5A1CC" style="OLC">
							<subsection commented="no" id="HC0D72C9F2C5B4EEFA7FF643F9D23BD7E"><enum>(ee)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HAA5DC6076E6B4F46909AD00C65980796"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>routine HIV/AIDS and STI screening services</term> means all of the following:</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H7B9FCD90CBF04ABA90BA01B9E90E6B7C" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A screening test for HIV/AIDS or any other STI, if such test is provided to an individual who—</text>
 <clause id="H67DA0C25E3D6453886820A6D19465C57"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is eligible for medical assistance under the State plan; and</text> </clause><clause id="HCE01F85E1C6E476F8D8855A9DBA2214C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is described in clauses (ii) through (v) of section 1861(jjj)(1)(A).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB19DCEF536D446C5B219AD6A2318D47E" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each of the services described in subparagraphs (B) through (F) of section 1861(jjj)(1).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8511DF194F6B4F68864D0E5B050D8630" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the terms <term>HIV/AIDS</term> and <term>STI</term> have the same meaning given such terms in section 1861(jjj)(2).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAE4B28CA9AB74BCDBA460CCA9F2D810E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No cost sharing for HIV/AIDS testing</header>
 <paragraph id="HC3D336A06E484D7593D3F9FD2ED5547C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1916(a)(2) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396o">42 U.S.C. 1396o(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HF877B8E05129488099FDAD65965B4D97"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C8F2E012215429D9DF92A4FCFB761FB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by striking <quote>; and</quote> at the end and inserting <quote>, or</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H451936EA51B441E28DE0555C1B2C42A9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2A3485388BE646269502EB4A34F1DDB6" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H9C950226C58D46528B7EBEA9985D3624"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">routine HIV/AIDS and STI screening services (as such term is defined in section 1905(ee)); and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD3BB661CB89449B9B7BCC7231FB6BDB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation on State option for alternative cost sharing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1916A(b)(3)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396o-1">42 U.S.C. 1396o–1(b)(3)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H689D1F84331245B3B06B1291BF49AFDC" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H2160DA09E85A433E974EA00B38BD0933"><enum>(xi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Routine HIV/AIDS and STI screening services (as such term is defined in section 1905(ee)).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HC07B13A788DC41FD8F11DB358D602019"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header> <paragraph id="H08C0B49F92BD4F66B23A30C568E0D387"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided by <internal-xref idref="H61DAD6487BD144A99F84594EDD6610D9" legis-path="101.(d)(2)">paragraph (2)</internal-xref>, the amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this section and shall apply to services furnished on or after such date.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H61DAD6487BD144A99F84594EDD6610D9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rules for changes requiring State legislation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a State plan for medical assistance under title XIX of the Social Security Act which the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines requires State legislation (other than legislation appropriating funds) in order for the plan to meet the additional requirement imposed by the amendments made by this section, the State plan shall not be regarded as failing to comply with the requirements of such title solely on the basis of its failure to meet this additional requirement before the first day of the first calendar quarter beginning after the close of the first regular session of the State legislature that begins after the date of the enactment of this Act. For purposes of the previous sentence, in the case of a State that has a 2-year legislative session, each year of such session shall be deemed to be a separate regular session of the State legislature.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="HA00475CDD90E43BE94C03560E4D69432"><enum>102.</enum><header>Coverage of HIV/AIDS and STI screening tests under Medicare</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1861 of the Social Security Act is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HBCD7D714AFF94854A7012D3108ACBFCF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (s)—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H0306C432E29F4C9EAC91016D59B947CC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (14);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HEF3649F1175D4989A9E459225C11E05A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of paragraph (15) and inserting <quote>; and</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB23F21931AFC41D9BED66F58A26C0531"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (16) and (17) as paragraphs (17) and (18), respectively; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF4751615A02E44F9B0C96270DC1677AB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (15) the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H64586B9E8CD243469EA126639B12DB4B" style="OLC">
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HA9ECE2DED5F649DEB9E445F10FDB6A18"><enum>(16)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">routine HIV/AIDS and STI screening services (as such term is defined in subsection (jjj)).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H089D6C4B1EF04A8BAF77C36B690FDAD8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6F6295A9A908480EB8038B4A14398A81" style="OLC">
						<subsection commented="no" id="HA7E26050A7F5440CBAD091E0CCBB47E9"><enum>(jjj)</enum><header>Routine HIV/AIDS and STI screening services</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H024477A034944322877F738C4D3AEE17"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>routine HIV/AIDS and STI screening services</term> means all of the following:</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HAEE0C9A2AA604F929902DF59B47238BF" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A screening test for HIV/AIDS or any other STI, if such test is provided in any health care setting (other than an inpatient hospital setting) and is provided to an individual who—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="HA26F49FBD26F4371AF365D0506BE42B4"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is enrolled in part B;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9D1285706BF4404BBF7BF5A98D605AB9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is at least 13 years of age;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H445E9631A6F54653A67C4BD343E74377"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a test for HIV/AIDS, is not known to the health care provider (directly, through information provided by the individual, or through access to an electronic medical record) to have had a previous positive test for HIV/AIDS;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H187FDD11315247E9A8EA5AF1ACA5B3CC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subject to <internal-xref idref="H09AD6BD44C6D43E881252B6B7D3C072C" legis-path="(ee)(1)(B)">subparagraph (B)</internal-xref>, with respect to a test for HIV/AIDS or a STI, is not known to the health care provider (directly, through information provided by the individual, or through access to an electronic medical record) to have had a test for the same condition within the previous 6 months; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HCD72BB108AA04FE1B71C9A09C567580E"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has been informed that such a test will be administered and has not objected to such a test.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09AD6BD44C6D43E881252B6B7D3C072C" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If a test described under <internal-xref idref="HAEE0C9A2AA604F929902DF59B47238BF" legis-path="(ee)(1)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref> is reactive and is for—</text>
 <clause id="H386125879A804A65AC51CE362C3BDA69"><enum>(i)</enum><text>HIV/AIDS, a confirmatory test; or</text> </clause><clause id="H57C3CBEAFD664B5EB1FFDC720373A1B3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a STI other than HIV/AIDS, if reasonable and necessary, a confirmatory test.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5AA67080BB84C56B5ED2EA1A05CCE76" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The interpretation of any tests provided under <internal-xref idref="HAEE0C9A2AA604F929902DF59B47238BF" legis-path="(ee)(1)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref> and <internal-xref idref="H09AD6BD44C6D43E881252B6B7D3C072C" legis-path="(ee)(1)(B)">subparagraph (B)</internal-xref>.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2BAAC0DCFC8F47B29B78EB1B5F0F8EDF" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Informing an individual who receives a test under <internal-xref idref="HAEE0C9A2AA604F929902DF59B47238BF" legis-path="(ee)(1)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref> or <internal-xref idref="H09AD6BD44C6D43E881252B6B7D3C072C" legis-path="(ee)(1)(B)">subparagraph (B)</internal-xref> of the results of such tests as close in time as possible to the determination of such results.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H373D72A5D0BC43149722240CE305E808" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an individual tests positive for HIV/AIDS on a screening test under <internal-xref idref="HAEE0C9A2AA604F929902DF59B47238BF" legis-path="(iii)(1)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref> and any confirmatory test under <internal-xref idref="H09AD6BD44C6D43E881252B6B7D3C072C" legis-path="(ee)(1)(B)">subparagraph (B)</internal-xref>—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H4A63C1F847B544648A2365387AA2FCA7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>post-test counseling concerning HIV/AIDS and STIs at the time the individual is informed of the results of the test; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HB294372C46B6455CB84114A36A940B72"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if appropriate, a referral to medical or mental health services.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF9E8F7AC765433E86C0AB57BC7344FA" indent="up1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>If an individual tests positive for a STI on a screening test under <internal-xref idref="HAEE0C9A2AA604F929902DF59B47238BF" legis-path="(iii)(1)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref> and any confirmatory test under <internal-xref idref="H09AD6BD44C6D43E881252B6B7D3C072C" legis-path="(ee)(1)(B)">subparagraph (B)</internal-xref>, the provision of information to such individual on the risk of STIs and HIV/AIDS and behaviors that reduce the risk of exposure to such conditions.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H899D31173DD84855A20F97B2908029E4" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this subsection:</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H937EB5989B8749F28357570433BA1E2C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>HIV/AIDS</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>HIV/AIDS</term> means infection with the human immunodeficiency virus and includes acquired immune deficiency syndrome and any condition arising from such syndrome.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5574D2C75B974E36B1D8A034DE067111"><enum>(B)</enum><header>STI</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>STI</term> means a sexually transmitted infection or sexually transmitted disease that is recognized by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, including chlamydia, gonorrhea, syphilis, hepatitis B, hepatitis C, and human papillomavirus.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></section><section id="H266E91804FF84D418EECB3A528657ED6"><enum>103.</enum><header>Coverage for routine HIV/AIDS and STI screening under group health plans</header>
				<subsection id="H24DBCA5214874CAEA6C3086EB255F8AC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Group health plans</header>
 <paragraph id="HB1217E1CF8A447D0BCED7473A38756D2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Public Health Service Act amendment</header><text>Title XXVII of the <act-name parsable-cite="PHSA">Public Health Service Act</act-name> is amended by inserting after section 2728 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-28">42 U.S.C. 300gg–28</external-xref>), as redesignated by section 1001(2) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref>), the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H00FE6BC1559440C495838EB0D4BB103B" style="OLC">
							<section id="H8E96E390B25D43338D6DAC3329B109C8"><enum>2729.</enum><header>Coverage for routine HIV/AIDS and STI screening</header>
 <subsection id="H93CE7897BCF448E5996BC926146C68DD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Coverage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A group health plan, and a health insurance issuer providing group or individual health insurance coverage, shall provide coverage for routine HIV/AIDS and STI screening under terms and conditions that are no less favorable than the terms and conditions applicable to other routine health screenings.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H20DD230C4CA1424AAFB4B581724A2406"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A group health plan, and a health insurance issuer providing group or individual health insurance coverage, shall not—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0AF3FFCC05D64489AF163E5E8F9DC95B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">deny to an individual eligibility, or continued eligibility, to enroll or to renew coverage under the terms of the plan, solely for the purpose of avoiding the requirements of this section;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE6CBFD4871054933813DD2932BD0BB06"><enum>(2)</enum><text>deny coverage for routine HIV/AIDS or STI screening on the basis that there are no known risk factors present, or the screening is not clinically indicated, medically necessary, or pursuant to a referral, consent, or recommendation by any health care provider;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H25A5097BA93D461A97D7D1EE367E6D88"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide monetary payments, rebates, or other benefits to individuals to encourage such individuals to accept less than the minimum protections available under this section;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H49E5502F54E840D187120CE9469A953B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>penalize or otherwise reduce or limit the reimbursement of a provider because such provider provided care to an individual participant or beneficiary in accordance with this section;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAB1A26FF68544C6F94925F73F24F5B75"><enum>(5)</enum><text>provide incentives (monetary or otherwise) to a provider to induce such provider to provide care to an individual participant or beneficiary in a manner inconsistent with this section; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4FFB08999BA4497A80F8C9345E1B2991"><enum>(6)</enum><text>deny to an individual participant or beneficiary continued eligibility to enroll or to renew coverage under the terms of the plan, solely because of the results of an HIV/AIDS or STI test, or other HIV/AIDS and STI screening procedure, for the individual or any other individual.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H106F222304494D4296C4BA02A8937587"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rules of Construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed—</text> <paragraph id="H81F28176913F413AA6631B37991BEBDD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to require an individual who is a participant or beneficiary to undergo HIV/AIDS or STI screening; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2C1EFD6FC7814E57B8194A1CDD5C497D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as preventing a group health plan or issuer from imposing deductibles, coinsurance, or other cost-sharing in relation to HIV/AIDS or STI screening, except that such deductibles, coinsurance or other cost-sharing may not be greater than the deductibles, coinsurance, or other cost-sharing imposed on other routine health screenings.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H741C0DE6A1064A3489A428DDFE18EFDD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A group health plan under this part shall comply with the notice requirement under section 716(d) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 with respect to the requirements of this section as if such section applied to such plan.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDA0655A7A7C74035B302BA1E2B0DBB51"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Preemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to preempt any State law in effect on the date of enactment of this section with respect to health insurance coverage that requires coverage of at least the coverage of HIV/AIDS or STI screening otherwise required under this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H39F50CEF3DA046569EC15FC0C5CED6FA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>ERISA amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 is amended as follows:</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HAEC3BB7676084573BD3EB5D0925C4DF5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>In subpart B of part 7 of subtitle B of title I, by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBE33D982A907433F945ABBE149437D44" style="OLC">
								<section commented="no" id="H5B710C924F634974989DE6AF888C6B92"><enum>716.</enum><header>Coverage for routine HIV/AIDS and STI screening</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="HF29B13284A9D442F8A5CA9A58EE7E133"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Coverage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A group health plan, and a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage, shall provide coverage for routine HIV screening under terms and conditions that are no less favorable than the terms and conditions applicable to other routine health screenings.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HCE599104EAC44DCB8E2EB1BA76797BA7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A group health plan, and a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage, shall not—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HF4B1D7EA962C4B7DB911FD551A8A68AB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">deny to an individual eligibility, or continued eligibility, to enroll or to renew coverage under the terms of the plan, solely for the purpose of avoiding the requirements of this section;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H0AE63477F4604A7EB93FE6512269C36D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>deny coverage for routine HIV screening on the basis that there are no known risk factors present, or the screening is not clinically indicated, medically necessary, or pursuant to a referral, consent, or recommendation by any health care provider;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF85E68E872144528A01D6B450B3FA121"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide monetary payments, rebates, or other benefits to individuals to encourage such individuals to accept less than the minimum protections available under this section;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H72879DB86A214A78B7BC9B102E13008B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>penalize or otherwise reduce or limit the reimbursement of a provider because such provider provided care to an individual participant or beneficiary in accordance with this section;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3C89BD46FD1E43A2BBE5136FFE488314"><enum>(5)</enum><text>provide incentives (monetary or otherwise) to a provider to induce such provider to provide care to an individual participant or beneficiary in a manner inconsistent with this section; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H39C87BA639894BCCA58DE09D12566EE6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>deny to an individual participant or beneficiary continued eligibility to enroll or to renew coverage under the terms of the plan, solely because of the results of an HIV test or other HIV screening procedure for the individual or any other individual.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H944FF010CFA34F5583768378EDC45681"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HE69F4D5A3A0D42BB9E0A69373D01CCB7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to require an individual who is a participant or beneficiary to undergo HIV/AIDS or STI screening; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H571C4E928D794CA0ACF1944134FC7814"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as preventing a group health plan or issuer from imposing deductibles, coinsurance, or other cost-sharing in relation to HIV/AIDS or STI screening, except that such deductibles, coinsurance or other cost-sharing may not be greater than the deductibles, coinsurance, or other cost-sharing imposed on other routine health screenings.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HE8C6B4CCFCD243BE9CA2F6E95E6CA23B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notice under group health plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A group health plan, and a health insurance issuer providing health insurance coverage in connection with a group health plan, shall provide notice to each participant and beneficiary under such plan regarding the coverage required by this section in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Secretary. Such notice shall be in writing and prominently positioned in any literature or correspondence made available or distributed by the plan or issuer and shall be transmitted, by whichever is earliest of the following:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H8AD885C6B0C74B9FAFF09117DFBED918"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the next mailing made by the plan or issuer to the participant or beneficiary.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HDA6836DDBDFF465EB20D75DF42280CDE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As part of any yearly informational packet sent to the participant or beneficiary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H20B3E4373DF7448F822CD31CE2FF0782"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than July 1, 2017.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HE66D3DBDC477425086D56C1866CC5A06"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Preemption; relation to State laws</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="H7F3CAD281F2E4063B61B77600DA1ABD1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to preempt any State law in effect on the date of enactment of this section with respect to health insurance coverage that requires coverage of at least the coverage of HIV/AIDS or STI screening otherwise required under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H915CEA31D9734E13921D1FF525529FA2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>ERISA</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect or modify the provisions of section 514 with respect to group health plans.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H71BFAE0A89CD4EDB872B4A08170B6867"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In section 732(a) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1191a">29 U.S.C. 1191a(a)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>section 711</quote> and inserting <quote>sections 711 and 716</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3E638A54C9124C1EA2AF5E639DEB9BF9"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the table of contents in section 1 of such Act, by inserting after the item relating to section 714 the following new item:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H419DE7CC88894931AE3923AE166B30D4" style="OLC">
								<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
									<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 715. Additional market reforms.</toc-entry>
									<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 716. Coverage for routine HIV/AIDS and STI screening.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H820A267E80D0461CB203AB090D20DB40"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Internal Revenue Code amendments</header>
 <subparagraph id="H13936FB4A15E44B98FC34EC81F68D80A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after section 9815 the following new section:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7D33BE94CC354149AA0368EB410FE708" style="OLC">
								<section commented="no" id="H0D41D8FECD6F4DEA84BE44330A4F5E8B"><enum>9816.</enum><header>Coverage for routine HIV/AIDS and STI screening</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="HC63D0D689FB44F4285BA31637EC0595F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Coverage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A group health plan shall provide coverage for routine HIV/AIDS and STI screening under terms and conditions that are no less favorable than the terms and conditions applicable to other routine health screenings.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H42381F7446E4481BB9178AF39E11224C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A group health plan shall not—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H49E4CE40BC8046B7BC761A9FE346FCF8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">deny to an individual eligibility, or continued eligibility, to enroll or to renew coverage under the terms of the plan, solely for the purpose of avoiding the requirements of this section;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H28F2AAA0A1B14D28A19691FE24521B4A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>deny coverage for routine HIV/AIDS or STI screening on the basis that there are no known risk factors present, or the screening is not clinically indicated, medically necessary, or pursuant to a referral, consent, or recommendation by any health care provider;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H14A2A71CB91A4273BA85ED69E3A4A45C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide monetary payments, rebates, or other benefits to individuals to encourage such individuals to accept less than the minimum protections available under this section;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HBEAF359D30904C1E97B168518CA23DCE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>penalize or otherwise reduce or limit the reimbursement of a provider because such provider provided care to an individual participant or beneficiary in accordance with this section;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H58D971713FB94DC498058B4B8261B784"><enum>(5)</enum><text>provide incentives (monetary or otherwise) to a provider to induce such provider to provide care to an individual participant or beneficiary in a manner inconsistent with this section; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H966A16500F094EEE88490154D0985C70"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">deny to an individual participant or beneficiary continued eligibility to enroll or to renew coverage under the terms of the plan, solely because of the results of an HIV/AIDS or STI test, or other HIV/AIDS and STI screening procedure, for the individual or any other individual.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HE4A1CBDD5A9D4FFF9A7DFFD574ECFAAE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H026BE06E305D4679B4AFB6DF21EB3D18"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to require an individual who is a participant or beneficiary to undergo HIV/AIDS or STI screening; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD8D59FBE29494DCBBCAD72BD2A8E55A0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as preventing a group health plan or issuer from imposing deductibles, coinsurance, or other cost-sharing in relation to HIV/AIDS or STI screening, except that such deductibles, coinsurance or other cost-sharing may not be greater than the deductibles, coinsurance, or other cost-sharing imposed on other routine health screenings.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4137839DC23F48F882119F3F129EFD51"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 4980D(d)(1) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>section 9811</quote> and inserting <quote>sections 9811 and 9816</quote>.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7363D6B83B8D41EB82814581A75DCEDE"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for subchapter B of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 9815 the following new item:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF72837E1029640F4BFE28EEB488528DA" style="OLC">
								<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
									<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 9816. Coverage for routine HIV/AIDS and STI screening.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB3F2C4840D4E4BDDAF6FCA114D7C65C5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application under Federal Employees Health Benefits Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 8902 of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H521458EA30714967A84C3F3464F8AD3F" style="USC">
 <subsection id="HDA9C4E50965C46C1B149AED1C6FD4962"><enum>(p)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A contract may not be made or a plan approved which does not comply with the requirements of section 2729 of the Public Health Service Act.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF0CD16E979BF4517ACAFB7E1165493C3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective dates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the amendments made by subsections (a) and (b) shall apply with respect to plan years beginning on or after July 1, 2017, and with respect to health insurance coverage issued on or after such date.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H019AE9CA0C6F4A6681BCE5E3D74749FB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Coordination of administration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and the Secretary of the Treasury shall ensure, through the execution of an interagency memorandum of understanding among such Secretaries, that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6EFB45B7524B40CD8F44EC5F97938A48"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">regulations, rulings, and interpretations issued by such Secretaries relating to the same matter over which two or more such Secretaries have responsibility under the provisions of this section (and the amendments made thereby) are administered so as to have the same effect at all times; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB9159B043FF44DB18308A3498D90F51A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordination of policies relating to enforcing the same requirements through such Secretaries in order to have a coordinated enforcement strategy that avoids duplication of enforcement efforts and assigns priorities in enforcement.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H80271836685442459AA342132041E231"><enum>104.</enum><header>Optional Medicaid coverage of low-income HIV/AIDS infected individuals</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H229E76E9790047EE9209AAA9BFD35F78"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1902 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HB4CC62BD3835481BA773AE976F2093A4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a)(10)(A)(ii)—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H62A0925DAC094C498D959BB4685CC3FB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of subclause (XXI);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4F642CFFD03542CAADF0E308D3A0151F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding <quote>or</quote> at the end of subclause (XXII); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H939FDDF4F65643A7AA81D3B239C4361E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5906D12147C74A5C85F686E2A9FB7C7F" style="OLC"> <subclause commented="no" id="HC741A6C9446B409FACDF18E79674D426"><enum>(XXIII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on or before December 31, 2017, who are described in subsection (ll) (relating to HIV/AIDS infected individuals);</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD4CB469CA0A74B52A2F2FAFF6367DABD"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H593FA1732CB14E09B7FAD8F228FC4DA8" style="OLC"> <subsection commented="no" id="HB549CACE8EDE411686DC14A8BAF5DD74"><enum>(ll)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">individuals described in this subsection are individuals—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H11006DFD9DFC4C2885DDB746F9EF89C2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>who are not described in subsection (a)(10)(A)(i);</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8D8282E84111447D904AAF2514AC57D5"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who have HIV/AIDS, as defined under section 1905(ee);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H06198A2814AC461186BC0A3649C833C1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whose income (as determined under the State plan under this title with respect to disabled individuals) does not exceed the maximum amount of income a disabled individual described in subsection (a)(10)(A)(i) may have to obtain medical assistance under the plan; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7D25F7648CCE4D8F9BE2DBD0142850A7"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whose resources (as determined under the State plan under this title with respect to disabled individuals) do not exceed the maximum amount of resources a disabled individual described in subsection (a)(10)(A)(i) may have to obtain medical assistance under the plan.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H17B4B5445B424247A77F8D242A44E2A9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enhanced match</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HB1D9E7784B5C44A48006F5EBE5AEA382"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The first sentence of section 1905(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d(b)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 1902(a)(10)(A)(ii)(XVIII)</quote> and inserting <quote>subclause (XVIII) and subclause (XXIII) of section 1902(a)(10)(A)(ii)</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6B1091CBC88F45799427E8D59F684098"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1905(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d(a)</external-xref>) is amended in the matter preceding paragraph (1)—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H59E9843077BF40E5B05A5F7B552CB12A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of clause (xv);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4D2F56763E8E4C17BF1BD9F1D202A461"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of clause (xvi);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E48794DCC7C4377847F33A56889E747"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding <quote>or</quote> at the end of clause (xvii); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9430328958D443469021D985A6E5656A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by inserting after clause (xvii) the following:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3DDE41543AFA4BBD85925A121549261F" style="OLC">
 <clause commented="no" id="H2A52DB315EE447ABBB2D1D81AB707B31"><enum>(xviii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">individuals described in section 1902(a)(10)(A)(ii)(XXIII);</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HC85B2C16CB9347E8A42615747E4E9B13"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exemption from funding limitation for territories</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1108(g) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1308">42 U.S.C. 1308(g)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD8397D7850B2449F8F7FD4EEC56DBBFE" style="OLC">
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H10FC98C321F54161ADDC436161944AA6"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Disregarding medical assistance for optional low-income HIV/AIDS infected individuals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The limitations under subsection (f) and the previous provisions of this subsection shall not apply to amounts expended for medical assistance for individuals described in section 1902(ll) who are only eligible for such assistance on the basis of section 1902(a)(10)(A)(ii)(XXIII).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H8BE9FC04C0824CF7954DA90697D7CF0E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header>
 <paragraph id="H0C007EC134C143A9B64EA268B9334431"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided by <internal-xref idref="H4A9E42F1AD584A5691DE78F0419F1BAF" legis-path="101.(e)(2)">paragraph (2)</internal-xref>, the amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this section and shall apply to services furnished on or after such date.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4A9E42F1AD584A5691DE78F0419F1BAF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rules for changes requiring State legislation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a State plan for medical assistance under title XIX of the Social Security Act which the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines requires State legislation (other than legislation appropriating funds) in order for the plan to meet the additional requirement imposed by the amendments made by this section, the State plan shall not be regarded as failing to comply with the requirements of such title solely on the basis of its failure to meet this additional requirement before the first day of the first calendar quarter beginning after the close of the first regular session of the State legislature that begins after the date of the enactment of this Act. For purposes of the previous sentence, in the case of a State that has a 2-year legislative session, each year of such session shall be deemed to be a separate regular session of the State legislature.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="H260FAECFA50D4E40A78EF37D4302BC3C"><enum>II</enum><header>Increased data collection and education for historically underrepresented populations</header>
			<section id="H25E9FC3ABA9245AB8B67E469D75010B5"><enum>201.</enum><header>People living with disabilities</header>
 <subsection id="HB0BC7D648E33424289F5E6C7EFA8EDEF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Tracking of information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall—</text> <paragraph id="H3D1A86B521274913B8DC235647ED3AA5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>track national HIV/AIDS and STI screening trends and the burdens of HIV/AIDS and STIs among people with disabilities, including such persons with mental, physical, cognitive, intellectual, or developmental disabilities; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF044C47E47BF4BA88DC792FACC034A7C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify and assess the barriers that prevent such persons from accessing HIV/AIDS and STI screening.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD460F2A15F6D46F4BC89BFD3DA3D9D43"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Tracking methodology</header>
 <paragraph id="HF2E7265093294BA7B83A9E289C239ED8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The tracking methods used by the Secretary under subsection (a) shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H212233534D7945869A4B803EBBDBF4F0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">focus upon historically underrepresented communities, including the deaf and hearing loss-related community and the cognitive, intellectual, developmental, mobility, or mental health disability communities; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0FA4DABCBF14479DBBA085CA1225746D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consider other factors that may contribute to increased burdens of HIV/AIDS and STIs, including race, socio-economic status, region, gender identity, and sexual behavior.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7058262351E0404BA00FF7D9DCBDC006"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sexual assault data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Tracking under subsection (a) shall include data collection on the incidence of sexual assault on people with mental, physical, cognitive, intellectual, or developmental disabilities for the purposes of understanding the prevalence of HIV/AIDS and STIs that result from such assaults.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC26372E4AA7342ED81FC1639AC6CE8E0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Deaf and hearing loss community</header>
 <paragraph id="HA65A8564FC5E4AB88F85993FA5A718A9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director, shall work with appropriate organizations and institutions to make comprehensive sex education materials that promote voluntary screening for HIV/AIDS and STIs accessible to the deaf and hearing loss community through language (including American Sign Language), modalities (including highly graphic formats with minimal text), and culturally appropriate information delivery.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H718E2671D57E4C53A5BBB94FF88D4F09"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Health careers and education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H7C8F5CE07015492A9889BFB6961E113F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>work with appropriate individuals, organizations, and institutions to increase the number of people who are deaf or living with hearing loss in public health careers for the purposes of—</text>
 <clause id="H7F829BF93BA04A71A4601B2D31CF2F5C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>building the public health infrastructure to improve data collection; and</text> </clause><clause id="HE18C335CDB0F4219B35F9B706FE422E8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>health information dissemination to people who are deaf or who live with hearing loss; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H940F74B8F56745C9839277C3C1CF1047"><enum>(B)</enum><text>engage students in elementary school, high school, college, and graduate school for the purposes of carrying out this paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB5B18AC2722041C78F4259E21AA2F4D1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Cognitive and intellectual disability community</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Director, shall work with appropriate national and local organizations to make comprehensive sex education materials accessible to people with intellectual disabilities by—</text>
 <paragraph id="H3FE9AF66F78A40889009A3C01BD3393D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>using plain language;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H62642486E2C442A496A8C7C3C743A6E7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>educating service providers about the signs and symptoms of sexual assault among people with cognitive and intellectual disabilities; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0B060A418E25497DA1C77150620066F7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>using other appropriate information delivery strategies.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF2BA3566AC0F4E2682C98C8130999292"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Women living with severe physical disabilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Director, shall work with Federal, State, and local entities to track access to pelvic examinations, mammograms, and other women’s health services for women with severe mobility impairments with the goal of improving access to such services.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H0B18D21F30554DE99B0E6DBF786CDD7D"><enum>202.</enum><header>Women who have sex with women</header>
 <subsection id="H48D84356A02940B68FF4997007E0D230"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National screening guidelines</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director, shall work with Federal, State, and local health entities to ensure that national screening guidelines for cervical cancer state that WSW should be subject to the same screening guidelines for cervical cancer as women who have sex only with men.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H009E205922BE478597A71999A3248172"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information collection</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director, shall, with respect to the WSW community—</text> <paragraph id="HE14715779997498D9BF2D23FA32992DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>track national trends in screening for HIV/AIDS and other STIs; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA0E781A3784E4F4FB86E0A29529D208E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>collect information on—</text> <subparagraph id="H12E43949A6074C508D35432937F5F21C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the burdens and behavior of HIV/AIDS and STIs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E9C112501E44A4C82C7DAA6F01AE769"><enum>(B)</enum><text>other reproductive health concerns.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H5D4BE9F80F4C470081D58213427ED9A4"><enum>203.</enum><header>Transgender community</header> <subsection id="H5D87564AB66C40C6AA0F18B3CA2790BF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Data collection</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director, shall work with Federal, State, and local health entities and transgender communities to improve information collection concerning the transmission, morbidity, and screening for HIV/AIDS and other STIs in transgender communities.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H32D9BCDCFC8C4252BF76A7EE43D9DFE4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information classification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of acquiring a comprehensive understanding of the unique health trends among, and aspects of, the transgender community, the Secretary shall promulgate regulations requiring that, for purposes of public health studies requiring data collection, the fact that an individual is transgender shall be a distinct category and data point.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="HE5A65768491549099A17E4E5B2BFEE0E"><enum>204.</enum><header>Report</header>
 <subsection id="HD4A69BE8F50D4765B5E14ADDD2D02709"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit a report to Congress on the activities required under this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H680F90D0BDEE40CEAB0385BAD6FA491E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report issued to Congress under subsection (a) shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H0A5563DBAFA64F46B14092B686558FC9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on the success of voluntary screening for HIV/AIDS and STIs, as well as other methods for preventing the transmission of HIV/AIDS and STIs among Medicaid and Medicare beneficiaries, patients at federally qualified health centers, individuals with health insurance, MSM, WSW, persons living with disabilities, the transgender community, and other groups that have been historically underrepresented in public health interventions for HIV/AIDS and STIs; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF5A2CC6FFF4841DCA971CFDEDAB2DEF3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations on how to improve existing measures with respect to race, socioeconomic status, region, gender identity, disability, age, and sexual behavior—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC4CE2F9D1CBB4A999FCA7F9F62CFF698"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to increase access to screening; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD63A981BA78F41748CE13DBCBF9FDB54"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to decrease the disparities in mortality and morbidity from HIV/AIDS and other STIs.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></title></legis-body></bill>


