<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H526C77AD453448BC9FB65A48AA53B76F" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4023 IH: Developing Tomorrow’s Engineering and Technical Workforce Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4023</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171011">October 11, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000585">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to award grants to States educational
			 agencies and local educational agencies to support, develop, and implement
			 formal and informal engineering education programs in elementary schools
			 and secondary schools.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H1D50AD0C504049B8A4767F33464DA78C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H28D85781C49A43E2B75AE355003A3CEC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Developing Tomorrow’s Engineering and Technical Workforce Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H6FF7A1FB0AFF4F4493F815C1377605E5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress makes the following findings:</text>
 <paragraph id="H617E97CDB8364B12931F8DB5F8E8F6E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The vitality of the innovation economy in the United States depends on the availability of an educated technical workforce. A key component of this workforce consists of engineers, engineering technicians, and engineering technologists.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H96AD77BBD6E44CB8A72EFD95EB9F5195"><enum>(2)</enum><text>There is a widening skills gap between what schools teach and the types of skills presently needed in the job market and the higher skills sets needed for the 21st century workforce.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3FCB9CCA78C7478983B5D532F0124C0A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Available evidence suggests that formal and informal engineering education both in and after school can stimulate interest and improve learning in mathematics and science as well as improve understanding of engineering and technology.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1549A5C719F942B8990A1BA68B43054A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Early engineering education is a vital component in attaining licensure as a professional engineer that requires rigorous education, training, experience, and continuing education.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC7EACBAD889D46BEB9BE622402440E1F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Few States have included engineering in their science or technology and vocational standards, and few local educational agencies and nonprofit entities provide informal or after-school engineering education programs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6C5E4E45C48448A2837965DE903B834D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>According to the National Academy of Engineering there is not at present a critical mass of teachers qualified to deliver formal and informal engineering instruction.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB91020E4B1C34609A939EF71364A360A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>It is imperative that teachers have relevant professional training that coordinates concepts in engineering with the diverse learning styles of students.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H2221326B1B73453CBAC3835CD6097308"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grant program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part F of title IV of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7251">20 U.S.C. 7251</external-xref> et seq.) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE9196D2AF66348969A0313FBB7532EAC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 4601—</text> <subparagraph id="H38A1979FDC18441E8CDC228D544EE251"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>(other than subpart 5)</quote> before <quote>part</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9597F42C4C594C3F9CD010FD711F6684"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H8DA993ABB7CD48D38FBEB48274EB1229" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H460526E721584160BC95506E9C6498BA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations for subpart 5</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out subpart 5—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6473BC98746E4D9394835E4DE602D111"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$20,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 and 2020; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H818955D25EC94EFFB3EBD46F37694169"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$21,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2021 and 2022.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H012830A97B0B47DDAB6DEA72AED3E0C6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H46233AD2A1F8478C97CB91809283E3CC" style="OLC"> <subpart id="HD6A46AB057B7447099B59FC7E6ABA7AA"><enum>5</enum><header>Engineering Education</header> <section id="HF97BAECE0C354FF187F32D897F8436D7"><enum>4651.</enum><header>Grant program authorized</header> <subsection id="H665FA2C3EC2C44979A7185DBE6792D3B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>From amounts appropriated under section 4601(c), the Secretary shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities to implement formal and informal engineering education programs in elementary schools and secondary schools to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H90763DB887C4456EB151EF288B7CCFBA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>teach students the overall analytical and experimental approaches used in engineering and engineering technology; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9059C290451346E3916B50CCD0461010"><enum>(2)</enum><text>increase participation of underrepresented student groups in the engineering and engineering technology pipeline.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H5139B4C6FC9342949DBA023E8DE6E79D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Maximum grant amount</header><text>A grant awarded under this subpart may not exceed $1,000,000.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HFAD3D12289B34C538A07A887CE4E4E11"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Matching funds</header><text>An eligible entity receiving a grant under this subpart shall provide non-Federal funds in amount equal to the grant amount. Such non-Federal funds may include in-kind support (such as equipment, supplies, materials, and participation of personnel in the development and implementation of activities to be carried out under the grant).</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="H719A0F132B5140CDBBBD2DBF606348A4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Uses of funds</header>
 <paragraph id="HB96D4A3DC23146CAB7713F576F491125"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity receiving a grant under this subpart shall use such funds to carry out a program that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAEA59567E3F84BFAA94F8E3335341EE1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provides engineering instructional materials based on review and analysis of the effectiveness of existing formal, or informal research-based and evidenced-based locally relevant instructional materials;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H26971FD091654D21819ABC7108CD3F2B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides professional development for pre-service and in-service teachers to teach engineering;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA41701207107436C9912C3D302BFD2B7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provides instructions on engineering and engineering technology during normal classroom hours or after school;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H204D4B1E345742AAA88152006176C46C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>incorporates evidence-based practices to increase diversity of student groups participating in the program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD65EF747125248D29071222DBEDE9AC6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>encourages participation of engineers from local private and public organizations to mentor the teachers and students; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8348A2EB0A07446C95973857562AEAA7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>encourages engineering faculty and students from institutions of higher education as mentors for the elementary school or secondary school students, and teachers as appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7F1508E969141749FF0A03FDCE5EE66"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State educational agencies</header><text>In the case of an eligible entity that is a State educational agency, such entity shall award subgrants to local educational agencies to carry out the program described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H058F2FDA66C34AFB80C53B414F8098D1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public-private partnerships</header><text>Each eligible entity awarded a grant under this subpart shall be encouraged to carry out the program funded under the grant in partnership with one or more of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H452ACD40118C4B4DB04008C8808DD841"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Elementary schools or secondary schools receiving assistance under this subpart.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD59407E8915C404DA78B766DA03FA57E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Institutions of higher education.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0C0E07656215435485CBB679142C6AAF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Private sector businesses.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE2C7325107324D06B0E081C349490954"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Nonprofit organizations.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2981A0C3BFF3472BBAB95AFDE4F3501A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Community-based organizations.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9AF1453F235B48EEA56B09E71D5AA7CC"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Public or private entities with demonstrated record of success in delivering educational support.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HED07F327D87B425DB55F3BC8A6291B34"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>An application for a grant under this subpart submitted by an eligible entity shall demonstrate long-term commitment for the proposed program through—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0F684C6982E1453489C2D68F87105901"><enum>(1)</enum><text>providing laboratory and instructional space;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2C654215BEE046738D995BF9704C7A32"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establishing ongoing professional training programs for pre-service and in-service teachers and teachers in-residence;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCE041E153CEE4D6A80B57D8A39B82489"><enum>(3)</enum><text>commitment to scaling successful programs for engineering and engineering technology education in elementary schools and secondary schools under the jurisdiction of the eligible entity; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H76E313F65F8E43E7B93FA4C9506FF0ED"><enum>(4)</enum><text>commitment to serving diverse student groups such as underrepresented or economically disadvantaged student groups.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9B95F6D166614D9A8AD28C384A257099"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HBA2BB4BEC1144E2AA75A07F3EAE39059"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <quote>eligible entity</quote> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3F13E146C7804548BDCEAF81F44C3F0D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State educational agency; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD1CA9DAB1B340D9857BE954B1BC39E3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a local educational agency that is not receiving a subgrant under this subpart for the fiscal year for which the agency is applying for a grant under this subpart.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CD3B376925346E58DFAE09393BF35E8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Instructional materials</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>instructional materials</quote> means materials that—</text> <subparagraph id="H67E2668FB0F04A06A426E493B8E32D54"><enum>(A)</enum><text>emphasize—</text>
 <clause id="HD07CCCD004E1432BB9EEFD73E0EF17DD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>engineering fundamentals and concepts, problem-based learning; and</text> </clause><clause id="H4F0359A2FDF14D4A85F16CD20381BDE9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>essential skills such as systems thinking, creativity, teamwork, communication, and ethical considerations;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25C9A77CD8124C58BC956D4E51CADA57"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are designed to introduce students to modern engineering and engineering technology tools such as computer-aided design, computer-aided manufacturing, statistical analysis, codes and standards, human factors, and reliability analysis; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF9050BD066BC4D889464DE7EA6CE23F6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>are aligned with and integrated into relevant science, engineering, and mathematics standards that may exist in the applicable State or may be developed.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB8F8DC3A1B27485EB75BD033188DDCD8"><enum>4652.</enum><header>Annual report to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the first grant is awarded under this subpart, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall provide a report to Congress on activities and results under this subpart. Such reports shall describe—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7ADF6C4A08D04283B4614259D5513490"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the total number of grant applications received for the preceding each year;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H12DFF76FDDE94328AC2BB32A4E3AE479"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number and geographic distribution of the grants for such year and for all grants awarded under this subpart;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC99A79A524AE42158A87EB1FDDD83AD2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>participation of minority-serving institutions of higher education, such as historically Black colleges and universities and Hispanic-serving institutions;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFBD3B71C376E43DE8D8B4B1376470BFE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>participation of underrepresented and economically disadvantaged student groups;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA28F89596B4C4AD0AA3C80F9C31C73AA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>plans for collaboration among eligible entities receiving a grant under this subpart;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8AA8D2C57E6A4C5D81B5DC3969AD79EA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>overall program outcomes and issues of concern; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9DE7436ABAC442D9B21C2E72B0935B7D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>recommendations for program revisions to achieve the desired program outcome.</text></paragraph></section></subpart><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HD112664E64AD4258808C7FEBB1F72288"><enum>4.</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents in section 2 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 4644 the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8D9F4BA6F106443CBEA3A99E3EDAD1BF" style="OLC">
				<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
					<toc-entry level="subpart">Subpart 5—Engineering Education</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry level="section">4651. Grant program authorized.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry level="section">4652. Annual report to Congress.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


