<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE13F4819EB7E47EB9DC42C697A87BB39" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2615 EH: Gulf Islands National Seashore Land Exchange Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IB</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2615</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To authorize the exchange of certain land located in Gulf Islands National Seashore, Jackson County, Mississippi, between the National Park Service and the Veterans of Foreign Wars, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H8156AF31B9D84FB1A47BFD8FBF5410D3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H851A2697CA0348C7AB3AC43B55E161D6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Gulf Islands National Seashore Land Exchange Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H0B5AFE7DAA9C4C278C131604166D7CD3" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Land exchange, Gulf Islands National Seashore, Jackson County, Mississippi</header> <subsection id="H305CD37FF85F447D94449B2CE71ADD81"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Land exchange authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the National Park Service (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) may convey to the Veterans of Foreign Wars Post 5699 (in this section referred to as the <quote>Post</quote>) all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to a parcel of real property, consisting of approximately 1.542 acres, located within the Gulf Islands National Seashore in Jackson County, Mississippi, and identified as <quote>NPS Exchange Area</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Gulf Islands National Seashore, Proposed Land Exchange with VFW, Davis Bayou Area—Jackson County, MS</quote>, numbered 635/133309, and dated June 2016.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="HCEAD273E3EB743E1B661EF1B78C51641"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Land To be acquired</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In exchange for the property described in subsection (a), the Post shall convey to the Secretary all right, title, and interest of the Post in and to a parcel of real property, consisting of approximately 2.161 acres, located in Jackson County, Mississippi, and identified as <quote>VFW Exchange Area</quote> on the map described in subsection (a).</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H843A421DFB8F4539BE75509354811AEE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Equal value exchange</header> <paragraph id="H91E6B5AAFB0D4AA3A1863D4BE9528AB3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The values of the parcels of real property to be exchanged under this section shall be determined by an appraisal conducted—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8BDDF2D853F44EF39641A4B0E40C2A99"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by a qualified and independent appraiser; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H33442523CCE64D1F967A02211BAAD941"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in accordance with nationally recognized appraisal standards.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3DE1492CABE04526AAECE1044B391F3D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Equalization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the values of the parcels of real property to be exchanged under this section, as determined pursuant to paragraph (1), are not equal, the values shall be equalized through—</text> <subparagraph id="H8DC6BBE03A4E4A8299E3945C9129F915"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a cash payment; or</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H943BC4F09A9C41059F9256DD94682855"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">adjustments to the acreage of the parcels of real property to be exchanged.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC91AE8C62D8B4394A8E504DB8928261E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Payment of costs of conveyance</header> <paragraph id="H30D2F065A48A4B9F91839A3B8FC63FAD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Payment required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall require the Post to cover costs to be incurred by the Secretary, or to reimburse the Secretary for such costs incurred by the Secretary, to carry out the land exchange under this section, including survey costs, costs related to environmental documentation, and any other administrative costs related to the land exchange. If amounts are collected from the Secretary in advance of the Secretary incurring the actual costs and the amount collected exceeds the costs actually incurred by the Secretary to carry out the land exchange, the Secretary shall refund the excess amount to the Post.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H153E3B7606CF4D10A10301C02F8C1173"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of amounts received</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts received as reimbursement under paragraph (1) shall be credited to the fund or account that was used to cover those costs incurred by the Secretary in carrying out the land exchange. Amounts so credited shall be merged with amounts in such fund or account and shall be available for the same purposes, and subject to the same conditions and limitations, as amounts in such fund or account.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF0EAECC175EC4D19A84FF2985ACA7BAA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Description of property</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The exact acreage and legal description of property to be exchanged under this section shall be determined by surveys satisfactory to the Secretary and the Post.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H20DF8A67E0924DD195E22B17091D69CD"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Conveyance agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The exchange of real property under this section shall be accomplished using a quit claim deed or other legal instrument and upon terms and conditions mutually satisfactory to the Secretary and the Post, including such additional terms and conditions as the Secretary considers appropriate to protect the interests of the United States.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HE62CAFF60D554646B00B9DE00741B6D1"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Valid existing rights</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The exchange authorized under this section shall be subject to valid existing rights.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="HB36B419A24E14130AD2170D25383381D"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Title approval</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title to the real property described in subsection (a) and the real property described in subsection (b) to be exchanged under this section shall be in a form acceptable to the Secretary.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H69835E33DBD94922892C1601D05F3DAD"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Treatment of acquired land</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Land and interests in land acquired by the United States under subsection (b) shall be administered by the Secretary as part of the Gulf Islands National Seashore.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H420F04557AE54E37AED3E0FDB9CC81FF"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Modification of boundary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon completion of the land exchange under this section, the Secretary shall modify the boundary of the Gulf Islands National Seashore to reflect such land exchange.</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20171128" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives November 28, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> <endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> </bill> 

