<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H0F11EF81EB9145A182D41E7ACF6E4F8E" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2857 IH: Supporting Families in Substance Abuse Treatment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2857</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170608">June 8, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000184">Mrs. Noem</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To support foster care maintenance payments for children with parents in a licensed residential
			 family-based treatment facility for substance abuse.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H355C5FDF6BC840AA88FE21CBFAD38EE5" style="OLC">
 <section id="HCA042B4C9D544899937FF3EDD0E421AC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supporting Families in Substance Abuse Treatment Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H5BD8C3B725534BEAB101D70B61F2B6C6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Foster care maintenance payments for children with parents in a licensed residential family-based treatment facility for substance abuse</header> <subsection id="HA20C499D246842B2A2A4681713F0F7A7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 472 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/672">42 U.S.C. 672</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6DA84C572509477192AEC25B1CECBBC1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(2)(C), by striking <quote>or</quote> and inserting <quote>, with a parent residing in a licensed residential family-based treatment facility, but only to the extent permitted under subsection (j), or in a </quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H56BA5000EFB14C2897FB980A95F89331"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9E7130ADF65E4EC4B44948AEBE3370AA" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HDC55790E72E54612B43B70D96BCB4C35"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Children placed with a parent residing in a licensed residential family-Based treatment facility for substance abuse</header> <paragraph id="HDF19E3D4BD374A47BB5D10B96D7DB68F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding the preceding provisions of this section, a child who is eligible for foster care maintenance payments under this section, or who would be eligible for the payments if the eligibility were determined without regard to paragraphs (1)(B) and (3) of subsection (a), shall be eligible for the payments for a period of not more than 12 months during which the child is placed with a parent who is in a licensed residential family-based treatment facility for substance abuse, but only if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H51953D302F5C447B8012BDFA4FF42117"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the recommendation for the placement is specified in the child's case plan before the placement;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H130BF5E015A945C3B922D0B00C7C864A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the treatment facility provides, as part of the treatment for substance abuse, parenting skills training, parent education, and individual and family counseling; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6B2F1B1E717847BEA77D7A35EA5B570D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the substance abuse treatment, parenting skills training, parent education, and individual and family counseling is provided under an organizational structure and treatment framework that involves understanding, recognizing, and responding to the effects of all types of trauma and in accordance with recognized principles of a trauma-informed approach and trauma-specific interventions to address the consequences of trauma and facilitate healing.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B60B9D6822A45A5814E4EE083590788"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text>With respect to children for whom foster care maintenance payments are made under paragraph (1), only the children who satisfy the requirements of paragraphs (1)(B) and (3) of subsection (a) shall be considered to be children with respect to whom foster care maintenance payments are made under this section for purposes of subsection (h) or section 473(b)(3)(B).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD1891C390322410580C2CC3A8EED5EF7"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 474(a)(1) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/674">42 U.S.C. 674(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>subject to section 472(j),</quote> before <quote>an amount equal to the Federal</quote> the first place it appears.</text> </subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8EDCD63523ED4A26BA94FD04D52AF446" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Effective date</header> <subsection id="H1FAF2D40955546E2AE228D1AC9058B0A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Effective dates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subsection (b), the amendments made by this Act shall take effect on October 1, 2017.</text>
			</subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5F656651E3C94C64B58A095D0155EBA3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transition rule</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA587DFD8A59F442484F90B9A7CC5B462"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a State plan under part E of title IV of the Social Security Act which the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines requires State legislation (other than legislation appropriating funds) in order for the plan to meet the additional requirements imposed by the amendments made by this Act, the State plan shall not be regarded as failing to comply with the requirements of such part solely on the basis of the failure of the plan to meet such additional requirements before the first day of the first calendar quarter beginning after the close of the first regular session of the State legislature that begins after the date of enactment of this Act. For purposes of the previous sentence, in the case of a State that has a 2-year legislative session, each year of the session shall be deemed to be a separate regular session of the State legislature.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3EEF995293D74793A8C656DB9DE12BBB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application to programs operated by Indian tribal organizations</header><text>In the case of an Indian tribe, tribal organization, or tribal consortium which the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines requires time to take action necessary to comply with the additional requirements imposed by the amendments made by this Act (whether the tribe, organization, or tribal consortium has a plan under section 479B of the Social Security Act or a cooperative agreement or contract entered into with a State), the Secretary shall provide the tribe, organization, or tribal consortium with such additional time as the Secretary determines is necessary for the tribe, organization, or tribal consortium to take the action to comply with the additional requirements before being regarded as failing to comply with the requirements.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


