<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE053B107D3B04E70BFA8DDDE4EC5F852" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4635 IH: To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to increase the number of peer-to-peer counselors providing counseling for women veterans, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4635</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171213">December 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001077">Mr. Coffman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="E000293">Ms. Esty of Connecticut</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to increase the number of peer-to-peer counselors
			 providing counseling for women veterans, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HE8F34F18612C4D75AB3E0C4DFF2F6D3E" style="OLC">
		<section id="H6810D96DD7D247109F0CF372B55758BC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Peer-to-peer counseling program for women veterans</header>
 <subsection id="HC9F54A49BE404D3ABE20A504B8278008"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1720F(j) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE5FBD7FD563A4C8BA772BD1B2D964D13" style="USC">
					<paragraph id="H39E58BECA8D84E7098B6F5B14BAFCC8F" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H8452D97F6AE748D59DE680BE94E24159"><enum>(A)</enum><text>As part of the counseling program under this subsection, the Secretary shall ensure that the program includes a sufficient number of peer counselors for women veterans to meet the demand for such counselors. Such counselors may be employees of the Department and may have expertise in—</text>
 <clause id="HF43CE8377752452C9557AC607AEAFF42" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>gender-specific issues and services;</text> </clause><clause id="H4D8547DE7B9647F792D17D062B76C931" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the provision of information about services and benefits provided under laws administered by the Secretary; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H50A56723FC454CFD8581659C2470F792" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>employment mentoring.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98B1739D7DB844278949BBBC6542B1F4" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this paragraph, the Secretary shall emphasize facilitating peer-to-peer counseling for women veterans who suffered sexual trauma while serving in the Armed Forces, have post-traumatic stress disorder or suffer from another mental health condition, or are otherwise at risk of becoming homeless.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBFAC8366793A49FBBA67DFD7C983DACF" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall conduct outreach to inform women veterans about the program and the assistance available under the program.</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C9250277ED74A399D62EAC67DA16478" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H622106A0316D451280124DF07098B41E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this paragraph, the Secretary shall facilitate engagement and coordination with such community organizations, State and local governments, institutions of higher education, chambers of commerce, local business organizations, organizations that provide legal assistance, and other organizations as the Secretary considers appropriate to facilitate the transition of women described in subparagraph (A) into their communities.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1942B189606B4460BE515D43952A7CD3" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>To the degree practicable, the Secretary shall coordinate facilitation of assistance under this paragraph with the program carried out under section 1144 of title 10.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H494E3101E1314A2C99D42E0A72B3F88B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall carry out paragraph (4) of section 1720F(j) of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), using funds otherwise made available to the Secretary. No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated by reason of such paragraph.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


