<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H331FF91DBDB44C138A25EEE0F1BB7415" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4718 IH: Recognition of Jerusalem as the Capital of the State of Israel Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4718</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171221">December 21, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000621">Mr. DeSantis</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000362">Mr. King of Iowa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001053">Mrs. Hartzler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000552">Mr. Gohmert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001177">Mr. McClintock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000460">Mr. Farenthold</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000815">Mr. Wenstrup</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000592">Mr. Rokita</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000289">Mr. Jordan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000606">Mr. Pittenger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001071">Mr. Jody B. Hice of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000813">Mrs. Walorski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001197">Ms. McSally</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000578">Mr. Gaetz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001172">Mr. Smith of Nebraska</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000065">Mr. Yoho</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001187">Mr. Meadows</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000598">Mr. Rothfus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001189">Mr. Messer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Z000017">Mr. Zeldin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000625">Mr. Donovan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000292">Mr. Johnson of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000816">Mr. Williams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000465">Mr. Ferguson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001243">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To recognize Jerusalem as the capital of Israel and to transfer to Jerusalem the United States
			 Embassy located in Tel Aviv.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HFACC244E4A1145F9827BB445D96AC077" style="OLC">
 <section id="H79D544C30E4147D49BFF50F9897530E1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Recognition of Jerusalem as the Capital of the State of Israel Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H48FD8D882C054A2C86C0FF03D77DFE46" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H38AD08798BC34990AFA851756C93B241"><enum>(1)</enum><text>For more than 3,000 years, the Jewish people have maintained a continuous connection and presence in the land of Israel and their eternal and indivisible capital city of Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF703880512D64DC5898BD006FD587F33"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The State of Israel was established on May 14, 1948, in the wake of World War II in order to serve as a homeland and place of refuge for the Jewish people.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H42FB3A08103A4653A0DBCDCAE842EAC0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>From 1948 to 1967, Jerusalem was a divided city and not all Israeli citizens of all faiths were entitled to visit the holy sites, and Jews from other countries were restricted in their access to holy sites in the area controlled by Jordan. In 1967, the city of Jerusalem was reunited during the conflict known as the Six Day War, and since 1967, Jerusalem has been a unified city administered by Israel, and persons of all faiths have been guaranteed full access to the holy sites within the city.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H17B530D78CCD4518A9CDA226624E3FDF"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On July 31, 1988, Jordan relinquished its disputed sovereignty claims to Judea and Samaria and East Jerusalem, and therefore sovereign claims to these areas remain <quote>disputed</quote>, not <quote>occupied</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H181F2516C93B47CC883094C18E8360B6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In 1990, Congress unanimously adopted Senate Concurrent Resolution 106, which declares that Congress <quote>strongly believes that Jerusalem must remain an undivided city in which the rights of every ethnic religious group are protected</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA0A548FE730E45D38649943F460AA9B6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In 1995, Congress overwhelmingly approved the Jerusalem Embassy Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/45">Public Law 104–45</external-xref>), requiring the establishment of the United States Embassy in Jerusalem not later than May 31, 1999.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF2620D337CF3482CBDF090E948A8126C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The United States maintains its embassy in the functioning capital in every country except in the State of Israel.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5AA3B83ECF15435A8C5D10C949470351"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Israel has far exceeded the 1907 Hague Regulation as directed by international law. Israel has taken all measures to restore and ensure public order and safety in Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H94B701E753074D33B09D0E1E941E37D3"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Jerusalem has been far safer and more protected under Israel’s administration than under any previous authorities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H488B5BED3A5047DF8785D76C1C6C66A3"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Civil life is entirely present in Jerusalem, and all government institutions and related frameworks are also present, including the Knesset, the Bank of Israel, the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, the Prime Minister’s and President’s offices, and the Supreme Court.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HD475E6811B10423DBC99F980CB3157F7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Recognition of Jerusalem as the capital of Israel and relocation of the United States Embassy from
			 Tel Aviv to Jerusalem</header>
 <subsection id="H0EF8DE99AF9F45E69203FF92D6AE49F4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Policy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States to recognize Jerusalem as the undivided capital of the State of Israel, both de jure and de facto.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2AEA3B84E78F45AD888E8F1F18EA4B7A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="HE8B8A002A21B41AE890310364EAC3ACA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the United States should recognize the sovereign status of an undivided Jerusalem as the capital of the State of Israel;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEEAF3B8F40514FC39760ACCC532303A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizing Jerusalem as the capital of Israel and transferring the United States Embassy to Jerusalem from Tel Aviv will send a signal of United States commitment and resolve to Israel;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBE7D8FC8A1B842259DFB4AC612817A66"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the President and the Secretary of State should publicly affirm as a matter of United States policy that Jerusalem must remain the undivided capital of the State of Israel;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H251D088A154B4CA2AE56C914CDDC9398"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the President should immediately implement the provisions of the Jerusalem Embassy Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/45">Public Law 104–45</external-xref>), as amended by section 4 of this Act, and begin the process of relocating the United States Embassy in Israel to Jerusalem; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBF73E36C90944C6395E38846E9DD6CA3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>United States officials should refrain from any actions that contradict United States law on this subject.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC6C7EFBBBECC47ADB5FF9E6534CDD3E6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Identification of Jerusalem on Government Documents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any official document of the United States Government which lists countries and their capital cities shall identify Jerusalem as the capital of Israel.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8CDC38A6D2AA4CBE95C7D35B046DA64C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Relocation</header><text>Not later than January 1, 2019, the President shall relocate the United States Embassy in Israel to Jerusalem.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HE6DCC459CB2847A98BF9E5F1386546C8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Amendment to the Jerusalem Embassy Act of 1995</header>
 <subsection id="HFEDA4ACB54B54D67AECEB1F3BE5BC3D3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Repeal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subsection (b) of this section, section 7 of the Jerusalem Embassy Act of 1995 is repealed.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5E634748C445492B9AB4F1D986958681"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The repeal specified in subsection (a) shall take effect on January 1, 2018.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H8ADCB829246340C188CDB1F464D091CE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Redesignation</header><text>At the time of the repeal specified in subsection (a), section 8 of the Jerusalem Embassy Act of 1995 shall be redesignated as section 7.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HD251CEA65C4A441F8134B1583773E9F7"><enum>5.</enum><header>Implementation report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to Congress a report that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB103DCA6B31D4202A15F584BDC5B6D7F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>details the Department of State’s plan to implement this Act;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H447B5FA6D576452AB30B947F96D2CE27"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes estimated dates of completion for each phase of the establishment of the United States Embassy in Jerusalem, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H93C384F3CD0642718506A2E956B97D08"><enum>(A)</enum><text>site identification;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7350F4B7E2C94124809C7FCDC7384152"><enum>(B)</enum><text>land acquisition;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3FDE704BDF7A4ADB9D4FBBB15692439E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>architectural, engineering, and construction surveys;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC1EC0B235194D0F8D532B629F7A9217"><enum>(D)</enum><text>site preparation; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4866C05248024C6FBA6F25A239E0BBF9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>construction; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF02EFFAD1DB7491DB7BDDF2F4EF19F85"><enum>(3)</enum><text>includes an estimate of the funding needed to implement this Act, including all costs associated with establishing the United States Embassy in Jerusalem.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


