<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HA501633CF94D4E1AB8FDD0A037037A18" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2705 IH: Truck, Trailer, and Transport Efficiency Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2705</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170525">May 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000583">Mr. Loudermilk</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000568">Mr. Griffith</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000604">Mr. Russell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To limit the applicability of the final rule entitled <quote>Greenhouse Gas Emissions and Fuel Efficiency Standards for Medium- and Heavy-Duty Engines and
			 Vehicles—Phase 2</quote> to the extent such final rule relates to trailers that do not themselves emit greenhouse gases in
			 connection with a propulsion system.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H9536705301794C02A46B05F612DB2FA5" style="OLC">
 <section id="H58A70B78FD854069981FEB9D82C9C78A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Truck, Trailer, and Transport Efficiency Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H377D975A3DCA42B8B9BDAF00A1D4FDB3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limitation of applicability of certain rule to the extent such rule relates to trailers that do not themselves emit greenhouse gases in connection with a propulsion system</header> <subsection id="H7085452905D04B5787743428BCA37435"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective as of the date of enactment of this Act, the final rule entitled <quote>Greenhouse Gas Emissions and Fuel Efficiency Standards for Medium- and Heavy-Duty Engines and Vehicles—Phase 2</quote> published in the Federal Register on October 25, 2016 (81 Fed. Reg. 73478), shall cease to apply to the extent such final rule relates to trailers that do not themselves emit greenhouse gases in connection with a propulsion system.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H189FFD3B826F450FA4DDAA55235A4201"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming changes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrators of the Environmental Protection Agency and the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, acting jointly, shall promulgate a final regulation revising the final rule cited in subsection (a) (including the amendments to the Code of Federal Regulations made thereby) so as to make such final rule inapplicable to the extent such final rule relates to trailers that do not themselves emit greenhouse gases in connection with a propulsion system.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


