<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE6F693678C0344818972D26F9A006875" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2147 IH: Veterans Treatment Court Improvement Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2147</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170426">April 26, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001077">Mr. Coffman</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to hire additional Veterans Justice Outreach
			 Specialists to provide treatment court services to justice-involved
			 veterans, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HC3BD9A1B394D4FAAB2E8C7379515B730" style="OLC">
 <section id="H40A906354D8541D9ACF15B5C575C2B93" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Treatment Court Improvement Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H866D35ACD3AA44A08BE83E6B3686BDC7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Hiring by Department of Veterans Affairs of additional Veterans Justice Outreach Specialists</header> <subsection id="HAC27CAB756164AC9B6E4E75B213B72C7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Hiring of additional Veterans Justice Outreach Specialists</header> <paragraph id="H5278F72EDFE648C0ABC08800ED9D753B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall hire not fewer than 50 Veterans Justice Outreach Specialists and place each such Veterans Justice Outreach Specialist at an eligible Department of Veterans Affairs medical center in accordance with this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H48F147BB0F1C4091B04B4A679E6AC5F7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that each Veterans Justice Outreach Specialist employed under paragraph (1)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9184BA4B44FD43D59771143CDB203268"><enum>(A)</enum><text>serves, either exclusively or in addition to other duties, as part of a justice team in a veterans treatment court or other veteran-focused court; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5C6ED80274A4A5784CCBB346EFDF0F4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>otherwise meets Department hiring guidelines for Veterans Justice Outreach Specialists.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4CE5A8CD97FF456E9F3C026155B65243"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Supplement not supplant</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the total number of Veterans Justice Outreach Specialists employed by the Department is not less than the sum of—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H9D716006B68A46F183AEED4D1BA7B78F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the total number of Veterans Justice Outreach Specialists that were employed by the Department on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H11E7C2D204904FC784F3F1BC334F0A85"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of Veterans Justice Outreach Specialists set forth in paragraph (1).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2F0B77B74A5549D38FA6780CB95B82C7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible Department of Veterans Affairs medical centers</header><text>For purposes of this section, an eligible Department of Veterans Affairs medical center is any Department of Veterans Affairs medical center that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB624923D81914C27AA3DD7635FA26FD1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>complies with all Department guidelines and regulations for placement of a Veterans Justice Outreach Specialist;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6E635939B723483DB564E3B67B605A5C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>works within a local criminal justice system with justice-involved veterans;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD99583F037C049F2A7775FFEA55BE96E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>maintains an affiliation with one or more veterans treatment courts or other veteran-focused courts; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE297A10EEA194C00A17D0E2EF0840122"><enum>(4)</enum><text>either—</text> <subparagraph id="HD534D9AAEC4A42D49BFD3C8B43B736B4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>routinely provides Veterans Justice Outreach Specialists to serve as part of a justice team in a veterans treatment court or other veteran-focused court; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8BD4CF80C46F45B0BBC27F7C3AEAAFC2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establishes a plan that is approved by the Secretary to provide Veterans Justice Outreach Specialists employed under subsection (a)(1) to serve as part of a justice team in a veterans treatment court or other veteran-focused court.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC08D9B294A184B9CB867DCCB8E30FAD0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Placement priority</header><text>The Secretary shall prioritize the placement of Veterans Justice Outreach Specialists employed under subsection (a)(1) at eligible Department of Veterans Affairs medical centers that have or intend to establish an affiliation, for the purpose of carrying out the Veterans Justice Outreach Program, with a veterans treatment court, or other veteran-focused court, that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H29AE2B8896A64DDC8783DBDD4BAAE50F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>was established on or after the date of the enactment of this Act; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H584FB7319A924522AA88EC953D3E8BA7"><enum>(2)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H9386E1B0DC74473C835B1DAC39FF761E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>was established before the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB349D3CF2A8B4D1680083BC588E9C8E0" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not fully staffed with Veterans Justice Outreach Specialists.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3322137B9BE54BBD95DE7269447A0C66"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports</header> <paragraph id="H7CFD36E08AF04E52A0C6B07B630C9E34"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Periodic reports by Secretary of Veterans Affairs</header> <subparagraph id="H08A88A0C975549068B73000F3B78201F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act and not less frequently than once every year thereafter, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to Congress a report on the implementation of this section and its effect on the Veterans Justice Outreach Program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5461244D3C0D4EEDB0AC212D28DF59F9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each report submitted under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> <clause id="H2F5C952526AF4BFBA236ED6E5E761C1F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The status of the efforts of the Secretary to hire Veterans Justice Outreach Specialists pursuant to subsection (a)(1), including the total number of Veterans Justice Outreach Specialists hired by the Secretary pursuant to such subsection and the number that the Secretary expects to hire pursuant to such subsection.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE620ADDFDE04433FA55D23CD7FDD12F8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The total number of Veterans Justice Outreach Specialists assigned to each Department of Veterans Affairs medical center that participates in the Veterans Justice Outreach Program, including the number of Veterans Justice Outreach Specialists hired under subsection (a)(1) disaggregated by Department of Veterans Affairs medical center.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3BC920FFF8BF4567857CDF91DA573B49"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The total number of eligible Department of Veterans Affairs medical centers that sought placement of a Veterans Justice Outreach Specialist under subsection (a)(1), how many Veterans Justice Outreach Specialists each such center sought, and how many of such medical centers received no placement of a Veterans Justice Outreach Specialist under subsection (a)(1).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H64B53459674E4F09BEDAAE8A5F468ED7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The total number of justice-involved veterans who were served or are expected to be served by a Veterans Justice Outreach Specialist hired under subsection (a)(1).</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5891811E581F46F18AB0D77932997BB6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report by Comptroller General of the United States</header>
 <subparagraph id="H9C1C7F39FFF74B4AACB9D9E37FDBDF72"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report on the implementation of this section and the effectiveness of the Veterans Justice Outreach Program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56EABEC8B9DC41489B2E66074E2C6865"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report required by subparagraph (A) shall include the following:</text> <clause id="HA84D4D5CA5B84B62A33C297056D01432"><enum>(i)</enum><text>An assessment of whether the Secretary has fulfilled the Secretary's obligations under this section.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7A57E889232A459989583C237A5AD8FA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The number of veterans who are served by Veterans Justice Outreach Specialists hired under subsection (a)(1), disaggregated by demographics (including discharge status).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9D515915C3B2496694F23C005E20E89F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>An identification of any subgroups of veterans who underutilize services provided under laws administered by the Secretary, including an assessment of whether these veterans have access to Veterans Justice Outreach Specialists under the Veterans Justice Outreach Program.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE10CFFC6DF8B41189AFB63CA907E2259"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Such recommendations as the Comptroller General may have for the Secretary to improve the effectiveness of the Veterans Justice Outreach Program.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H387E33F558F244D4A59E49FFE1EC5DAD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <paragraph id="H777ADF9481E84C158781B12D0C2AC5E3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out subsection (a) $5,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2027.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HECE21104E89046D4B292AA8566293D77"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Identification of offsets</header><text>The Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that identifies such legislative or administrative actions as the Secretary determines will result in a reduction in expenditures by the Department of Veterans Affairs that is equal to or greater than the amounts authorized to be appropriated by paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H060213D396D64D388069924CE380023A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H721D57A4C5D2475DB375D3C038D069D1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Justice team</header><text>The term <term>justice team</term> means the group of individuals, which may include a judge, court coordinator, prosecutor, public defender, treatment provider, probation or other law enforcement officer, program mentor, and Veterans Justice Outreach Specialist, who assist justice-involved veterans in a veterans treatment court or other veteran-focused court.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB78EE6F1DA41483291E4E5AD37C791C8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Justice-involved veteran</header><text>The term <term>justice-involved veteran</term> means a veteran with active, ongoing, or recent contact with some component of a local criminal justice system.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4F4F1683418D46359F12406E01F98D84"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Local criminal justice system</header><text>The term <term>local criminal justice system</term> means law enforcement, jails, prisons, and State and local courts.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA75CA34E08AE49D58A0CB2D8D5C10A07"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Veterans Justice Outreach Program</header><text>The term <term>Veterans Justice Outreach Program</term> means the program through which the Department of Veterans Affairs identifies justice-involved veterans and provides such veterans with access to Department services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H75A8B46C720C4AA2AC7FD01E58507A2C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Veterans Justice Outreach Specialist</header><text>The term <term>Veterans Justice Outreach Specialist</term> means an employee of the Department of Veterans Affairs who serves as a liaison between the Department and the local criminal justice system on behalf of a justice-involved veteran.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDF56C57E95814A23B388E0238ADA4BF6"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Veterans treatment court</header><text>The term <term>veterans treatment court</term> means a State or local court that is participating in the veterans treatment court program (as defined in section 2991(i)(1) of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3797aa">42 U.S.C. 3797aa(i)(1)</external-xref>)).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


