<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF6FE4907E16B42C3AB1970587008DF8C" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2847 EH: Improving Services for Older Youth in Foster Care Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2847</legis-num>
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To make improvements to the John H. Chafee Foster Care Independence Program and related provisions.</official-title>
</form> 
<legis-body id="H3ED459EC8AD9441FAA36B5884C1C846E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB90766212E914E518CA6AFBD87F1E8BA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Improving Services for Older Youth in Foster Care Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H86FCDC9B0EAE48948FB669CB8B356EB1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improvements to the John H. Chafee Foster Care Independence Program and related provisions</header> <subsection id="H1FA6C5B483EE452FA96412A5EBFCCA40"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority To serve former foster youth up to age <enum-in-header>23</enum-in-header></header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 477 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/677">42 U.S.C. 677</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC45B913A3D3B41F58113CB653F100DFA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(5), by inserting <quote>(or 23 years of age, in the case of a State with a certification under subsection (b)(3)(A)(ii) to provide assistance and services to youths who have aged out of foster care and have not attained such age, in accordance with such subsection)</quote> after <quote>21 years of age</quote>;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HAEB681713B40491BBA02F7E906BEA7AD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(3)(A)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6F4E23BDA89D424F972C15A405165363"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(i)</quote> before <quote>A certification</quote>;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5C4D1897DADA453C826441078BF74F8E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>children who have left foster care</quote> and all that follows through the period and inserting <quote>youths who have aged out of foster care and have not attained 21 years of age.</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB7AA9E8272AB47758A114AFAA3798D8B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H1138CFFDAE27441D9386F671ACD31264" style="OLC"> <clause id="HED468EFBB088407A9403646B92E82A92" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>If the State has elected under section 475(8)(B) to extend eligibility for foster care to all children who have not attained 21 years of age, or if the Secretary determines that the State agency responsible for administering the State plans under this part and part B uses State funds or any other funds not provided under this part to provide services and assistance for youths who have aged out of foster care that are comparable to the services and assistance the youths would receive if the State had made such an election, the certification required under clause (i) may provide that the State will provide assistance and services to youths who have aged out of foster care and have not attained 23 years of age.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H43E75EFDFE8B43AA98B80123103D8BDA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(3)(B), by striking <quote>children who have left foster care</quote> and all that follows through the period and inserting <quote>youths who have aged out of foster care and have not attained 21 years of age (or 23 years of age, in the case of a State with a certification under subparagraph (A)(i) to provide assistance and services to youths who have aged out of foster care and have not attained such age, in accordance with subparagraph (A)(ii)).</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB36DCBED04394CDB812E546660FB84F6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authority To redistribute unspent funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 477(d) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/677">42 U.S.C. 677(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA216FC68AD5F44FF998806604FC50F2C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by inserting <quote>or does not expend allocated funds within the time period specified under section 477(d)(3)</quote> after <quote>provided by the Secretary</quote>; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H9A46A9E5CA64459EAAD6947E3742CEA5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HE1222F6977F540D6957C04489C0CAA18" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="HB7AEC73C602446AABD44D3A1FE55CE36"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Redistribution of unexpended amounts</header> 
<subparagraph id="H659E8E0C8ECD4A2EAA9509709A708496"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Availability of amounts</header><text>To the extent that amounts paid to States under this section in a fiscal year remain unexpended by the States at the end of the succeeding fiscal year, the Secretary may make the amounts available for redistribution in the second succeeding fiscal year among the States that apply for additional funds under this section for that second succeeding fiscal year.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HABE4BC04AF80466594066D691867B03E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Redistribution</header> <clause id="H89BFCB189382432A8AE932D369B1D941"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall redistribute the amounts made available under subparagraph (A) for a fiscal year among eligible applicant States. In this subparagraph, the term <term>eligible applicant State</term> means a State that has applied for additional funds for the fiscal year under subparagraph (A) if the Secretary determines that the State will use the funds for the purpose for which originally allotted under this section.</text> </clause>
<clause id="H3D92036F978C40D78A21C2376E160346"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Amount to be redistributed</header><text>The amount to be redistributed to each eligible applicant State shall be the amount so made available multiplied by the State foster care ratio (as defined in subsection (c)(4), except that, in such subsection, <quote>all eligible applicant States (as defined in subsection (d)(5)(B)(i))</quote> shall be substituted for <quote>all States</quote>).</text> </clause> <clause id="H4668D53F89244EB9A217CCF3782B5E22"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Treatment of redistributed amount</header><text>Any amount made available to a State under this paragraph shall be regarded as part of the allotment of the State under this section for the fiscal year in which the redistribution is made.</text> </clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6AF5F5B720524F43834AAAB2C0F54C28"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Tribes</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>State</term> includes an Indian tribe, tribal organization, or tribal consortium that receives an allotment under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9608F779F14F42E98CDC533359E66389"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Expanding and clarifying the use of education and training vouchers</header> <paragraph id="H5A265511B37841A9A99D6F2F0DE95A12"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 477(i)(3) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/677">42 U.S.C. 677(i)(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H42514D6498C64005911CEA79C39EAA42"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>on the date</quote> and all that follows through <quote>23</quote> and inserting <quote>to remain eligible until they attain 26</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H65363DD9BD55416BAEB741C15DE7AA62"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, but in no event may a youth participate in the program for more than 5 years (whether or not consecutive)</quote> before the period.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H74613EED06B5414DB4FF31F5E4A6CBBE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 477(i)(1) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/677">42 U.S.C. 677(i)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>who have attained 14 years of age</quote> before the period.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H037C6714F117423EAE484CB8E00A44AD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Other improvements</header><text>Section 477 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/677">42 U.S.C. 677</external-xref>), as amended by subsections (a), (b), and (c) of this section, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0AFA2CD1729E48A0B54C577D9BD95B22"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the section heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Independence Program</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Program for Successful Transition to Adulthood</header-in-text></quote>;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H8BDCDCD683974EDABEB8EF40CD20B53C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> 
<subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H641BD10ABBAC497181FE1E608AE3174A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> <clause id="H8D514AB375684B2BA5A06149DB1341EB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>identify children who are likely to remain in foster care until 18 years of age and to help these children make the transition to self-sufficiency by providing services</quote> and inserting <quote>support all youth who have experienced foster care at age 14 or older in their transition to adulthood through transitional services</quote>;</text> </clause>
<clause id="HD09D41FD9FCC4C5E96D67829F7150CD8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>and post-secondary education</quote> after <quote>high school diploma</quote>; and</text> </clause> <clause id="HD67D0C8BAF3742CF9FB373611CB29ED0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>training in daily living skills, training in budgeting and financial management skills</quote> and inserting <quote>training and opportunities to practice daily living skills (such as financial literacy training and driving instruction)</quote>;</text> </clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6B4117B9974E4263AA7C7DC55EAF9267"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>who are likely to remain in foster care until 18 years of age receive the education, training, and services necessary to obtain employment</quote> and inserting <quote>who have experienced foster care at age 14 or older achieve meaningful, permanent connections with a caring adult</quote>;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4D4C1C8F08E24F72A729886F9B88C6E9"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>who are likely to remain in foster care until 18 years of age prepare for and enter postsecondary training and education institutions</quote> and inserting <quote>who have experienced foster care at age 14 or older engage in age or developmentally appropriate activities, positive youth development, and experiential learning that reflects what their peers in intact families experience</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2BF8C9AACCE14805A11DDCE66C200746"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (4) and redesignating paragraphs (5) through (8) as paragraphs (4) through (7);</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H085013F3A20F4F5BA97330AB23B8E975"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6A6F4D673D4847CAA51C8DDC4DD9075B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(D), by striking <quote>adolescents</quote> and inserting <quote>youth</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA4F135D3AF9245239890A4E9E62EE907"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text> 
<clause id="HE213A829197742289C221630D3D64A06"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D)—</text> <subclause id="H51327E0749EE4520986A777B504522DE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>including training on youth development</quote> after <quote>to provide training</quote>; and</text> </subclause>
<subclause id="H666D9AB185CD493AB91E5DE56675D56B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>adolescents preparing for independent living</quote> and all that follows through the period and inserting <quote>youth preparing for a successful transition to adulthood and making a permanent connection with a caring adult.</quote>;</text> </subclause></clause> <clause id="HA2486EBBA0434EA7B5EB8981C4CEA57E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (H), by striking <quote>adolescents</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>youth</quote>; and</text> </clause>
<clause id="HB32085CE85E5441D9121C17A77F5865C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (K)—</text> <subclause id="H9F5D1B1862E44CFFB61539CD0CBB7EF7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>an adolescent</quote> and inserting <quote>a youth</quote>; and</text> </subclause>
<subclause id="HFEAAA4C368F9456FB7039D9EEE1944C6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the adolescent</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>the youth</quote>; and</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H689794378590414C82FB6884EA58E5C0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (f), by striking paragraph (2) and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H0E6B0ACE067C4AC5AAD9373FB7F6F980" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H4E1EB08D938540A4B798AE0B9AE676F9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report to congress</header><text>Not later than October 1, 2018, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate a report on the National Youth in Transition Database and any other databases in which States report outcome measures relating to children in foster care and children who have aged out of foster care or left foster care for kinship guardianship or adoption. The report shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HB105E1F57F404B9F9926611161EE487A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of the reasons for entry into foster care and of the foster care experiences, such as length of stay, number of placement settings, case goal, and discharge reason of 17-year-olds who are surveyed by the National Youth in Transition Database and an analysis of the comparison of that description with the reasons for entry and foster care experiences of children of other ages who exit from foster care before attaining age 17.</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBB680CD50EA44F249F394114A2BA4C19"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of the characteristics of the individuals who report poor outcomes at ages 19 and 21 to the National Youth in Transition Database.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7D3DB2277BDC428E8270DAEE14BDB37C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Benchmarks for determining what constitutes a poor outcome for youth who remain in or have exited from foster care and plans the executive branch will take to incorporate these benchmarks in efforts to evaluate child welfare agency performance in providing services to children transitioning from foster care.</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC440A1A80A3B4A6F91EE09184A6FD909"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An analysis of the association between types of placement, number of overall placements, time spent in foster care, and other factors, and outcomes at ages 19 and 21.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1FF6AB7139FD44DFBDC71907DC6D0FA2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>An analysis of the differences in outcomes for children in and formerly in foster care at age 19 and 21 among States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HB1D4EDB7DE464A00812EC92C43D9ABF2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Clarifying documentation provided to foster youth leaving foster care</header><text>Section 475(5)(I) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/675">42 U.S.C. 675(5)(I)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after <quote>REAL ID Act of 2005</quote> the following: <quote>, and any official documentation necessary to prove that the child was previously in foster care</quote>.</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20170620" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives June 20, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> <endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> </bill> 

