<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF6C34D38625843A68515F65D4DD5312E" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3237 IH: To require the Secretary of State to withhold certain assistance for Honduras until the President certifies to Congress that the Government of Honduras has settled all known commercial disputes with United States citizens.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3237</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170713">July 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000409">Mr. Rohrabacher</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of State to withhold certain assistance for Honduras until the President
			 certifies to Congress that the Government of Honduras has settled all
			 known commercial disputes with United States citizens.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HE021CBDC402048DC82F8F3AC3485A797" style="OLC">
		<section id="H55D428D77A884900B89FAF83A7A4D531" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Limitation on assistance to Honduras</header>
 <subsection id="H6701E3A8C47144628EA964916AE85748"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the amounts made available to the Secretary of State for assistance for Honduras for fiscal year 2017, $50,000,000 may not be obligated or expended by the Secretary until the date on which the President certifies to Congress that the Government of Honduras has settled all commercial disputes with United States citizens that were filed before the date of enactment of this Act, including disputes relating to the confiscation of real property.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H90EEF85D3F094ECA8B414109EA701C8D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Commercial dispute; confiscation of real property</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a), the terms <quote>commercial dispute</quote> and <quote>confiscation of real property</quote> have the meanings given those terms for purposes of the certification required under section 7045(a)(4)(B)(xii) of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/31">Public Law 115–31</external-xref>).</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


