<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB58C9035EB6548A68A7CD6D2538CF108" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1542 IH: Helping Ensure Life- and Limb-Saving Access to Podiatric Physicians Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1542</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170315">March 15, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000292">Mr. Johnson of Ohio</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001251">Mr. Butterfield</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000813">Mrs. Walorski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000487">Mr. Royce of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001087">Mr. Crawford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001105">Mrs. Comstock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000815">Mr. Wenstrup</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001181">Mr. Meehan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000570">Mr. Ben Ray Luján of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000062">Mr. Yarmuth</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to cover physician services delivered by podiatric
			 physicians to ensure access by Medicaid beneficiaries to appropriate
			 quality foot and ankle care, to amend title XVIII of such Act to modify
			 the requirements for diabetic shoes to be included under Medicare, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H89DE9E0C36E248549F4840C8A934DC3B" style="OLC">
 <section id="HF4FE70E17CE84BC79A4677FD99E004EE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Helping Ensure Life- and Limb-Saving Access to Podiatric Physicians Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>HELLPP Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H42C2487FB9A84246B4C6558B93100E43"><enum>2.</enum><header>Recognizing doctors of podiatric medicine as physicians under the medicaid program</header> <subsection id="H9D111C14F3D141BA9380599B4795FC49"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1905(a)(5)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d(a)(5)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 1861(r)(1)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (1) and (3) of section 1861(r)</quote>.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H7FA53389836E4614855A7255262951A3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HF07C97127C6447EE8C0BEA40FC083A08"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply to services furnished on or after January 1, 2018.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H242B3A0481914762B90A5247BE0BBB70"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Extension of effective date for State law amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a State plan under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396</external-xref> et seq.) which the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines requires State legislation in order for the plan to meet the additional requirement imposed by the amendment made by subsection (a), the State plan shall not be regarded as failing to comply with the requirements of such title solely on the basis of its failure to meet these additional requirements before the first day of the first calendar quarter beginning after the close of the first regular session of the State legislature that begins after the date of enactment of this Act. For purposes of the previous sentence, in the case of a State that has a 2-year legislative session, each year of the session is considered to be a separate regular session of the State legislature.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0EF950F5F3A3452FADDB52CA271833BA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Clarifying medicare documentation requirements for therapeutic shoes for persons with diabetes</header>
 <subsection id="HCF231327B7DA4A59B435899877C2D0DD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1861(s)(12) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(s)(12)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD450AECDD6924E2F9B98938939D75F92" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HCFDBEE50D7854154A675388C41FAAB0A"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subject to section 4072(e) of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1987, extra-depth shoes with inserts or custom molded shoes with inserts (in this paragraph referred to as <quote>therapeutic shoes</quote>) for an individual with diabetes, if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H11E5D14858874206A468570EAD96028C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the physician who is managing the individual’s diabetic condition—</text> <clause id="H96C61288623C4732B360D613F81A53D8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>documents that the individual has diabetes;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H03020D014DBF4511BB2EC3598EBE6429"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>certifies that the individual is under a comprehensive plan of care related to the individual’s diabetic condition; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H051F16C53FDF42CCAF479FE572451C10"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>documents agreement with the prescribing podiatrist or other qualified physician (as established by the Secretary) that it is medically necessary for the individual to have therapeutic shoes;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4AB73B6C4A0455598B999B17C8AF683"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the therapeutic shoes are prescribed by a podiatrist or other qualified physician (as established by the Secretary) who—</text>
 <clause id="HBB354A3FF41D46918432D616E566895A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>examines the individual and determines the medical necessity for the individual to receive the therapeutic shoes; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7E94A6FB6BD647C3BD18D865A96B7650"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>communicates in writing the medical necessity to a certifying doctor of medicine or osteopathy for the individual to have therapeutic shoes along with findings that the individual has peripheral neuropathy with evidence of callus formation, a history of pre-ulcerative calluses, a history of previous ulceration, foot deformity, previous amputation, or poor circulation; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33A21AA60D08478A86763EEF14C05016"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the therapeutic shoes are fitted and furnished by a podiatrist or other qualified supplier individual (as established by the Secretary), such as a pedorthist or orthotist, who is not the physician described in subparagraph (A) (unless the Secretary finds that the physician is the only such qualified individual in the area);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H944BADE2A946454384826C301016E94E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to items and services furnished on or after January 1, 2018.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD659109C63E34EA38CE1C2CD68D560AC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed as expanding Medicare coverage for therapeutic shoes for individuals with diabetes.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HB40F3BA7A55141F7A655C2196A785C4E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Budget savings: strengthening Medicaid program integrity through continuous levy on payments to
			 Medicaid providers and suppliers</header>
 <subsection id="H2203A623C00149DC85CC3CA507866B1D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6331">Section 6331(h)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (defining specified payment) is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (B), by striking the period at the end of subparagraph (C) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H6CE89BB4A8AA4642AAF882C8493D3A61" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="HE67BE25D93DA4F4DA505457C1F66F81F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any payment to any Medicaid provider or supplier under a State plan under title XIX of the Social Security Act.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H59B22F3FBF294896AF510000062F063E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to levies issued after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


