<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC9EC217DBBFD4F0AB9B92FDFFA733650" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3220 IH: Preserving Taxpayers’ Rights Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3220</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170713">July 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001195">Mr. Smith of Missouri</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001107">Mr. Curbelo of Florida</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001065">Mr. Holding</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to preserve taxpayers’ rights to administrative appeal
			 of deficiency determinations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HE3DFB4AEDB724496AC45D927F1A398CE" style="OLC">
		<section id="H047CF2F2D4734733B3D8254EA88C157B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title, etc</header>
 <subsection id="H159436CFF7324E9187F0160D3B4FF6C0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preserving Taxpayers’ Rights Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HF9AF6F58CBEE40D098345149F1A00D88"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents of this bill is as follows:</text>
				<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
					<toc-entry idref="H047CF2F2D4734733B3D8254EA88C157B" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title, etc.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HF37C2BE0CC1040FF89D6F29190838121" level="section">Sec. 2. Ensuring taxpayer right to appeal.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H0CF9FAEF2B1F44C3863E6ADCD570F4C8" level="section">Sec. 3. Appeals dispute resolution procedures.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H4DA31363953C4F309F888421F57D604D" level="section">Sec. 4. Restriction on Secretarial authority to designate cases for litigation.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H8069527A3B144970A04BCA300A56FAAE" level="section">Sec. 5. Modification of authority to issue designated summons.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H8BF2AE49805A4EB4AA433F2C9117154C" level="section">Sec. 6. Limitation on access of non-Internal Revenue Service employees to returns and return
			 information.</toc-entry>
				</toc>
			</subsection></section><section id="HF37C2BE0CC1040FF89D6F29190838121" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Ensuring taxpayer right to appeal</header>
 <subsection id="H47179326814B4C1B9635831ADAB0AEBD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subsection (a) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6212">section 6212</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HD6743B33B0564FF69DF4CD84D1E85E9B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">In general</header-in-text>.—If the Secretary</quote> and inserting</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1479AA7317A94B62AFB1D5D6B869ED8C" style="OLC">
 <text><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">In general</header-in-text>.—</text><paragraph id="HBFFE77532ADD484C98F2DA4F4716E911"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>If—</text> <subparagraph id="HB1AA2089F4EE4DE7903DEA5F434E0D3F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE4B3D88B730A4940887BCA88CCF78B4C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>44, he is authorized</quote> and inserting</text> <quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H51455343BC37424C987F8FEB7B29D4B9" style="OLC"> <text>44, and</text><subparagraph id="H432D8A1EF5664C6ABF7C2D09E10B73F8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the requirements of paragraph (2) have been met with respect to such deficiency,</text> </subparagraph><quoted-block-continuation-text quoted-block-continuation-text-level="paragraph">the Secretary is authorized</quoted-block-continuation-text><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H47E40CFD13D64502A9AD29B505C3FACD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block act-name="" id="HB88C728C962F4E5C8F1A156E6AE31FDE" style="OLC">
						<paragraph id="H13B825AA48494273AF202975281D25CB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Opportunity for administrative review in the Office of Appeals</header>
 <subparagraph id="H03C59C4C692A40ADBC44DFF55BEB9A6A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The requirements of this paragraph are met with respect to a deficiency if, prior to the issuance of the notice of deficiency under paragraph (1)—</text>
 <clause id="H4D88507164434CCF887511E0A72A59A7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the taxpayer has been issued a letter of proposed deficiency that explains the basis for the determination of deficiency and allows the taxpayer an opportunity for administrative review in the Internal Revenue Service Office of Appeals, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDAEA5C05C0FD42F39D9ED193C0357BD0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>either—</text> <subclause id="HBB18981A3EFD42ACB42674A431F6552E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the time provided in such letter for requesting administrative review in the Internal Revenue Service Office of Appeals has expired and the taxpayer has not made such request, or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H6CA4775779064237B22F4B48D5DF4A64"><enum>(II)</enum><text>such Office of Appeals officially concluded the administrative review process with respect to such deficiency.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB47BB8D48FAD4CC9AE3E1FD48236D246"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Frivolous tax positions</header><text>The Secretary is authorized to issue regulations limiting the application of subparagraph (A) in cases involving solely the failure or refusal to comply with the tax laws because of moral, religious, political, constitutional, conscientious, or similar grounds, or for other positions listed as frivolous under section 6702(c).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49164406980344C6ACE890DA4524F213"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Cases designated for litigation</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply in the case of issues designated for litigation in accordance with section 7124, and the taxpayer’s right to administrative review in the Internal Revenue Service Office of Appeals as provided in this paragraph shall not otherwise be denied.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H32581477E363492290FB2C87A79356CB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Opportunity for appeal if fewer than 60 days remain on statute of limitations</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6212">Section 6212</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block act-name="" id="H90EFEE5D2BC149669400FE5F90DD2542" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H5E45612C755E4F09A1F27C86B7EE03CA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Opportunity for appeal if fewer than 60 days remain on statute of limitations</header><text>In the case of any issues relating to a potential deficiency with respect to which 60 days or fewer remain in the period applicable under section 6501, if the taxpayer agrees to the extension of such period by 12 months, the Secretary shall issue a letter of proposed deficiency described in subsection (a)(2)(A)(i) allowing the taxpayer an opportunity for administrative review of such issues in the Internal Revenue Service Office of Appeals before a notice of deficiency is issued under this section. Rules similar to the rules of subsection (a)(2)(B) shall apply for purposes of this subsection.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCCF0DCB688F24A018A94E623ADAE9E29"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to notices of deficiency issued after the date of the introduction of this Act.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H0CF9FAEF2B1F44C3863E6ADCD570F4C8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Appeals dispute resolution procedures</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subsection (a) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7123">section 7123</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block act-name="" id="H10DCDD829BFB4284850263ABEF0B0837" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H7C96423B1684402382DE76F507E82D43"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Referral to appeals procedures</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe procedures by which any taxpayer may request—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB5F6256601AF42D982417AE0B8448F6F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>early referral of one or more unresolved issues from the examination or collection division to the Internal Revenue Service Office of Appeals, or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF56AED6A5FE149BFA62ADBFEB93BEC80"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consideration by such Office of Appeals of issues included in—</text> <subparagraph id="H225C79DDCC214DF797F0ED0A15BE41C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a letter of proposed deficiency described in section 6212(a)(2)(A),</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H981E5D2A75DD4F1F9C250A66895AF084"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a notice of deficiency pursuant to section 6212, whether or not the taxpayer has filed a petition with the Tax Court pursuant to section 6213(a), or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33BE39ABB3554F518FC37F22BC3C90D3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a claim for refund, whether or not the taxpayer has filed suit in a district court or the United States Court of Federal Claims with respect to the issues included in such claim or refund.</text>
						</subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">Such regulations may limit such procedures in cases involving solely the failure or refusal to
			 comply with the tax laws because of moral, religious, political,
			 constitutional, conscientious, or similar grounds, or for other positions
			 listed as frivolous under section 6702(c). Such procedures shall not be
			 available in the case of issues designated for litigation in accordance
			 with section 7124, and the taxpayer’s right to administrative review in
			 the Internal Revenue Service Office of Appeals as provided in section
			 6212(a)(2) shall not otherwise be denied.</continuation-text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="H4DA31363953C4F309F888421F57D604D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Restriction on Secretarial authority to designate cases for litigation</header>
 <subsection id="HD701DB3CDBA54E4EAF314F5451D921D0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/74">Chapter 74</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by redesignating section 7124 as section 7125 and by inserting after section 7123 the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block act-name="" id="H6CF8712CFEC44E69A9E2930E805A1471" style="OLC">
					<section id="H2D4C7C7D601D4C8B9352899BDE2410C8"><enum>7124.</enum><header>Restriction on Secretarial authority to designate cases for litigation</header>
 <subsection id="H968A1E9360854287A3AAB6696E005267"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may designate issues arising from the examination or collection division for litigation, and not permit the taxpayer to request consideration of such issues by the Internal Revenue Service Office of Appeals under section 7123(a), only to the extent such issues relate to listed transactions (as defined in section 6707A(c)(2)).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HED05D6D664F94C6D83F6BD9CAFA909AC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Settlement</header><text>In offering terms under a settlement agreement for purposes of the resolution of any issues arising from the examination or collection division, the Secretary may offer terms that preclude the taxpayer from requesting consideration of such issues by the Office of Appeals under section 7123(a) only to the extent such issues relate to listed transactions (as defined in section 6707A(c)(2)).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H710A71F25419490D9FB430BE66E8A5D5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/74">chapter 74</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7124">section 7124</external-xref> and inserting the following new items:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE8406A1B228E4AD892C67B5C3DAF58C1" style="OLC">
					<toc>
						<toc-entry idref="H2D4C7C7D601D4C8B9352899BDE2410C8" level="section">Sec. 7124. Restriction on Secretarial authority to designate cases for litigation.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 7125. Cross references.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD7BA8DC95C39437BBB164142A1E15405"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to the designation of issues for litigation, and offers of settlement terms, after the date of the introduction of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H8069527A3B144970A04BCA300A56FAAE"><enum>5.</enum><header>Modification of authority to issue designated summons</header>
 <subsection id="H9839C344B8864828A64F4D42AD2EBCA6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Paragraph (1) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6503">section 6503(j)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>coordinated examination program</quote> and inserting <quote>coordinated industry case program</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H36853FDE35B240E7830E3754F8367D70"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designated summons</header><text>Clause (i) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6503">section 6503(j)(2)(A)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block act-name="" id="H2A737B7B3B374E4CAA441755515A68B8" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H128AFC334C7E40329D57B89552A103CF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the issuance of such summons is preceded by a review and written approval of such issuance by the Large Business and International Division Commissioner and the Division Counsel of the Office of Chief Counsel (or their successors)—</text>
 <subclause id="HD4C71680B89B4387B2E08662026B5AB2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>which clearly establishes that the taxpayer did not reasonably cooperate with reasonable requests by the Secretary for witnesses, documents, meetings, and interviews, and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H9627B493EE2A45D393615A252942325B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>which is attached to such summons,</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="HA056FC3E5E804FB2903758A89D92AA7C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Burden of proof</header><text>Subsection (j) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6503">section 6503</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block act-name="" id="HA5B4B2CD67274A2AA90697572EFFA0E8" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H54012E9B68CE48D493E35B9FA7074D66"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Burden of proof</header><text>In any court proceeding described in paragraph (3), the Secretary shall bear the burden of proving that the corporation described in paragraph (1) did not reasonably cooperate with reasonable requests by the Secretary for witnesses, documents, meetings, and interviews.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H793283B4FD624A67AA5652530ADEA507"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to summonses issued after the date of the introduction of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H8BF2AE49805A4EB4AA433F2C9117154C"><enum>6.</enum><header>Limitation on access of non-Internal Revenue Service employees to returns and return information</header>
 <subsection id="H5C497F8DF26840E59E3970FAC2406EA2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7602">Section 7602</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H8F9C287B2BAE4360993D9D6CD4FC07B4" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HF22D92D2D2094FDE9B864950604D64E8"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Limitation on access of persons other than Internal Revenue Service officers and employees</header><text>No person other than an officer or employee of the Internal Revenue Service shall be designated under section 6103(n) to receive any books, papers, records, or other data obtained pursuant to this section, other than for the sole purpose of serving as an expert, and no person other than an officer or employee of the Internal Revenue Service or the Office of Chief Counsel may question a witness under oath whose testimony was obtained pursuant to this section.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H29B4E03B92824246A46AB3719D4A3F18"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header>
 <paragraph id="HFF8E5D34D11C4B8D83AF38EB8B0330FC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendment made by this section shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1FA2B8D99D1B413D9009F1A522ECC0F4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application to contracts in effect</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to any contract in effect under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">section 6103(n)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, pursuant to temporary Treasury Regulation section 301.7602–1T proposed in Internal Revenue Bulletin 2014–28, Treasury Regulation section 301.7602–1(b)(3), or any similar or successor regulation, that is in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


