<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCD67BB54CCD7468DA7FAB6E745C32BCE" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1917 IH: Blocking Regulatory Interference from Closing Kilns Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1917</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170405">April 5, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000292">Mr. Johnson of Ohio</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000591">Mrs. Roby</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001151">Mr. Murphy of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To allow for judicial review of any final rule addressing national emission standards for hazardous
			 air pollutants for brick and structural clay products or for clay ceramics
			 manufacturing before requiring compliance with such rule.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H8A25613EDCFC40928B3E3A22866CB2DC" style="OLC">
 <section id="H0C59CC588C0D4BF0ABFCE9F96FD4FFEF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Blocking Regulatory Interference from Closing Kilns Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H1D34AAB92BD34422AD601D90E06893D9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Extending compliance dates (pending judicial review) of rules addressing national emission standards for hazardous air pollutants for brick and structural clay products manufacturing or clay ceramics manufacturing</header> <subsection id="H31A5A3BDA9E648A883F26B2FD5A223C5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Extension of compliance dates</header> <paragraph id="H49B1F6E783B14CA6A8E5731F04C78DAB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>Each compliance date of any final rule described in subsection (b) is deemed to be extended by the time period equal to the time period described in subsection (c).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H46598FD3B75846E2B2BB2B6F0867CC29"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>compliance date</term> means, with respect to any requirement of a final rule described in subsection (b), the date by which any State, local, or tribal government or other person is first required to comply.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1F20E13E576645EBB818AC48A81580CD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Final rules described</header><text>A final rule described in this subsection is any final rule to address national emission standards for hazardous air pollutants (NESHAP) for brick and structural clay products manufacturing or clay ceramics manufacturing under section 112 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7412">42 U.S.C. 7412</external-xref>), including—</text>
 <paragraph id="H12197F86D59F4EC99C7AEF7A82FB755A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the final rule entitled <quote>NESHAP for Brick and Structural Clay Products Manufacturing; and NESHAP for Clay Ceramics Manufacturing</quote> published at 80 Fed. Reg. 65469 (October 26, 2015);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE5A3EE1C7D5B46C3B8B6923D05612720"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the final rule entitled <quote>NESHAP for Brick and Structural Clay Products Manufacturing; and NESHAP for Clay Ceramics Manufacturing: Correction</quote> published at 80 Fed. Reg. 75817 (December 4, 2015); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA89C94F3DDFE4330BC01A38517A32A3C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any final rule that succeeds or amends the rule described in paragraph (1) or (2).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H74851B2993734E159246A917066F1781"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Period described</header><text>The time period described in this subsection is the period of days that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4A94D23B638E4DA38B483E8946537B5F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>begins on the date that is 60 days after the day on which notice of promulgation of a final rule described in subsection (b) appears in the Federal Register; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF8FFEA01E46545BDA111318DD37C2B50"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ends on the date on which judgment becomes final, and no longer subject to further appeal or review, in all actions (including actions that are filed pursuant to section 307 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7607">42 U.S.C. 7607</external-xref>))—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1F8484DEA57A4CA89B6AE807E9A733A4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that are filed during the 60 days described in paragraph (1); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B8F9F989BDD4CE9BF70585413C198A1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that seek review of any aspect of such rule.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


