<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H68922F4DB7D848F4B7BBB70B981EB41C" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3331 IH: To amend title XI of the Social Security Act to promote testing of incentive payments for behavioral health providers for adoption and use of certified electronic health record technology.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3331</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170720">July 20, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000290">Ms. Jenkins of Kansas</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XI of the Social Security Act to promote testing of incentive payments for
			 behavioral health providers for adoption and use of certified electronic
			 health record technology.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HCC8FD3E87EC04ED799F19755EA89B915" style="OLC">
		<section id="H7F3A8B5CCE7641C5A0F376CF8677A6F7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Testing of incentive payments for behavioral health providers for adoption and use of certified
 electronic health record technology</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1115A(b)(2)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1315a">42 U.S.C. 1315a(b)(2)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new clause:</text>
			<quoted-block id="H90BAC65C5F074BA09D884378A2C1E8A4" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H6349900C732743C48FAF6B6D4A92F68A"><enum>(xxv)</enum><text>Providing incentive payments to behavioral health providers, such as a public or private hospital that is principally a psychiatric hospital (as defined in section 1861(f)), a community mental health center (as described in section 1913(b)(2) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300x-2">42 U.S.C. 300x–2(b)(2)</external-xref>)), an accredited residential or outpatient mental health treatment facility, an accredited substance abuse treatment facility, a clinical psychologist (as defined in section 1861(ii)), and a clinical social worker (as defined in section 1861(hh)(1)), for adopting certified EHR technology (as defined in section 1848(o)(4)) and using such technology to improve the quality and coordination of care through the electronic exchange of health information.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


