<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H7A292024C019424BAC0E94908BB6D4C6" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4467 IH: Strengthening Aviation Security Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4467</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171128">November 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001071">Mr. Jody B. Hice of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Federal Air Marshal Service to utilize risk-based strategies, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H4AD731B5CCAF4B8193183B89CB7FDDBD" style="OLC">
 <section id="H912589F03B95454CAF7B9A65495D39B3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthening Aviation Security Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HE185C956539E42EAB85780706D7081C6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Use of risk-based strategies by Federal Air Marshal Service</header> <subsection id="H121A48470D8B4F45B046A24E7B699570"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) of section 44917 of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H752FCF1D73A04F458E12F3777A5777E7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (7), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon at the end;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H99684E5EBFDF4B348374A5331A0E0443"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (8), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6A1893FA48314591B70A6341A33ADA66"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAFA0C338235C4E698D2F4065FD87CCE2" style="USC"> <paragraph id="H2FF13C3F50B341B6BB0A814CCCC07A54"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall require the Federal Air Marshal Service to utilize a risk-based strategy when allocating resources between international and domestic flight coverage, including when initially setting its annual target numbers of average daily international and domestic flights to cover;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCA53FE14D2364FDE8DCCEA7F6E2987F3"><enum>(10)</enum><text>shall require the Federal Air Marshal Service to utilize a risk-based strategy to support domestic allocation decisions; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H103F75BD70974A04B022601CF4811DFD"><enum>(11)</enum><text>shall require the Federal Air Marshal Service to utilize a risk-based strategy to support international allocation decisions.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0B4C096058D1430FAD582344D1EA923B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report that describes the compliance of the Federal Air Marshal Service with the requirements specified in paragraphs (9) through (11) of subsection (a) of section 44917 of title 49, United States Code, as added by this Act, and the documented methodology used by the Federal Air Marshal Service to conduct risk assessments in accordance with such paragraphs.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC348772D9AC84D95B10F018AF7AEA973"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The Transportation Security Administration shall begin carrying out the requirements specified in paragraphs (9) through (11) of subsection (a) of section 44917, United States Code, added by this Act, by not later than the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


