<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2ED7E0059D6D4D0FA2E15636CBAB6255" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3769 IH: Freight Infrastructure Reinvestment Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3769</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170913">September 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001165">Mr. Sires</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the National Freight Mobility Infrastructure Fund, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HDF9D4057F63C430896FA68242881E748" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE86EE9FD567649058C8506E1592F8421" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Freight Infrastructure Reinvestment Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HD726D968C3DF401792221F5F87EA9016"><enum>2.</enum><header>National Freight Mobility Infrastructure Improvement Program</header> <subsection id="H07973EC2C68C4BE6A3D0161DDF734373"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary of Transportation shall establish a National Freight Mobility Infrastructure Improvement Program under which the Secretary is authorized to make grants, on a competitive basis, to States and designated entities for eligible costs associated with projects to improve efficiency and capacity with respect to freight mobility in the United States.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H4FCE0148092844469B042F53C1AD4BD8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grant applications</header>
 <paragraph id="HBC878287FFF74FEDBA1070D4DE25E774"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a grant under the program a State or designated entity shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such form, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1F4CFCA88F35450DA2A5F5FB297AFE40"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Solicitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall conduct a national solicitation for applications under the program.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2AD63F4713994D67ABD66B5D71944DF6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant criteria</header> <paragraph id="H9F6F243A319E499FBD6DA7456A58DB73"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in accordance with this subsection, shall establish criteria for selecting among applications submitted for grants under the program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H93F57C93321E4E0A9A37E25FF895469B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>A project is eligible for a grant under the program only if the Secretary determines that the project—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H57181A094484421A8DF514E9E1197905"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is of national or regional significance, including projects to assist—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HC63F33930AD24CEDB597A73D83726423"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the construction of grade separations at railroad, highway, and railroad-highway junctions;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0ECBFF2D0FED4B8785A6A99000A1965F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the construction of railroad bypasses and spurs;</text> </clause><clause id="H1D9C67C2409C4AA2A82EEB4F56E60F28"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the construction of railroad side tracks;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H976454DF6C8E47909BB41C08AAC90BFC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the expansion of rail and highway tunnels to accommodate wider, taller, and additional volumes of vehicular and rail freight and container stacks;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7C52CD3BFD264BB3A6882A305CAC88B5"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the addition of railroad track and intermodal facilities at international gateways, land, air, and sea ports, points of congestion, and logistic centers;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H087908B8ABC24E80BDB4C667F291FC37"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">highway and road construction (including reinforcement for heavy weight vehicles and heavy traffic volume) at international gateways, land, air, and sea ports, points of congestion, and logistic centers, including freight intermodal connectors, to better accommodate and speed the flow of freight traffic;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H4CDEFE491A8B41BB85819DDD8891D4BA"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the construction and improvement of rail and highway bridges that carry a substantial amount of freight;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H4CF9AB7D516A452DA36F32B51436F9B4"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the construction of highway ramps built to carry a substantial amount of freight;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H1C4127EDFF2244E59C0EC439AFD36E95"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>the construction of highway lanes, including lanes that segregate freight and passenger vehicular traffic; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H16F2D766CADD401A8DA8785F78FA8501"><enum>(x)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the construction and improvement of marine terminal facilities used for freight;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8ECFD8EEDE04C858124D091B7BF3F6B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>will improve freight mobility, capacity, and efficiency in the United States;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6AEA74EEF8224EEF9AAE36F1F65866CF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is cost effective;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7E9BADBF253470CB1B640CE400F38A1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is based on the results of preliminary engineering;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78AD0FD7AD284CCAB4219CBDAF30DB6B"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is justified based on the extent to which the project—</text> <clause id="HBEB9DFF0660D4EFE9BD06E72DDF75B76"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">will enhance State, regional, or national economic development, performance, and efficiency as measured by—</text>
 <subclause id="HF2354D8B270440F5992703BD85CD6203"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the creation of new businesses and jobs and the retention of existing businesses and jobs;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HD4BD2FCD0CF94BEE880F0F2BBD04EF44"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">State and local tax receipts; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H420CCD89B21E43C681C923B02CC85990"><enum>(III)</enum><text>improved safety, as measured by reductions in accidents, injuries, and fatalities; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H29088D52100D4615B2AA7ABFC45A7B09"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">will maximize economic opportunities for communities; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7AB0E619164B44B5AFEB54EF9307A522"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is supported by an acceptable degree of non-Federal financial commitments, including that—</text> <clause id="H0681EB88A6664BB9AF317CE48BCC9217"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the project provides for the availability of contingency amounts that, as determined by the Secretary, are reasonable to cover unanticipated cost increases; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7A9EB08A1EB2498590716FA960A4556C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>each proposed non-Federal source of financing is stable, reliable, and available within the project timetable.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H815948EBFAD2493EA5CD3E794147552A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In selecting a project for a grant under the program, the Secretary shall consider the extent to which the project—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HADD9F35DB5D64282B068943A0F41E19B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>meets the requirements specified in paragraph (2);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05D90C95AF844E3D8BED963A5E437A65"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilitates freight throughput of higher volume and values;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93A8F0B4E9614B5D9F4E9C184E494C26"><enum>(C)</enum><text>uses operational efficiencies, including intelligent transportation systems, that enhance the efficiency or effectiveness (or both) of the project;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C24CFC20B1C43F697DEB60C7F1DAA2A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>helps maintain or protect the environment; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD59209ED82974BE2B8BEDD77B715C93E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>improves or enhances segments of the primary freight network designated under section 167(d) of title 23, United States Code.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H865B7D86622E44DE80150923A30CE39C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Congressional notification and disapproval</header>
				<paragraph id="H34E028438C4E41BABC153E0FE2764C1A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notification</header>
 <subparagraph id="HBBE8EC83F21E450AB82A02F0497ECE82"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>At least 60 days before making a grant for a project under the program, the Secretary shall notify, in writing, the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate of the proposed grant.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H685963ACB22943B389BFE4B58CD4312E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The notification shall include an evaluation and justification for each successful project that includes—</text>
 <clause id="HF8F8DCD746354D32A5746693429CB80C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a detailed explanation of how the project satisfied grant criteria and considerations;</text> </clause><clause id="H408A9794E400445792A9B1E58482A739"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount of the proposed grant award; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB371F65CDADA46DC9DCE6F1FCAED8ADD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an executive summary of the project application submitted for funding.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E07F9AE32FD43FCB988EDB111CD8B19"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Disapproval</header><text>The Secretary may not make a grant or any other obligation or commitment to fund a project under the program if a joint resolution is enacted disapproving funding for the project before the last day of the 60-day period described in paragraph (1)(A).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H37965FBC38904974BF57D0D23EA08AD7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports</header>
 <paragraph id="H413131F39C944A288946A48EC32ED860"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>The Secretary shall make available on the internet website of the Department of Transportation at the end of each fiscal year an annual report that lists each project for which a grant has been provided under the program during that fiscal year.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H3CCD28487D8642CAAC969E828E99DD59"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Comptroller general</header>
 <subparagraph id="H23C18EDD73894E7488CE4CACBFF95824"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct an assessment of the administrative establishment, solicitation, selection, and justification process with respect to the funding of grants under the program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDBA8FC48EACB43FCA6B0B296A0C82286"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the initial awarding of grants under the program, the Comptroller General shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report that describes—</text>
 <clause id="H49D860A95A5A4555B1C93FFA4A41AD06"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the adequacy and fairness of the process by which each project was selected, if applicable; and</text> </clause><clause id="H0CFC9A222F0D4D698CAD59C104A10918"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the justification and criteria used for the selection of each project, if applicable.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAECEE701389C44B5A4CAD3E1B66CED92"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall carry out the program using amounts made available to the Secretary from the National Freight Mobility Infrastructure Fund established under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9512">section 9512</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5C2528990BE54EBCBA2D301D31E35C23"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Limitation on grant distribution</header><text>Not more than 10 percent of the amounts available during a fiscal year for grants under the program may be used for projects located in a single State.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE356AB4DF29E4C94A9C1BE80583A4A1A"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Full funding grant agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may enter into a grant under the program that provides funding for a project in more than 1 fiscal year. An agreement for such a grant shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H363BA6E549EC48DD8566832DA9699AAC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish the maximum amount of Federal financial assistance for the project;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF5794D7C663B40CE95232A7C13D0D84D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish the time period for Federal financial assistance for the project;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC83A6A9EBCA47BABC0423A57AB0834F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide grant funds for the fiscal year in which the grant is made; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6930A657AF0A47CF816A06485E529AD2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>include a commitment, that is not an obligation of the Federal Government and that is contingent on the availability of funds, for grant amounts to be provided in fiscal years following the fiscal year in which the grant is made.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA7C9FCF09388429DAA7926E03278BA21"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Non-Federal financial commitments</header>
 <paragraph id="H8A10069ACADD494F9FC707383A1A321E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal share</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal share of the cost of a project for which a grant is made under the program, as estimated by the Secretary, shall be not more than 80 percent.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H373FA9EAE64E452F9132A505F41CB344"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In assessing the stability, reliability, and availability of proposed sources of non-Federal financing for purposes of subsection (c)(2)(F)(ii), the Secretary shall consider—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFDD342E9390A4C95B5B8F8F0DB714897"><enum>(A)</enum><text>existing financial commitments;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86AE0836D6F8420CBC7F478C5536652A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the degree to which financing sources are dedicated to the purposes proposed;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3CC3FB1B39444B38AE41B5DDCFD609D3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any debt obligation that exists or is proposed by the grant recipient for the proposed project; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8DD9E581DB343E697036ED352C5693C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the extent to which the project has a non-Federal financial commitment that exceeds the required non-Federal share of the cost of the project.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H5C83EA571D104875A1397D68307C9D9D"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Highway construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant made to assist the construction of a highway under the program shall be subject to the requirements relating to such construction under title 23, United States Code.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD90BAC950BA04E62B325295B8AE2848C"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Other terms and conditions</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that all grants made under the program are subject to terms, conditions, and requirements that the Secretary decides are necessary or appropriate for purposes of this section, including requirements for the disposition of net increases in the value of real property resulting from the project assisted under the program.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAAFFA0B79DE54B34A9968B62D9DD30A2"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the program, the Secretary shall seek to minimize administrative costs, including overhead, enforcement, and auditing costs related to the program.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC5AC4FCF7AB54C0BB886E73F4D66BBE0"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report on the activities of the Secretary under the program.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5D45800155F54E6EB995453C79334171"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue regulations to carry out this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H185F6280D86F4015ACE8A0DBBAF08C4F"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the following definitions apply:</text> <paragraph id="H0D8241BE83B84B3AA8230DB567BD3EBF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Designated entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>designated entity</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H23D5B51233894FE8AE1F18490D89D302"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State or a group of States.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BC2E3BBA4DA426FB602FF71C6E538B2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A metropolitan planning organization that serves an urbanized area (as defined by the Bureau of the Census) with a population of more than 200,000 individuals.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB963EE5A0C8B416EACEFD8124EBCDED6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A unit of local government or a group of local governments.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE738A12729C44BE7A0AF245D36D6DBBC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A political subdivision of a State or local government.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H191C3697A3934824B8D30956476640B6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A special purpose district or public authority with a transportation function, including a port authority.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B76DAC32E3D451A8EDD9F8D8126F17D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A Tribal government or a consortium of Tribal governments.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDA6FB717BD94B9893A00C31DE3ED369"><enum>(G)</enum><text>A multistate or multijurisdictional group of entities described in this paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC382ECCE983F4A7FBF335DFD1A13D432"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible costs</header><text>The term <term>eligible costs</term> means the costs of a project with respect to—</text> <subparagraph id="HF1AAD76F59D447DFBAC4193A47113F55"><enum>(A)</enum><text>development phase activities, including planning, feasibility analysis, revenue forecasting, environmental review, preliminary engineering and design work, and other pre­con­struc­tion activities; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6D47FFA3193474DA47B5CB73540DBE2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>construction, reconstruction, rehabilitation, acquisition of real property (including land related to a project and improvements to land), environmental mitigation, construction contingencies, acquisition of equipment, and operational improvements.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E2E4926E4F74FCDBAF8A1828F631A0A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>program</term> means the National Freight Mobility Infrastructure Improvement Program established under subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H05AE50E7FC69421A8B095E2EF4E37464"><enum>(4)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101(a) of title 23, United States Code.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H9BF2CBC03A7D43058DB773B9F19D1B8B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Freight mobility infrastructure tax</header> <subsection id="H3EA9CB76362D438081471FC95A3CFD38"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Imposition of tax</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/33">Chapter 33</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding after subchapter C the following new subchapter:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H94870DA8BB464D6E8911502BFDF7CC08" style="OLC">
					<subchapter id="H32BE5C07FA3F41B0A8BBE362B55726FB"><enum>D</enum><header>Transportation By Freight And Highway</header>
						<toc container-level="subchapter-container" idref="H32BE5C07FA3F41B0A8BBE362B55726FB" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
							<toc-entry idref="H5E1B856AEF804103A1E2CE57C815E2E1" level="section">Sec. 4286. Imposition of tax.</toc-entry></toc>
						<section id="H5E1B856AEF804103A1E2CE57C815E2E1"><enum>4286.</enum><header>Imposition of tax</header>
 <subsection id="H00145F3B38C944EDB726636A49EB6E7D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is hereby imposed upon taxable ground transportation of property within the United States a tax equal to 1 percent of the amount paid for such transportation.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="H1065F8DA701C42EF89B1384168AB33EE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>By whom paid</header>
 <paragraph id="H4AB5CE4AA5774B6D9D5AEB540D6C4683"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided by paragraph (2), the tax imposed by subsection (a) shall be paid—</text> <subparagraph id="H5121E906B4144587B5244AFF7E33808B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by the person making the payment subject to tax, or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDDF7D9720D004E8EAA4296AB7D2F974B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of transportation by a related person, by the person for whom such transportation is made.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H402556B2150B4DD1BE6A4CC8E8FC886A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Payments made outside the United States</header><text>If a payment subject to tax under subsection (a) is made outside the United States and the person making such payment does not pay such tax, such tax—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7FA6C3BD381A4CAB863AB880ED5CD9E7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be paid by the person to whom the property is delivered in the United States after the final segment of transportation in the United States, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB705D75D739F40E3844D2058C08A5136"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall be collected by the person furnishing the last segment of such transportation.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H071FACA52F3644D8A5F2DBC91A9052AC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Determinations of amounts paid in certain cases</header><text>For purposes of this section, rules similar to the rules of section 4271(c) shall apply.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7BE76C3C33334770B58A24B267755AC0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transportation by related persons</header><text>In the case of transportation of property by the taxpayer or a person related to the taxpayer, the fair market value of such transportation shall be the amount which would be paid for transporting such property if such property were transported by an unrelated person, determined on an arms’ length basis.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAE8393CD96984F74941CCFA09969AB9E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this subchapter—</text> <paragraph id="H695B3B72F09C40769D346EDAB7DED76C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Taxable ground transportation</header> <subparagraph id="H82BE8854C5DB42139AEFF4C6798B0113"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>taxable ground transportation</term> means transportation of property by—</text>
 <clause id="H0FCD2FA089C845E5BA022B98B3B6C22A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>freight rail, or</text> </clause><clause id="H1A7108BB7B304CB9B37EEFC462D65772"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>commercial motor vehicle (as defined in section 31101(1) of title 49, United States Code) for a distance of more than 50 miles.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1D3B7BB97CF4A6F857937231E7154E7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Passenger baggage excluded</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term <term>property</term> does not include baggage accompanying a passenger traveling on an established line.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B3DF3F296784BC38FF8807D7FAB9AA7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Related person</header><text>A person (hereinafter in this paragraph referred to as the <quote>related person</quote>) is related to any person if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H230BCEB0C18D411EA8F3728AD4286C18"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the related person bears a relationship to such person specified in section 267(b) or 707(b)(1), or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A947A5EB9184E5D8DAF5C717B891DFB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the related person and such person are engaged in trades or businesses under common control (within the meaning of subsections (a) and (b) of section 52).</text>
 </subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">For purposes of the preceding sentence, in applying sections 267(b) and 707(b)(1), <quote>10 percent</quote> shall be substituted for <quote>50 percent</quote>.</continuation-text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB713F1176080416C98765E64245A8717"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Exemption for United States and possessions and State and local governments</header><text>The tax imposed by subsection (a) shall not apply to the transportation of property purchased for the exclusive use of the United States, or any State or political subdivision thereof.</text></subsection></section></subchapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H15C8F22A9404482EA1795547785B3BE3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Credits or refunds to persons who collected certain taxes</header><text>Section 6415 of such Code is amended by striking <quote>or 4271</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>4271, or 4286</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H40CC9EC3004A423EB10C606D8F7ABF82"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury shall issue regulations to carry out the amendments made by this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3C3BD89865A34E3EA0399D94DEA4EFDD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to transportation beginning on or after the last day of the 180-day period beginning on the date of the issuance of regulations under subsection (c).</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HEF8AF40011704CDF9BB59B4E30527836"><enum>4.</enum><header>National Freight Mobility Infrastructure Fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/98">chapter 98</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
			<quoted-block id="HB856B267733A4AFC9375DD46BE38A044">
				<section id="H275D19C597D94466AEF659C38B60881E"><enum>9512.</enum><header>National Freight Mobility Infrastructure Fund</header>
 <subsection id="H79F7B3E9D0F041718A4BE4EF0F4DEAE8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Creation of Trust Fund</header><text>There is established in the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the <quote>National Freight Mobility Infrastructure Fund</quote> (hereinafter in this section referred to as the <quote>Fund</quote>) consisting of such amounts as may be appropriated or credited to such Fund as provided in this section or section 9602(b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H97BB1E7A119047998E12D70D6F4C3024"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transfers to the fund</header><text>There are hereby appropriated to the Fund amounts equivalent to taxes received in the Treasury under section 4286.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H93C3C119AE1D405B9E2E4811CE8C99A4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Expenditures from fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts in the Fund shall be made available to the Secretary of Transportation for each of the fiscal years 2017 to 2042, without further appropriation, for making expenditures to meet the obligations of the United States to carry out section 2 of the Freight Infrastructure Reinvestment Act of 2017, not more than 4 percent of which for any fiscal year may be used for administrative expenses.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


