<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H15E028BFB1F547198EDC54A3B9B84DAE" key="H" public-private="public">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4282 IH: Protecting UACs Through Enhanced Sponsor Vetting Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4282</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20171107">November 7, 2017</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001105">Mrs. Comstock</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000625">Mr. Donovan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Director of the Office of Refugee Resettlements of the Department of Health and Human Services to establish additional procedures for making placement determinations for all unaccompanied alien children who are in Federal custody by reason of their immigration status, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form> 
<legis-body id="HEE826FF9C9374E97B03784FB6327B9E3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H87BFD9BDF3834A229C6DDC626F6873D8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting UACs Through Enhanced Sponsor Vetting Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H672C2E3B806E42228A26A0BB4FA3A982"><enum>2.</enum><header>Additional procedures for placement decisions for unaccompanied alien children</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 462 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/279">6 U.S.C. 279</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5DDC8CCC11E84D1687D45502A8987821"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b)(1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H3FBA7B79520B490794E8BCFCF1E3ED94"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (K), by striking <quote>; and</quote> at the end;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB9877120D2AE4BCBBCBB64142EDED667"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (L), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5D0632845B8B4849991DA208E27783A3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCA1E1D46276C45B08EE636FD92C420CF" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="H8A9E4D5365CF429B9F731C73B31B41A1"><enum>(M)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing notification of the prospective placement of an unaccompanied alien child with a sponsor to the Governor of the State and the chief executive of the county in which the sponsor resides.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0E66DAB3D4CD478998149FEEFAFA96DC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b)(2), by amending subparagraph (A) to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBA2CD89E2C16466B9CFE983E26B4EB63" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="H0CFC2D2F077A4B078270E462B75A755A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall coordinate with appropriate juvenile justice professionals, the Director of the Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services, the Assistant Secretary of the Bureau of Border Security, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and appropriate State and local law enforcement officials to ensure that such determinations ensure that unaccompanied alien children described in such subparagraph—</text> <clause id="H56B23623889642A4BC86A2A22F557B31"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are likely to appear for all hearings or proceedings in which they are involved;</text> </clause>
<clause id="H8DF89857927147FDBB174E762302B123"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are protected from smugglers, traffickers, members of a designated trans­na­tion­al criminal organization, or others who might seek to victimize or otherwise engage them in criminal, harmful, or exploitive activity, including by conducting a thorough criminal history background check utilizing the Next Generation Identification System or its successor system on prospective sponsors;</text> </clause> <clause id="HF9CA2065989D4FCABF2316F502008F11"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>are placed in a setting in which they are not likely to pose a danger to themselves or others; and</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H24D9E54B0C034FFB93FC561CBCC09BF3"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subsection (g) as subsection (h) and—</text> <subparagraph id="H512BD529FB164CA89AD76082BB1B2324"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1) of such subsection, by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5A1D4A28BFBF46289EA9DBF8E7C08BF3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2) of such subsection, by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9CF77C86EB2C4DFEA75CBF7398FF7BAD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9B753E3156944DCABF31F1C8EA52E1EE" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H34D7B1679DF746F3A4A6F7FD60557EF9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>transnational criminal organization</term> means a criminal organization that has been designated as a transnational criminal organization by the Office of Foreign Assets Control at the Department of the Treasury.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0A49A807527E4A95B225FBB9E3722E9D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (f) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3E8864E8E776481C99B084B4AA372E8E" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="HE74A97267A174AAE9EC3BB824923F636"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Additional procedures for making placement determinations</header> 
<paragraph id="HA21756C831A84729A95AEDE8067041BA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Criminal records checks</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall coordinate with the Attorney General to conduct a thorough criminal history background check utilizing the Next Generation Identification System or its successor system for all prospective sponsors before placement of an unaccompanied alien child.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H12336ABC1100479596AC158D43E9F4F6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation with relevant law enforcement entities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall consult with relevant law enforcement entities, including Federal, State, and local law enforcement, prior to making a determination on whether it is appropriate to place an unaccompanied alien child with a prospective sponsor. This consultation will examine any criminal activity in which the prospective sponsor may have been, or is currently, involved.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2ED8ABD1345E4E33B4F4C3CBC5F1C47E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notification to State and local governments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall notify relevant State and local governments of the decision to place an unaccompanied alien child with a sponsor. This notification will include the Governor of the state where the sponsor resides, as well as the mayor or equivalent officeholder of the locality where the sponsor resides.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H7F96178B30EC479FAE5C37E1F0537CD9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Transnational criminal organization intelligence sharing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall provide to the Terrorist Screening Center information uncovered during the placement process of an unaccompanied alien child that establishes membership in, or affiliation with, a designated transnational criminal organization of either an unaccompanied alien child or a prospective sponsor.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></section>
</legis-body>
</bill> 


