<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE11344AE843B44B5B619A23E962CDEB2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1270 IH: Living Donor Protection Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1270</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170301">March 1, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001056">Ms. Herrera Beutler</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To promote and protect from discrimination living organ donors.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H53503E4C89194A4CBD33E74EA550E3B0" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCEAFB77D801046918999FC0A8DF08DD5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Living Donor Protection Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9C5EC0888ECA46218D38CA031ACD5E06" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on denial of coverage or increase in premiums of life or disability insurance for living organ donors</header> <subsection id="H4DD7F963EA79416BBDC0563E46AEA0D4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, it shall be unlawful to—</text>
<paragraph id="HC5FFFCF047B242749ACC8387459690F4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>decline or limit coverage of a person under any life insurance policy, disability insurance policy, or long-term care insurance policy, due to the status of such person as a living organ donor;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCBDF37AE42114583B278CD3258B1ADFF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>preclude a person from donating all or part of an organ as a condition of receiving a life insurance policy, disability insurance policy, or long-term care insurance policy;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H65665B221D4C4778A6D2999BE0D8B91F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider the status of a person as a living organ donor in determining the premium rate for coverage of such person under a life insurance policy, disability insurance policy, or long-term care insurance policy; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAC9153C2FC2B484CBF3F4A5B987BF2A5"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">otherwise discriminate in the offering, issuance, cancellation, amount of such coverage, price, or any other condition of a life insurance policy, disability insurance policy, or long-term care insurance policy for a person, based solely and without any additional actuarial risks upon the status of such person as a living organ donor.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H68D1B345756F4F7F8596B98DDCE6424E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>A State insurance regulator may take such actions to enforce subsection (a) as are specifically authorized under the laws of such State.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H15DE6BF8F20A4E16AA01AA61D8198629"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="H29754BB6837644EF8A920F760D7A0A22"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Disability insurance policy</header><text>The term <term>disability insurance policy</term> means a contract under which an entity promises to pay a person a sum of money in the event that an illness or injury resulting in a disability prevents such person from working.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H656CE7A65AA24265A5D9B9B6A173D6F5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Life insurance policy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>life insurance policy</term> means a contract under which an entity promises to pay a designated beneficiary a sum of money upon the death of the insured.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCFCACB7842EE45CF8DDBF4B8052C8D85"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Living organ donor</header><text>The term <term>living organ donor</term> means an individual who has donated all or part of an organ and is not deceased.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9786D226177B43E6A34BD18C85F74856"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Long-term care insurance policy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>long-term care insurance policy</term> means a contract for which the only insurance protection provided under the contract is coverage of qualified long-term care services (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7702B">section 7702B(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986).</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H04F0E6AC46544FA4BCF65EE428C3908D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Clarification of organ donation surgery as qualifying as a serious health condition under FMLA</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 101(11) of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2611">29 U.S.C. 2611(11)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>(including recovery from surgery related to organ donation)</quote> after <quote>physical or mental condition</quote>.</text></section> <section id="HFCE5B418A4AD4BB1A6A2C6DF9E3153DA"><enum>4.</enum><header>Updating of educational materials on the benefits of live organ donation</header> <subsection id="H64609E2D29D64D319E3B500D1E9A807D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall review and update materials related to live organ donation in order to educate the public on—</text>
<paragraph id="H61EFBD1309064285AC8C95140902281C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the benefits of live organ donation; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H23D8A15F4A51429BA13436B8A2CFF249"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the impact of live organ donation on the access of a living organ donor to insurance.</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">Such updating shall include information on the changes made by sections 2 and 3 of this Act.</continuation-text></subsection>
<subsection id="H66486144F10741A6AF7DCD83296E2B40"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Methods of updating</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall update, as appropriate—</text> <paragraph id="H1CA697389FDD4CC6AC919B24D5C54F0A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Public Service Announcements previously provided by the Secretary;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H38DD55A8B16D4E838115A7564ED0AB0A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>publicly accessible Web sites (such as organdonor.gov, or a successor Web site) that are maintained by the Secretary and that contain information and resources regarding live organ donation; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF139AB57141D4A2B80D5ADF91F0E2FBB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>other media determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

