<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H78741625CC9041C2B827EC7B4C91A002" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1827 IH: Medical Leave for Disabled Veterans Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1827</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170330">March 30, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000620">Mr. Delaney</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001191">Ms. Sinema</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000570">Mr. Ben Ray Luján of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001304">Mr. Brown of Maryland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001170">Ms. Shea-Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000062">Mr. Yarmuth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell of Alabama</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson of Indiana</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 to provide a partial exemption to veterans from
			 the eligibility requirements, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HC64F2FA4DDE7448E8813FD70D9D5CF40" style="OLC">
 <section id="H96AE56DF0B2044AB80C2A28A32A15E1F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medical Leave for Disabled Veterans Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H65F3328CE349404F8083E0BCA54A689D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Eligibility adjustment for veterans</header> <subsection id="H929DE90296CB4A3DA08380131E8D6739"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Eligibility based on time in employment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 101(2) of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2611">29 U.S.C. 2611(2)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9D44CBBA688D4808B35330C02BE160D3" style="OLC">
					<subparagraph id="H80E839C4BA824BBD81D500205119D644"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Veterans</header>
 <clause id="HDC09D92FFB6041BAA7DFC772D8C9383E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Eligibility based on time in employment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the eligibility requirements in paragraph (2)(A), an employee who is a veteran shall be deemed an eligible employee for purposes of leave described in clause (iii) if—</text>
 <subclause id="H21F81B9D7DCC4A0E9793C9E31B3C80AB"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such employee has a service-connected disability (as defined in section 101 of title 38, United States Code) rated at between 30 and 50 percent by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and such employee has been employed for at least 8 months by the employer with respect to whom leave is requested under section 102 and has at least 833 hours of service with such employer during the previous 8-month period;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HADA51E27BCBF40CB93EAECF54AA233C0"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such employee has a service-connected disability rated at 60 percent or higher by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and such employee has been employed for at least 6 months by the employer with respect to whom leave is requested under section 102 and has at least 625 hours of service with such employer during the previous 6-month period; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H3BC0BA3F27F64EC8BD4B55FDE9FC3D31"><enum>(III)</enum><text>such employee—</text> <item id="HEBD7C109BDAB4574B01827EA5A9F3CF7"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>is not covered under subclause (I) or (II);</text>
 </item><item id="H8D119AE6094046D08079509115027419"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>retired from the Armed Forces under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/61">chapter 61</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, by reason of a service-connected disability either—</text>
 <subitem id="H6F47EE678DCE488A86FEBA5797A7BBC5"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>rated at between 30 and 50 percent under the standard schedule of rating disabilities in use by the Department of Veterans Affairs at the time of such retirement; or</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="HB583D58FDC3B4F2F839B34E7AC6663D4"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>rated at 60 percent or higher under such schedule; and</text> </subitem></item><item id="H05B44A9CEBA34D5CBEF5B5CDEA548DB8"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>either—</text>
 <subitem id="H7DD20F14F82F4648A0C05612818F7F84"><enum>(AA)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to an individual covered under subitem (AA) of item (bb), has been employed for at least 8 months by the employer with respect to whom leave is requested under section 102 and has at least 833 hours of service with such employer during the previous 8-month period; or</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="H70D64D10262A49989CA53702E27C4366"><enum>(BB)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to an individual covered under subitem (BB) of such item, has been employed for at least 6 months by the employer with respect to whom leave is requested under section 102 and has at least 625 hours of service with such employer during the previous 6-month period.</text>
 </subitem></item></subclause></clause><clause id="HF37C9914613B4CF3A745B51042273060"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>To be eligible for the eligibility adjustment described in clause (i)—</text> <subclause id="H4FD09FE950614A34A212B247E128D0B0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an employee described in subclause (I) or (II) of such clause shall submit to the employer a certification from a Department of Veterans Affairs medical provider or from a non-Department of Veterans Affairs facility or medical provider through which the Secretary of Veterans Affairs has furnished hospital care or medical services to the employee under the laws administered by the Secretary; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H61374C7DCDAD4A878B44AB1D9C1FDAFE"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an employee described in subclause (III) of such clause shall submit to the employer a certification from the Secretary of Defense describing the retirement of the individual from the Armed Forces under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/61">chapter 61</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="HFC3BC6FF075E485BAA0C6B051A478EB9"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Leave described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Leave described in this clause is leave under section 102(a)(1)(F) that—</text> <subclause commented="no" id="H5FCA907CBE314EF7977C386EE0F21346"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an employee described in subclause (I) or (II) of clause (i) takes to receive hospital care or medical services for which the employee is eligible to receive pursuant to <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/17">chapter 17</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, regardless of whether such hospital care or medical services is furnished by the Department of Veterans Affairs; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H791209CAD9EE4FB4B3A06AA46DE616DA"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an employee described in subclause (III) of such clause takes to receive hospital care or medical services relating to the service-connected disability described in item (bb) of such subclause.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA7379A61B7674FF3BFF4070042B21051"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Entitlement to leave</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 102(a)(1) of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (29 U.S.C. 2612(A)(1)) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6F5E37CE3332477D80DFE78DCC7C125C" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H99EEAF4C3D1A498DB0699467714D6FDE"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to receive hospital care or medical services as a veteran for a service-connected disability, as described in section 101(2)(E).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


