<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF3F63C6C48784ECC931BD4BC4E7A5DAA" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4547 IH: Strengthening Protections for Social Security Beneficiaries Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4547</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171205">December 5, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000174">Mr. Sam Johnson of Texas</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend titles II, VIII, and XVI of the Social Security Act to improve and strengthen the
			 representative payment program.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H0C6044C2F4E442BB904D5A4B41FF0742" style="OLC">
 <section id="H47C9C60681364C48B65634D03DD1B471" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthening Protections for Social Security Beneficiaries Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HB9E3394031CB4F38B31ED9B607F30CA5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
			<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
				<toc-entry idref="H47C9C60681364C48B65634D03DD1B471" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HB9E3394031CB4F38B31ED9B607F30CA5" level="section">Sec. 2. Table of contents.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HB2312260DABD4ED2A9A0CDA6C8B77AB3" level="title">Title I—Strengthening Oversight and Beneficiary Protection</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H849F36E4922B4BBE936F318CBBFD5388" level="section">Sec. 101. Stronger monitoring of representative payees.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HC5A15AC85E9E43A6839110041E91E58C" level="section">Sec. 102. Reducing the burden on families.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HE471BF097D28430E9AF1DF6B51211EAC" level="section">Sec. 103. Protecting beneficiaries through information sharing.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HFF4CD5EA419E43E38BB7ECA826CB2275" level="section">Sec. 104. Clarifying overpayment liability for child in child welfare system.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HCA64AA135FA140C9838B884D9B7DECE8" level="section">Sec. 105. Reports.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H87B2DA809B514C2DB922333958415BA8" level="title">Title II—Improving Payee Selection and Quality</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H53E0445C54AF4ED69DBE6AC81B5E5C25" level="section">Sec. 201. Advance designation of representative payees.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HC9AEFF428861404A9FE369D97B37D478" level="section">Sec. 202. Prohibition on individuals convicted of certain crimes serving as representative payees.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HCB983F875A644ADD9319F052948D44C9" level="section">Sec. 203. Prohibition on individuals with representative payees serving as representative payees.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H1D9B3E39E4194E7C9D74B42C9AB19A46" level="section">Sec. 204. Reassessment of payee selection and replacement policies.</toc-entry>
			</toc>
		</section><title id="HB2312260DABD4ED2A9A0CDA6C8B77AB3"><enum>I</enum><header>Strengthening Oversight and Beneficiary Protection</header>
			<section id="H849F36E4922B4BBE936F318CBBFD5388" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>101.</enum><header>Stronger monitoring of representative payees</header>
 <subsection id="H3E98B1C1B6BC4EE1ACC2D24C33DD77E8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Protection and advocacy for beneficiaries with representative payees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 205(j)(6) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/405">42 U.S.C. 405(j)(6)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDD7BC73D268445CA9C9D5BE701032144" style="OLC">
						<subparagraph id="H8302F1F4D20045B19A2994280CB8D77A" indent="up2"><enum>(C)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H6EB84C57B10048079FE2993E6AF51EC3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner of Social Security shall make annual grants directly to the protection and advocacy system serving each of the States and the American Indian consortium for the purpose of conducting reviews of representative payees in accordance with this subparagraph. The total amount used by the Commissioner for such grants each year—</text>
 <subclause id="H3695BBB38C274C1B9B46507165E81730" indent="up1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall be an amount sufficient, as determined by the Commissioner in consultation with each of the protection and advocacy systems, to carry out all of the activities described in clause (ii); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H97A139804D3A4D3E93C48D73A3D66848" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall not be less than $25,000,000.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H5EC406ECA1CC4CC78A219027E0AFF2AD" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A protection and advocacy system awarded a grant under this subparagraph shall use the grant funds to—</text>
 <subclause id="H106B8B566EB34792B5FD878FBB8498F8"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct all periodic onsite reviews pursuant to this paragraph and such other reviews of representative payees as the Commissioner may request, including reviews conducted in response to allegations or concerns about the performance or suitability of the payee;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H36647D0C7BA6490D96AFD4BE11547B22"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct additional reviews that the protection and advocacy system has reason to believe are warranted;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H6037FD5022A3430BB5D340B9B5323239"><enum>(III)</enum><text>develop corrective action plans to assist representative payees in conforming to requirements specified by the Commissioner;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H6F38ED59D887458FB32F072102F87147"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>submit a report to the Commissioner on each completed review containing such information as the Commissioner shall require; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H41C76BC3543947BA98786147660BB07C"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct an initial onsite assessment of any organization that begins collecting a fee for its services as a representative payee to ensure that such organization is established as such a representative payee in accordance with requirements specified by the Commissioner.</text>
								</subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">A protection and advocacy system may refer beneficiaries to other programs or services as the
 protection and advocacy system considers appropriate.</continuation-text></clause><clause id="HA64FDBB467F34162A21AF1D801EF5FB2" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>To be eligible to receive grants under this section, a protection and advocacy system shall submit an initial application to the Commissioner at such time, in such form and manner, and accompanied by such information and assurances as the Commissioner may require.</text>
							</clause><clause id="H89CFA3E59A594E4492016721248D284B" indent="up1">
								<enum>(iv)</enum>
								<subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H8DE87CD472FF49E786B6DFAFEC0389BB"><enum>(I)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subclause (II), the Commissioner shall ensure that any funds used for grants under clause (i) shall be allocated to the protection and advocacy systems serving each of the States and the American Indian consortium in a manner such that the amount provided to each protection and advocacy system bears the same ratio to the total of such funds as the number of represented beneficiaries in the State or American Indian consortium in which such protection and advocacy system is located bears to the total number of represented beneficiaries.</text>
								</subclause><subclause id="HCA4B951DBB9A48A490069D490EDB147B" indent="up1">
									<enum>(II)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of an annual grant to a protection and advocacy system under clause (i) shall—</text> <item id="H56EDA438A73E4C1AA48C0E014078455C"> <enum>(aa)</enum> <text>in the case of a protection and advocacy system serving American Samoa, Guam, the United States Virgin Islands, or the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, or the American Indian consortium, not be less than $30,000; and</text>
									</item><item id="HB6157DA659F448D5973C146E08E6776C">
										<enum>(bb)</enum>
 <text>in the case of a protection and advocacy system serving any other State, not be less than $60,000.</text> </item></subclause><subclause id="HB3C4B5EB238A4BAC80975774EAD0BD94" indent="up1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Funds provided to a protection and advocacy system through a grant under clause (i) for a one-year period shall remain available through the end of the following one-year period.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H665ECD9E9A17479BB9F0E4C2CE119AEB" indent="up1"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this clause, the term <term>represented beneficiary</term> means an individual—</text> <item id="H072710150ABC4457A4CF93A57785BC3C"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>who is entitled to benefits under this title, title VIII, or title XVI; and</text>
 </item><item id="HBCC97F1B43D7454B8AF83E804B04C877"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>whose benefits have been certified for payment to a representative payee.</text> </item></subclause></clause><clause id="HDA5DB18626E04E6D8BF0453FA5C34BCE" indent="up1"> <enum>(v)</enum> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H3E9D7000E2B64812B7FA726AE8D75C33"><enum>(I)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner shall make annual grants, in an amount equal to 4 percent of the total amount of grants awarded each year under clause (i), to an eligible national association for the provision of training and technical assistance, administrative support, and data collection services to protection and advocacy systems in connection with grants awarded under clause (i).</text>
								</subclause><subclause id="H1E3B8E278D8D4C12B53DDC2D728524BA" indent="up1">
									<enum>(II)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this clause, the term <term>eligible national association</term> means a national disability association with extensive knowledge and demonstrated experience in providing training, technical assistance, and administrative oversight to protection and advocacy systems that monitor representative payees.</text>
								</subclause></clause><clause id="HE6518A632420483DAA1F1874A4C80577" indent="up1">
								<enum>(vi)</enum>
 <text>In conducting reviews under this section, a protection and advocacy system shall have the same authorities, including access to records, facilities, and persons, as such system would have for purposes of providing services under subtitle C of title I of the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15041">42 U.S.C. 15041</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H320D6F5569F24639BCBB562FA327FCBD" indent="up1"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Whenever benefit amounts under this title are increased by any percentage effective with any month after November 2018 as a result of a determination made under section 215(i), each of the dollar amounts specified in clauses (i)(II) and (iv)(II) shall be increased by the same percentage.</text>
							</clause><clause id="HEC95710620444228849C8EFD9B500212" indent="up1">
								<enum>(viii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated to carry out the requirements of this subparagraph. Such requirements shall be carried out using amounts otherwise authorized.</text>
							</clause><clause id="H17F3F2F039024F838217767A49F94F63" indent="up1">
								<enum>(ix)</enum>
 <text>In this subparagraph:</text> <subclause id="H3AD85BC2DF0C4D95900D77881A4FC5D2"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text>The term <term>American Indian consortium</term> means a consortium established under subtitle C of title I of the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15041">42 U.S.C. 15041</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
								</subclause><subclause id="H7C944494CBCC4453956A0CA3784A5489">
									<enum>(II)</enum>
 <text>The term <term>protection and advocacy system</term> means a protection and advocacy system established under subtitle C of title I of the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15041">42 U.S.C. 15041</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
								</subclause><subclause id="HBC97AE954F5E479FA28A68F1BE2A0387">
									<enum>(III)</enum>
 <text>The term <term>State</term> means the several States of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text>
								</subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF8666FC304744FF784686C48DF43DC9A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Expansion of periodic onsite review requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 205(j)(6)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/405">42 U.S.C. 405(j)(6)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HEA34773B423B41D182F73561810AFD85"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>or</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1A6D3A2A56A84A5E8857C09E94E582EF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; or</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8E1552F0446B4B0AB19448EF77652123"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding after clause (iii) the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6C6DDEB0CCAC401C94829D5816AD2244" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H0753FECF92AC4F8F84F37894F29C592E" indent="up2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the representative payee collects a fee for its services.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9C57129473B844318131E6A6B3EE5CAD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding after clause (iv) (as added by paragraph (3)) the following flush text:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8E4D30ABD0D94D78B57F0DCB042EC30A" style="OLC">
							<quoted-block-continuation-text quoted-block-continuation-text-level="section">The Commissioner shall also conduct periodic onsite reviews of individual and organizational
			 payees, including payees who are related to the beneficiary and primarily
			 reside in the same household, selected on the basis of risk-factors for
			 potential misuse or unsuitability associated with such payees or
			 beneficiaries.</quoted-block-continuation-text><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7E99A721489B4F938814F30629997B9F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Availability of grant funds</header>
 <paragraph id="H9EA08C0027CC489C9ADACCDF7672F091"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Protection and advocacy system grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grants described under clause (i) of subparagraph (C) of section 205(j)(6) of the Social Security Act (as added by subsection (a)) shall be awarded on August 1, 2018, and annually thereafter, and funds provided by such grants to a protection and advocacy system may be used to reimburse the protection and advocacy system for amounts expended by the protection and advocacy system during the period beginning on May 1, 2018, and ending on such date for hiring and start-up costs in preparation to carry out reviews of representative payees in accordance with such subparagraph.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF49AF7DE1E0C402E8436629C6A3825D3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National Association grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grants described under clause (v) of such subparagraph shall be awarded on May 1, 2018, and annually thereafter.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC5A15AC85E9E43A6839110041E91E58C"><enum>102.</enum><header>Reducing the burden on families</header>
 <subsection id="HF5F53270128D4392BDB6FE5A88B4F490"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Title II</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 205(j)(3) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/405">42 U.S.C. 405(j)(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HADF85130B7484F57AE8A3CDC56797D75"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (D) through (G) as subparagraphs (E) through (H), respectively;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H14ED142D4362480CBA70D5F54555FEE4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (C) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4CE57BB5F8054EAA93C90E6E9FBF67C5" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HE4F0335858174340A6255BB75A870E9D"><enum>(D)</enum> <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H199AD752F70049CDAAFF71106B34BADB"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (A) shall not apply in any case where the other person to whom such payment is made is—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" id="HE07357E796B6407CBD2C737E0AE9276E"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a parent, or other individual who is a legal guardian of, a minor child entitled to such payment who primarily resides in the same household;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HF3E9770A82384CF49AC899C7BBED248C"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a parent of an individual entitled to such payment who is under a disability (as defined in section 223(d)) who primarily resides in the same household; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HDA9A3D1F63B7464BABA89654425978BE"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the spouse of the individual entitled to such payment.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HCFC4329041644652B4D431A0196858B8" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Commissioner of Social Security shall establish and implement procedures as necessary for the Commissioner to determine the eligibility of such parties for the exemption provided in clause (i). The Commissioner shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to determine eligibility for such exemption.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9F35CC51FD19463A98F5DE2971FC7159"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subparagaph (E) (as so redesignated), by striking <quote>and (C)</quote> and inserting <quote>(C), and (D)</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H31A1E990E954460EB14573AA54AE1A1E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subparagraph (F) (as so redesignated), by striking <quote>(D)</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>(E)</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H11665393FDBD4D0EBA818C22D7371F7D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Title VIII</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 807(h) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1007">42 U.S.C. 1007(h)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H5F6687C2351F45978D2DA912BEF2F706"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (3) through (5) as paragraphs (4) through (6), respectively; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCE3F868365644D2EAE0B657E451B8728"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H181F1A9A468742978499DEA057427C60" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H6A3F5CEB37934E008C7E069ED14B43AD"><enum>(3)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HAA9EA60F5BAC4F6A986E8AFC51F49A61"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall not apply in any case where the other person to whom such payment is made is the spouse of the individual entitled to such payment.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8FB9BD5AEFFA4512BF9E480DB7B91B88" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Commissioner of Social Security shall establish and implement procedures as necessary for the Commissioner to determine the eligibility of such parties for the exemption provided in subparagraph (A). The Commissioner shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to determine eligibility for such exemption.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1AF4953FC07E469EB14BA656C9C200DA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Title XVI</header><text>Section 1631(a)(2)(C) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1383">42 U.S.C. 1383(a)(2)(C)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HE233BD5646F44EA9A8F1F0ED88110518"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating clauses (iv) and (v) as clauses (v) and (vi), respectively;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD1FAA7C6A9EA4853B4BE7B5D6031F850"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after clause (iii) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H606E0966D2AC4A31BBD497526B47C094" style="OLC"> <clause id="HBE2297B52A5A403B872DEB3A11217169" indent="up2"><enum>(iv)</enum> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HFC75A74A7A0943199F0001AB6D6491C9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Clause (i) shall not apply in any case where the representative payee is—</text>
 <item id="HA0B0D0018C994B9B87133D249F78A724" indent="up1"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a parent, or other individual who is a legal guardian of, a minor child entitled to such payment who primarily resides in the same household;</text>
 </item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE84709895AF644C284B141290F2C5307" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a parent of an individual entitled to such payment who is under a disability who primarily resides in the same household; or</text>
 </item><item id="HD57BC01279B34A6496EC4AFF7F84094F" indent="up1"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the spouse of the individual entitled to such payment.</text> </item></subclause><subclause id="H9C6A27690AF544398839D0F7F161E65E" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The Commissioner of Social Security shall establish and implement procedures as necessary for the Commissioner to determine the eligibility of such parties for the exemption provided in subclause (I). The Commissioner shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to determine eligibility for such exemption.</text>
								</subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDF342CC65F6644F59E5DF70FBF3334E9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in clause (v) (as so redesignated), by striking <quote>and (iii)</quote> and inserting <quote>(iii), and (iv)</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H49FC0A12618F46E68D4CBC4796FBC0FE"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause (vi) (as so redesignated), by striking <quote>(iv)</quote> each time it appears and inserting <quote>(v)</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB54F8DAF79FC4799BEE0A52016C5A7FD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text> </subsection></section><section id="HE471BF097D28430E9AF1DF6B51211EAC" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>103.</enum><header>Protecting beneficiaries through information sharing</header> <subsection id="H95E5EAC261D94F2BB2B8A1C76F9FF1F9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Information sharing To determine State foster care status</header> <paragraph id="H353CB0480DBA4CD798623869AF2A30BF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 205(j) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/405">42 U.S.C. 405(j)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7ACE267A4B984D2ABFCE938AD95845BC" style="OLC">
							<paragraph id="H981FCD6ADCAD46C5B2CBB96599A1799A" indent="up1"><enum>(11)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HDCFE12548DCA45C4A981AAAB8C7906CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Commissioner of Social Security shall—</text> <clause id="H154FD811DB8B4342BF77A5EF32C5FFBC" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>enter into agreements with each State with a plan approved under part E of title IV for the purpose of sharing and matching data, on an automated monthly basis, in the system of records of the Social Security Administration with each Statewide and Tribal Automated Child Welfare Information System to identify represented minor beneficiaries who are in foster care under the responsibility of the State for such month; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFDCA4362ACBF4AD3ACD6D32D88EEBC40" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in any case in which a represented minor beneficiary has entered or exited foster care or changed foster care placement in such month, redetermine the appropriate representative payee for such individual.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F92C322AF894E7DBE1BD577EB8CD895" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph—</text> <clause id="H108EDA7035284FE6AAC0CD82D47FCB7C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>State</term> has the meaning given such term for purposes of part E of title IV;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB85DF953454C4D2082CD77349F6F3C15"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the term <term>Statewide and Tribal Automated Child Welfare Information System</term> means a statewide mechanized data collection and information retrieval system described in section 474(a)(3)(C); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB6BA2FE4ACFC4E00BA0E41F650A989EE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the term <term>represented minor beneficiary</term>, with respect to an individual for a month, means a child (as defined for purposes of section 475(8)) entitled to benefits under this title for such month whose benefits are certified for payment to a representative payee.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4DEC775AAF414DC6B36617824F75A728"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming change</header><text>Section 471(a)(8)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/671">42 U.S.C. 671(a)(8)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>the program established by title II,</quote> after <quote>XX,</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H66F5BF04C5FB4B5382DFB3C5687F054C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>GAO study and report</header> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H96616754B58D4B17B696AFD3A1199D99"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As soon as possible after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall evaluate—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H48EE8BFED5F744A1A3F29859CC1AD158"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of represented minor beneficiaries in foster care under the responsibility of a State for each month during the previous year;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H2FAAA0CDA7484E709CF9065FCA5A2F58"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>whether the representative payee for each represented minor beneficiary is—</text> <subclause commented="no" id="H69AE8C7A66104AAE84FFC60A958F4FF4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a governmental child welfare agency;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H94B077B296FE488A9D48B469C3928015"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an organizational payee that is not a governmental child welfare agency;</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HCF9C2A94A4DC4D4CAF2FBBB0BAF2D9DD"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a foster parent or child-care institution (within the meaning of part E of title IV); or</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H0054DE0EC62345198DCF85A20E1ED000"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>another individual; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="H947FEF6273C744B4886C6BB757E56265"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether funds were conserved, used for direct expenses of the minor beneficiary, or used to reimburse the State for foster care maintenance costs.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HCE961496F9F04469B0D7E5FD5CFE8545"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 36 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit to Congress a report on the results of the evaluation required under subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA2B18BA22A4742E3A52B3E34DD44BAA6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HF3C32F59BAF94594A2482C03DB69890F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the term <term>State</term> has the meaning given such term for purposes of part E of title IV of the Social Security Act; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H6A4669C72F434BF48DDD04F2FC810945"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>represented minor beneficiary</term>, with respect to an individual for a month, means a child (as defined for purposes of section 475(8) of the Social Security Act) entitled to benefits under title II of such Act for such month whose benefits are certified for payment to a representative payee.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H42DE36A5F1CD44FAB24914A638A0F456"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Effective date</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HE5849DEDDB5A40B6972C968B7DFC7B26"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amendments made by this subsection shall apply with respect to months beginning on or after the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE0EC2BB68883498FAB9B1A04C9E56FC3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception if State legislation required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a State plan under part E of title IV of the Social Security Act that the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines requires State legislation (other than legislation appropriating funds) in order for the plan to meet the additional requirement imposed by the amendments made under this subsection, such plan shall not be regarded as failing to comply with the requirements of such title solely on the basis of its failure to meet this additional requirement before the first day of the first calendar quarter beginning after the close of the first regular session of the State legislature that begins after the date of the enactment of this Act. For purposes of the previous sentence, in the case of a State that has a 2-year legislative session, each year of such session shall be deemed to be a separate regular session of the State legislature.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H08930C2B8748477298EB5576B85F6AD6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Improving coordination with adult protective services</header>
 <paragraph id="H6C6C36807F4E4BCE931240A6199F9AF8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner of Social Security shall study and test the administrative feasibility of improving information sharing, in partnership with State agencies that provide adult protective services, with respect to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H18E1246958ED4115B588E049A6426F95"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the assessment of an individual’s need for a representative payee in connection with benefits to which the individual is entitled under title II or title XVI of the Social Security Act; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C2E9EBCAA2D404882313A88DDE4C790"><enum>(B)</enum><text>oversight of individuals and organizations serving as representative payees.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B58B829299C460BAA07B4B90687C538"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than June 30, 2022, the Commissioner of Social Security shall conclude the study described in paragraph (1) and submit to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate a report on the results of such study.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H289F8351941A414394140FAFC39D5AC1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Study on potential To coordinate with State courts</header>
 <paragraph id="HE583D8EE638A44908575190E0AADA284"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner of Social Security shall enter into an agreement with the Administrative Conference of the United States to conduct a study that includes—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H666EEC4AFFE04FAB876915B6DC5B5807"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an overview of potential opportunities for information sharing between the Social Security Administration and State courts and relevant State agencies;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38A2FEED5A064702B67802F567145C3E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a detailed analysis of the barriers to such information sharing, including any Federal or State statutory barriers;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8726D78D65564A44977358BA34EDF5D4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of how such information sharing would be implemented, including any additional infrastructure needed; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89F10917519F487D8BB613AE1A5DDB51"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of any risks or other factors that the Social Security Administration and the Congress should consider before implementing such information sharing.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5B8FF9143A94F7BA7DCF9C1735EC1EB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than June 30, 2020, the Commissioner of Social Security shall submit to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate and make publicly available a report on the results of the study conducted under paragraph (1).</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFF4CD5EA419E43E38BB7ECA826CB2275"><enum>104.</enum><header>Clarifying overpayment liability for child in child welfare system</header>
 <subsection id="HC0994854F0CD43A6A0C1AB474355A3F4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendment to title II</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 204(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/404">42 U.S.C. 404(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6EEADE8AAEB94323B0E21F829BFDF09A" style="OLC">
						<paragraph id="HAEF5D5168F0C485781DC5031CA604BF1" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HCA7749F13D234F879F0335AD77520C7F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When any payment of more than the correct amount is made on behalf of an individual who is a represented minor beneficiary for a month in which such individual is in foster care under the responsibility of a State and the State is the representative payee of such individual, the State shall be liable for the repayment of the overpayment, and there shall be no adjustment of payments to, or recovery by the United States from, such individual.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H777C2DD050B34CB9B7D0715C1AE4C140" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>represented minor beneficiary</term> has the meaning given such term in subsection (j)(11)(B)(iii).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="HECD38316D17D4245AC5167E49FC7ABD6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amendment to title XVI</header><text>Section 1631(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1683">42 U.S.C. 1683(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H57A3FBB37A53498E93153585166DD09A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (3) through (7) as paragraphs (4) through (8), respectively; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H92B5D99AC00A4A72ABFBCF21CC55AFB6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCBC25C0C3125498186D0426F4B4A8A2A" style="OLC">
							<paragraph id="H2C4EAB9AB8AB450AB86D66E36ECD980A" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HBE02BCC4B02249BDA9A478E2318C4832"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When any payment of more than the correct amount is made on behalf of an individual who is a represented minor beneficiary for a month in which such individual is in foster care under the responsibility of a State and the State is the representative payee of such individual, the State shall be liable for the repayment of the overpayment, and there shall be no adjustment of payments to, or recovery by the United States from, such individual.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13BDB143B63844FB84D66F3171EA6422" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>represented minor beneficiary</term>, with respect to an individual for a month, means a child (as defined for purposes of section 475(8)) entitled to benefits under this title for such month whose benefits are certified for payment to a representative payee.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H65097B9DB6AC4A4BA5B34BD1C723C7F5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to overpayments made on or after the date of the enactment of this Act and to any other overpayments that have not been recovered as of such date.</text>
				</subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCA64AA135FA140C9838B884D9B7DECE8" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>105.</enum><header>Reports</header>
 <subsection id="HDB117E053AD74D65ADF084422C4BD5EB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report on benefits misused</header><text>Section 205(j) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/405">42 U.S.C. 405(j)</external-xref>), as amended by section 103(a), is further amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H10E00F671B904E9FA80770B9E6EA3F3F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (6)—</text> <subparagraph id="H0B3C948C453846A9938C33006983ADAA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(A) In addition to</quote> and inserting <quote>In addition to</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCAAA780BE6F9491293D8F76EFC30900E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (B); and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H35167938C05D4939894F5C33A7531BCC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDE36045617104A6A8CB269E682A1F3C3" style="OLC">
							<paragraph id="H356C02C30A8F486DB6C0DEDA22943877" indent="up1"><enum>(12)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA190C9D8126C4D7C8D0B728A80AD287A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Not later than January 31 of each fiscal year, the Commissioner shall submit to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate a report on the results of all reviews of representative payees conducted during the previous fiscal year in connection with benefits under this title, title VIII, or title XVI. Such report shall summarize problems identified in such reviews and corrective actions taken or planned to be taken to correct such problems, and shall include—</text>
 <clause id="H9872207D7EC54FDAA1ABA4850AFF0299" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of such reviews;</text> </clause><clause id="HB0BD23259D6C44A5BED13452E9BDF2D9" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the results of such reviews;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF5B0B1EF13D943538765C9C8FE3A0053" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the number of cases in which the representative payee was changed and why;</text> </clause><clause id="HEE0A17E9B49F4530B146EEE2398DB057" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of reviews conducted in response to allegations or concerns about the performance or suitability of the payee;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFA801C8120EF411AB1D746C24D685CFD" indent="up1"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the number of cases discovered in which there was a misuse of funds, and the total dollar amount of benefits determined by the Commissioner during such fiscal year to have been misused by a representative payee (regardless of the fiscal year in which such misuse occurred);</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCF526E0F1D3F4A96AFA031CED2E2C551" indent="up1"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the number of cases discovered in which such misuse of funds resulted from the negligent failure of the Commissioner to investigate or monitor a representative payee;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H793DFCFB034D4ACB9251A74C839D7130" indent="up1"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the final disposition of such cases of misuse of funds, including—</text> <subclause id="H937E33D001B64A4CBCB5888DCE1EFA56"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any criminal, civil, and administrative penalties imposed;</text>
 </subclause><subclause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H58017974E280449EB01889B43671F14A"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total dollar amount of misused benefits repaid to beneficiaries and alternative representative payees under each of—</text>
 <item id="H4B05D16B657F4EB8B5649C46C6335EA8"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">paragraph (5) (on the basis of a negligent failure of the Commissioner described in such paragraph);</text>
 </item><item id="H6E1396AE7C734748914D3F9D37924EE5"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>paragraph (5) (on any other basis); and</text> </item><item id="H892A7DD7BD3E41F9B60E4C542F992E63"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>paragraph (7); and</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H6568D4B071E64F3F9A0BFA6AFF57B8E5"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the total dollar amount of misused benefits recovered under each of—</text> <item id="H0E11154FB8A14E38826B70F8E2CAEA69"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>paragraph (5); and</text>
 </item><item id="HB8BA30387D424A608D44D511A58B5282"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>paragraph (7);</text> </item></subclause></clause><clause id="H86F5948F2BA44DFAB4D605D9ECEC8BAE" indent="up1"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any updates to prior year reports necessary to reflect subsequent recoveries and repayments pertaining to misuse determinations made in prior years; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD9AA84E5543C49D5B295A78BBAFC6375" indent="up1"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>such other information as the Commissioner deems appropriate.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H39674C3A374745E683FAB5B4A0DE4ECA" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report required under this paragraph for a fiscal year shall include the information described in clauses (i) through (ix) of subparagraph (A) with respect to—</text>
 <clause id="HEB69A218CEB8449DB25F0E332AE0FE16"><enum>(i)</enum><text>all representative payees reviewed during such fiscal year;</text> </clause><clause id="H48A928F2D9934C95806BFB084DBA912C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>all such representative payees that are organizations, separated by whether such organization collects a fee for its services as a representative payee;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H743DC26FCFC14D2F88FCB07719CE198C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>all such representative payees that are individuals serving 15 or more individuals; and</text> </clause><clause id="H66287C75DC4745AC8422710B813A055A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all such representative payees that are individuals serving less than 15 individuals, separated by whether such representative payee is a family member.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H41455BA2B138489EB6B0DA1E7DD9762F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report on elimination of the accounting form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner shall—</text> <paragraph id="H23F27C67143E40A390E14BE5131289D6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a study on the changes made by the amendments made by section 102 of the <short-title>Strengthening Protections for Social Security Beneficiaries Act of 2017</short-title>, which shall include the impact of such changes on families, beneficiaries, and the operations of the Social Security Administration; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H27751D0AC1B548EAAC263CD62EB7D5EE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than January 1, 2021, submit a report on the results of such study to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8CF859AAF00B4DBA80A7F2D695EAB8B1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report on the advanced designation policy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner shall—</text> <paragraph id="H65517C552FAD4EDDAAA18B2DC237D907"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a study on the changes made by the amendments made by section 201 of the <short-title>Strengthening Protections for Social Security Beneficiaries Act of 2017</short-title>, which shall include the impact of such changes on beneficiaries and the operations of the Social Security Administration; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H61EC8DD8E95C42CDB863743352C03401"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than January 1, 2025, submit a report on the results of such study to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="H87B2DA809B514C2DB922333958415BA8"><enum>II</enum><header>Improving Payee Selection and Quality</header>
			<section id="H53E0445C54AF4ED69DBE6AC81B5E5C25" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>201.</enum><header>Advance designation of representative payees</header>
 <subsection id="H3F2C2D063DCF412AB46738FA1EA35831"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 205(j)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/405">42 U.S.C. 405(j)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H72811DDF3D084BE4B534FEF99BEBEA7A" style="OLC">
						<subparagraph id="H6C9E45F6A22547029E5758BA799EE201" indent="up2"><enum>(C)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H3E772FF40BAD448C88732AB18FEF356F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual who is entitled to or is an applicant for a benefit under this title, title VIII, or title XVI, who has attained 18 years of age or is an emancipated minor, may, at any time, designate one or more other individuals to serve as a representative payee for such individual in the event that the Commissioner of Social Security determines under subparagraph (A) that the interest of such individual would be served by certification for payment of such benefits to which the individual is entitled to a representative payee. If the Commissioner of Social Security makes such a determination with respect to such individual at any time after such designation has been made, the Commissioner shall—</text>
 <subclause id="H6FEA1BB2FFE649C08B9833F56041F1FE" indent="up1"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">certify payment of such benefits to the designated individual, subject to the requirements of paragraph (2); or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H18E6C1AACEF146239E4F94BC30C4EF09" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if the Commissioner determines that certification for payment of such benefits to the designated individual would not satisfy the requirements of paragraph (2), that the designated individual is unwilling or unable to serve as representative payee, or that other good cause exists, certify payment of such benefits to another individual or organization, in accordance with paragraph (1).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HA503DC1A4F6947CBB58F2A2E7C8B183B" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An organization may not be designated to serve as a representative payee under this subparagraph.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H80C28773A3A94CCD9C00E8D4C4C835C4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall take effect on the date that is 2 years after the date of the enactment of this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD60634EE122446E2BF8B330BBBE35514"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this section, the Commissioner of Social Security shall promulgate regulations specifying the information an individual is required to provide to the Commissioner in order to designate another individual to serve as the individual’s representative payee under section 205(j)(1)(C) of the Social Security Act (as added by subsection (a)).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H54937EFA22DA47A682DBD486E1C39EDF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notification to beneficiaries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than January 1, 2020, and annually thereafter, the Commissioner of Social Security shall notify each individual entitled to a benefit under title II, VIII, or XVI of the Social Security Act of the name of any individual designated to serve as the individual’s representative payee under section 205(j)(1)(C) of such Act (as added by subsection (a)).</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="HC9AEFF428861404A9FE369D97B37D478"><enum>202.</enum><header>Prohibition on individuals convicted of certain crimes serving as representative payees</header>
 <subsection id="HBBDB004B7BAA47A7B31F1F2C80CEA02A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendments to title II</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 205(j)(2) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/405">42 U.S.C. 405(j)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H2C17215F7F574BA8B28040D658F544F0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H262908832C494B619B11278497C94DCC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (i)—</text> <clause id="H4BFD0D20F27A4459B4D1C14D68A37390"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subclause (V), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5544E1661E9547138F73B5A317F4923A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subclause (VI), by striking the period and inserting <quote>, and</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="HF2E5F41209A64F058D261F8751142158"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
								<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H42B4FABFB0234AC2BFF916CDD2B26E34" style="OLC">
 <subclause id="H1C40D371CE2D49C2B95F0D6ED6371195" indent="up3"><enum>(VII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine whether such person has been convicted, under Federal or State law, of a felony provided under clause (iv), or of an attempt or a conspiracy to commit such a felony.</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E07CDAD00384FCCB6B514EFD3451819"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1D6F000A5B9A40E4ABBC7643F0C310A8" style="OLC"> <clause commented="no" id="H0B24996C6DDA420EB5D1C5342AF88AD4" indent="up3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The felony crimes provided under this clause, whether an offense under State or Federal law, are the following:</text>
 <subclause commented="no" id="HDF4D32DD8146456E8893931181A0E3B1"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Human trafficking, including as prohibited under sections 1590 and 1591 of title 18, United States Code.</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HD05D43D30E43479497ECA0B2D389038E"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">False imprisonment, including as prohibited under section 1201 of title 18, United States Code.</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H0411130F64B8498D81D88888EEF33B95"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Kidnapping, including as prohibited under section 1201 of title 18, United States Code.</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H4179141629354A28A91CCF709B3CC298"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rape and sexual assault, including as prohibited under sections 2241, 2242, 2243, and 2244 of title 18, United States Code.</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H4300A2E9F59948F6BDC0935B47681EE1"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">First-degree homicide, including as prohibited under section 1111 of title 18, United States Code.</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H08D4B7126E634AAFA853C7243C7880A3"><enum>(VI)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Robbery, including as prohibited under section 2111 of title 18, United States Code.</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HFBAF95A1322B49B7B96F6DE760DEBA50"><enum>(VII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Fraud to obtain access to government assistance, including as prohibited under sections 287, 1001, and 1343 of title 18, United States Code.</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HDC7DB0FB5BFA43D98EB6461746D1DA52"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>Fraud by scheme, including as prohibited under section 1343 of title 18, United States Code.</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HFE9A86CCD1EE4182839DFD36345461DA"><enum>(IX)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Theft of government funds or property, including as prohibited under section 641 of title 18, United States Code.</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HFA0D0FD698D34D84B7B93CAF50B287FC"><enum>(X)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Abuse or neglect, including as prohibited under sections 111, 113, 114, 115, 116, or 117 of title 18, United States Code.</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HFDF3E72A45D643159D73EF2B2B92ADD1"><enum>(XI)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Forgery, including as prohibited under section 642 and chapter 25 (except section 512) of title 18, United States Code.</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H660C8A3B9F174780B2670D88B46F0F38"><enum>(XII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identity theft or identity fraud, including as prohibited under sections 1028 and 1028A of title 18, United States Code.</text>
									</subclause><continuation-text commented="no" continuation-text-level="clause">The Commissioner of Social Security may promulgate regulations to provide for additional felony
			 crimes under this clause.</continuation-text></clause><clause id="HC27D789BB26B4C6FB71ADBB8775AFCF0" indent="up3"><enum>(v)</enum>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0357DEEAB56949329682EE887C40F5DA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>For the purpose of carrying out the activities required under subparagraph (B)(i) as part of the investigation under subparagraph (A)(i), the Commissioner may conduct a background check of any individual seeking to serve as a representative payee under this subsection and may disqualify from service as a representative payee any such individual who fails to grant permission for the Commissioner to conduct such a background check.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HFB9E5DC2DA814495BE02AB4F6F17064C" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The Commissioner may revoke certification of payment of benefits under this subsection to any individual serving as a representative payee on or after January 1, 2019, who fails to grant permission for the Commissioner to conduct such a background check.</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3097947822344925BB20CE28655616AC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)—</text> <subparagraph id="H7F1D3EA23C304AAF83B68D47C05D4405"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (i)—</text>
 <clause id="HB2D72615568443CEBB0D081ECF827C34"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subclause (IV), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text> </clause><clause id="H7F9AC8024BAA4C26AACD6761A63AD3EC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subclause (V), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>, or</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1847A3A6AE604D44B0B6DA38B43F234F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H02A20DFA0A4742F4803071708C08D593" style="OLC"> <subclause id="HD743AD57C98B421B999A2DC1E1FD3460" indent="up3"><enum>(VI)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">except as provided in clause (vi), such person has previously been convicted as described in subparagraph (B)(i)(VII).</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2040C2A01DCA404F9D5999DA3A4399E5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1D23653E8963473081E1AB2A0B1F6523" style="OLC"> <clause commented="no" id="HF2E74D0FC27346898A119CFF312F0320" indent="up3"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner of Social Security may grant an exemption from the provisions of clause (i)(VI), if the Commissioner determines that such exemption is in the best interest of the individual entitled to such benefits, to any person who—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEC42507338B944C79651B3C585A8CB59"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is the custodial parent of a minor child for whom the person applies to serve;</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HA3513442DEB144B3980985F552222A6C"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is the custodial spouse of the beneficiary for whom the person applies to serve;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H691F662C1D884968968AFDDCA2234870"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is the custodial parent of a beneficiary who is under a disability (as defined in section 223(d)) which began before the beneficiary attained the age of 22, for whom the person applies to serve;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HE409F2A9CDA24045A39639323206D98F"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is the custodial court appointed guardian of the beneficiary for whom the person applies to serve;</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HADD89724BE5D4971B0E09DD700FCD0B5"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is the custodial grandparent of a minor grandchild for whom the person applies to serve;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H25ECB150F1254B7D95328FF3E36DC88F"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>is the parent who was previously representative payee for his or her minor child who has since turned 18 and continues to be eligible for such benefit; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H9DA5C9FC1CD44663BB56437321F464D2"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>received a presidential or gubernatorial pardon for the relevant conviction.</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAABBC8E4D7144D1790F8CBB29E4126E4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amendments to title VIII</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 807 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1007">42 U.S.C. 1007</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE98831EFD28A4B0DBD9C4D0D7F955714"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <subparagraph id="H51E2ECB2DDFE4D3DA621B27666687406"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text>
 <clause id="H6BA3823941304DFD907CBEFBAD0A1E29"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text> </clause><clause id="HAD0AFD46E7604698A09D1CA2A528CA49"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (F), by striking the period and inserting <quote>, and</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H29277420F5964A8D8C3F4876BBBCF7DD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2B64A04B7C164BB18A7B33D3CD3FCEC2" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HAA19857EE67F4898A79F265D27DECA3C"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine whether such person has been convicted, under Federal or State law, of a felony provided under paragraph (4), or of an attempt or a conspiracy to commit such a felony.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3CEE922E7C204FC1898C0DB46C526989"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H21746D09C7C14889BFE93341669F177A" style="OLC"> <paragraph commented="no" id="HAF26F2E66B7A49BBB7344AFDCF32177D"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The felony crimes provided under this paragraph, whether an offense under State or Federal law, are the following:</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H473AB8C583E44341BF87957E0C309E3E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Human trafficking, including as prohibited under sections 1590 and 1591 of title 18, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HCE08E574D88649D39F3113A914E684E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">False imprisonment, including as prohibited under section 1201 of title 18, United States Code.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H78B930CDD1AD4389939EA312F5885EED"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Kidnapping, including as prohibited under section 1201 of title 18, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6808A3EAF8634782AF786A44D983FABE"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rape and sexual assault, including as prohibited under sections 2241, 2242, 2243, and 2244 of title 18, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H122F15D690C84A84B319EE74CBDE7A9A"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">First-degree homicide, including as prohibited under section 1111 of title 18, United States Code.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HDFC7FCC409824CD58C1D21347A09B000"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Robbery, including as prohibited under section 2111 of title 18, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB35585DABBE04C43B3B576DF9E183E38"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Fraud to obtain access to government assistance, including as prohibited under sections 287, 1001, and 1343 of title 18, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HDEC4CDF89F8E49908273F3EE3604F002"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Fraud by scheme, including as prohibited under section 1343 of title 18, United States Code.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC25C5BD5B8904F4B8ABF8447958AAF56"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Theft of government funds or property, including as prohibited under section 641 of title 18, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HCE519D3D14144470A4CFF54524B67843"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Abuse or neglect, including as prohibited under sections 111, 113, 114, 115, 116, or 117 of title 18, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H910DCB26EED142CCAA556E46E2755D74"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Forgery, including as prohibited under section 642 and chapter 25 (except section 512) of title 18, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2D25F499C3864F56995F7A959729CC9F"><enum>(L)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identity theft or identity fraud, including as prohibited under sections 1028 and 1028A of title 18, United States Code.</text>
									</subparagraph><continuation-text commented="no" continuation-text-level="paragraph">The Commissioner of Social Security may promulgate regulations to provide for additional felony
			 crimes under this clause.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H20CDC93EE0664E2199FB9CAA906C293A" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H8F8147767EAD4204B0AC85CA4E8F6EB4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>For the purpose of carrying out the activities required under paragraph (2) as part of the investigation under paragraph (1)(A), the Commissioner may conduct a background check of any individual seeking to serve as a representative payee under this subsection and may disqualify from service as a representative payee any such individual who fails to grant permission for the Commissioner to conduct such a background check.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC614FD926EAA4700BA71DA0FA2A025C1" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Commissioner may revoke certification of payment of benefits under this subsection to any individual serving as a representative payee on or after January 1, 2019 who fails to grant permission for the Commissioner to conduct such a background check.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H18A40352088B4FBAA2B246E671860987"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (d)—</text> <subparagraph id="HB33B6504D33B481EB8F621F2A794F21F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text>
 <clause id="HB4DC75177B834CB3B57A657086D65284"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (D), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text> </clause><clause id="HF6149216E1E44BC89D5825976F4ADBCA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (E), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>, or</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2F707656395F4E68A9D4B141D0E23A81"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H841B330DCDF74C9483B905A5929B15A9" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H6A53401BBE314ACC90656C0C421CD762"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">except as provided in paragraph (2)(D), such person has previously been convicted as described in subsection (b)(2)(G).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1DF9AE6B17BE410BBD76392C0E234436"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8E3C556BE9F7427B977747BCC6231CAA" style="OLC"> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H5794FC6DD33444E0B65CA0D4CA37D718"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner of Social Security may grant an exemption from the provisions of paragraph (1)(F), if the Commissioner determines that such exemption is in the best interest of the individual entitled to such benefits, to any person who—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H02D6341C5D1E46C89BB895C5F47D5D17"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is the custodial spouse of the beneficiary for whom the person applies to serve;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H8D9F767D4F424F8B8FA266763A9F6C30"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is the custodial court appointed guardian of the beneficiary for whom the person applies to serve; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HBCAB9DF70E3B481D8000FAF98CC0CB00"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>received a presidential or gubernatorial pardon for the relevant conviction.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H84FEAF793C9E482FBD17E32316888FEA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Amendments to title XVI</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1631(a)(2)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1383">42 U.S.C. 1383(a)(2)(B)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H22B125192843426CA1DAB750E845E728"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (ii)—</text> <subparagraph id="HCCCC4ED372F742A2A86C3ADFE83F8D44"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subclause (V), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E284715ECBA45678F0D4E10A5377DCB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subclause (VI), by striking the period and inserting <quote>, and</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H52FD6ECCA8EF4C9C88F98BE8E2A67C03"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H602A5B39AC0948EC8B74734EA8133BD0" style="OLC">
 <subclause id="H924580878DC94281BAEB62F586AF00B7" indent="up3"><enum>(VII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine whether such person has been convicted, under Federal or State law, of a felony provided under clause (xv), or of an attempt or a conspiracy to commit such a felony.</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC2FBE2E923E45358A45A8AF4CCE696E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (iii)—</text> <subparagraph id="H59905FF037D943C4BCCD5A48A5EFBC8D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subclause (IV), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1679E480685421EA677043558A61829"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subclause (V), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>, or</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B8143B809594174B87CB9E6FB01A4C0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD154F7AC479645D5968700A09B8CC1FE" style="OLC">
 <subclause id="H46F6F779B6504EE8B8167F6F2E358145" indent="up3"><enum>(VI)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">except as provided in clause (xvii), such person has previously been convicted as described in clause (ii)(VII).</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D579DACB1684F4BA19F6097630FEE66"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H194728ECE0CA4308BF46910C199E562A" style="OLC"> <clause commented="no" id="H68B3D3A769AE47B58A479E3AF7AC94AC" indent="up3"><enum>(xv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The felony crimes provided under this clause, whether an offense under State or Federal law, are the following:</text>
 <subclause commented="no" id="H862CB59782B6430097DE76284C84D84F"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Human trafficking, including as prohibited under sections 1590 and 1591 of title 18, United States Code.</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H47023C8760444108BAFEDD5DE38336CF"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">False imprisonment, including as prohibited under section 1201 of title 18, United States Code.</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H4E342A58991248929E5BA75A272FFC6A"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Kidnapping, including as prohibited under section 1201 of title 18, United States Code.</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HA888D9A644434367A6855E8B67163D65"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rape and sexual assault, including as prohibited under sections 2241, 2242, 2243, and 2244 of title 18, United States Code.</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HE93DE186E22440369EA3F0397A56399C"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">First-degree homicide, including as prohibited under section 1111 of title 18, United States Code.</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HBE7474781EFC4A76B82A318A5871EBD6"><enum>(VI)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Robbery, including as prohibited under section 2111 of title 18, United States Code.</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HCD962AB625E046CF8CED54E600E367E4"><enum>(VII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Fraud to obtain access to government assistance, including as prohibited under sections 287, 1001, and 1343 of title 18, United States Code.</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HB242C04B70C0409DA9D44B00BF8DE3A6"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>Fraud by scheme, including as prohibited under section 1343 of title 18, United States Code.</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HC8871701261E42B4A7031FE4C396F563"><enum>(IX)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Theft of government funds or property, including as prohibited under section 641 of title 18, United States Code.</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HE3D5D6F591A54B6E82731990429BAB4E"><enum>(X)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Abuse or neglect, including as prohibited under sections 111, 113, 114, 115, 116, or 117 of title 18, United States Code.</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H096A34C6EC2A4E9FADA98FE112F87354"><enum>(XI)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Forgery, including as prohibited under section 642 and chapter 25 (except section 512) of title 18, United States Code.</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HC207E58B7F8741078EC7A6F8454480E4"><enum>(XII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identity theft or identity fraud, including as prohibited under sections 1028 and 1028A of title 18, United States Code.</text>
								</subclause><continuation-text commented="no" continuation-text-level="clause">The Commissioner of Social Security may promulgate regulations to provide for additional felony
			 crimes under this clause.</continuation-text></clause><clause id="HA14C9D67570144E0AE1CF4F9B7E9C5D7" indent="up3"><enum>(xvi)</enum>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H027F9655A6854AEDB3DD9D280195394B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>For the purpose of carrying out the activities required under clause (ii) as part of the investigation under clause (i)(I), the Commissioner may conduct a background check of any individual seeking to serve as a representative payee under this subsection and may disqualify from service as a representative payee any such individual who fails to grant permission for the Commissioner to conduct such a background check.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA125F682B2234E919475CBD61B0D72E5" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The Commissioner may revoke certification of payment of benefits under this subsection to any individual serving as a representative payee on or after January 1, 2019, who fails to grant permission for the Commissioner to conduct such a background check.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="HC02D54B2A61F4864A22573A31912E67E" indent="up3"><enum>(xvii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner of Social Security may grant an exemption from the provisions of clause (iii)(VI), if the Commissioner determines that such exemption is in the best interest of the individual entitled to such benefits, to any person who—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9D82526BF1A042CB88F2207AFB129DD3"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is the custodial parent of a minor child for whom the person applies to serve;</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H0431437879BC4114870E8D140AD6AA76"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is the custodial spouse of the beneficiary for whom the person applies to serve;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HC78D25A54FE0469C8D466E09F495EFA4"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is the custodial parent of a beneficiary who is under a disability which began before the beneficiary attained the age of 22, for whom the person applies to serve;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HF2FA5C913F6141C5B6337E5921420EE9"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is the custodial court appointed guardian of the beneficiary for whom the person applies to serve;</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H5E9289E78E354B3192552C88DDCE6F7D"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is the custodial grandparent of a minor grandchild for whom the person applies to serve;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H5349DD4F582342BE8205C9C1CF7F473E"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>is the parent who was previously representative payee for his or her minor child who has since turned 18 and continues to be eligible for such benefit; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HE0E5DA9428234D8E97ACD7E7D0599A27"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>received a presidential or gubernatorial pardon for the relevant conviction.</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H142EE585453743948B7B63473801C544"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application to new appointments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subsection (e), the amendments made by subsections (a), (b), and (c) shall apply with respect to any individual appointed to serve as a representative payee pursuant to section 205(j), 807, or 1631(a)(2) of the Social Security Act on or after January 1, 2019.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="H545C163DFF6B49D2930D88EE3A0C0B3A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Application to prior appointments</header>
 <paragraph id="HFCEA129C3F6E4AA58409F71B08ACD6FF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than January 1, 2024, the Commissioner of Social Security shall conduct a review of each individual serving as a representative payee pursuant to 205(j), 807, or 1631(a)(2) of the Social Security Act, to determine whether such individual has been convicted of a felony as described in section 205(j)(2)(B)(i)(VII), 807(b)(2)(G), or 1631(a)(2)(B)(ii)(VII), respectively (as such provisions are added by this section). Except as provided in section 205(j)(2)(C)(vi), 807(d)(2)(D), or 1631(a)(2)(B)(xvii) (as so added), any individual determined by the Commissioner to have been so convicted may not serve as a representative payee on or after the date of such determination.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0AE9A6A92B4145609A86809D2884E5C6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In conducting reviews under paragraph (1), the Commissioner shall prioritize reviews of the following categories of individuals, in the following order:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3C17F64E8F3242AEB3A3258EEF74DC2F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual serving as representative payee for 15 or more individuals.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H03941E4FF5B74FA99D07F1D97BBA0586"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual serving as representative payee for an individual who is not related to the representative payee.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H810182AF95F34FA29A6879717FA09058"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An individual serving as representative payee for an individual who has attained the age of 18 and is not the spouse of the representative payee.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2DFAF314BA5544208F10C86B2F01C80D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Periodic review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Commissioner of Social Security shall issue regulations to establish a process for reviewing each individual serving as a representative payee pursuant to section 205(j), 807, or 1631(a)(2) of the Social Security Act not less than once every 5 years to determine whether any such individual has been convicted of a felony as described in subsection (e)(1) of this section and is not subject to an exemption as described in such subsection.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="HCB983F875A644ADD9319F052948D44C9" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>203.</enum><header>Prohibition on individuals with representative payees serving as representative payees</header>
 <subsection id="HF14AA5B72B834A04A794A5AD11F52FB4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendment to title II</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 205(j)(2)(C)(i) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/405">42 U.S.C. 405(j)(2)(C)(i)</external-xref>), as amended by section 202(a)(2), is further amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD31B3D70544A448FBC45BE2CA6B9122E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subclause (V), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD07084A70FFD457E91F11548ECD0B104"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subclause (VI), by striking the period and inserting <quote>, or</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H86C7F566D21F4F969D478CF899C9E2D1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H98FF9A141BC348448170A347D6696AD3" style="OLC"> <subclause id="id152040AC12E4483EAA3112EC3CC8F28B" indent="up3"><enum>(VII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such person’s benefits under this title, title VIII, or title XVI are certified for payment to a representative payee during the period for which the individual’s benefits would be certified for payment to another person.</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5C4FAE4EB4AB431182A1679BC58E5FBF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amendment to title VIII</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 807(d)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1007">42 U.S.C. 1007(d)(1)</external-xref>), as amended by section 202(b)(2), is further amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB6EC340308A947E9B86A813F77F58960"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD57AC01BF558496EA8EC9479F8514352"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (F), by striking the period and inserting <quote>, or</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4B5E442E8AC64E6B944B6D1006B3FB67"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0D887A7A851742F2AC29E17F2FBE2D4B" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HF09CBC99E23C466BBFF3F660E6E1FECE"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such person’s benefits under this title, title II, or title XVI are certified for payment to a representative payee during the period for which the individual’s benefits would be certified for payment to another person.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H548EBB09A52045339E8C5285D2AF8E68"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Amendment to title XVI</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1631(a)(2)(B)(iii) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1383">42 U.S.C. 1383(a)(2)(B)(iii)</external-xref>), as amended by section 202(c)(2), is further amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H61AE6BA400984ADB9472BFF234CE931A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subclause (V), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H70053062ECDA4C4A916F8A428F072015"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subclause (VI), by striking the period and inserting <quote>, or</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7E31BB13C76C4451974448BB7B996DC1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4CC7F5A340E141F9BDB56AA369117155" style="OLC"> <subclause id="HD01ECA79158A445D969424DB6CAA7170" indent="up3"><enum>(VII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such person’s benefits under this title, title II, or title VIII are certified for payment to a representative payee during the period for which the individual’s benefits would be certified for payment to another person.</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H32200677B753467CBAE1E0FA10CDA3A2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header>
 <paragraph id="HB56B5161B89A4742A9FD314AE0A9AB46"><enum>(1)</enum><header>New appointments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to any individual appointed to serve as a representative payee under title II, title VIII, or title XVI of the Social Security Act on or after January 1, 2019.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H25C6B154A3E74D18ADF51E16D10AA2BB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prior appointments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to individuals serving as a representative payee whose benefits under this title, title VIII, or title XVI are certified for payment to another representative payee as of January 1, 2019, the Commissioner shall take any steps necessary to terminate such individual’s service as a representative payee as soon as possible, but no later than January 1, 2024.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1D9B3E39E4194E7C9D74B42C9AB19A46" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>204.</enum><header>Reassessment of payee selection and replacement policies</header>
 <subsection id="HC61939B6B06C4D3D957D3C356E89AE02"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner of Social Security shall conduct, with opportunity for public comment, a review and reassessment of—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA6689F889D2D45CA9EF96B50A9D60FB6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the appropriateness of its order of preference for selecting representative payees, including payees who may be creditors of the beneficiary or who are private, for-profit institutions; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC6B9BF935AC24B4C9184FB1D65FD6B07"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the effectiveness of its policy and operational procedures in properly determining when to change a representative payee, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H774F6368F61242B1A6662CE2593D61DB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>from a payee that has a higher order of preference (such as a family member) to a payee that has a lower order of preference (such as a creditor); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC1DE811E19449C9B34276E04648827D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>when a request to change payees arises from someone other than the beneficiary.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDF16EC9C4C8A4FE4A85A62E1D4BC9854"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commissioner of Social Security shall submit to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate and make publicly available a report on the results of the review and reassessment under subsection (a).</text>
				</subsection></section></title></legis-body></bill>


