<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1E7147E83A274FCAAB5462686FEFE1B5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2948 IH: To amend the S.A.F.E. Mortgage Licensing Act of 2008 to provide a temporary license for loan originators transitioning between employers, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2948</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170620">June 20, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001187">Mr. Stivers</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001191">Ms. Sinema</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000611">Mr. Poliquin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the S.A.F.E. Mortgage Licensing Act of 2008 to provide a temporary license for loan originators transitioning between employers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H55009C209B6043BC9CF67492B061A04A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H27337D61C0594CB980ADA7435216BC11" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Eliminating barriers to jobs for loan originators</header> 
<subsection id="H0CBDDB7F301647EA908150D4EE271BCB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The S.A.F.E. Mortgage Licensing Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5101">12 U.S.C. 5101</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HF05C0AE1594A401186C3C15B94BFABFA" style="OLC"> <section id="HA5046E56B62A440193B5796F1112EBC5"><enum>1518.</enum><header>Employment transition of loan originators</header> <subsection id="H222C1916F190477C8F8CF5657B5D5E68"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Temporary authority To originate loans for loan originators moving from a depository institution to a non-Depository institution</header> <paragraph id="H7DABDCFAE2A9472FB7EFAD1A01676A7F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon employment by a State-licensed mortgage company, an individual who is a registered loan originator shall be deemed to have temporary authority to act as a loan originator in an application State for the period described in paragraph (2) if the individual—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3DE9DBF5A8C44F96BD194A478131ED35"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has not had an application for a loan originator license denied, or had such a license revoked or suspended in any governmental jurisdiction;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF8C38E67EFDE46EEA06637C1F12D79F0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has not been subject to or served with a cease and desist order in any governmental jurisdiction or as described in section 1514(c);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1536D077F33744CDA03218290E5825E2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has not been convicted of a felony that would preclude licensure under the law of the application State;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H70D5EA3FB81E48938548D521EF7FBC46"><enum>(D)</enum><text>has submitted an application to be a State-licensed loan originator in the application State; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF4C4D19441C145609CD5253EE23F5459"><enum>(E)</enum><text>was registered in the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry as a loan originator during the 12-month period preceding the date of submission of the information required under section 1505(a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6B53B182472D4FDF877C1E7104EEFC5B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The period described in paragraph (1) shall begin on the date that the individual submits the information required under section 1505(a) and shall end on the earliest of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD54F47C359964AB6836B6CD52A31D6A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date that the individual withdraws the application to be a State-licensed loan originator in the application State;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H731C9FAD5F4846368A3E41C313543F58"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date that the application State denies, or issues a notice of intent to deny, the application;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5E5918B96D5F4349B53659CA704B6805"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date that the application State grants a State license; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H265C995CD90A40C4AF1A7004A6D476C0"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date that is 120 days after the date on which the individual submits the application, if the application is listed on the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry as incomplete.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H25AA12AE1B974B9B8F7BFBFA8A4F6EFC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Temporary authority To originate loans for State-Licensed loan originators moving interstate</header> 
<paragraph id="HE86ECC97DACA43CD9ED2045759350B2C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State-licensed loan originator shall be deemed to have temporary authority to act as a loan originator in an application State for the period described in paragraph (2) if the State-licensed loan originator—</text> <subparagraph id="H3CB3916B4BAD46EF839394F8D32375C0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>meets the requirements of subparagraphs (A), (B), (C), and (D) of subsection (a)(1);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA4DD49B1635A489993CEB893ED805C3E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is employed by a State-licensed mortgage company in the application State; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H677C0061D3CA477B8BD8FF6A79C5ACD4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>was licensed in a State that is not the application State during the 30-day period preceding the date of submission of the information required under section 1505(a) in connection with the application submitted to the application State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD8F5EEFAD98942958DC0AB5DF70DAEAA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The period described in paragraph (1) shall begin on the date that the State-licensed loan originator submits the information required under section 1505(a) in connection with the application submitted to the application State and end on the earliest of—</text> <subparagraph id="H47C9725330024F2193D872F032B7665D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date that the State-licensed loan originator withdraws the application to be a State-licensed loan originator in the application State;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD5C4B7B575BC4B0F8B6D2C21C74675D8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date that the application State denies, or issues a notice of intent to deny, the application;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB8C5187BB91D4949A4BDEEBDF717EBF8"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date that the application State grants a State license; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2F1A76E6F5C14ABDACDA7F60CBA3F62A"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date that is 120 days after the date on which the State-licensed loan originator submits the application, if the application is listed on the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry as incomplete.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC6E24A40FB2F41579590B70B018EDCD2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header> <paragraph id="H31F8971361EE4C73AB7A81109A4B7896"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person employing an individual who is deemed to have temporary authority to act as a loan originator in an application State pursuant to this section shall be subject to the requirements of this title and to applicable State law to the same extent as if such individual was a State-licensed loan originator licensed by the application State.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H071685405BA44D16911EED76207CB518"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any individual who is deemed to have temporary authority to act as a loan originator in an application State pursuant to this section and who engages in residential mortgage loan origination activities shall be subject to the requirements of this title and to applicable State law to the same extent as if such individual was a State-licensed loan originator licensed by the application State.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFFC8B0D274094B8690A88AE2C1754965"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the following definitions shall apply:</text> 
<paragraph id="HCD9AA8C135944247B66D4F160D216061" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>State-licensed mortgage company</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State-licensed mortgage company</term> means an entity licensed or registered under the law of any State to engage in residential mortgage loan origination and processing activities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE9341741722E478281F915863D4CCE73"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>application State</term> means a State in which a registered loan originator or a State-licensed loan originator seeks to be licensed.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8C78C8C56A0246E881BAAF6E041E67C1" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Housing and Economic Recovery Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4501">42 U.S.C. 4501</external-xref> note) is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 1517 the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1F9122BD3F284AB7A979AE097026BF2B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 1518. Employment transition of loan originators.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="H3E83735972C64AC5A14ABA30128B5539"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amendment to civil liability of the Bureau and other officials</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1513 of the S.A.F.E. Mortgage Licensing Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5112">12 U.S.C. 5112</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>are loan originators or are applying for licensing or registration as loan originators.</quote> and inserting <quote>have applied, are applying, or are currently licensed or registered through the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry. The previous sentence shall only apply to persons in an industry with respect to which persons were licensed or registered through the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry on the date of the enactment of this sentence.</quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HE8B4B05988E64E7CA4119956DA1CDAC0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act and the amendments made by this Act shall take effect on the date that is 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

