<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCD6FEA45CAD944ADA6C83908934E9D98" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3246 IH: Teachers and Parents at the Table Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3246</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170714">July 14, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000602">Miss Rice of New York</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to establish a Teacher Advisory
			 Committee and a Parents and Families Advisory Committee.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H071AB337A76D45ADB41C224F12C81753" style="OLC">
 <section id="HA82CCECC7E10474780AED7E198CBE198" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Teachers and Parents at the Table Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HFB7AA97FC9FE4A809751E53B8375AFF4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Teacher Advisory committee</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6301">20 U.S.C. 6301</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by inserting after section 1004 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6304">20 U.S.C. 6304</external-xref>) the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="HB69BF149C39B46D58F45C4BD3D42785C" style="OLC">
				<section id="HC6841A78C9C44AED9B659D66C429CE8D"><enum>1005.</enum><header>Teacher Advisory Committee</header>
 <subsection id="HB8FC04864080486C87C71729AB2E000E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Congress finds as follows:</text> <paragraph id="HCFBDD27F09BF4DFA810EB01861D8EE13"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Expert teachers offer an important resource to policymakers as they can bring their expertise and perspective from the classroom to inform policy so that positive outcomes for all students will be maximized.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H873603B2DC3443A99110283391E0CA64"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">State Teachers of the Year represent a valuable resource with a body of expert knowledge and skill about instructional practice, 21st century learning, and school functioning that can be infused into policymaking to promote better outcomes for prekindergarten, elementary, and secondary students.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H84C4E1ABDBBE411893A3B3EC0C6104BA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>State Teachers of the Year have been selected by their communities and States as models of their profession and represent every State in the Nation and every discipline and grade level.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H218E96DD2CC2466C836F240150668F19"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary shall establish an advisory committee, to be known as the Teacher Advisory Committee (referred to in this section as the <quote>Committee</quote>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6D6FFD41CD184629A020A55B25270537"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The duty of the Committee shall be to bring the perspective of expert teachers to policymakers regarding the implementation and impact of the Every Student Succeeds Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/95">Public Law 114–95</external-xref>) and to make policy recommendations.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="HC7AD586017284B03B5C1826C24CF1A1E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Membership</header>
 <paragraph id="H79845AC2B0264FB1897316BDC500D603"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The membership of the Committee shall consist of not more than 10 teachers employed in a public elementary school and not more than 10 teachers employed in a public secondary school who—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H972A2F1D5A6F49ACBA412704BA585F62"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are past or present finalists or State Teachers of the Year, or are nominated from organizations representing teachers and have demonstrated similar evidence of expertise;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H14C8818836D941F7AE6462E90A9D8A49"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have experience working with educational policy;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEBBE9731825143259E9E33C13EB0AF47"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have a demonstrated history of working as a teacher leader in the policy arena; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H60E4B101E1EA4BB2A032A2FD20BD1833"><enum>(D)</enum><text>have submitted an application to the Secretary to serve on the Committee.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H224247DF70484964A25866F3FCEA6552"><enum>(2)</enum><header>List; appointment</header><text>The Secretary shall compile a list of teachers submitting applications under paragraph (1)(D). The members of the Committee shall be appointed sequentially as follows:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB3831332131743F2A2A6A925E2762FCD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Secretary shall appoint 4 teachers from the list.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5EEB140622DE46F99543B2ABD559955C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Majority Leader of the Senate shall appoint 4 teachers from the list.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8DF4EC165DF5400FA7B1707488373134"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Minority Leader of the Senate shall appoint 4 teachers from the list.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA17D52814FCC440D9787D10869BF7376"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Speaker of the House of Representatives shall appoint 4 teachers from the list.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B7B205C10104085840DC7DA0EC71D0E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Minority Leader of the House of Representatives shall appoint 4 teachers from the list.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H49CE21C7894B49B7845B128DAE1E22AD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Special requirements</header> <subparagraph id="H1D23F317198D4FA484212175C9A06AD8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Finalists or State Teachers of the Year</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less than half of the members of the Committee shall be past or present finalists or State Teachers of the Year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D250E07B8DA422F960FF309937C80EE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Representation requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The members of the Committee shall represent the diversity of the teaching workforce from multiple geographic, grade level, and specialty areas (such as English Language Learners, high ability, et al.).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C1BEAA64FDD46BABFA9C91A06BE7CEE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Term</header><text>Each member of the Committee shall serve on the Committee for a 3-year term.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE457B185194944669F591B2B0DC66E69"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Annual report</header> <paragraph id="H3260A5A26598438483B4C55EA7D45344"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Committee shall submit to Congress and the Secretary—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2D6F35E35FB8429485AD7851587A2591"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">2 reports per year on the monitoring carried out under subsection (c); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9150D6E897E74B7A9D7E143EA9062968"><enum>(B)</enum><text>on a quarterly basis, updates on such monitoring.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7DE6D6B604B4C0194D35F389E7EA1B6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents of report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The reports submitted under paragraph (1) shall provide the perspective of members of the Committee and surveys of teachers in the networks represented on the Committee on not more than 3 topics per year determined by the Committee in consultation with policymakers; such topics might include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC090E9F14F3247508235C6166906E7BD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>testing and assessment;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5CC7957DD6B4F7FB1EFC893FFE89292"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the equitable distribution of teachers;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HADEC0DC2A38441589A57E21D63829E65"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the diversity of the teaching workforce;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4AC7068C49B844CCA214CFACE5DCA913"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Every Student Succeeds Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/95">Public Law 114–95</external-xref>) in rural schools; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H929532A42FC34861B9B77891F2ABFE5C"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other topics of relevance determined by the Committee in consultation with policymakers and members of other Department school and family engagement fellowships (such as the School Ambassadors Program).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H41A20CC964BA489297483F166D8E0798"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Federal Advisory Committee Act applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provisions of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/92/463">Public Law 92–463</external-xref>; 5 U.S.C. App.) shall apply to the Committee.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="H8FB04A49A7B24E93A2E33B55D9DB64D4"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Compensation</header>
 <paragraph id="HDAAB65747EAD486E9C1DD97F0B81CCD4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each member of the Committee may be compensated at not to exceed the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay in effect for a position at level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 of title 5, United States Code, for each day during which that member is engaged in the actual performance of the duties of the Committee.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H548A75102C524C4085E3E38B035838D5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">While away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the Committees, members of the Committee shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in the same manner as persons employed intermittently in the Government service are allowed expenses under section 5703(b) of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB0947242CBEE4F05B77866253DC1C784"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Additional requirements</header><text>The following additional requirements shall apply to the Committee:</text> <paragraph id="H03EDAF9C83554652BE30616FCFBDCCD2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee shall meet in person at least once per year for deliberation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H72C981AA012049F2BAEBF5A41DE94F53"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee shall be available for consultation with officials at the Department and the authorizing Committees of Congress regarding the contents of the reports submitted under subsection (e) .</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD5C5CE0F710E4C37A6BBB71D12B98D96"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>State Teacher of the Year</quote> means any person who has been recognized as a State Teacher of the Year by the Council of Chief State School Officers.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H07F2A62C6B9F4720B600B74FF4ED451A"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization of funds</header><text>Of the amounts appropriated to, and available at the discretion of, the Secretary for programmatic and administrative expenditures for fiscal years 2018 through 2022, a total of $500,000 shall be used to establish and carry out the functions of the Committee established under this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="HE952DF982E804FF1A9354BE3A9C3364F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Parents and Families Advisory Committee</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6301">20 U.S.C. 6301</external-xref> et seq.), as amended by section 2 of this Act, is further amended by inserting after section 1005 (as added by such section 2) the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="H83A79AB081BD4BC489A3E49A0C12EFEF" style="OLC">
				<section id="HC073E09BECCB43C29B0C064FDB42622B"><enum>1006.</enum><header>Parents and Families Advisory Committee</header>
 <subsection id="H5117326088C54B998F09425C70024518"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="H0BC35F27235741B6B28754039BA9E431"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Parents and families have a major influence on their children’s achievement in school and throughout life.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE8CFCEE7CCA441528AF37190F8EDD5F8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Parents and family members offer an important resource to policymakers as they provide a unique perspective as consumers of our Nation’s public schools.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H16E4A4E618A24CB48F7C0CE522D61EF4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>All parents and family members—regardless of income, education, or cultural background— are critical in their child’s learning and development and want their child to reach their fullest potential.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6E22DA86B0124321A7D8B079D551169B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary shall establish an advisory committee, to be known as the Parents and Families Advisory Committee (referred to in this section as the <quote>Committee</quote>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE28B479CB844431AB4B2759456B8A3CB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties and focus</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The duty of the Committee shall be to monitor the effects of this Act on children and families, and review and analyze implementation of State and local parent and family engagement policies, school-parent compacts, and other family engagement activities described in section 1116 and part E of title IV.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="H3F0C0587481E418C9964F47DF11B1317"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Membership</header>
 <paragraph id="HE1AE997B522D4F669ADF8998195DC3AE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The membership of the Committee shall consist of 10 parents or family members of children enrolled in a public elementary school and 10 parents or family members of children enrolled in a public secondary school who—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE682C3F3444447DA881A0417043F6626"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have a demonstrated history of parental involvement and family engagement in schools; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H329829DB58FD4FCD9FC006D71C6E7424"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have submitted an application to the Secretary to serve on the Committee.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6068D299B6814C32965B1F63D0EBADCF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>List; Appointment</header><text>The Secretary shall compile a list of parents and family members submitting applications under paragraph (1)(B). The members of the Committee shall be appointed as follows:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB1D24C52DBCE40EBB4A8ECE1BB4660C0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Secretary shall appoint 4 parents or family members from the list.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4B9614A2D534BED8CE26BAE4F306328"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Majority Leader of the Senate shall appoint 4 parents or family members from the list.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E26AB99AB8F40E39D568CCE8E5F8232"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Minority Leader of the Senate shall appoint 4 parents or family members from the list.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE54977B869E04D149F50CB5EA0A8E4C9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Speaker of the House of Representatives shall appoint 4 parents or family members from the list.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33AECEEF548B4A6E9C73032DF24A07B0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Minority Leader of the House of Representatives shall appoint 4 parents or family members from the list.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6EBA6B69906C4100914A4841A3208C7F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Representation requirement</header>
 <subparagraph id="H272F4F1BAB3D48368735CB48C35469D5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The members of the Committee shall represent multiple geographic areas and a diversity of students, and shall include at least one parent or family member representing each of the following student groups:</text>
 <clause id="H806A1DD1337C4113A6CC75B558F721C5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Economically disadvantaged students.</text> </clause><clause id="H504CE8137FCC45DDAA9BE10F322913EA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Students from major racial and ethnic groups.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD76C79E95D7944338BC8BE121692E297"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Children with disabilities.</text> </clause><clause id="H77F03A9DF8AC41DDABA92956A04754F7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>English learners.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8FCCFB310DA24B1E948AB7D034852DD4"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Students who are members of an Indian tribe or tribal organization, as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b</external-xref>).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5246E07C03D648D89A738F8CE3785E37"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Special consideration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consideration should also be given to representation of students’ gender identity, migrant status, and residence in rural areas in the appointment of members of the Committee.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD68B3EE43D4C49D6B9776BBE5BDAF524"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Advisors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If requested by the Committee, the Secretary may provide access to not more than 5 research advisors to the Committee, such as researchers, practitioners or representatives from national nonprofit organizations with expertise in family engagement in education, to provide evidence-based information and materials.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF326BCB3C8A7404E8AC2372B557EFEB4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Term</header><text>Each member of the Committee shall serve on the Committee for a 3-year term.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEDD4266B013246BCAF6E3F1D3BF7C781"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Annual report</header> <paragraph id="HB55307C2EF3F475BB1A278152F1B67F5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Committee shall submit to Congress and the Secretary—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3F434D7C715443E3AE2CAB87EB477BBE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on an annual basis, a report and policy recommendations on the review and analysis carried out under subsection (c); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCEC5EF89A74943EFAC7955FB1CAA98EF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>on a quarterly basis, updates on such review and analysis.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDEF7B69BA16940598E2A65D79E867071"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents of report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report submitted under paragraph (1) shall provide the perspective of parents and families on not more than 3 topics per year determined by the Committee. Such topics may include the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2D9B532CE7BA4BB0B05695822B9EF1CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The effects of this Act on parental involvement and family engagement in education, including schools and classrooms.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBFAC172A57F54B9B9560AF06E52D037B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Direction for State education authorities and local education authorities for implementing written family engagement policies under section 1116 and part E of title IV.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25B1F7E2E7414F74AFB64884579B0966"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommendations for strengthening family engagement policy and implementation in order to meet the goals of section 1116 and part E of title IV.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1D6C5BDDE65E47DB9405FDE14C8D554D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Federal Advisory Committee Act applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provisions of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/92/463">Public Law 92–463</external-xref>; 5 U.S.C. App.) shall apply to the Committee.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="H4FDD887DBDD3441DB1CC904A3F813A28"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Compensation</header>
 <paragraph id="HDA6121603B494816978377314B97AF19"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each member of the Committee may be compensated at not to exceed the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay in effect for a position at level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 of title 5, United States Code, for each day during which that member is engaged in the actual performance of the duties of the Committee.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H49D1C7A1483E4691A1F38D591A023499"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">While away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the Committees, members of the Committee shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in the same manner as persons employed intermittently in the Government service are allowed expenses under section 5703(b) of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H901ADCA94503466BB939CBC00F58A449"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Additional requirements</header><text>The following additional requirements shall apply to the Committee:</text> <paragraph id="H405482FF3C294970BD3D51D2B601592D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee shall meet in person at least once per year for deliberation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCE76C91CA17A4E09B993FA16DB2431DD"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee shall be available for consultation with officials at the Department and the authorizing Committees of Congress regarding the contents of the reports submitted under subsection (e) .</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9BFC97A81CE948E38AE9025A7F4B7C48"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H55E38B0E8A7242B299340609BF0F6648"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>family engagement</quote> means a shared responsibility of families and schools for student success—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8DDF0BE34EB5433EB1498002C1AD39D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in which schools and community-based organizations are committed to reaching out to engage families in meaningful ways and families are committed actively to support their children’s learning and development;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B7276453DFF4869A6EC571030C43985"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that is continuous from birth through young adulthood; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1C708F768E4470BBAABEA2CC70957E3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that reinforces learning that takes place in the home, school, and community.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB36072F7E6143C1AED5F374F01F2CE9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>parental involvement</quote> means the participation of parents or family members in regular, two-way, and meaningful communication involving student academic learning and other school activities, including ensuring—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD1C1917DF80A48929F79A48A2417B28E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that parents or family members play an integral role in assisting their child’s learning;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF8A9B7D7268E45298A33ECD6EC0ABC53"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that parents or family members are encouraged to be actively involved in their child’s education at school;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F01B962B5AE47D98167E32F363B499C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that parents or family members are full partners in their child’s education and are included, as appropriate, in decisionmaking and on advisory committees to assist in the education of their child; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9FCA9174006E4B4289D638AD2FF1A21A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the carrying out of other activities, such as those described in section 1116.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2FD71C8AE9414165B5588A63E36CC010"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization of funds</header><text>Of the amounts appropriated to, and available at the discretion of, the Secretary for programmatic and administrative expenditures for fiscal years 2018 through 2022, a total of $500,000 shall be used to establish and carry out the functions of the Committee established under this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


