<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HAE4ACC0A10CB4503A0F01DEF83E54E30" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4206 IH: Medicare Care Coordination Improvement Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4206</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171101">November 1, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001275">Mr. Bucshon</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001158">Mr. Marchant</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to modernize the physician self-referral
			 prohibitions to promote care coordination in the merit-based incentive
			 payment system and to facilitate physician practice participation in
			 alternative payment models under the Medicare program, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H99B50BC55E1845BDB1BAAB10F25B494C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H23E1C440705543BEAF7D391C84E6A366" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medicare Care Coordination Improvement Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H3DBB931BC4FB43E3A00B9A0E337D1A2B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Modernization of limitations on physician self-referral</header> <subsection id="H03E5D839AFD34CF5B374FBE1EB445A0D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Waivers To promote care coordination by facilitating participation in alternative payment models</header> <paragraph id="H3705B4187E1944828DA4F839796F866A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1833 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H83F63986D0DB43279007699BAC2335E1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (z), as added by section 101(e)(2) of the Medicare Access and CHIP Reauthorization Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/10">Public Law 114–10</external-xref>), by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
						<quoted-block id="H1010E5DDB27A41E4BEB65C05C5D29060" style="OLC">
							<paragraph id="H410668BDC9DD426FAD53F84D233234A0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Waiver authority</header>
 <subparagraph id="H5D6CDA0057CB42EEB9513F1D41FC87A3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provisions of subsection (f) of section 1899 shall apply with respect to covered APM entities to the same extent and in the same manner as such provisions apply with respect to accountable care organizations under such section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C7EEAA2C4A34281950DB5893D38204C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Covered APM entities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term <term>covered APM entity</term> means, subject to subparagraph (C), each of the following:</text> <clause id="H380FC1DE295640E986FE6258AB64A3FF"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible alternative payment entity as defined in paragraph (3)(D).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H53442CD4C6934D5580BC3D6B0D12B2B3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity participating in an alternative payment model as defined in paragraph (3)(C), including such participation that qualifies as a clinical practice improvement activity under section 1848(q)(2)(B)(iii)(VI).</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCDB0D60B54F7477B80EFD2CE12AB5FDD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity participating in a physician-focused payment model for which comments and recommendations have, under subparagraph (C) of section 1868(c)(2), been submitted indicating that such model meets the criteria described in subparagraph (A) of such section.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE5E309BBC6B141C284B0456AF4B43AB0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity participating in any other model that the Secretary determines is a covered APM for purposes of subparagraph (A), including such a determination made pursuant to physicians submitting a proposal to the Secretary for an alternative payment model.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF3635F07D902474DA8F8671D9B7ACA30"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity engaging in activities that the Secretary has determined constitute significant progress toward establishing a model referred to in any of clauses (i) through (iv).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22B7AF5E342D4070AEF31C0D3136BD36"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Certain requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A model referred to in any of clauses (i) through (iv) of subparagraph (B) may not be considered a covered APM entity for purposes of subparagraph (A) unless the model meets the requirements described in section 1877(b)(6)(B).</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H152051044928403295835C81834FFAD3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subsection (z), as added by section 514(a) of the Medicare Access and CHIP Reauthorization Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/10">Public Law 114–10</external-xref>), as subsection (aa).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDFC4143F79B0400CBB33267BB2F19765"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 514(c)(1) of the Medicare Access and CHIP Reauthorization Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/10">Public Law 114–10</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>subsection (z)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (aa)</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB7BEFB7246854CE5AE85131927242E1B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Expansion of administrative authority To provide exceptions to physician ownership and compensation
			 arrangement prohibitions To promote care coordination</header>
 <paragraph id="HB1A5C17747534A14B48A5293D01CB028"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Promoting care coordination</header><text>Section 1877(b)(4) of the Social Security Act (U.S.C. 1395nn(b)(4)) is amended by striking <quote>risk of program or patient abuse</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>significant risk of program or patient abuse, including those that would promote care coordination, quality improvement, or resource conservation by physician practices under part B</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEE4C63DCAE734BD485A85957954CB41E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Care coordination in mips and participation in apms</header><text>Section 1877(a) of the Social Security Act (U.S.C. 1395nn(a)) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H6C6FCEE85728451EB515F2AF4B236B0F" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H9C79D2F60379411C87897AA241E029EB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Secretary may not impose requirements under this section that could adversely affect—</text> <subparagraph id="H04C82E1EF2B441BDAAFD8D9AEB480D9D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>physician care coordination in the merit-based incentive payment system under section 1848(q); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D28A95C22C14FC0B273C872B9F45273"><enum>(B)</enum><text>physician participation in an alternative payment model under 1833(z).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1BC05B610C4E432EAFDD3FB1C8DD2D44"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exception facilitating the development and operation of alternative payment models</header><text>Section 1877(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395nn">42 U.S.C. 1395nn(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H32C3816B89A543F0AA833DE403B990D6" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="H2F77A6BE5FD543568CB5864AA35C3368"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Development and operation of alternative payment models</header>
 <subparagraph id="H2091F61BAC3D4E63A2E80D3839DE49CA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of services furnished pursuant to an arrangement that meets the requirements described in subparagraph (B) entered into for the purpose of developing or operating an alternative payment model, including—</text>
 <clause id="H82512890D04041078F63A2C81B2346B8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>advanced alternative payment models described in section 1833(z) (including physician-focused payment models referred to in section 1868(c));</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6FCCF8329E054E79A177B5C7C84F973C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>MIPS APMs (as defined by the Secretary); and</text> </clause><clause id="H04C7AD8873984E8F91064C1347C795D8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other alternative payment model that the Secretary may, by regulation, specify.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8AA0B60289FA431089CC4022B4CBB9DA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The requirements described in this subparagraph with respect to an arrangement relating to an alternative payment model are as follows:</text>
 <clause id="HE2C73309C2E1463E945A810790C0B633"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The arrangement is in writing, identifies the services, items, or actions subject to the arrangement and is signed by the parties to the arrangement.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H296D61CC4B0444E49215B673DBB19614"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Items and services furnished subject to the arrangement are furnished at fair market value. In this clause, the term <term>fair market value</term> has the meaning given such term in subsection (h)(3), except that the Secretary may not take into account the volume or value of referrals in determining such value for purposes of this clause.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3FCFAD21E8A347E093F8333313A63D44"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The arrangement includes a description of the alternative payment model.</text> </clause><clause id="H19F22277A5494F539BF90B517E5491C1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under the arrangement written reports are submitted to the Secretary on a semi-annual basis on the progress achieved in the development and operation of the alternative payment model</text>
 </clause><clause id="H897F42485D384DE1A2B5AE16E2F05579"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The arrangement meets such other requirements as the Secretary may impose by regulation as needed to protect against a significant risk of program patient abuse</text>
							</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


