<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Enrolled-Bill" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD69F0047007043AA84AB177967C2D367" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title> HR 2210 ENR: To designate the community living center of the Department of Veterans Affairs in Butler Township, Butler County, Pennsylvania, as the “Sergeant Joseph George Kusick VA Community Living Center”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">One Hundred Fifteenth Congress of the United States of America</congress><session display="yes">At the First Session</session><enrolled-dateline>Begun and held at the City of Washington on Tuesday, the third day of January, two thousand and seventeen</enrolled-dateline> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2210</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no"></current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To designate the community living center of the Department of Veterans Affairs in Butler Township, Butler County, Pennsylvania, as the <quote>Sergeant Joseph George Kusick VA Community Living Center</quote>.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HEF9440F62A5645FA95BBFF3AE5796D0B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H17F21A82D160424D8B33D3A8114D5421" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="HC859D18F67D745669B1585373884E46A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sergeant Joseph George Kusick of Bruin, Pennsylvania, was assigned to the command and control detachment of the 5th Special Forces Group (Airborne) of the Army during the Vietnam War.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6725CAF183454DA8BA67CF2D0FDD4820"><enum>(2)</enum><text>On November 8, 1967, Kusick distinguished himself by exceptionally valorous actions while serving as a radio operator of a special forces reconnaissance team on a combat mission deep in hostile territory.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H5906238B003B46949888849B046EE0CF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>During an enemy ambush, Kusick, though seriously wounded, refused aid and radioed the forward air controller to advise him of the critical situation.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1E4FB506D172431490D6D7B715F30BB7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>While the team leader led a withdrawal to a landing zone, Kusick maintained contact with the controller and requested emergency extraction.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HE104059DFA784E0496B6566497661B9D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Realizing the importance of having a radio operator on the ground to direct landings, Kusick refused evacuation by the first helicopter.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF68127E0C1E14293842F7C2F5199FD4B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>After the second helicopter was shot down, and in the midst of enemy fire, Kusick continued to maintain radio contact and called for a hoist extraction of the men still remaining on the ground.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H84F483F0B9DB450088EE0DD6E656E066"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The last helicopter, which Kusick boarded, was shot down by intense Viet Cong fire and crashed in flames, resulting in Kusick’s death.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1EA1AC10AF8743FA855819750D785F63"><enum>(8)</enum><text>On December 22, 1967, Kusick was posthumously awarded the Silver Star Medal for gallantry in action.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HCF19EC61275C4FF69756E2F8C76CCEEF"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The citation to accompany the award of the Silver Star Medal stated that <quote>Kusick’s gallantry in action, at the cost of his life, was in keeping with the highest traditions of the military service and reflects great credit upon himself, his unit, and the United States Army</quote>.</text> </paragraph></section> 
<section id="HF45C0822B250496E8CDD06AFD892C651"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sergeant Joseph George Kusick VA Community Living Center</header> 
<subsection id="H64A5FBB7024947DABBC0AA9BE99EFFB8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The community living center of the Department of Veterans Affairs in Butler Township, Butler County, Pennsylvania, shall after the date of the enactment of this Act be known and designated as the “Sergeant Joseph George Kusick VA Community Living Center”.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H00527324BB8041F38F7382CE17457D86"><enum>(b)</enum><header>References</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any reference in any law, regulation, map, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the community living center referred to in subsection (a) shall be deemed to be a reference to the “Sergeant Joseph George Kusick VA Community Living Center”.</text> </subsection></section> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><role>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</role></attestation-group><attestation-group><role>Vice President of the United States and President of the Senate.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill> 


