<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H707D8351FB1740FABEB167875B7B8EBD" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3810 IH: Commission to Verify Iranian Nuclear Compliance Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3810</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170921">September 21, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000607">Mr. Francis Rooney of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Commission to Verify Iranian Nuclear Compliance.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H950594B6E88145F8B0BD6351DDC2FC07" style="OLC">
 <section id="H3D1300420973432A8095348992944DF5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Commission to Verify Iranian Nuclear Compliance Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HF211FC3BCDBA4699A2D4CA1BBE15DAB6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Commission to Verify Iranian Nuclear Compliance</header> <subsection id="H227DA103AE544783B898CF47089412A0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established in the legislative branch the Commission to Verify Iranian Nuclear Compliance (hereafter in this Act referred to as the <quote>Commission</quote>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H65BE31B93C974C96AF079E46D024ADC9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Functions and duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall—</text> <paragraph id="HEEE60FE4BE6741ABA5A72E4BFA202773"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">continually verify that the Islamic Republic of Iran is complying with its obligations and commitments under the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action (hereafter in this Act referred to as the <quote>JCPOA)</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H25ACC3C81BF541A7A38C7BD2D7745FE7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>continually assess the adequacy of the safeguards and other control mechanisms and other assurances contained in the JCPOA with respect to Iran’s nuclear program to ensure Iran’s activities permitted thereunder are not being used to further any nuclear-related military or nuclear explosive purpose, including for any research on or development of any nuclear explosive device or any other nuclear-related military purpose;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H54E6FDC62EF14B16BF8D77C93F887589"><enum>(3)</enum><text>continually assess the capacity and capability of the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) to effectively implement the verification regime required by or related to the JCPOA, including whether the IAEA has sufficient access to investigate suspicious sites or allegations of covert nuclear-related activities and whether it has the required funding, manpower, and authority to administer the verification regime required by or related to the JCPOA; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA9986804D61E4F5F8673754B53FB98AE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>submit to Congress the reports required by section 5.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H38E48B6FDD314149B131CDC8AE45CF2D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Membership</header> <subsection id="H61265D74FA114E968A8A9D053F14E04D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Selection and membership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall be composed of 20 members as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="H57AFAC451E5449D283C5DE2F5E937541"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Four Members of the House of Representatives appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives. Two Members shall be selected from the majority party and two Members shall be selected, after consultation with the minority leader of the House, from the minority party.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7E0B4BE1369A49F99346723C23BB50C1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Four Members of the Senate appointed by the President of the Senate. Two Members shall be selected, after consultation with the majority leader, from the majority party, and two Members shall be selected, after consultation with the minority leader, from the minority party.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H427593D3FE4148E68D64451EC24A5A71"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Two Members of the House of Representatives appointed by the chairman of the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE284EFCE91C048A0972EF9F1AB1B38EC"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Two Members of the House of Representatives appointed by the ranking minority member of the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1662CE4F9D6B44E584267E3E96CFBE83"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Two Members of the Senate appointed by the chairman of the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H362AC8B201BE4914BEB2B8331E30B2A0"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Two Members of the Senate appointed by the ranking minority member of the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7EE401D03C444174A1153FFC7D3C6ED8"><enum>(7)</enum><text>One member of the Department of State appointed by the President of the United States.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEBB687A06CAF40858906A8C2B986FBBA"><enum>(8)</enum><text>One member of the Department of Defense appointed by the President of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5FF0CA43A2524D6B98D36DC5066F490E"><enum>(9)</enum><text>One member of the Department of Energy appointed by the President of the United States.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2FB8D6C86E4141BABB67201D0B8EB37C"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">One member of the Department of the Treasury appointed by the President of the United States.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H7CEFDC0BA3574D2895164253DEBC867C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Chairperson and Co-Chairperson</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H5457D2862A70447F956D135778173189"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There shall be a Chairperson and Co-chairperson of the Commission.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H5D5E066AEEC6422B9C835B0D977CBE9A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designation of Chairperson</header><text>At the beginning of each odd-numbered Congress, the President of the Senate, on the recommendation of the majority leader, shall designate one of the Senate Members as Chairperson of the Commission. At the beginning of each even numbered Congress, the Speaker of the House of Representatives shall designate one of the House Members as Chairperson of the Commission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8FA32DF8FB084F34970357BBE4177869"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Designation of Co-chairperson</header><text>At the beginning of each odd-numbered Congress, the President of the Senate, on the recommendation of the minority leader, shall designate one of the Senate Members as Co-chairperson of the Commission. At the beginning of each even numbered Congress, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, on the recommendation of the minority leader, shall designate one of the House Members as Co-chairperson of the Commission.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1145F888A4674E77A5077A1401129F34"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition on compensation</header><text>Members of the Commission may not receive additional pay, allowances, or benefits by reason of their service on the Commission.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H161459AB78B6424AA0663B12696A0C7F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Testimony of witnesses, production of evidence; issuance of subpoena; administration of oaths</header>
 <subsection id="HE4EF52BF91764EC8849DCA0281DEB7DB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Testimony of witnesses and production of evidence</header><text>In carrying out this Act, the Commission may require, by subpoena or otherwise, the attendance and testimony of such witnesses and the production of such books, records, correspondence, memorandums, papers, and documents as it deems necessary.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDAB3972C4AF541919847133748551AA5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Subpoenas</header><text>Subpoenas shall be issued jointly by the Chairperson and Co-chairperson of the Commission, and may be served by any person designated by the Chairperson and Co-chairperson.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF9AB3DC1E19341F7AFA278D73BD4A1B9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administration of oaths</header><text>The Chairperson of the Commission, or any member designated by the Chairperson, may administer oaths to any witness.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HBE6F0E18786A427BB0DA36447101C426"><enum>5.</enum><header>Commission reports</header>
 <subsection id="H1D5DB0BB10AB41C98D38CF093E466827"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report on matters covered by this Act</header><text>The Commission shall submit to Congress a report with respect to the matters covered by this Act not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and on an annual basis thereafter. The Commission shall provide information relating to the JCPOA to Members of the House and Senate as requested.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFBCB8598A48E423185DB276C878F3CB1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report on expenditures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each fiscal year for which an appropriation is made the Commission shall submit to Congress a report on its expenditures under such appropriation.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7DDF538360A54B768AC7EBB05F137CB5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Justification of budget</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall prepare and submit to Congress a justification of the annual budget of the Commission at the time of submission of the annual budget of the President to Congress pursuant to section 1105(a) of title 31, United States Code.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H28EC842EB78D4A00A9668CAB43A4CEF8"><enum>6.</enum><header>Staff of commission</header>
			<subsection id="H27F493D6ACCB4CEBA3F1FEC96EEC6051"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Staff</header>
 <paragraph id="HE281D22FCBEE40BA98A36972083656C8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Staff director</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall have a staff director, who shall be appointed jointly by the Chairperson and Co-chairperson of the Commission and whose pay shall be fixed jointly by the Chairperson and Co-chairperson of the Commission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H44D71EF0663A4F25A28A74F852F03C24"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other staff</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chairperson of the Commission shall appoint and fix the pay of other personnel of the Commission, subject to the approval of at least 2 of the following members of the Commission:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H57501AD3756C45BEA070D8406F0C8B27"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Co-chairperson of the Commission.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1129031CCDAE497BB21FF5E5E531F7C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of each even numbered Congress, a Senate member of the Commission designated by the President of the Senate, on the recommendation of the majority leader. For purposes of each odd-numbered Congress, a House member of the Commission designated by the Speaker of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3642A5A6907C4D3C8B7F56A069CB3C9F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>For purposes of each even numbered Congress, a Senate member of the Commission designated by the President of the Senate, on the recommendation of the minority leader. For purposes of each odd numbered Congress, a House member of the Commission designated by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, on the recommendation of the minority leader.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H8E40055877084A11B45BA3B73CE9D1EB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment of employees as House employees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of pay and other employment benefits, rights, and privileges, and for all other purposes, including the applicability of the Rules of the House of Representatives and the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995, each employee of the Commission shall be considered an employee of the House of Representatives. For purposes of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995, the Commission shall be considered an employing office with respect to its employees.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H64DE2B03C72643988FAE95D2E9E35C85"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Detailees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any Federal Government employee may be detailed to the Commission without reimbursement from the Commission, and such detailee shall retain the rights, status, and privileges of his or her regular employment without interruption.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4F7662EF344C4E1AA0B756A76F674931"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consultant services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission is authorized to procure the services of experts and consultants in accordance with section 3109 of title 5, United States Code, but at rates not to exceed the daily rate paid a person occupying a position at level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H9665D081F4D044C494E3B3F524C3B92F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Security clearances</header><text>All members of the Commission shall hold appropriate security clearances by reason of their participation on the Commission.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H95E74A2292414472A11F0E1405013652"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Foreign travel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Foreign travel for official purposes by members and staff of the Commission may be authorized by either the Chairperson or Co-chairperson of the Commission.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H0272676DC0C34752A8CD28E896368A7F"><enum>7.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Commission for each fiscal year such sums as may be necessary to carry out this Act.</text>
 </section><section commented="no" id="H24C423CEBEA44496879627093DFD89ED"><enum>8.</enum><header>Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <quote>Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action</quote> or <quote>JCPOA</quote> means the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action, signed at Vienna July 14, 2015, by Iran and by the People’s Republic of China, France, Germany, the Russian Federation, the United Kingdom and the United States, with the High Representative of the European Union for Foreign Affairs and Security Policy, and all implementing materials and agreements related to the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


