<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H8C0F241CB12C44A68F4A63FDC332D1FE" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4126 IH: Transparency in Energy Production Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4126</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171025">October 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000435">Ms. Ros-Lehtinen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001107">Mr. Curbelo of Florida</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000465">Ms. Tsongas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the accurate reporting of fossil fuel production and emissions from public lands,
			 and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HB430205349FC41BB8215AE0B72A5D4B4" style="OLC">
 <section id="H2B0AC05EE18A4C879A28CEAC3FE98DBF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Transparency in Energy Production Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H344BA18942134FD8B4CB43769EB1B167"><enum>2.</enum><header>Online publication of carbon emissions</header> <subsection id="HB132A12B96E446DE8D063951EB3FC4E4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior shall make available to the public through the internet—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8B965425160B45AFAD329DD1AD1B3EFD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>information that describes for all covered operations—</text> <subparagraph id="HBDBC6AB427454E2B8A9C960BEB2B6398"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the aggregate amount of each fossil fuel, by type and by State, produced under Federal leases; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BE1AB17974543ADB7C5788AE948337F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for gas reported, the portion and source of such amount that was released by each of venting, flaring, and fugitive release;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF2BA5C98358482E9E93ADE6464CE1FD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>information that accurately describes the estimated amounts of existing fossil fuel resources on Federal lands under lease for the production of fossil fuels, and of Federal lands that have potential for such leasing; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCB4F7672EC704B378E0235C1B61C322E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>information that describes the amount and sources of energy, in megawatts, produced from operating solar, wind, and geothermal projects on Federal lands under lease for the production of renewable energy.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3B47C77C1A2F4623B4E4B63F773609C7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Format</header><text>Information made available under this section shall be presented in a format that—</text> <paragraph id="H18FF3651150B425A98CA59A7853E240E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">translates such amounts and portions into emissions of metric tons of greenhouse gases expressed in carbon-dioxide equivalent using both the 20-year and 100-year Global Warming Potential-weighted emission values;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7F9581D4426E4A7EB2B8ACF47AF211C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for energy produced from solar, wind, and geothermal projects, includes an estimate of the greenhouse gas emissions that would result from production of the same amount of energy from fossil fuel resources; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB2C4DADFC3D04D30A854339F1A6E2977"><enum>(3)</enum><text>allows—</text> <subparagraph id="HD764B304DADE46FA931E88DA145AA74D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>downloading in a machine readable format; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H26844DD7AFD04E07B5C1C2150DA106C4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>accessing the information without payment of any fee or other charge.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9E3F5B2718FC4258BBE806E3FA8C84E8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Data publication frequency</header><text>The data made available under this section shall be updated at least annually.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H1B99FFB7307E4534BA6B15822CE8DBFE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Accurate measurement and reporting of methane emissions from Federal lands</header>
 <subsection id="HE43DB625166C4ECDA20BA8753BFC8131"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, if the Secretary of the Interior determines that revisions or promulgation of rules are needed to implement section 2 with regard to methane emissions, the Secretary shall initiate a process under the Federal Oil and Gas Royalty Management Act of 1982 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1711">30 U.S.C. 1711</external-xref> et seq.), the Mineral Leasing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/181">30 U.S.C. 181</external-xref> et seq.), or other applicable law to promulgate regulations to require accurate measuring and reporting to the Secretary, by each holder of a lease for the production of fossil fuels on Federal land, of the actual amount of methane gas produced under such lease, including all such gas not sold by or on behalf of the lessee.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB11F4B22AC8B4A109232BBB6F26CEDC7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reporting of gases</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The rules shall include requirements for reporting by holders of leases, to the maximum extent possible, the amount and source of all vented, flared, and fugitive releases of gas resulting from the production of fossil fuels from Federal lands.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HE4F4B572AFC7452DAEE99A03681CB563"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Every 2 years, the Secretary shall submit a report to Congress that includes—</text> <paragraph id="H561D484A4F584FA6921AB1C050AD291A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>efforts underway by the Department of the Interior to decrease greenhouse gas emissions from covered operations on Federal lands and waters;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFF7FEA46867C4F628DCA76126B762749"><enum>(2)</enum><text>plans for future reductions in greenhouse gas emissions from covered operations on Federal lands and waters; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF3566C0C6E144D89BEFA9FA781AA5723"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of greenhouse gas emissions reductions resulting from such efforts and plans that have been observed during the period covered by the report, and the amount of such reductions that are expected in the future.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H078BACE44D6149AE9455C128AEA00C4B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HC8CD294BF05C4F729329F99BD6FA8459"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered operations</header><text>The term <quote>covered operations</quote> means all fossil fuel operations that are subject to the mineral leasing laws or title V of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1761">30 U.S.C. 1761</external-xref> et seq.), regardless of size, including production, storage, gathering, processing, transportation, and handling operations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H126C4A702F62480890882E6BE8ED43AF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Flaring</header><text>The term <quote>flaring</quote> means the intentional and controlled burning of gas that occurs in the course of oil and gas or coal operations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6ABE8D66E0CC4FCD9AE1AFBABAE7FA5A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Fossil fuel</header><text>The term <quote>fossil fuel</quote> means all natural fuels, including oil, natural gas, natural gas liquids, and coal.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD56CD5758FB14BC8A808D5FC98FB8D38"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Fugitive release</header><text>The term <quote>fugitive release</quote> means the unintentional and uncontrolled release of gas into the atmosphere in the course of oil and gas or coal operations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0CA5AB43377A468B8E86E1B34AD19160"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Global Warming Potential-weighted emission</header><text>The term <quote>Global Warming Potential-weighted emission</quote> means the ratio of the time-integrated radiative forcing from the instantaneous release of 1 kilogram of a trace substance relative to that of 1 kilogram of carbon dioxide, measured in metric tons of carbon dioxide equivalent for each greenhouse gas according to the most recent, and any subsequent, decisions by the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change regarding global warming potentials.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6704B665CDE8432AB49F659BAABF1686"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Resources</header><text>The term <quote>resources</quote> means oil, gas, and coal resources, both identified and inferred, that are both technically recoverable and economically recoverable using the range of past, and predicted future, commodity prices.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFD222EC1D24E42888B20710062ADA94E"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Venting</header><text>The term <quote>venting</quote> means the intentional and controlled release of gas into the atmosphere in the course of oil and gas operations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7C3445E40329469BB3544DECB3CF1AB8"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Produced and production</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <quote>produced</quote> and <quote>production</quote> mean extracted, mined, withdrawn, sold, stored, released (including release by venting, flaring, or fugitive release), flared, used for beneficial purposes, or otherwise emitted during production.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


