<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2E13311BF45D417CA70A7DBA9992C472" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4163 IH: Cyber Shield Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4163</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171027">October 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a voluntary program to identify and promote Internet-connected products that meet
			 industry-leading cybersecurity and data security standards, guidelines,
			 best practices, methodologies, procedures, and processes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HA23EA0F2B914465AB417E4A25C417D77" style="OLC">
 <section id="HC269CA0EF8D04071B6761E6164F88A10" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cyber Shield Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HFB34FE7629514F4EA042AD25336564EB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC59D154263A84AC7A73DFCCAF58DC8F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>Advisory Committee</term> means the Cyber Shield Advisory Committee established under section 3(a);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H29B57AF0F9AE421EA3F6FBC5C7D5543C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>benchmarks</term> means standards, guidelines, best practices, methodologies, procedures, and processes;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5E926D23487B439D9A5D634EC0C4BF2B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>covered product</term> means a consumer-facing physical object that can—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1C2C9B3A86794228978567D8073013C6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>connect to the Internet; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCBA2D58495194EC29265E694666DB37A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>collect, send, or receive data;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H16F5987345DF496FA13DA4D28249D6E6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>Cyber Shield program</term> means the voluntary program established under section 4(a)(1); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H57F70D4137FD485393E54DD15439FBF9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Commerce.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="HCDBE8D05DAE8443EADA81627B3CEFFE7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Cyber Shield Advisory Committee</header> <subsection id="H62B0B3B7A86C437BBF1539F3C3EB604F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish a Cyber Shield Advisory Committee.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HA75BC0CDC15A46008AD4E1EAE66674E6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header>
 <paragraph id="H69A18CC5AD854EB0A71DFAE5F22DEF37"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Advisory Committee shall provide recommendations to the Secretary regarding—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3F912BF3078241639E7CEE6CC8C0FC65"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the format and content of the Cyber Shield labels required to be established under section 4; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7A6D0A9182D4F888FC7BB96C89019BF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the process for identifying, establishing, reporting on, adopting, maintaining, and promoting compliance with the voluntary cybersecurity and data security benchmarks required to be established under section 4.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H69E301FE382B496AA070A17F88DDE1BD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public availability of recommendations</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall publish, and provide the public with an opportunity to comment on, the recommendations provided to the Secretary under paragraph (1).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDC038F59C6FD4714B5198DC1BBC4099E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Members, chairman, and duties</header>
				<paragraph id="H59E5C5750F7B4467AAE1B73BCA6990DC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appointment</header>
 <subparagraph id="HD9A4D10C8D884545B69B8E716193F20D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall be composed of members appointed by the Secretary from among individuals who are specially qualified to serve on the Advisory Committee based on their education, training, or experience.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2887D2D355D44FD082E94F8E87B55482"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Representation</header><text>Members appointed under subparagraph (A) shall include—</text> <clause id="H397926B17E1E4CF7A9391D54AAA82E0D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>representatives of the covered products industry, including small, medium, and large businesses;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB59635514F1E4E2E92CFBA97853DAB9B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>cybersecurity experts;</text> </clause><clause id="H16746A45806B4FC3A6593A94FFB79FB8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>public interest advocates; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H93551431F459496C8F2B36A72FA18751"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Federal employees with expertise in certification, covered devices, or cybersecurity, including employees of the Department of Commerce, the Federal Trade Commission, and the Federal Communications Commission.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2941388743454714BA7A4509CAD54FA2"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>In appointing members under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall ensure that—</text> <clause id="HFEEE1F2893354C35A02C18E271E51C53"><enum>(i)</enum><text>each interest group described in clauses (i) through (iv) of subparagraph (B) is proportionally represented on the Advisory Committee, including—</text>
 <subclause id="HAB265B13A4EC44419DEB5CF4C9533688"><enum>(I)</enum><text>businesses of each size described in such clause (i);</text> </subclause><subclause id="H97881A5DDC234CDB9946D3D59BE6A627"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Federal employees with expertise in each subject described in such clause (iv); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H3261624E00264644A47A11D6CF7805FC"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Federal employees from each agency described in such clause (iv); and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H99115F5150CE41A883DE0E2CE6037733"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>no single interest group is represented by a majority of the members of the Advisory Committee.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B90D4285B454D4AAC201131082F6FCB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Chair</header><text>The Secretary shall designate a member of the Advisory Committee to serve as Chair.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6677C364A56D4DBBBA29F349EA182000"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Pay</header><text>Members of the Advisory Committee shall serve without pay, except that the Secretary may allow a member, while attending meetings of the Advisory Committee or a subcommittee of the Advisory Committee, expenses authorized under section 5703 of title 5, United States Code, relating to per diem, travel, and transportation.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H990E178754504B5BB18FBBC02FCE0DD2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Support staff; administrative services</header>
 <paragraph id="HBE07DA9229C441A6A27FC33CE49F7516"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Support staff</header><text>The Secretary shall provide support staff for the Advisory Committee.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H37FACAE5880F47069E913B597CF29556"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative services</header><text>Upon request by the Advisory Committee, the Secretary shall provide any information, administrative services, and supplies that the Secretary considers necessary for the Advisory Committee to carry out its duties and powers.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD9406DCE06254D25883C9AAC965C01FE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>No termination</header><text>Section 14 of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) shall not apply to the Advisory Committee.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HB0365A570A434331ACF186FE499B1375"><enum>4.</enum><header>Cyber Shield program</header>
			<subsection id="H03213074C7264D65A2DC7C9173F3B747"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of program</header>
 <paragraph id="HA70C908DD587471D81D64EB807417AD9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a voluntary program to identify and certify covered products with superior cybersecurity and data security through voluntary certification and labeling of, and other forms of communication about, covered products and subsets of covered products that meet industry-leading cybersecurity and data security benchmarks to enhance cybersecurity and protect data.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBA849B65FEDC41D8A57A764DDB209230"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grades</header><text>Labels applied to products under the Cyber Shield program—</text> <subparagraph id="HF43CDDD0D78943C0BBB08C7E5A38464F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may be digital; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97DDD45E97EF401BB97E4C31113691BE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may be in the form of different grades that display the extent to which a product meets the industry-leading cybersecurity and data security benchmarks.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H39CCBF62C01B495D9D39353EB3F3D1A1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish a process for consulting interested parties, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and other Federal agencies in carrying out the Cyber Shield program.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF8B9CF34F07B4588885BA2367AB2FD90"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>In carrying out the Cyber Shield program, the Secretary—</text> <paragraph id="H8CC33034A6C74269BB964EC47DA9C337"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1E3B75E0835C49608694196B220052E7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish and maintain cybersecurity and data security benchmarks, by convening and consulting interested parties and other Federal agencies, for products with the Cyber Shield label to ensure that those products perform better than their less secure counterparts; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H88085EF426464F129430542904D5CE5F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in carrying out subparagraph (A)—</text> <clause id="H304DBD2F26D446B0A3B16D64F834A124"><enum>(i)</enum><text>engage in an open public review and comment process;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCD8540F426D747F98A12C4F6E655859B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in consultation with the Advisory Committee, identify and apply cybersecurity and data security benchmarks to different subsets of covered products based on—</text>
 <subclause id="HC4D42B5A8FAE46C9AA9DF22B02301230"><enum>(I)</enum><text>cybersecurity and data security risk;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H7AE883D935E34CBB8C6E5BB3A388D0E7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the sensitivity of the information collected, transmitted, or stored by the product; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H63F220392815401087BCC6C950859F84"><enum>(III)</enum><text>product functionality; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HB58493985D68487C8D4888E6F0DFEEB6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to the extent possible, incorporate existing benchmarks when establishing and maintaining cybersecurity and data security benchmarks;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F9E64696FC04DA0960BD740BC6DFEAA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may not establish benchmarks under paragraph (1) that are—</text> <subparagraph id="HB5FC16BC2BF54FFF85C3AE2C664F2FA4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>arbitrary, capricious, an abuse of discretion, or otherwise not in accordance with law; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8AE61B84A7B4481CBC7DDE0FE6D68755"><enum>(B)</enum><text>unsupported by evidence;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2DF52F02C79145898CD2A1C46B71C260"><enum>(3)</enum><text>shall permit a manufacturer or distributor of a covered product to display a Cyber Shield label reflecting the extent to which the product meets the industry-leading cybersecurity and data security benchmarks established under paragraph (1);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H46D539E2CBE6413C82603DF152C188C9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>shall promote technologies that are compliant with the cybersecurity and data security benchmarks established by the Secretary as the preferred technologies in the marketplace for—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4DB972F04DC441F4BDA66C8573E069FB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enhancing cybersecurity; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56F96B67CFD94A88AFFD3BC96B69A40B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>protecting data;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF0887B8127B4200AF18AFF83E35F1B0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>shall work to enhance public awareness of the Cyber Shield label, including through public outreach, education, research and development, and other means;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3CF4D16AF77842629EEE0CAEE5F2D371"><enum>(6)</enum><text>shall preserve the integrity of the Cyber Shield label;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA865AF860B344B2B845C6AAE5BB40595"><enum>(7)</enum><text>if helpful in fulfilling the obligation under paragraph (6), may elect to not treat a covered product as a Cyber Shield-certified product until the product meets appropriate conformity standards, which may include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD6E1D9F043B14CB1B8832F6B47A84E08"><enum>(A)</enum><text>testing by an accredited third-party certifying laboratory or other entity in accordance with the Cyber Shield program; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C8A378EED394E289B36E3F7CD7D91C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>certification by the laboratory or entity described in subparagraph (A) as meeting the applicable cybersecurity and data security benchmarks established by the Secretary;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE39FE3008314F88BF1BF2FC27F82D23"><enum>(8)</enum><text>not less frequently than once every 2 years after establishing cybersecurity and data security benchmarks for a product category under paragraph (1), shall review and, if appropriate, update the cybersecurity and data security benchmarks for that product category;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3A866A21C9A344E9883E6EDF660DB4D3"><enum>(9)</enum><text>shall solicit comments from interested parties and the Advisory Committee prior to establishing or revising a Cyber Shield product category or benchmark (or prior to the effective date of the establishment or revision of a product category or benchmark);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H66FDF0FD00574BB59C7B2340BE928153"><enum>(10)</enum><text>upon adoption of a new or revised product category or benchmark, shall provide reasonable notice to interested parties of any changes (including effective dates) to product categories or benchmarks, along with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4E72D56CF03B4511A7E9A1D74099918B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an explanation of the changes; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD010A1192894E76A74EA311A1A27C6D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as appropriate, responses to comments submitted by interested parties; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCDCCFD6AE82A47068E4B6A4DC74C77E2"><enum>(11)</enum><text>shall provide appropriate lead time prior to the applicable effective date for a new or a significant revision to a product category or benchmark, taking into account the timing requirements of the manufacturing, product marketing, and distribution process for the product or products addressed.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE8A75D358AF7441486BC335E75E35F93"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Deadlines</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish cybersecurity and data security benchmarks for covered products under subsection (c)(1), which shall take effect not later than 60 days after the date on which the benchmarks are established.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBBA3A3C45D20422ABA2680C63A5CB11B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Advisory Committee, may enter into a contract with a third party to administer the Cyber Shield program if—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7B8CA9224FA649EE850C34863725E806"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the third party is an impartial administrator; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1DE94974E67041D29671987E3F7A46C1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>entering into the contract improves the cybersecurity and data security of covered products.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8B16F82644694D0D9413F8E6C10E485A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Program evaluation</header>
 <paragraph id="HF43B1558BE23489B9596BF6920A66ECC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 4 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than every 2 years thereafter, the Inspector General of the Department of Commerce shall evaluate the Cyber Shield program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7D42582D1BEC4EFA9E923ABC8DE04F71"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In conducting an evaluation under paragraph (1), the Inspector General of the Department of Commerce shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5A16C9178D8144278408A8AF7DD5D051"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evaluate the extent to which the cybersecurity and data security benchmarks established under the Cyber Shield program address cybersecurity and data security threats;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE1FD75622CF45059C482F196E0E8018"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assess how the benchmarks have evolved to meet emerging cybersecurity and data security threats;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEFC182AF98944C9A9C5BB9B61A54EB56"><enum>(C)</enum><text>conduct covert testing to evaluate the integrity of certification testing; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A90A5CCBD4A4B829F5E25367D5B87C3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>assess the costs to businesses of participating in the Cyber Shield program.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2555CF238B944973A1DB81881DC8ABF8"><enum>5.</enum><header>Cyber shield digital product portal</header> <subsection id="HCAF2712C83F24F559315BB48FFDA12F8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall make publicly available on the website of the Department of Commerce in a searchable format—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6BCCF4E8E4944883A5390D56EF93D5E1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a web page providing information about the Cyber Shield program; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCE1C2D9056F848558AFE50C259968332"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a database of covered products certified under the Cyber Shield program.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H61E686997BA245C6B199D4DC3AD79B7D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The database established under subsection (a) shall include—</text> <paragraph id="HE0F869BBC390424A84C5D32C694A6417"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the cybersecurity and data security benchmarks for each product category; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0F1C39195A08445D92281A899D7D79F6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for each covered product certified under the Cyber Shield program—</text> <subparagraph id="HF02167CC8F544FA1BC8EAEE38A64BA93"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the certification for the product;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF0684D6595D40459834EB554D141C51"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the name and manufacturer of the product;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDBEF27B059A44D3796017686D54430F2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the contact information for the manufacturer;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0DD55265FCE4342AE7FF541072B73E3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the functionality of the product;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6DC726BB55564953BA3938ED807725D0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the location of any applicable privacy policy; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6514DDF0377344978344C666A42AC11A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any other information the Secretary determines necessary and appropriate.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H24AD961F1A3643E480349681971F5839"><enum>6.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The decision of a manufacturer of a covered product not to participate in the Cyber Shield program shall not affect the liability of the manufacturer for a cybersecurity or data security breach of that covered product.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


