<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB34E967532A442AD84D49763C81BAF9C" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3986 IH: Stopping the Iron Pipeline Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3986</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171005">October 5, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000248">Mr. Serrano</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the establishment of a national standard for incorporating a passive identification
			 ability into all firearms sold in the United States.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HE8580C9878144C23B0259ED2BC8855ED" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE94ABFE6026846FFAB76BF11F82FD71E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stopping the Iron Pipeline Act of 2017</short-title></quote> .</text> </section><section id="H8824BDAD4A194579BF1FBB5FB278B481"><enum>2.</enum><header>Passive capability to identify lost and stolen firearms</header> <subsection id="H7AD8335F82494950A26BD61726680105"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of national standard</header> <paragraph id="HC3D633D4F5E1479798A5F66C0ECFB78C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General shall, in consultation with the National Institute for Standards and Technology, establish in regulations a national standard for the incorporation of a passive identification capability into all firearms sold in the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE425846D94E24C488FF3C9D401380A88"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Passive identification capability defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>passive identification capability</term> means a technology that—</text> <subparagraph id="H8B1C893951A744FD93AE8C2DA116B2FB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enables a firearm to be identified by a mobile or fixed reading device; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE241185A5CE43CDB3EF62EB8C0A8D2F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not emit or broadcast an electronic signal or other information that would enable the firearm or its owner to be monitored or tracked.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6CDE938F5355443DAFEC2394192C0FBE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In developing the standard, the Attorney General shall give equal priority to the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HD0C81F955E5E48EE8EC33ED3098C03C6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The right of firearm owners to maintain their full right to privacy under the 4th Amendment and their right to legally own firearms under the 2nd Amendment.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06994127FCD84B47ADE3D8A238BA8D54"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The ability of law enforcement authorities to use the capability to track lost and stolen guns.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D7B192079774219B05AF3EC1D0C6D20"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The ability of manufacturers to incorporate the capability using existing firearm manufacturing processes.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A691BAE74DD4DA88CF5F13FE0301034"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The resistance to tampering and destruction of the technology used to incorporate the capability.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF0B4C1EB710D42E5AC3F26613390B5D0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition; penalty</header> <paragraph id="HED82A8937FFF439CA182C3C0AD79F667"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>It shall be unlawful for a person, in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce, to manufacture a firearm that does not have a passive identification capability that meets the national standard established under subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4D4C6F391ED44FE2BEF51107D8487983"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Civil penalty</header><text>After notice and opportunity for hearing, the Attorney General shall impose on a person who violates paragraph (1) a civil money penalty in such amount, not exceeding $2,500 per firearm, as the Attorney General shall prescribe in regulations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H68073C7D520045C09DE3D655BBCCBEFC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This subsection shall take effect on such date as the Attorney General shall prescribe in regulations that is not later than 3 years after the establishment of the national standard under subsection (a).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


