<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2FFF0CBEBA0C40FD94B74B49D73B3D3D" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3247 IH: Protect United States Security in the Arctic Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3247</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170714">July 14, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the President to develop and submit to Congress a strategy to protect United States
			 interests in the Arctic region, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H948070451ED441649D36FAE91720F698" style="OLC">
 <section id="H7C5EF0130CC249CC8E47AD7E996959DA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protect United States Security in the Arctic Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H54E2806894EF40DB89ED01D6EC22E99E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H7ABE73F2BA104C8D83DE23B995F5785D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States has important economic, security, and national defense interests in the Arctic region.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H91B7D3A550164FD085DC645FF8817912"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The United States Government has issued several key reports and strategies on the Arctic region over the last four years, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD706675ED1ED4DB28B9306532723FE39"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Department of Defense Report to Congress on Strategy to Protect United States National Security Interests in the Arctic Region (December 2016);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA973C49D71094EB988D0B7012B3B0B69"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the 2015 Year In Review: Progress Report on the Implementation of the National Strategy for the Arctic Region (March 2016);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF0C9AA834A543538F11551CD9F7F3A5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Implementation Plan for the National Strategy for the Arctic Region (January 30, 2014); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCCDAE2849DC644E595D587661C86943A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the National Strategy for the Arctic Region (May 2013), which set forth the United States Government’s strategic priorities for the Arctic region.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0170798CE4284518ADCCE2B03208ECB7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>According to the Council on Foreign Relations, the Arctic region is warming at double the rate of the rest of the world, opening new routes for ships and development of natural resources throughout the Arctic region.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCEF83980693B42DA9F0450DB173C0D7F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The rapidly warming Arctic region threatens fisheries and wildlife habitat, existing infrastructure and communities throughout Alaska, including increased vulnerability to coastal erosion. Alaska native communities are particularly vulnerable to the changing climate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6CB99B9D654A474FA448A5C2980A4A05"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Given these developments, the United States needs to bolster its infrastructure and assets in the Arctic region to safeguard its strategic interests, defend its national borders, protect the environment, and maintain its scientific and technological leadership.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H8045EAAAFBD64ADDBFE92E01F1227572"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="H92F8D4E63BCC4B9F9B1919E8A5B5EB56"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the President should continue to convene the Arctic Executive Steering Committee established on January 21, 2015, pursuant to Executive Order 13689 (80 Fed. Reg. 6425; relating to enhancing coordination of national efforts in the Arctic); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAA19F74B6CDA45B1A5BE7A9CF0D0150A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the United States should ratify the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea in order to allow the United States to secure its claim to offshore resources present along the Arctic’s extended continental shelf.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HD69E55E8D6E74C858E39768DA749E35C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Strategy to protect United States interests in the Arctic region</header>
 <subsection id="HFB25163AD4B649148FC83649C76D1A2E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall develop and submit to Congress a strategy to protect United States interests in the Arctic region.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H71A634FE242D47CD84E2DECD08FFE27D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Goals</header><text>The strategy required under subsection (a) shall include the following goals:</text> <paragraph id="HA5EB68935A3B49C28EC216E5F27A7D1B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Improve telecommunications, navigation, ocean and coastal mapping, and Coast Guard and other infrastructure to support a sustained security and emergency response presence for the State of Alaska.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H650C94E01EAF454FB4F511453A4A92CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Direct the United States representative to the Arctic Council to use the voice and vote of the United States to conduct increased confidence-building and cooperative security measures with the other member countries of the Arctic Council.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H420D33C3FF9D42079F13F763B0227EE5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Support climate resilience efforts across the Arctic region.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3C7CC683A4A442DBB0D5DC410C3F4F77"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Sustain robust research funding to understand the ongoing climate changes in the Arctic region and the global impact of such changes.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H362BE181331C41F690CF3237229B4E96"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of prior reports and strategies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The strategy required under subsection (a) shall be informed by the reports and strategies described in section 2(2) and other relevant United States Government reports and strategies regarding the Arctic region.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HF2DB0BFD0335465988000C9858C97BE2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Comptroller General of the United States report</header>
 <paragraph id="HEF4C6681C17D4DF394853A6255DF38DC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 45 days after the date of the enactment of the this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report assessing the cost and procurement schedule for new United States icebreakers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDE6D8CF8BE7741C68B5BE7E76FABD2B7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required in paragraph (1) shall include an analysis of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H0F95A5765B994C5BBE4CA341828B42D2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The current status of the efforts of the Coast Guard to acquire new icebreaking capability, including coordination through the Integrated Program Office.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA582C36280DC4EBDB93D084A32BA24B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Actions being taken by the Coast Guard to incorporate key practices from other nations that procure icebreakers to increase knowledge and reduce costs and risks.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF333FCD53FA486BACD1906C1488A018"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The extent by which the cost and schedule for building Coast Guard icebreakers differs from those in other countries, if known.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5BC41547BC5D492A851B828BBCAC40AC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The extent that innovative acquisition practices (such as multiyear funding and block buys) may be applied to icebreaker acquisition to reduce the cost and accelerate the schedule.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B8A513F18F94DB0A5BA582B074255B0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A capacity replacement plan to mitigate a potential icebreaker capability gap if the Polar Star cannot remain in service.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H54C28D383EDF42B5922240B223FD0BC7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Any other matters the Comptroller General considers appropriate.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HFB83E0F0FD99483C87C10B824FA71F54" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authorization to procure Coast Guard icebreakers</header> <subsection id="HC06A9968686D495C9FF2934F26A1C9B6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consistent with the plan required by section 3523 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>), the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating may enter into a contract to procure up to three Coast Guard heavy icebreakers to defend United States interests in the Arctic Region, beginning in fiscal year 2018.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC078D465B50F4BD4A70FB086D662613F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Liability subject to appropriations</header><text>Any contract entered into under subsection (a) shall provide that—</text> <paragraph id="H317D06045C1841308B90319327161239"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any obligation of the United States to make a payment under the contract is subject to the availability of appropriations for that purpose; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H96B5EFB9CF6C4A6DA8357B8AE1434828"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the total liability to the Government for termination of such contract shall be limited to the total amount of funding obligated under such contract at the time of termination.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H653067CC9E844C4F963ED9FC19B1809E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consistent with such section, the Secretary shall report to the relevant congressional committees on plans of such department to—</text>
 <paragraph id="HCA3440054FB04AFE8CA24EAF995E0401"><enum>(1)</enum><text>procure and sustain icebreakers in addition to the vessels authorized by subsection (a); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA586194238EC4AF696D4CD4FDC2FB379"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure that at least three Coast Guard icebreakers are operational at all times.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


