<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H719B81039A194B7AB01DEA34D0E79A51" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3329 IH: Hizballah International Financing Prevention Amendments Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3329</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170720">July 20, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000487">Mr. Royce of California</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Hizballah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015 to impose additional
			 sanctions with respect to Hizballah, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HBFCFF7C84E3A4CF29574CF6AC152CB14" style="OLC">
		<section id="H0FBC1EC535C5424B8D18550C524DF8C0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="HADDF35BDC6A54E7F8FFB12D9009F413B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Hizballah International Financing Prevention Amendments Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H6F9D03E28D5B4886B609C18B41B96ACA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
					<toc-entry idref="H0FBC1EC535C5424B8D18550C524DF8C0" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H335B057E322D4159B328E951F3BD5892" level="title">Title I—Prevention of access by Hizballah to international financial and other institutions</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HF0D598179A0249E68B84240E41C23A10" level="section">Sec. 101. Mandatory sanctions with respect to fundraising and recruitment activities for Hizballah.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H7D956BFFDADF4F1D860E8C6C43DE8A8A" level="section">Sec. 102. Modification of report with respect to financial institutions that engage in certain
			 transactions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H5A1977218F6740BEA572A37733443F80" level="section">Sec. 103. Sanctions against foreign states that support Hizballah.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H7712FBF26D00424EBA1CC0A25E6D6AD3" level="section">Sec. 104. Prohibitions and conditions with respect to certain accounts held by foreign financial
			 institutions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HB9328FEF90A9444ABBDF4F76448DB9AC" level="title">Title II—Narcotics trafficking and significant transnational criminal activities of Hizballah</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HFB89A84251924F7F98BBB6D60B55152C" level="section">Sec. 201. Blocking of property of Hizballah.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H2C5187A27005438DA7CCC9176826401E" level="section">Sec. 202. Report on racketeering activities engaged in by Hizballah.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HFB8A3FC69A974C73B1E68091266D6A50" level="section">Sec. 203. Modification of report on activities of foreign governments to disrupt global logistics
			 networks and fundraising, financing, and money laundering activities of
			 Hizballah.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H8DFC9C3BF95F4ADAA93F86D04658D483" level="section">Sec. 204. Report on combating the illicit tobacco trafficking networks used by Hizballah and other
			 foreign terrorist organizations.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H2F5DC144B7E14EECAFEE6A0FE83D17EA" level="title">Title III—General provisions</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H4B17C0E489C44D4ABFC108BE99F8C577" level="section">Sec. 301. Regulatory authority.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HC86D3A138A354C57AD746203A3E065B5" level="section">Sec. 302. Implementation; penalties; judicial review; exemptions.</toc-entry>
				</toc>
			</subsection></section><title id="H335B057E322D4159B328E951F3BD5892" style="OLC"><enum>I</enum><header>Prevention of access by Hizballah to international financial and other institutions</header>
			<section id="HF0D598179A0249E68B84240E41C23A10"><enum>101.</enum><header>Mandatory sanctions with respect to fundraising and recruitment activities for Hizballah</header>
 <subsection id="H6C41EB1170FF42E0968B6000F8F280C7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 101 of the Hizballah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/102">Public Law 114–102</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) is amended to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF9BA95401A9F4697ABEFBB2EC6AC43F0" style="OLC">
						<section id="H10715E42A0C7462FAE0DD02CBC555023"><enum>101.</enum><header>Mandatory sanctions with respect to fundraising and recruitment activities for Hizballah</header>
 <subsection id="HCF07CD6EA222472992EBAFDB399CCFB0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall impose the sanctions described in subsection (b) with respect to any foreign person that the President determines knowingly assists, sponsors, or, provides significant financial, material, or technological support for—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB706D5A0DE394123ABB9FCDD9B9C80C1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Bayt al-Mal, Jihad al-Bina, the Islamic Resistance Support Association, the Foreign Relations Department of Hizballah, the External Security Organization of Hizballah, or any successor or affiliate thereof;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB582562808344B6A9B076F25EE077BEC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>al-Manar TV, al Nour Radio, or the Lebanese Media Group, or any successor or affiliate thereof;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2231D31CF8114D9493AA92DCF277AFAB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a foreign person determined by the President to be engaged in fundraising or recruitment activities for Hizballah; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDE35E25395F94644B1EEC9BEA29EFCDE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a foreign person owned or controlled by a foreign person described in paragraph (1), (2), or (3).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0C933BCC49644E2D8BBFEE7805CA7DCB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header> <paragraph id="HCA7113CACCEE484AAC145B7D73C09CA5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The sanctions described in this subsection are the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1EA2C408A12E45749E92F17698BCFF3A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Asset blocking</header><text>The exercise of all powers granted to the President by the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.) (except that the requirements of section 202 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref>) shall not apply) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of a foreign person determined by the President to be subject to subsection (a) if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text>
									</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4B9D0153B17475489FE4984227186C4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Aliens ineligible for visas, admission, or parole</header>
 <clause id="H60AB305916AA4AEAABBCAC8084F35D23"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Visas, admission, or parole</header><text>An alien who the President determines is subject to subsection (a) is—</text> <subclause id="HA38BC8B78BFF41E0A966C0ACC1F692DE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HFA044BA68DCE4A33A5F850BE3BEB5108"><enum>(II)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H3EDE2D0D32B74D9385B48F585D8D460D"><enum>(III)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
											</subclause></clause><clause id="H1F0D0B99A850427AB9363009B77E7D25"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header>
 <subclause id="HB01EFD709E4E4656A43261DFA28CE071"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The issuing consular officer, the Secretary of State, or the Secretary of Homeland Security shall revoke any visa or other entry documentation issued to an alien who the President determines is subject to subsection (a), regardless of when issued.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD445BD6F7DB54B33906B30A80A155CEB"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Effect of revocation</header><text>A revocation under subclause (I) shall take effect immediately and shall automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the possession of the alien.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H70E846074DB24B928A268CB1FF4A286D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>The penalties provided for in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) shall apply to a person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of regulations prescribed under paragraph (1)(A) to the same extent that such penalties apply to a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of such section 206.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBABFC1F80BBA42A58802F64BC5742AB6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The President may exercise all authorities provided under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1702">50 U.S.C. 1702</external-xref> and 1704) to carry out this section.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="HEA87679C88F648C28AB1D129E4AFED8E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Waiver</header>
 <paragraph id="HD06FF01E19FE40F1915F399A4C096651"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may, for periods not to exceed 180 days, waive the imposition of sanctions under this section with respect to a foreign person or foreign persons if the President certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that such waiver is in the national security interests of the United States.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="H06E7ADCF0BC74E4E9D952E6A0A54D51D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header>
 <subparagraph id="HD590A1D32CB6412F88EFD4DD49F3805B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Before waiver exercised</header><text>Before a waiver under paragraph (1) takes effect with respect to a foreign person, the President shall notify and brief the appropriate congressional committees on the status of the involvement of the foreign person in activities described in subsection (a).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H392F798EB4FA42EBADF9407BA2777682"><enum>(B)</enum><header>After waiver exercised</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the issuance of a waiver under paragraph (1) with respect to a foreign person, and every 120 days thereafter while the waiver remains in effect, the President shall brief the appropriate congressional committees on the status of the involvement of the foreign person in activities described in subsection (a).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEDFE1A8198BD425B9AE4E2C1181B5B99"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Hizballah International Financing Prevention Amendments Act of 2017</short-title>, and every 180 days thereafter, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that lists the foreign persons that the President has credible evidence knowingly assists, sponsors, or provides significant financial, material, or technological support for the foreign persons described in paragraph (1), (2), (3), or (4) of subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1A7713240A494A71B6AF4965C720424A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H2328D1ED640A49F4975BBB8C9F97A2F4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Admitted; alien</header><text>The terms <term>admitted</term> and <term>alien</term> have meanings given those terms in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC3FA40F57D934DDC8742DC47A85DDA3D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HB48F2136B0D7427F8465BD21F294885E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Ways and Means, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7C8071DAC4F4485A894BECA3A6F6386"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B2A252173AB4D01A6920E2EBEDDA9E4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Entity</header><text>The term <term>entity</term> means a partnership, association, corporation, or other organization, group, or subgroup.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1785B7E8C5EC419292C407FD7030CFE0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Fundraising or recruitment activities</header><text>The term <term>fundraising or recruitment activities</term> includes online fundraising and other online commercial activities, or other means of such fundraising, recruitment, and retention, as determined by the President.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1A2880C519F54BB8A78098318130B7F4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Hizballah</header><text>The term <term>Hizballah</term> has the meaning given such term in section 102(f).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H36BA40B46FC648B1B06254AC5E4BF4EE"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Person</header><text>The term <term>person</term> means an individual or entity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3C334BC8A1934AA9A7DFD43D248FB808"><enum>(7)</enum><header>United States person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means a United States citizen, permanent resident alien, entity organized under the laws of the United States (including foreign branches), or a person in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5228D56C6FDD439FBB8F93C320609A99"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents for the Hizballah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015 is amended by striking the item relating to section 101 and inserting the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H80D36D021DBD4D28962E555D59A13274" style="OLC">
						<toc>
							<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 101. Mandatory sanctions with respect to fundraising and recruitment activities for Hizballah.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection></section><section id="H7D956BFFDADF4F1D860E8C6C43DE8A8A"><enum>102.</enum><header>Modification of report with respect to financial institutions that engage in certain transactions</header>
 <subsection id="HF480213A90C34CDB9A6295D8869CE1F9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (d) of section 102 of the Hizballah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/102">Public Law 114–102</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) is amended to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H986E19FC22E6422D8C9A4C37A4B76C35" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="H38F5283666D1417AAAF8FFEDEF60BCFB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report on financial institutions organized under the laws of state sponsors of terrorism</header>
 <paragraph id="H8E0AA7E6741C4958AB52D5BD24930A0B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Hizballah International Financing Prevention Amendments Act of 2017</short-title>, and annually thereafter for a period not to exceed three years, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF9E96FE3E7BE423E9908A658374E21B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifies each foreign financial institution described in paragraph (2) that the President determines engages in one or more activities described in subsection (a)(2);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8BD7D4B64BC48FBB8EC5B57ABD4D16C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides a detailed description of each such activity; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3BB6796CE89B4113AA92A4530CFEBB4E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contains a determination with respect to each such foreign financial institution that is identified under subparagraph (A) as engaging in one or more activities described in subsection (a)(2) as to whether or not such foreign financial institution is in violation of Executive Order 13224 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note; relating to blocking property and prohibiting transactions with persons who commit, threaten to commit, or support terrorism) by reason of engaging in one or more such activities.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC16905AB9CF479D90D8AB7B98FBFD89"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign financial institution described</header>
 <subparagraph id="H5C549693974F456288BEB2902B500AA2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A foreign financial institution described in this paragraph is a foreign financial institution—</text> <clause id="HCCC246FD5E284C37ADB06A8AB18E23D5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that, wherever located, is—</text>
 <subclause id="HAC7EE238DD1A4B9B98AC0ED9A5B77CB1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>organized under the laws of a state sponsor of terrorism or any jurisdiction within a state sponsor of terrorism;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H43F5EE735F0E4E1781B1AF54015FFF63"><enum>(II)</enum><text>owned or controlled by the government of a state sponsor of terrorism;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HC19E42A88F7146338EB23858FAC62657"><enum>(III)</enum><text>located in the territory of a state sponsor of terrorism; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H8F2DF79E5D204799B53A8768C1D760A0"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>owned or controlled by a foreign financial institution described in subclause (I), (II), or (III); and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H68AF32335D4D49FFA383B6BEBAFC262E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the capitalization of which exceeds $10,000,000.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE80DE1C523C3448A9FAB8C917885D711"><enum>(B)</enum><header>State sponsor of terrorism</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>state sponsor of terrorism</term> means a country the government of which the Secretary of State has determined is a government that has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism for purposes of—</text>
 <clause id="HF999FA9F39454366B331A963B414C40A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>section 6(j) of the Export Administration Act of 1979 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4605">50 U.S.C. 4605(j)</external-xref>) (as continued in effect pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.));</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2E81DBE1A186445BB5FC231EC9CA32A3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>section 620A of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2371">22 U.S.C. 2371</external-xref>);</text> </clause><clause id="H1A38E4325C434E24AB3E3A2C31760C97"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>section 40 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2780">22 U.S.C. 2780</external-xref>); or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0FA1844AA98947BDBBDD42B511836393"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any other provision of law.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H4AB51983EC5C488A96637A085A3C2002"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of the Congress that the President should apply the sanctions contained in section 102 of the Hizballah International Financing Prevention Act with respect to foreign financial institutions that engage in prohibited activities described in such section with respect to any member of parliament or any cabinet official of the Lebanese Republic who is a member of Hizballah, or any affiliate of Hizballah.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H5A1977218F6740BEA572A37733443F80"><enum>103.</enum><header>Sanctions against foreign states that support Hizballah</header>
 <subsection id="H2CA35C95043A4C63824DBCCF18468259"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title I of the Hizballah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/102">Public Law 114–102</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA22D6855B4FB401DB0A986E8D5A1193D" style="OLC">
						<section id="H6CB694DC15BC4D178DD1F52115CBA465"><enum>103.</enum><header>Sanctions against foreign states that support Hizballah</header>
							<subsection id="H3816BE86AEAC4D8088F1D47D316507A3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sanctions against certain agencies and instrumentalities of foreign states</header>
 <paragraph id="H7BDE6C1F46564D9E8C2E76433EF10BC8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this section, and as appropriate thereafter, the President shall impose the sanctions described in paragraph (3) with respect to any agency or instrumentality of a foreign state described in paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H00D70957864B4C51BE589D4C3BD86F13"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agency or instrumentality described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An agency or instrumentality of a foreign state described in this paragraph is an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state that the President determines has, on or after the date of the enactment of this section, knowingly provided significant financial or material support for, or arms or related material to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H033DBB72DAB14BBB838711DAFF636871"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Hizballah; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F5A71FB111543ECBB57BEECC8C310C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity owned or controlled by Hizballah.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H048E24DBE19C4B0299D3FFC63AD8159D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The sanctions described in this paragraph are the exercise of all powers granted to the President by the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.) (except that the requirements of section 202 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref>) shall not apply) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDAC8D5143FB141DDB9C34877BABD0F9A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions against state sponsors of terrorism</header>
 <paragraph id="H9FE407ABF64B432D822BABEF780FDE69"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state that engages in the activities described in subsection (a) that is an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state described in paragraph (2), the President shall, pursuant to section 6 of the Export Administration Act of 1979 (as continued in effect pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.)), require a license under the Export Administration Regulations to export or re-export to that foreign state any item designated by the Secretary of Commerce as <quote>EAR 99</quote>, other than food, medicine, medical devices, or similarly licensed items.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2B82D997AD5749ABB3BF5AE5AF2CCA32"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign state described</header><text>A foreign state described in this paragraph is a foreign state that—</text> <subparagraph id="HB5678F23AD2842DFB7806572BB8C238B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the President determines has, on or after the date of the enactment of this section, knowingly provided significant financial or material support for, or arms or related material to—</text>
 <clause id="H65E29C1E7C154E589F3BAD9FD4427C01"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Hizballah; or</text> </clause><clause id="H0F8F9DAD554B444A98E253257E4322A0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an entity owned or controlled by Hizballah; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC27955D0607470CBD63FF2033A4980A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is a state sponsor of terrorism.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6CD84E7632C54027A0DB9AC88BEAF23A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver</header> <paragraph id="H2329C81BEC284193BDE6BED5BAA9AAA5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may, for periods not to exceed 180 days, waive the imposition of sanctions under this section with respect to a foreign state or an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state if the President certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that such waiver is vital to the national security interests of the United States.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="H296A2750EDE84645B9DEDD9C2FB2C377"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header>
 <subparagraph id="H10CD2D3F5F6B40C193C7F4A84D616B04"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Before waiver exercised</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before a waiver under paragraph (1) takes effect with respect to a foreign state or an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state, the President shall notify and brief the appropriate congressional committees on the status of the involvement of the foreign state in activities described in subsection (b)(2) or involvement of the agency or instrumentality of a foreign state in activities described in subsection (a)(2), as the case may be.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC54E6A545EFD464C95AA612195601D01"><enum>(B)</enum><header>After waiver exercised</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the issuance of a waiver under paragraph (1) with respect to a foreign state or an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state, and every 120 days thereafter while the waiver remains in effect, the President shall brief the appropriate congressional committees on the status of the involvement of the foreign state in activities described in subsection (b)(2) or involvement of the agency or instrumentality of a foreign state in activities described in subsection (a)(2), as the case may be.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4FC671A2D2C946EDB6CBF208037376D0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H76B18E751031468DB8B4A93E81FEC2AC"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Agency or instrumentality of a foreign state; foreign state</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>agency or instrumentality of a foreign state</term> and <term>foreign state</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 1603 of title 28, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD1F57630443040CE81BF130E44AB2DEA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H663F70D4C35C412BB6AA2D010AAEA3C7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Financial Services, the Committee on Ways and Means, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3F4752D511774268A602AE59E059694E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF61F7B9C71F2497DBA80D1B8DD3517A6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Arms or related material</header><text>The term <term>arms or related material</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HFAA959F26B664313AA5E337833E9DA9E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>nuclear, biological, chemical, or radiological weapons or materials or components of such weapons;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42A234D582D04382A9718F8226D4436D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ballistic or cruise missile weapons or materials or components of such weapons;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE5EF700D56C4B2689D74B5B5F63A244"><enum>(C)</enum><text>destabilizing numbers and types of advanced conventional weapons;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBBD52E1BA5AA4B32BE285F66CAA86EFA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>defense articles or defense services, as those terms are defined in paragraphs (3) and (4), respectively, of section 47 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2794">22 U.S.C. 2794</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H59A7A52D88C740AF9664CE54A81A4EF3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>defense information, as that term is defined in section 644 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2403">22 U.S.C. 2403</external-xref>); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H71775D34AF404158B382ED3E49257D78"><enum>(F)</enum><text>items designated by the President for purposes of the United States Munitions List under section 38(a)(1) of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2778">22 U.S.C. 2778(a)(1)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDFABD78398AE4F978E24061055B9EA89"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Export Administration Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Export Administration Regulations</term> means subchapter C of chapter VII of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFAA61C4DD2C54587B4FC7B2723943390"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Hizballah</header><text>The term <term>Hizballah</term> has the meaning given that term in section 102(f).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3B892D9231CE4707B3049BF2FF2943BF"><enum>(6)</enum><header>State sponsor of terrorism</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>state sponsor of terrorism</term> means a country the government of which the Secretary of State has determined is a government that has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism for purposes of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDC60961964DB47CFB0B8C5C06DC99AC0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 6(j) of the Export Administration Act of 1979 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4605">50 U.S.C. 4605(j)</external-xref>) (as continued in effect pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.));</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD364FD8046FA4413B9DB60BD7AD77328"><enum>(B)</enum><text>section 620A of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2371">22 U.S.C. 2371</external-xref>);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE2411AB89FC8470FBFC0D14E26E80A18"><enum>(C)</enum><text>section 40 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2780">22 U.S.C. 2780</external-xref>); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97083FD08F0A4F73B253BBAF3BE084B8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other provision of law.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H2AB79891DEF34E84B1F744B5DDBFBC9A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents for the Hizballah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 102 the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE2082A7AF9EA4FEC86BEF0853A3D0F5B" style="OLC">
						<toc>
							<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 103. Sanctions against foreign states that support Hizballah.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section id="H7712FBF26D00424EBA1CC0A25E6D6AD3"><enum>104.</enum><header>Prohibitions and conditions with respect to certain accounts held by foreign financial institutions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 104(c)(2)(A)(ii) of the Comprehensive Iran Sanctions, Accountability, and Divestment Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8513">22 U.S.C. 8513(c)(2)(A)(ii)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting before <quote>or support for acts of international terrorism</quote> the following <quote>, including Hizballah (as defined in section 102(f)(1)(E) of the Hizballah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/102">Public Law 114–102</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note), and any affiliates or successors thereof,</quote>.</text>
			</section></title><title id="HB9328FEF90A9444ABBDF4F76448DB9AC" style="OLC"><enum>II</enum><header>Narcotics trafficking and significant transnational criminal activities of Hizballah</header>
			<section id="HFB89A84251924F7F98BBB6D60B55152C"><enum>201.</enum><header>Blocking of property of Hizballah</header>
 <subsection id="HB33E8E8BA7394BADB472E1C1323BC7AE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 201 of the Hizballah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/102">Public Law 114–102</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) is amended to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H232EE4CB5C6D4ABBB312AB8653BCAABA" style="OLC">
						<section id="HA6986A31DA854BE381A0817F3A6E57C5"><enum>201.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions with respect to Hizballah</header>
 <subsection id="H3CD59A6B80BC4928B8945591BB180688"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this section, and as appropriate thereafter, the President shall impose the sanctions described in subsection (b) with respect to Hizballah, including by reason of Hizballah’s significant transnational criminal activities.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H24C6E1EBCC9946DC9FA3C4B64AF8C46F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text>The sanctions described in this subsection are sanctions applied with respect to a foreign person pursuant to Executive Order 13581 (75 Fed. Reg. 44,757) (as such Executive order was in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this section).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3B2539E818614F7B98CFC029BEED69C5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>Hizballah</term> has the meaning given such term in section 102(f).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="HA16495CE0F9A47B7926A6F57D2439635"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header><text>The table of contents for the Hizballah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015 is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2590BECF53D74123AD199751A4A6AA94"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking the item relating to title II and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8B50629A59DB4BAE98F65FF0271F3491" style="OLC"> <toc> <toc-entry bold="off" level="title">Title II—Imposition of Sanctions With Respect to Hizballah and Reports and Briefings on Narcotics Trafficking and Significant Transnational Criminal Activities of Hizballah</toc-entry></toc> <after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block> <continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">and</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF0A757F82254CBB810A340B8046B9EA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the item relating to section 201 and inserting the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC7B91CCEEBF1469A8FDE1E7790FE7E7A" style="OLC">
							<toc>
								<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 201. Imposition of sanctions with respect to Hizballah.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H89F4024B7F71402E8954F699E13ADAF2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section take effect on the date that is 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H2C5187A27005438DA7CCC9176826401E"><enum>202.</enum><header>Report on racketeering activities engaged in by Hizballah</header>
 <subsection id="H6B292B068151494FAB79B2EF0AF7E06F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 202 of the Hizballah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/102">Public Law 114–102</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) is amended to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H63A4410F2DEC4F76AAF8EF756BFAA16D" style="OLC">
						<section id="HB0AF719D00A04F59B81757D74B1374D8"><enum>202.</enum><header>Report on racketeering activities engaged in by Hizballah</header>
 <subsection id="H559E3FBA98A444A49ED584B7B786EA64"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Hizballah International Financing Prevention Amendments Act of 2017</short-title>, and annually thereafter for the following 5 years, the Assistant Attorney General for the Criminal Division of the Department of Justice and the Administrator of the Drug Enforcement Administration, in coordination with the Secretary of the Treasury and the heads of other applicable Federal agencies, shall jointly submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HF69C2CB87267496F98DFF4737FF164D5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Activities that Hizballah, and agents and affiliates of Hizballah, have engaged in that are racketeering activities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9E620EE3A22F484194F9ED06A87CC2FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The extent to which Hizballah, and agents and affiliates of Hizballah, engage in a pattern of such racketeering activities.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDB0108DC7E7A40FC9F820771E25F27CD"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Form of report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report required under subsection (a) shall be submitted in an unclassified form but may contain a classified annex.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA798976F27E2469CA5E79058B073430F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H89FA0548A0C34F39B909072929E3B2AA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H41809C981CD94AFCA4707F7936A5305C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD199F0BEC51141C2B3116008F5746B55"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A2373960B8F4712889BB672FE4E5B72"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Hizballah</header><text>The term <term>Hizballah</term> has the meaning given that term in section 102(f).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6300C1450A024A9BB190872350C0CB1E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Racketeering activity</header><text>The term <term>racketeering activity</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1961(1) of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H9B3DBF50386342DE9997A94CDAB8225B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents for the Hizballah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015 is amended by striking the item relating to section 202 and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDC3835F69A9E4AD08C8786252221ED94" style="OLC">
						<toc>
							<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 202. Report on racketeering activities engaged in by Hizballah.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection></section><section id="HFB8A3FC69A974C73B1E68091266D6A50"><enum>203.</enum><header>Modification of report on activities of foreign governments to disrupt global logistics networks
			 and fundraising, financing, and money laundering activities of Hizballah</header>
 <subsection id="H2314777309C6475FADDEA178D04AD7F3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 204(a)(1) of the Hizballah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/102">Public Law 114–102</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H88650F1AC6B846E0A13B6775BBC9FF0C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>this Act</quote> and inserting <quote>the <short-title>Hizballah International Financing Prevention Amendments Act of 2017</short-title>, and annually thereafter for the following 5 years</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0AF01EFCFFE641C6B27E938B7EE1D77C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D)(ii)(II), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H16FC7EF9559C4613ADF36E3E3171B020"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by striking <quote>and free-trade zones.</quote> and inserting <quote>free-trade zones, business partnerships and joint ventures, and other investments in small and medium-sized enterprises;</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA4D5B7FEBC32489CA94A01A389282093"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFA0559179AF24A518D3C6AF252C26196" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H7D73555B5F714754A57B113787A65A2C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a list of provinces, municipalities, and local governments outside of Lebanon that expressly consent to, or with knowledge allow, tolerate, or disregard the use of their territory by Hizballah to carry out terrorist activities, including training, financing, and recruitment;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE793BF3134F74F20BD07E1B6702DCE79"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a description of the total aggregate revenues and remittances that Hizballah receives from the global logistics networks of Hizballah, including—</text>
 <clause id="HAA16EB881BA54C319F2AED7454C8D6D1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a list of Hizballah's sources of revenue, including sources of revenue based on illicit activity, revenues from Iran, charities, and other business activities; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD0F4D3AE30244189A1E1B0848BF9FC83"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a list of Hizballah's expenditures, including expenditures for ongoing military operations, social networks, and external operations; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCF14676FDFB4006870583435D0C9AE6"><enum>(H)</enum><text>a survey of national and transnational legal measures available to target Hizballah's financial networks.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCDF0FC7BD05B47638125308C4479A6B3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report on estimated net worth of senior Hizballah members</header>
 <paragraph id="HCA5DCE09786640159B8D350BD776FBC1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than annually thereafter for the following 2 years, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that contains—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE96F8D8B546E4D11B6D7AD999DA702F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the estimated total net worth of each individual described in paragraph (2); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CAB9B23F715443CBF46AAC0A8B7C00C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of how funds of each individual described in paragraph (2) were acquired, and how such funds have been used or employed.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB3CD5584F5147DC9A5813E3EDEF1FD1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Individuals described</header><text>The individuals described in this paragraph are the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HC36A0B433BF246D08066873782EB84EF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Secretary General of Hizballah.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3DE5FBC3BF7475784F0EF6714BA3695"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Members of the Hizballah Politburo.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA3AC50C37A1424DA064EC83905D1831"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other individual that the President determines is a senior foreign political figure of Hizballah, is associated with Hizballah, or otherwise provides significant support to Hizballah.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H69BBA6D123F7460190B9694606AD230D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form of report; public availability</header>
 <subparagraph id="HE6D89AC0D12F42E9B2A655F30902554E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9163F049F31643689AEABDA89FCBDDA5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The unclassified portion of the report required under paragraph (1) shall be made available to the public and posted on the website of the Department of State and all United States Embassy websites.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H96F4F2BA85354CF490AA234A216B1D2B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="HD53A495FA3A14621869865AA7482AA18"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text>
 <clause id="HE7A874ABA2C141C4AD37153B309371E5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE6DF7010C0B14A09A1945E85DB591A76"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD01B3C0932984070B0EDDD94B15883E8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Funds</header><text>The term <term>funds</term> means—</text> <clause id="H6CEF3353D22647ACA88547701686406C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>cash;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD4D5725611AC4967A74D99A171DFC903"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>equity;</text> </clause><clause id="H9109266136F240B39AD265F82E1644FD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other intangible asset the value of which is derived from a contractual claim, including bank deposits, bonds, stocks, a security (as defined in section 2(a) of the Securities Act of 1933 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/77b">15 U.S.C. 77b(a)</external-xref>)), or a security or an equity security (as those terms are defined in section 3(a) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)</external-xref>)); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCF08FA183CD045C0A5C14678092EACB6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>anything else of value that the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9388AF3D02CF41BF8B46CBE6722F1F74"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Senior foreign political figure</header><text>The term <term>senior foreign political figure</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1010.605 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation).</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8DFC9C3BF95F4ADAA93F86D04658D483"><enum>204.</enum><header>Report on combating the illicit tobacco trafficking networks used by Hizballah and other foreign
			 terrorist organizations</header>
 <subsection id="H4D8E666A2A824CC18D5F364A4630DD88"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on combating the illicit tobacco trafficking networks used by Hizballah and other foreign terrorist organizations to finance their operations, as described in the report submitted to Congress in December 2015 by the Department of State, the Department of Justice, the Department of the Treasury, the Department of Homeland Security, and the Department of Health and Human Services entitled, <quote>The Global Illicit Trade in Tobacco: A Threat to National Security.</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5D2FA638C8874818B13B93D1F6E464FC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters To be addressed</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="H7518C5A60EB14D6D90510E4277F05675"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of the steps to be taken by Federal agencies to combat the illicit tobacco trafficking networks used by Hizballah, other foreign terrorist organizations, and other illicit actors.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEB9C8FF1650E4C9C943B0F4F32C845C1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of the steps to be taken to engage State and local law enforcement authorities in efforts to combat illicit tobacco trafficking networks operating within the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB97D7C5C3C1F40D196D0743BC2702439"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of the steps to be taken to engage foreign government law enforcement and intelligence authorities in efforts to combat illicit tobacco trafficking networks operating outside the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8773EACAE2DB4355A53C4D07168CAA6C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Recommendations for legislative or administrative action needed to address the threat of illicit tobacco trafficking networks.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0120F005204247568204D8AB2E41ABAC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD5885527D84643BAB7388F7B9ABE8698"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Homeland Security, the Committee on the Judiciary, the Committee on Financial Services, and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H970D0B6DECEA46CB8C1B2E47CF9ED8A7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, the Committee on the Judiciary, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, and the Committee on Finance of the Senate.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="H2F5DC144B7E14EECAFEE6A0FE83D17EA" style="OLC"><enum>III</enum><header>General provisions</header>
			<section id="H4B17C0E489C44D4ABFC108BE99F8C577"><enum>301.</enum><header>Regulatory authority</header>
 <subsection id="HBABF22DA16B3414893C449B5BF1CB0B5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall, not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, prescribe regulations as necessary for the implementation of this Act and the amendments made by this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H12CA2D2B32E3479E80BA4931EB3D5DCA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Briefing to Congress</header><text>Not later than 10 days before the prescription of regulations under subsection (a), the President shall brief the appropriate congressional committees of the proposed regulations and the provisions of this Act and the amendments made by this Act that the regulations are implementing.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB763AB1987CD418983405C3A1045270E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="H575B128A529A489FA46F2B52737D3A95"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0FB0EC8B35C94492B896EBAB6EF8C624"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="HC86D3A138A354C57AD746203A3E065B5"><enum>302.</enum><header>Implementation; penalties; judicial review; exemptions</header>
 <subsection id="H18B2ACC1490147FFA5CA738A49CE6633"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title I of the Hizballah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/102">Public Law 114–102</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note), as amended by section 103 of this Act, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H72F33F9E5F5A4A02B97435005294E15D" style="OLC">
						<section id="H07B7200EF61747ECA416E8A75C50C49D"><enum>104.</enum><header>Implementation; penalties; judicial review; exemptions; rule of construction</header>
 <subsection id="H9E5FE35F045549B6AC9E90667D8FCBBD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may exercise all authorities provided under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1702">50 U.S.C. 1702</external-xref> and 1704) to carry out sections 101 and 103.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H720436892CED4274B440666272D6EB7B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>The penalties provided for in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) shall apply to a person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of regulations prescribed to carry out section 101 or 103 to the same extent that such penalties apply to a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of such section 206.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="H242C92379E7C44EE99E9E2F0DE31B983"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Procedures for judicial review of classified information</header>
 <paragraph id="HC1BAD1B9790D4A57B0873A5369F4A23A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a finding, or a prohibition, condition, or penalty imposed as a result of any such finding, is based on classified information (as defined in section 1(a) of the Classified Information Procedures Act (18 U.S.C. App.)) and a court reviews the finding or the imposition of the prohibition, condition, or penalty, the President may submit such information to the court ex parte and in camera.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H29B97816728C4EC9B4304D1E3D5BF839"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to confer or imply any right to judicial review of any finding under section 101 or 103 or any prohibition, condition, or penalty imposed as a result of any such finding.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4B0B34ED4B2E4754AE0A730D003EC085"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exemptions</header><text>The following activities shall be exempt from sections 101 and 103:</text> <paragraph id="HB23FE94BEF0145C2B62C7549DC9ED3E5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Any authorized intelligence, law enforcement, or national security activities of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBC7E04F641174CA0ABE18680DD8B4D13"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any transaction necessary to comply with United States obligations under the Agreement between the United Nations and the United States of America regarding the Headquarters of the United States, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, or under the Convention on Consular Relations, done at Vienna April 24, 1963, and entered into force March 19, 1967, or any other United States international treaties.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H01FFCDE65B494479AFF654D566DE91B1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in section 101 or 103 shall be construed to limit the authority of the President under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.) or under any other provision of law.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7E3E6BB5276544729B0ACFE9FD0C0B9A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents for the Hizballah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 103, as added by section 103(b) of this Act, the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3AFF49B281034DCD86530424614769D4" style="OLC">
						<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
							<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 104. Implementation; penalties; judicial review; exemptions; rule of construction.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection></section></title></legis-body></bill>


