<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="HFD41C50427424733A78E9C38E84F192E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1365 EH: Department of Homeland Security Acquisition Innovation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>115th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 1365</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require certain acquisition innovation, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HFBB67B59B29741D0A182157E6C058BCF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H06676CB0664E40B599A808AEB3F13B7E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Department of Homeland Security Acquisition Innovation Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H36C69DABE41C47A2AC887DE945C58259"><enum>2.</enum><header>Acquisition innovation</header> <subsection id="H0409CDACA4294433921900704FCB9F33"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title VII of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/341">6 U.S.C. 341</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HACB3FF240EC34A7A93240D12EB21BD2E" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="HBC59B12162074B428A6A37A7D3AC640B"><enum>710.</enum><header>Acquisition innovation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Under Secretary for Management may—</text> <paragraph id="H3B0F519C44D24D7C8C609495EA4F5D36"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designate an individual within the Department to manage acquisition innovation efforts of the Department;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC2E366C1D85D44409789228B13A4455D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>test emerging acquisition best practices to carrying out acquisitions, consistent with the Federal Acquisition Regulation and Department acquisition management directives, as appropriate;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H648C359978D745008AF8F420E7EC0021"><enum>(3)</enum><text>develop and distribute best practices and lessons learned regarding acquisition innovation throughout the Department;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H519951AFB50D4C0990D233F6EEE34D59"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establish metrics to measure the effectiveness of acquisition innovation efforts with respect to cost, operational efficiency of the acquisition program (including timeframe for executing contracts), and collaboration with the private sector, including small businesses; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0A8C5E5504694D67B6C75E2A3831787B"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine impacts of acquisition innovation efforts on the private sector by—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC06B645D6041426D9FA77B62F6F96988"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">engaging with the private sector, including small businesses, to provide information and obtain feedback on procurement practices and acquisition innovation efforts of the Department;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H46008D9FA402445AA55A62AA7ECC3ED4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>obtaining feedback from the private sector on the impact of acquisition innovation efforts of the Department; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBAC2B216FA514544A89B7B048DF012D1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>incorporating such feedback, as appropriate, into future acquisition innovation efforts of the Department.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HADED3D1174BE4DB7944527B189697542"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 709 the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H494CC5ABB6ED4FB4B14FE8065CA25AB6" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 710. Acquisition innovation.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2B79537747DD43D29B18F41AB9BACD38"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date on which the Secretary of Homeland Security submits the annual budget justification for the Department of Homeland Security for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022, the Secretary shall, if appropriate, provide information to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate on the activities undertaken in the previous fiscal year in furtherance of section 710 of the Homeland Security Act, as added by subsection (a) of this Act, on the following:</text> <paragraph id="H0AFED35B95AE42648C181D2C5A7032C6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Emerging acquisition best practices that were tested within the Department during such year.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC3962167ADF341B8B2AA62880B930AA9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Efforts to distribute best practices and lessons learned within the Department, including through web-based seminars, training, and forums, during such year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H89AD259D7801471BB5E1DB81DB83DB0B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Utilization by components throughout the Department of best practices distributed by the Under Secretary of Management pursuant to paragraph (3) of such section 710.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1AE8C64BF4BD4A70A96F3B7A4728876C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Performance as measured by the metrics established under paragraph (4) of such section 710.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2DF09B768B7F439880536E2C7775B1B3" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Outcomes of efforts to distribute best practices and lessons learned within the Department, including through web-based seminars, training, and forums.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6F6C516F9206448A83FEEF30C2F4D979"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any impacts of the utilization of innovative acquisition mechanisms by the Department on the private sector, including small businesses.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8A538620DAC64817945FB8C207CD26B2"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The criteria used to identify specific acquisition programs or activities to be included in acquisition innovation efforts and the outcomes of such programs or activities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4061FF215CD648129B01CEF3FEF59436"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Recommendations, as necessary, to enhance acquisition innovation in the Department.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20170322" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives March 24, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> <endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> </bill> 

