<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H82D5AC2023BF4C369874F5B83B467E31" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3010 IH: Promoting Good Cyber Hygiene Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3010</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170622">June 22, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B001284">Mrs. Brooks of Indiana</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the identification and documentation of best practices for cyber hygiene by the
			 National Institute of Standards and Technology, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HD25C69A8DA5147A398955C91A180FED0" style="OLC">
 <section id="H83A80BC2B6244B80A3849EF464C7EDA8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Promoting Good Cyber Hygiene Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H0AD18D7BB94C498CB7DCADE7533BC21B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Cyber hygiene best practices</header> <subsection id="H6CDD6B7A0D21456997442A68D64D3FDC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the National Institute of Standards and Technology, in consultation with the Federal Trade Commission and the Department of Homeland Security, after notice and an opportunity for public comment, shall establish a list of best practices for effective and usable cyber hygiene for use by the Federal Government, the private sector, and any individual or organization utilizing an information system or device. Such list shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H70DC0BFC9CAB4D438E7ABEC7E62351C4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be a list of simple, basic controls that have the most impact in defending against common cybersecurity threats and risks;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCECDEC8BAB944948A74F75EF46C9ED2C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>utilize technologies that are commercial off-the-shelf and based on international standards; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD2676644AE274AF5ADABD0631636CE61"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to the degree practicable, be based on and consistent with the Cybersecurity Framework contained in Executive Order 13636, entitled Improving Critical Infrastructure Cybersecurity, issued in February 2013, or any successor framework.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3FA438D047714C6797D46D588720960E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Voluntary practices</header><text>The best practices on the list established under this section shall be considered voluntary and are not intended to be construed as a list of mandatory actions.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB07F32640F264A639B9D396555FF30AD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Baseline</header><text>The best practices on the list established under this section are intended as a baseline for the Federal Government, the private sector, and any individual or organization utilizing an information system or device. Such entities are encouraged to use and improve on those best practices.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H96BFCC426D264C218B9F7F0944A3E589"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>The National Institute of Standards and Technology shall review and update the list of best practices established under this section on an annual basis.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H180C7C5BD2124F90A6DAE75A54B553B8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The list of best practices established under this section shall be published in a clear and concise format and made available prominently on the public websites of the Federal Trade Commission and the Small Business Administration.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5D886F61DC9A4A88A445D282C921F1D9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Other federal cybersecurity requirements</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to supersede, alter, or otherwise affect any cybersecurity requirements applicable to Federal agencies.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEC701EB1BC964AA3A0DD043F22FB3B4A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out subsection (a), the agencies shall consider the benefits, as they pertain to cyber hygiene, of emerging technologies and processes that provide enhanced security protections, including multi-factor authentication, data loss prevention, micro-segmentation, data encryption, cloud services, anonymization, software patching and maintenance, phishing education, and other standard cybersecurity measures to achieve trusted security in the infrastructure.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H6BF1D3CDD48A46019ACCB3D85F6BFECB"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Study on emerging concepts To promote effective cyber hygiene for the internet of things</header>
 <paragraph id="H006E36E0D4E14903842DF3A6BF23F5AE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Internet of things defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>Internet of Things</quote> means the set of physical objects embedded with sensors or actuators and connected to a network.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDDC644E20D2D4AB9AFE6B969E3ABC3B8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Study required</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology and the Federal Trade Commission, shall conduct a study on cybersecurity threats relating to the Internet of Things.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1A10DA459B1143A0952C774CBF2A60C6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Matters studied</header><text>As part of the study required by paragraph (2), the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HA689E99770E145C2877480FEC4664C81"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assess cybersecurity threats relating to the Internet of Things;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEEBCF38A0C914B73A414049BE3863271"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assess the effect such threats may have on the cybersecurity of the information systems and networks of the Federal Government (except for the information systems and networks of the Department of Defense and the intelligence community (as defined in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003</external-xref>))); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F2AEF11026949B29EAC919240997504"><enum>(C)</enum><text>develop recommendations for addressing such threats.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A19A516BCB94439BD460F35639F059A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Report to congress</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE57C7D0C8A6F43CEB31B0F7107ED63EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>complete the study required by paragraph (2); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF3175A2293A4B06BD753999564199CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit to Congress a report that contains the findings of such study and the recommendations developed.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


