<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H9597467A4FCB4C71942BFEEDBDF01C4F" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2152 IH: Citizens’ Right to Know Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2152</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170426">April 26, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000592">Mr. Poe of Texas</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="W000798">Mr. Walberg</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require States and units of local government receiving funds under grant programs operated by
			 the Department of Justice, which use such funds for pretrial services
			 programs, to submit to the Attorney General a report relating to such
			 program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HD736C044204947CE8EEB3E46050B1678" style="OLC">
 <section id="H698B6A14B0A444B5B7E70035FDCC5363" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Citizens’ Right to Know Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H17D4E2234FFE4C4581AE91A27C8FFE0B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reporting requirement for Department of Justice grant recipients using funds for pretrial services programs</header> <subsection id="H6FC6108636CB4014AA9A2B87141B0275"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each fiscal year in which a State or unit of local government receives funds under any grant program operated by the Department of Justice, including the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance grant program under subpart I of part E of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3750">42 U.S.C. 3750</external-xref> et seq.), and which uses funds received under such program for a pretrial services program, the State or unit of local government shall submit to the Attorney General a report which contains the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H7613F896FCF04E94895A4A92D9C74E14"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The name of each defendant participating in a pretrial release program administered by the pretrial services program, and whether, as applicable, each occasion on which such defendant failed to make an appearance.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD43DC57DC90A46A8B10FE9A7162B3926"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Information relating to the previous arrest record of each defendant participating in the pretrial services program.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE5EEEF5E482F476985EB4BDA35569704"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Publication requirement</header><text>Subject to any applicable confidentiality requirements, the Attorney General shall, on an annual basis, make publicly available the information received under subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H60C8530ACDB24AE9B9334553B86A1ED9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reduction in funding</header><text>The Attorney General shall, for State or unit of local government which fails to comply with the requirement under subsection (a) for a fiscal year, reduce the amount that the State or local government would otherwise receive under each grant program described in subsection (a) in the following fiscal year by 100 percent.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H60F2AB65428348EFBAC1DED5ABA0CFA9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reallocation</header><text>Amounts not allocated to a State or unit of local government under subsection (c) shall be reallocated under each such grant program to States and units of local government that comply with the requirement under subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8E595A75C24D44CCB7D79407C7C2724F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>failed to make an appearance</term> means an action whereby any defendant has been charged with an offense before a court and who is participating in a pretrial release program for which funds received under a grant program referred to in subsection (a) are used as a condition of pretrial release—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD360991D91954510B6C59E5300661007"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not appear for any court date regarding such charge;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAE5A6AC9043547788267C698FF03F080"><enum>(2)</enum><text>does not appear for any one appointment with the pretrial services program; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1B65912ECC3841E494E3319658CF9173"><enum>(3)</enum><text>does not appear for any post-release appearance the court may require.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

