<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0ACC24F0C7DB4E9582EAC36E414734E7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><form><distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 556</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170113">January 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000567">Mr. Lance</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Administrator of the Federal Highway Administration to make an exception to the Manual on Uniform Traffic Control Devices to allow for certain colored markings between longitudinal parallel lines for celebratory or ceremonial purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB5FD3EF15E72416392623EEA96A3B457" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HBB2775D2F546446BB9BC1E25CB5AB0B6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Blue Line Use Exception Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote>BLUE Act of 2017</quote>. </text></section> <section id="HA35EBF3412F2432494858F0C8BB38BDE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Manual on Uniform Traffic Control Devices exception</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any provision in the Manual on Uniform Traffic Control Devices relating to the space between parallel longitudinal lines on roads or the color of line markings, the Administrator of the Federal Highway Administration shall grant an exception to allow for the use of colored markings in the space between longitudinal parallel lines for ceremonial or celebratory purposes if the State transportation department (as defined in section 101 of title 23, United States Code) of the State where such markings are to be used approves of such use. </text> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

