<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE03EE70C1BF4429BBEB9B5DB836E3DFB" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2207 IH: Community College to Career Fund Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2207</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170427">April 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000127">Mr. Nolan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000799">Mr. Walz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000465">Ms. Tsongas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000563">Mr. Lipinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000535">Mr. Gutiérrez</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act to support community college and industry
			 partnerships, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H727D289B8C354BA191AC49C5F402E5C7" style="OLC">
 <section id="HA48969B00F454FBAA89087286811C749" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Community College to Career Fund Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HD139364936D44AA2B1AA2791DB6768E1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Community College to Career Fund</header> <subsection id="H2951C9773D654EA398CE09B6E617C376"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title I of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3111">29 U.S.C. 3111</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HADCF8ED1ACB2477DB518FD67F79714A2" style="OLC">
					<subtitle id="H2DCA145EAE8C4E718FCB40B39085A13E"><enum>F</enum><header>Community College to Career Fund</header>
						<section id="H384F26B71B69462B959B5527998FC97C"><enum>199.</enum><header>Community college and industry partnerships program</header>
 <subsection id="H63961C592CFA447B9F8C0A2F662A1407"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the end of the first full fiscal year after the date of enactment of the Community College to Career Fund Act, from funds appropriated under section 199A, the Secretary of Labor (in coordination with the Secretary of Education and the Secretary of Commerce) shall award competitive grants to eligible entities described in subsection (b) for the purpose of developing, offering, improving, and providing educational or career training programs for workers. The grants shall be awarded for periods of 3 years.</text>
							</subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H5B6E59F710B74D56A5FEFADD1BFD4D27"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header>
								<paragraph id="HE28F34731A1C4C7494C3C3F4CE0018C8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Partnerships with employers or an employer or industry partnership</header>
 <subparagraph id="HC3BCB7E9B76B45278088AFBA46FB422B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>General definition</header><text>For purposes of this section, an <quote>eligible entity</quote> means any of the entities described in subparagraph (B) (or a consortium of any of such entities) in partnership with employers or an employer or industry partnership representing multiple employers.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CDEC8C8DECE466DAAD421BC02A1A713"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Description of entities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The entities described in this subparagraph are—</text> <clause id="H79A3207B659E47AB9A217BD3E2E8B4B4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a community college;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB50DE7E452AC431D966CCA71F6F144F6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a 4-year public institution of higher education (as defined in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>)) that offers 2-year degrees, and that will use funds provided under this section for activities at the certificate and associate degree levels;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD71B97961535434C9B73CD3F2FEE1B6B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a Tribal College or University (as defined in section 316(b) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059c">20 U.S.C. 1059c(b)</external-xref>)); or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3D2B8542F7BC4265A64D0343F2C5C652"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a public or private nonprofit, 2-year institution of higher education (as defined in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>)) in the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, the United States Virgin Islands, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, or the Republic of Palau.</text>
										</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6E1830C531945918DEF59BD0063B839"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional Partners</header>
 <subparagraph id="HC2971C0941B74343A185CE1116608CEB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Authorization of additional partners</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to partnering with employers or an employer or industry partnership representing multiple employers as described in paragraph (1)(A), an entity described in paragraph (1) may include in the partnership described in paragraph (1) one or more of the organizations described in subparagraph (B). Each eligible entity that includes one or more such organizations shall collaborate with the State or local board in the area served by the eligible entity.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1CCA99A2ADA047C8B8CEAB6511E97BFB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Organizations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The organizations described in this subparagraph are as follows:</text> <clause id="H07CBF43EA2E74FFEA28C8B971E9496CF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A provider of adult education (as defined in section 203) or an institution of higher education (as defined in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>)).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3D67FD0C3B9949339784698FECB8F334"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A community-based organization.</text> </clause><clause id="HFA791A032A664273B00C00B538AA5E03"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A joint labor-management partnership.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H61F0B9BC5A23496BACEAAD4702EC42FC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A State board.</text> </clause><clause id="H84116D28988D4D1C896981D0ACBF8218"><enum>(v)</enum><text>An elementary school or secondary school, as defined in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB01FA364D4C44E2ABAAFF0B19E384BDB"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Any other organization that the Secretaries consider appropriate.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9B775D2D20CC4DD6826208692F7C95A8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Educational or career training program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the Governor of the State in which at least 1 of the entities described in subsection (b)(1)(B) of an eligible entity is located shall establish criteria for an educational or career training program leading to a recognized postsecondary credential for which an eligible entity submits a grant proposal under subsection (d).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2C24DAC97D674A09A761DF7FF33A4A76"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity seeking a grant under this section shall submit an application containing a grant proposal, for an educational or career training program leading to a recognized postsecondary credential, to the Secretaries at such time and containing such information as the Secretaries determine is required, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="HAFFD1AA610E74CB8B0270C36D802F5A1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a detailed description of—</text> <subparagraph id="HE20DE2DA18354666BEF2A6AF17772DEC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the extent to which the educational or career training program described in the grant proposal fits within an overall strategic plan consisting of—</text>
 <clause id="H05E7EAEC7C6F43C2A51234B3E91CACE0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the State plan described in section 102 or 103, for the State involved;</text> </clause><clause id="H100904D7E1784D07ACEB7A8A4C90818A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the local plan described in section 108, for each local area that comprises a significant portion of the area to be served by the eligible entity; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7472837D37A344BB979438155D64871E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a strategic plan developed by the eligible entity;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H99CDAE359F03431587770F7994BD6199"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the extent to which the program will meet the needs of employers in the area for skilled workers in in-demand industry sectors and occupations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5E7A02E73374D89AB32EE300DECC0A8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the extent to which the program will meet the educational or career training needs of workers in the area;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E4C616AE06A4BA2BBB48A03FE217F07"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the specific educational or career training program and how the program meets the criteria established under subsection (e), including the manner in which the grant will be used to develop, offer, improve, and provide the educational or career training program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE6911106153D4AA9AA795D2889B94936"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any previous experience of the eligible entity in providing educational or career training programs, the absence of which shall not automatically disqualify an eligible institution from receiving a grant under this section; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB99D85DAE0FD4B4C9A94D65399D5F822"><enum>(F)</enum><text>how the program leading to the credential meets the criteria described in subsection (c); and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H63EAE2E3731C425BA17E673DAA207976"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a detailed plan on how the entity will ensure that the program will meet the performance measures described in subsection (g), and an assurance that the entity will annually submit to the Secretary information on the performance of the program on the performance measures described in subsection (g).</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2334304D5F20478CBCBA97220C481489"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Criteria for award</header>
 <paragraph id="HCC10F818B2F049C7ADAA835B2844CF07"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Grants under this section shall be awarded based on criteria established by the Secretaries, that include the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB6A90B70347348FAA08B569695E8223E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A determination of the merits of the grant proposal submitted by the eligible entity involved to develop, offer, improve, and provide an educational or career training program to be made available to workers.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H07E8EA05F61B402E8707C244F8CD5021"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An assessment of the likely employment opportunities available in the area to individuals who complete an educational or career training program that the eligible entity proposes to develop, offer, improve, and provide.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78E5D0AA220C491B9305A82C85AB8E77"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An assessment of prior demand for training programs by individuals eligible for training and served by the eligible entity, as well as availability and capacity of existing (as of the date of the assessment) training programs to meet future demand for training programs.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H94CD44388C4543FA98E1E2871BDCE1A4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants under this section, the Secretaries shall give priority to eligible entities that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8FBA226F0997425599D5A411226E84D5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>include a partnership, with employers or an employer or industry partnership, that—</text> <clause id="H7201315D3E2F4171881F26A35C59F59C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>pays a portion of the costs of educational or career training programs; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H46368901F1D047A8957D893943A0BAEC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>agrees to hire individuals who have attained a recognized postsecondary credential resulting from the educational or career training program of the eligible entity;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA2DE29E13B08428C94611B94F92DDA12"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enter into a partnership with a labor organization or labor-management training program to provide, through the program, technical expertise for occupationally specific education necessary for a recognized postsecondary credential leading to a skilled occupation in an in-demand industry sector;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8BDB46A094574D37ADB9EBC235A6B59E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>are focused on serving individuals with barriers to employment, students who are veterans, spouses of members of the Armed Forces, incumbent workers who are low-skilled and who need to increase their work-related skills;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE82A479F2FF24B85907F3E8DD8E138E0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>include any eligible entities serving areas with high unemployment rates; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0BA9507A8F0F488FAAC2E99089BC511B"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are eligible entities that include an institution of higher education eligible for assistance under title III or V of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1051">20 U.S.C. 1051</external-xref> et seq.; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1101">20 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD46FAD37452248C4921814A10929CAEE"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Grant funds awarded under this section shall be used for one or more of the following:</text> <paragraph id="H65C012338BCE421FB54926AE7A85B418"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The development, offering, improvement, and provision of educational or career training programs, that provide relevant job training for skilled occupations, that lead to recognized postsecondary credentials, that will meet the needs of employers in in-demand industry sectors, and that may include registered apprenticeship programs, on-the-job training programs, and programs that support employers in upgrading the skills of their workforce.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H75B34F4FF2474A32B833E0D610327070"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The development and implementation of policies and programs to expand opportunities for students to earn a recognized postsecondary credential, including a degree, in in-demand industry sectors and occupations, including by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7879960CFE804FE5AE7B74D7E0AB4FC1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>facilitating the transfer of academic credits between institutions of higher education, including the transfer of academic credits for courses in the same field of study;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H319D8E75931D408995515842D583B675"><enum>(B)</enum><text>expanding articulation agreements and policies that guarantee transfers between such institutions, including through common course numbering and use of a general core curriculum;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7AF21709A0F4A93BAF99A6AC2AA3412"><enum>(C)</enum><text>developing or enhancing student support services programs; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23ABAEBD48EC4CD3A84B0FDE6D58CF5D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>establishing policies and processes for assessing and awarding course credit for work-related learning.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA63D34D03875478F96D8BF447904BBE9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The creation of career pathway programs that provide a sequence of education and occupational training that leads to a recognized postsecondary credential, including a degree, including programs that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H83E5C09B441745C5A9B9B01B8BE6A10D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>blend basic skills and occupational training;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7C8D38CB286447194171DC6D07B28FF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilitate means of transitioning participants from non-credit occupational, basic skills, or developmental coursework to for-credit coursework within and across institutions;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4AF269669A3B408D98AEA024C10DED37"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">build or enhance linkages, including the development of dual enrollment programs and early college high schools, between secondary education or adult education programs (including programs established under the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2301">20 U.S.C. 2301</external-xref> et seq.) and title II of this Act);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5C72D117B5541CC8EB0E167F8FD633A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>are innovative programs designed to increase the provision of training for students, including students who are members of the National Guard or Reserves, to enter skilled occupations in in-demand industry sectors;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6620726E7C1848CDBBEC26FA5EACB49C"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support paid internships that will allow students to simultaneously earn credit for work-based learning and gain relevant employment experience in an in-demand industry sector or occupation, which shall include opportunities that transition individuals into employment; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3CF147667B2A4E3BBD050BE24F2786C3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>develop competency-based education programs that offer an outcome-oriented approach through which recognized postsecondary credentials are awarded based on successful demonstration of skills and proficiency.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDDEA206EA54F4408992D10CD861DE318"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The development and implementation of—</text> <subparagraph id="H931E8D4A7AD1474C989D931A5927ABCF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a Pay-for-Performance program that leads to a recognized postsecondary credential, for which an eligible entity agrees to be reimbursed under the grant primarily on the basis of achievement of specified performance outcomes and criteria agreed to by the Secretary; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H423A2C0F5FFF42A4848EAAB7998E0606"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a Pay-for-Success program that leads to a recognized postsecondary credential, for which an eligible entity—</text>
 <clause id="H38F52E9BDD0B45AD8FC79DA867F5B5C5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>enters into a partnership with an investor, such as a philanthropic organization that provides funding for a specific project to address a clear and measurable educational or career training need in the area to be served under the grant; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFA2A06D74A234912B31EB6305E24F695"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>agrees to be reimbursed under the grant only if the project achieves specified performance outcomes and criteria agreed to by the Secretary.</text>
										</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD36407C6D6A3453790382E2B41A032B2"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Performance measures</header>
 <paragraph id="H5E7BEA7B6BB5473EBE6644D146D03D95"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish performance measures for the programs carried out under this section.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBEDBA1F38C8C4397820BB11EF1519EC1"><enum>(2)</enum><header> Measures</header><text>The performance measures shall consist of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H958616512B3442CA86CDF7C250360211"><enum>(A)</enum><text>indicators of performance, including the number of program participants who are in unsubsidized employment during the second quarter after exit from the program; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E547ADC195D4928868E96DEA24BE225"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a level of performance for each indicator described in subparagraph (A).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HBCE09FC08D2A48F38BCE065F14254F5A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Monitoring progress</header><text>The Secretary shall monitor the progress of eligible entities that receive grants under this section in ensuring that their programs meet the performance measures.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H32CDBA615529492EBD2E92BD5CAA5BC3"><enum>199A.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <subsection id="H3DA4B2E8726F4E39A82EDD57C4B32BBC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out the program established by section 199. Funds appropriated under this subsection shall remain available until the end of the 5th full fiscal year after the date of enactment of the Community College to Career Fund Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0D623290B9E7475BB961E0A6D7EE6D8C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administrative Cost</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not more than 5 percent of the amounts made available under subsection (a) may be used by the Secretaries for Federal administration of the program described in that subsection, including providing technical assistance and carrying out evaluations for the program described in that subsection.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0C5D1F4D0871444486C3E67A49326CCF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Period of availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The funds appropriated pursuant to subsection (a) for a fiscal year shall be available for Federal obligation for that fiscal year and the succeeding 4 fiscal years.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HFED324F61DF142B6AF7C2B7A1030AAF1"><enum>199B.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this subtitle:</text> <paragraph id="HA422FD2E8C6C4A959A5050422052B2AE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Community College</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>community college</term> has the meaning given the term <quote>junior or community college</quote> in section 312(f) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1058">20 U.S.C. 1058(f)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB846892F06BA4E0B830D19DDCD28E136"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Educational or career training program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>educational or career training program</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H01099293A1184251BD7A1E816D0B6AAE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a career pathway program, as defined in section 3; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD0ABDBFEC7F435892C92F54950B9333"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a program with an integrated education and training approach, as defined in section 203.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></subtitle><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H0FC334B44FC840B2A59AFFC1F74A8423"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act is amended by inserting after the items relating to subtitle E of title I the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA8D825F870074EB1A6969ECD431C78FF" style="OLC">
					<toc>
						<toc-entry idref="H2DCA145EAE8C4E718FCB40B39085A13E" level="subtitle">Subtitle F—Community College to Career Fund</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry idref="H384F26B71B69462B959B5527998FC97C" level="section">Sec. 199. Community college and industry partnerships program.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry idref="H32CDBA615529492EBD2E92BD5CAA5BC3" level="section">Sec. 199A. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry idref="HFED324F61DF142B6AF7C2B7A1030AAF1" level="section">Sec. 199B. Definitions.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA1C6FF7937684D70BFBC88ABC0B65DE2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This Act, including the amendments made by this Act, takes effect as if included in the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


