<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCD1EC33B278F488C8CB0FBA6EECCE325" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2928 IH: To direct the Secretary of Transportation to issue regulations to require air carriers to disclose to consumers the actual wheels-off and wheels-on times for certain domestic passenger flight segments, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2928</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170615">June 15, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001165">Mr. Sires</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Transportation to issue regulations to require air carriers to disclose
			 to consumers the actual wheels-off and wheels-on times for certain
			 domestic passenger flight segments, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HCE688EA9AFF84C0681CC00BDFD6DE050" style="OLC">
		<section id="HB711DF35206E46E7A9F8F5BFC0F0F45D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Consumer information on actual flight times</header>
 <subsection id="H89BF6D36AE424C93ADE9A602D5C2821F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Transportation shall modify regulations contained in section 234.11 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, to ensure that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8B3D5BF904CC4BADB13256591A92AB91"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a reporting carrier (including its contractors), during the course of a reservation or ticketing discussion or other inquiry, discloses to a consumer upon reasonable request the projected period between the actual wheels-off and wheels-on times for a reportable flight; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H42183BE83D9D4B9DA2998270886A4143"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a reporting carrier displays, on the public internet website of the carrier, information on the actual wheels-off and wheels-on times during the most recent calendar month for a reportable flight.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4E50F31A54984AFEA87AC77FE128B029"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the terms <quote>reporting carrier</quote> and <quote>reportable flight</quote> have the meanings given those terms in section 234.2 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act).</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


