<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H6658058DC9C7419DB466403DA8C0E776" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4435 IH: Go to High School, Go to College Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4435</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171116">November 16, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000464">Mr. Faso</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000455">Ms. Fudge</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000625">Mr. Donovan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000602">Miss Rice of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001187">Mr. Stivers</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000380">Mr. Kildee</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to allow the Secretary of Education to award Early
			 College Federal Pell Grants.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H54C42CE86C6D47CA83A03AB7AF956339" style="OLC">
 <section id="H52A424ADFDBB4D73BC147B105695E738" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Go to High School, Go to College Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HAE770E3116DB47C4A94EA8250F7B0DAA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Early College Federal Pell Grant</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 401 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a">20 U.S.C. 1070a</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="HDD15D6EBFC9E4E1F8B3AA4B6724DD29D" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="H523620165B834C2ABA8FECB5E4492C2C"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Early College Federal Pell Grants</header>
 <paragraph id="HAEF39DEA820C48FBB4B956A173A46B11"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding the requirement under section 484(a)(1) that a student not been enrolled in an elementary or secondary school to be eligible to receive a Federal Pell Grant under this section, for the award years beginning on July 1, 2017, and ending on June 30, 2023, the Secretary shall carry out a program to award Early College Federal Pell Grants to eligible students to support enrollment in, and completion of, postsecondary courses offered through an early college high school.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD6DCD57FA8E34E73884027A95C520C39"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Maximum period for Early College Federal Pell Grants</header><text>An eligible student may receive an Early College Federal Pell Grant under this subsection in an amount equal to the cost of not more than 4 full-time postsecondary semesters, or the equivalent of 4 full-time postsecondary semesters, as determined by the Secretary by regulation, while enrolled in postsecondary courses offered by an early college high school.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H846A6DF9E63F4AD8941BFEA2FE230003"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Counting of awards for purposes of Federal Pell Grants</header>
 <subparagraph id="H7B44791E8D7141DA852137CF87C3789D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An Early College Federal Pell Grant received under this subsection shall be counted toward the maximum period for which a student may receive Federal Pell Grants under this section, as provided under subsection (c)(5).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA2E9E5D1F6D14F1EBFC18FA6D7398EC8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may waive the requirement under subparagraph (A) on a case-by-case basis for any student demonstrating evidence of a credible disruption or redirection in course of study necessitating additional time to complete a postsecondary degree or credential.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6E779FFF2BC4F46886BF54D18C9BD87"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header>
 <subparagraph id="H961C67C80AEB43FBBD1A7BEB256F96D9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in this subsection, an Early College Federal Pell Grant received under this subsection shall have the same terms and conditions, and be awarded in the same manner, as Federal Pell Grants awarded under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97009954C45E4082AFB68243C0D3A77B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Minimum completion</header><text>An eligible student may only receive an Early College Federal Pell Grant under this subsection upon completion of a full-time postsecondary semester, or the equivalent of a full-time postsecondary semester, as determined by the Secretary by regulation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H42FCA36333F243DDB118BDFC94E0AFF5"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Amount</header><text>The Secretary shall pay an eligible institution that is engaged in a partnership as part of an early college high school an amount equal to the cost of tuition, fees, and books for each postsecondary course (including with respect to the postsecondary courses completed to satisfy the requirement under subparagraph (B)) an eligible student completes through such early college high school, provided such eligible student satisfies the requirement under subparagraph (B).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3DB170A12BB24C74AB29D5FE72DB7EDD"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>Each early college high school shall annually submit to the Secretary a report on the program of postsecondary courses provided to eligible students that includes the following information that is reported for all eligible students and disaggregated by each student subgroup of eligible students:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE4D3C59D8D724B13A2F5ACA9419C0C9A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Total number and percentage of eligible students who enroll in and subsequently complete the program at the early college high school.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5BA2B3D9BDC7467B911E475B564C85D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The number of postsecondary credits earned by eligible students while enrolled in the early college high school that may be applied toward a postsecondary degree or credential program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5DB9DF8BC5D94E9CB8C436D661CBBC3F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The percentage of eligible students enrolled in the early college high school who concurrently earn a secondary school diploma and an associate degree or equivalent.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28A066D5BE6442D6927C62722971638F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The percentage of early college high school graduates completing the program who enroll in a postsecondary institution.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H633A234F5B964EA2B6F668B675F54073"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The total amount of Early College Federal Pell Grants awarded to eligible students served by the early college high school.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA31CBEB902234191AC8ED598E3718F90"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="H704C3F2BB42B4D7495D520AEABCD49FB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Early college high school</header><text>The term <term>early college high school</term> has the meaning given the term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE5BB1D9424694D19802E3436811A39F4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligible institution</header><text>The term <term>eligible institution</term> means an institution that—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HD26E7E1468D4456EA9C87D5C28E5FD19"><enum>(i)</enum><text>complies with the existing requirements of being an eligible institution under this title; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H4A0C643644F447CA97F05C4CB9231E26"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>demonstrates that it—</text> <subclause commented="no" id="HC5CE72B1133A4883B389BBD1A413EBE2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is participating in a statewide articulation agreement;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HCDB12DE462134FF5B80E197E38E89399"><enum>(II)</enum><text>has an articulation agreement in place with at least one public institution of higher education; or</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H2486C673FEED42898FEF7D6D65A231BF"><enum>(III)</enum><text>has a track record of students successfully transferring credits earned at the institution to public institutions of higher education.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8608C7FF2E6C46B6B6BA1C83A63CD685"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Eligible student</header><text>The term <quote>eligible student</quote> means a student enrolled at an early college high school who, if such student met the requirements of section 484 for eligibility for a Federal Pell Grant, would be awarded a Federal Pell Grant after the determination of the expected family contribution for such student.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8FD2C77CF4FA4F669C0C4D96C61A479F"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Student subgroup</header><text>The term <term>student subgroup</term> means—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H4FFD929CEE8245D0851ECA0BA61BFB38"><enum>(i)</enum><text>economically disadvantaged students;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H387478B78AA847539834771257EF0D7D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>students from major racial and ethnic groups;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H3B3AA72BA9994517B680F9256B57E2C2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>children with disabilities; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HDE07ED7D101148AEB199274C8424E42D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>English learners.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section></legis-body></bill> 

