<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB6E188DE02104B26AED397811ABE3763" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3167 IH: Debt Ceiling Alternative Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3167</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170706">July 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001183">Mr. Schweikert</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001187">Mr. Meadows</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000449">Mr. Fortenberry</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">the Budget</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide that, in the event that the Secretary of the Treasury estimates that the debt ceiling
			 will be reached, the Secretary is required to issue GDP-linked bonds to
			 pay the principal and interest on the public debt and the President is
			 authorized to request the rescission of certain unobligated balances and
			 sell certain mortgage-related assets, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H164B331965434F8C9B92A9160AAE33B1" style="OLC">
 <section id="H0C15F9C3BA884CC4AFEBDBBD3DC9157E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Debt Ceiling Alternative Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HBE194BA3CB7B4A31A1404EC9177C4953"><enum>2.</enum><header>Estimate that borrowing will reach the statutory debt limit</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If the Secretary of the Treasury makes an estimate of net marketable borrowing for a quarter that estimates that the debt of the United States, as defined in section 3101 of title 31, United States Code, will reach the statutory limit during such quarter, the Secretary shall immediately notify Congress of such estimate, and the Secretary of the Treasury shall issue bonds described under section 3 and the President may take the actions described under sections 4 and 5.</text>
		</section><section id="H0FBE4BD61CBA4B799962D95BDF452407"><enum>3.</enum><header>Issuance of GDP-linked bonds to pay the principal and interest on the public debt</header>
 <subsection id="HEAA7882033B846A2BDD19625902D4752"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the issuance of a notification to Congress under section 2, the Secretary of the Treasury shall issue bonds—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFA9B2A8D5C7B43E5BDD66E5BFB01EE06"><enum>(1)</enum><text>with an interest rate linked to the nominal gross domestic product of the United States; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4C00D3C874B74FA78FD5239FFA53B817"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the proceeds from which may only be used to pay the principal and interest on obligations of the United States held by the public or the Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and Disability Insurance Trust Fund.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCC10AFFB932B4AF2B68AC38E65E43D82"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Obligations exempt from public debt limit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Obligations issued under subsection (a) shall not be taken into account in applying the limitation in section 3101(b) of title 31, United States Code, to the extent that such obligation would otherwise cause the limitation in section 3101(b) of title 31, United States Code, to be exceeded.</text>
			</subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HA48D3384DBDD43C2BF09686C28DA0535"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report on certain actions</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H481766CE21A141FBA8B78C71BC28E9C7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Secretary of the Treasury issues bonds under subsection (a), the Secretary shall thereafter submit a report each week, until all such bonds are redeemed, providing an accounting relating to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H531E80D3478C4AACAD9C07A630B960F7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the principal on mature obligations and interest that is due or accrued of the United States; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE86A19461C484338B46A445D27D9C5AD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any bonds issued pursuant to subsection (a).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H5275B1D8B215482998DAEC77630F560D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall be submitted to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H01689C54FC614F50A6C1CF64BA5671BE"><enum>4.</enum><header>Rescission of unobligated balances</header>
 <subsection id="HDAD3573B94514996B9DC0F2CAC7B999D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Identification of unobligated balances</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the issuance of a notification under section 2, the President may issue a message to Congress containing a list of budget authority proposed to be rescinded. Such list may only contain items related to unobligated balances of funds made available before the beginning of the fiscal year during which such notification is made.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0833FF9E2FE4478B9F2A19959003A8A3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Expedited consideration of rescissions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A message issued pursuant to subsection (a) shall be deemed a special message for purposes of the expedited procedures described under section 1017 of the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/688">2 U.S.C. 688</external-xref>).</text>
			</subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H49B4E9CBB2904E1F9CE3422400438CFE"><enum>5.</enum><header>Sale of mortgage-related assets</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Upon the issuance of a notification to Congress under section 2, the President may order the sale of the following assets, with the proceeds from such sales deposited in the Treasury:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H9F05E614AB8641978DB2CFF8EED8E259"><enum>(1)</enum><text>On-balance sheet non-performing mortgages of the Federal National Mortgage Association.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2147671853E94FD1A545E03EF4257088"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Other mortgages owned or held by the Federal National Mortgage Association.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE984CF788FAF41F58C63C9C0D1FFEF80"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Real estate owned properties of the Federal National Mortgage Association.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H9FC14E55CC91468C81A269EA670B2AB4"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On-balance sheet non-performing mortgages of the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3969B5F7B172451393BDEABEB22553F9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Other mortgages owned or held by the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H89A283B0D93349B993CAA9937E498F0F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Real estate owned properties of the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2D695F664BE44EB1A8F557AB70015F12"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Mortgage-backed securities held by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System or any Federal reserve bank.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


