<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0146FD3C943E4A47BF3DD4F16715BE30" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><form><distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 859</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170203">February 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prevent conflicts of interest that stem from executive Government employees receiving bonuses or other compensation arrangements from nongovernment sources, from the revolving door that raises concerns about the independence of financial services regulators, and from the revolving door that casts aspersions over the awarding of Government contracts and other financial benefits.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBDA21B7DC6AA4C9D9D2A97B585F43A24" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8CC9310751D2410FB1FAE840CD556246" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Financial Services Conflict of Interest Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H2B6C9B8D12554C61923592A75346E03F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Restrictions on private sector payment for Government service</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 209 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC18631A241E2410F8E39FE4D5691CC1C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="HFD567383B26B4D95864DEA5877580176"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>any salary</quote> and inserting <quote>any bonus or salary</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA9068CB1DAC147AAAD660F574A78EE1C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>his services</quote> and inserting <quote>services rendered or to be rendered</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAAF0606E1B104659A617F5C84E3FD7ED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H72E76766A52F4919B0E5CB2C2FF3A14D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(1)</quote> after <quote>(b)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC84D0F97763C4556A377C56F100EE175"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCEC799A172E942C49236EA2F719F90E8" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="HD3AF4E5B9DAC47D18923BFF28C00C778" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), a pension, retirement, group life, health or accident insurance, profit-sharing, stock bonus, or other employee welfare or benefit plan that makes payment of compensation contingent on accepting a position in the Federal Government shall not be considered bona fide.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBFE296BBA2B448B8BE9057205615FAF0" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>For purposes of paragraph (2), compensation includes a retention award or bonus, severance pay, and any other payment linked to future service in the Federal Government in any way.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H8C46CD14FF59412A91A6598F933F31F3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Requirements relating to slowing the revolving door among financial services regulators</header> 
<subsection id="H2D17A3A2AA254E3BA99942D216136770"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA5916A02AFF04052AF0170C707FF9929" style="OLC"> <title id="H2FD07CBB75BB46A9A788C6B5A81D3087"><enum>VI</enum><header>Special requirements for financial services regulators</header> <section id="H2D2B467DBBAB4F27BD590B67992764DE"><enum>601.</enum><header>Definitions</header> <subsection id="H15316E3C37274A22BCE5FEFCE006490F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In this title, the terms <term>designated agency ethics official</term> and <term>executive branch</term> have the meanings given those terms under section 109.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1E899EC9654445EE9D6AEB5822736CF1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Other definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this title:</text> <paragraph id="HCEC1E1B2257949E38045F91EF93FDA49"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered financial services agency</header><text>The term <term>covered financial services agency</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB8C4CDB007DD49DCB89C7CABBA155474"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a primary financial regulatory agency (as defined in section 2 of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5301">12 U.S.C. 5301</external-xref>)); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6B2F5EDF95EB44459446C49EE5CFE269"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes—</text> 
<clause id="H5D3DDBA29556415082395660DC6946DB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System;</text></clause> <clause id="H5C0572AD15344B0B94849C05438A4C89"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB4BE867AC3B14D779CED6882035A780C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation;</text></clause> <clause id="H9D458BE0A1764CD487860CF1CA186413"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the National Credit Union Administration;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H64A678685C9744229CB74304F9DF44DF"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the Securities and Exchange Commission;</text></clause> <clause id="H5589E2E7C770432789913984C90A5796"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the Federal Housing Finance Agency;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD677FB35E8214859A5C03AB09A3A6D80"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection;</text></clause> <clause id="HF7BA71DE69B14A17BC20519E734976BB"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the Commodity Futures Trading Commission;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6AFC524FEC624E56B3538F513A779269"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>the Department of the Treasury;</text></clause> <clause id="H81710BBB6944408C963D5D2B3DA78988"><enum>(x)</enum><text>the National Economic Council; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA6A48AC07F774AAEB7C21C561BEE5B74"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>the Council of Economic Advisors.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBD776A5666F24A82A14BF677B9920BF0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered financial services regulator</header><text>The term <term>covered financial services regulator</term> means an officer or employee of a covered financial services agency who occupies—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1E3288C9E1364E2683B7CF7789844B12"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a supervisory position classified above GS–15 of the General Schedule;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEB1728AAFECE46E498561874E3865E7B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a position not under the General Schedule, a supervisory position for which the rate of basic pay is not less than 120 percent of the minimum rate of basic pay for GS–15 of the General Schedule; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE7FC2AACEF254963A6AD7916EE6F7A3D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other supervisory position determined to be of equal classification by the Director.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE158543A8BE74C9B8FFC9CD353DEADEF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Office of Government Ethics.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFC480ABBFE1F4366942716AD930586AB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Former client</header><text>The term <term>former client</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="HE868D0C772E9463EB5ADB1DD8117C339"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a person for whom a covered financial services regulator served personally as an agent, attorney, or consultant during the 2-year period ending on the date (after such service) on which the covered financial services regulator begins service in the Federal Government; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8FC34B1EA2A440D68A12C0DE215D2797"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include—</text> <clause id="H5603CA3C25BC40C79EA076A649FF0544"><enum>(i)</enum><text>instances in which the service provided was limited to a speech or similar appearance; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6144F8C48CB441E9A0CF0464A6EE5D1A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a client of the former employer of the covered financial services regulator to whom the covered financial services regulator did not personally provide such services.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDC7BD030AFAE4BD4AFC19975FE81D5FE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Former employer</header><text>The term <term>former employer</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HAE7941A592914641AFD82310898833BB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a person for whom a covered financial services regulator served as an employee, officer, director, trustee, or general partner during the 2-year period ending on the date (after such service) on which the covered financial services regulator begins service in the Federal Government; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD4A190DFAD7E43FE93744415746C7943"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include—</text> 
<clause id="HB4E3FFA81E4E42C48047B15197C34DA7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an entity in the Federal Government, including an executive branch agency;</text></clause> <clause id="H1CB339AF95474106A99255356CACAE4F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a State or local government;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4E693E761CF8480690679E4955D5AF07"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the District of Columbia;</text></clause> <clause id="HB8D587EACC204B50AF2D00A31070498F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an Indian tribe, as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>); or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HEEF767E9FE61471CB5F11D46C6B48060"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the government of a territory or possession of the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H7F25EDD8E07F4197A6076FC218403BC0"><enum>602.</enum><header>Conflict of interest and eligibility standards for financial services regulators</header> <subsection id="HC5532B51F6974A93B1AFD69167FF57DA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A covered financial services regulator shall not make, participate in making, or in any way attempt to use the official position of the covered financial services regulator to influence a particular matter that provides a direct and substantial pecuniary benefit for a former employer or former client of the covered financial services regulator.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1624DFEF7B474921A8901E720AB13310"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Recusal</header><text>A covered financial services regulator shall recuse himself or herself from any official action that would violate subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H80D30BEBB9A247D2A6AF9C495FB304B8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver</header> <paragraph id="HEF4939D4565F40119C6D8E4CC0005D6B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The head of the covered financial services agency employing a covered financial services regulator, in consultation with the Director, may grant a written waiver of the restrictions under subsection (a) if, and to the extent that, the head of the covered financial services agency certifies in writing that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD5E05FE553E043469991BAA5A3433490"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the application of the restriction to the particular matter is inconsistent with the purposes of the restriction; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H23CCA288FB1743C9B29B9C0B0F9FCFB2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>it is in the public interest to grant the waiver.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAF98B8444DE241ACBB1FBC6C36C8C3AF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>The Director shall make each waiver under paragraph (1) publicly available on the Web site of the Office of Government Ethics.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H32ECDE0F333548128A3E63CF99EB5C75"><enum>603.</enum><header>Negotiating future private sector employment</header> <subsection id="HF8A50A6F5F4249DDADDD94C74B881F30"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (c), and notwithstanding any other provision of law, a covered financial services regulator may not participate in any particular matter which involves, to the knowledge of the covered financial services regulator, an individual or entity with whom the covered financial services regulator is in negotiations of future employment or has an arrangement concerning prospective employment.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5753389339A441C3AB7C5074D68B15D3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Disclosure of employment negotiations</header> 
<paragraph id="H13137980371D43DC9202AEED5F48D0A5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a covered financial services regulator begins any negotiations of future employment with another person, or an agent or intermediary of another person, or other discussion or communication with another person, or an agent or intermediary of another person, mutually conducted with a view toward reaching an agreement regarding possible employment of the covered financial services regulator, the covered financial services regulator shall notify the designated agency ethics official of the covered financial services agency employing the covered financial services regulator regarding the negotiations, discussions, or communications.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H21B300EDBCB543648EEF309D5A73E378"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information</header><text>A designated agency ethics official receiving notice under paragraph (1), after consultation with the Director, shall inform the covered financial services regulator of any potential conflicts of interest involved in any negotiations, discussions, or communications with the other person and the applicable prohibitions.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H054BD77DA2E44C8EBA567D8B96F24A16"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waivers only when exceptional circumstances exist</header> 
<paragraph id="H8B8F1ADF9DC242E29EBF04B9ECA1EB0A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The head of a covered financial services agency may only grant a waiver of the prohibition under subsection (a) if the head determines that exceptional circumstances exist.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCB4AADDE593644AB911ED49F34EA3EEC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review and publication</header><text>For any waiver granted under paragraph (1), the Director shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5D5C09275E294AD5ACE4146CDB08C3FA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>review the circumstances relating to the waiver and the determination that exceptional circumstances exist; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H677B16CAB7D54D5F9E8962F6DE5782F3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make the waiver publicly available on the Web site of the Office of Government Ethics, which shall include—</text> 
<clause id="H77FDE3E96E744EF9A8EDDE7ED9CDF13D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the name of the private person or persons involved in the negotiations or arrangement concerning prospective employment; and</text></clause> <clause id="HD84803A3EA4443D79F4B2D3EC1A1EA19"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the date on which the negotiations or arrangements commenced.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H44F33332EC634CE98AFBFA95D428910B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Scope</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>negotiations of future employment</term> is not limited to discussions of specific terms or conditions of employment in a specific position.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H02C37A62AC4B458BAC2B5CC1E2BF64A4"><enum>604.</enum><header>Recordkeeping</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Director shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE4059DB668614A798F2D86625FAC0015"><enum>(1)</enum><text>receive all employment histories, recusal and waiver records, and other disclosure records for covered executive branch officials necessary for monitoring compliance with this title;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H81C87F1409764EC58366C8B1B8FD1776"><enum>(2)</enum><text>promulgate rules and regulations, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Personnel Management and the Attorney General, to implement this title;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H14C327B54C004088B3CE23EACB15B680"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide guidance and assistance where appropriate to facilitate compliance with this title;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2ED02AD9E08D47A98AE2617A486930E1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>review and, where necessary, assist designated agency ethics officials in providing advice to covered financial services regulators regarding compliance with this title; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7704C29887FF4EDFB437DD1AC6CCDDCC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>if the Director determines that a violation of this title may have occurred, and in consultation with the designated agency ethics official and the Counsel to the President, refer the compliance case to the United States Attorney for the District of Columbia for enforcement action.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H46AAF732FEB848F7BC74DA9DA897AA54"><enum>605.</enum><header>Penalties and injunctions</header> <subsection id="H53F43D157D00497F87384C656C9BFD1E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Criminal penalties</header> <paragraph id="H95CD1599F9704DA48BF7E38DEC2ED398"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any person who violates section 602 or 603 shall be fined under title 18, United States Code, imprisoned for not more than 1 year, or both.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD1227FA9F6714E42BF47323B30D06D03"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Willful violations</header><text>Any person who willfully violates section 602 or 603 shall be fined under title 18, United States Code, imprisoned for not more than 5 years, or both.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4F70DB75538E40B7B37AD96737EDD702"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Civil enforcement</header> <paragraph id="HD77A75B13B5A4299BF3B61737E6D0CF6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General may bring a civil action in an appropriate district court of the United States against any person who violates, or whom the Attorney General has reason to believe is engaging in conduct that violates, section 602 or 603.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5C302913E929426FA969F03970C4AF33"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Civil penalty</header> 
<subparagraph id="H097508277E54472AB747EBFF2A509CDE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon proof by a preponderance of the evidence that a person violated section 602 or 603, the court shall impose a civil penalty of not more than the greater of—</text> <clause id="H6D4B9C87393C4CECAF2B5872FA5AE940"><enum>(i)</enum><text>$100,000 for each violation; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF998E66C1AC1400B9658F02FC9E61527"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount of compensation the person received or was offered for the conduct constituting the violation.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7D7E9565D1404321BEE939816C042234"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>A civil penalty under this subsection shall be in addition to any other criminal or civil statutory, common law, or administrative remedy available to the United States or any other person.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H807118999E5D46048DFA80E38B460A26"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Injunctive relief</header> 
<subparagraph id="H5F0BAB866EA9466D9E98606D8B793B06"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In a civil action brought under paragraph (1) against a person, the Attorney General may petition the court for an order prohibiting the person from engaging in conduct that violates section 602 or 603.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1C578FC9C98B41EB9EB438C74C0F4E31"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Standard</header><text>The court may issue an order under subparagraph (A) if the court finds by a preponderance of the evidence that the conduct of the person violates section 602 or 603.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD49462C3B9254641A5CB8E04670313EF"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>The filing of a petition seeking injunctive relief under this paragraph shall not preclude any other remedy that is available by law to the United States or any other person.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></title><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="H29C5DCFBF28C4A78B9EE1B1BD6E8296A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibition of procurement officers accepting employment from Government contractors</header> <subsection id="HA562972E46F344AAB48631C70154EA29"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Expansion of prohibition on acceptance by former officials of compensation from contractors</header><text>Section 2104 of title 41, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3E31E2B8C3D44B0593B915EFB61813FD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="HCD2CCDB3E37D4F51B5F6CC63089BF9B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1)—</text> 
<clause id="HB9FE1F7BFE3340188224503CC9B50B72"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or consultant</quote> and inserting <quote>consultant, lawyer, or lobbyist</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="H0EC9D3F0948A4D1B91DC37FF3DAF6639"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>one year</quote> and inserting <quote>2 years</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD47B0C5CC5814EEB9139C75C30B9CAC1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>personally made for the Federal agency</quote> and inserting <quote>participated personally and substantially in</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA8D6F169CFAC42DEA31413601BBF6595"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subsection (b) and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H992852D4F30E4F85A6FEABFC7BF33785" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H651CF9A0A7F540A3AA6D2364ED483E34"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on compensation from affiliates and subcontractors</header><text>A former official responsible for a Government contract referred to in paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of subsection (a) may not accept compensation for 2 years after awarding the contract from any division, affiliate, or subcontractor of the contractor.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC8E7C3DDD64F41F7B15243830DD41C87"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement for procurement officers To disclose job offers made on behalf of relatives</header><text>Section 2103(a) of title 41, United States Code, is amended in the matter preceding paragraph (1) by inserting after <quote>that official</quote> the following: <quote>, or for a relative (as defined in section 3110 of title 5) of that official,</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC9B997E5787F424CA26E8AF5A462FA68"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirement on award of Government contracts to former employers</header> 
<paragraph id="HF352C5CC1BD347A787D165DFA1FA1E07"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/41/21">Chapter 21</external-xref> of title 41, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC2DF63AA77A644638A206A12DD6B6F21" style="USC"> <section id="HA8068A2441474937BE6AA1CCF567AD20"><enum>2108.</enum><header>Prohibition on involvement by certain former contractor employees in procurements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">An employee of the Federal Government may not be personally and substantially involved with any award of a contract to, or the administration of a contract awarded to, a contractor that is a former employer of the employee during the 2-year period beginning on the date on which the employee leaves the employment of the contractor.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H17C98C391F3E44E59B5AB7A08EFA06E3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/41/21">chapter 21</external-xref> of title 41, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H5445D9C77FC7459CAA9431BA87E5BAB7" style="USC"> <toc> <toc-entry idref="HA8068A2441474937BE6AA1CCF567AD20" level="section">2108. Prohibition on involvement by certain former contractor employees in procurements.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H94453027AF924BD29AEED264E45A631F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Administrator for Federal Procurement Policy and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF5871E2EAFD5460B9BED441A6D0259F9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in consultation with the Director of the Office of Personnel Management and the Counsel to the President, promulgate regulations to carry out and ensure the enforcement of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/41/21">chapter 21</external-xref> of title 41, United States Code, as amended by this section; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF5954610971E4BD19C6517307D519560"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in consultation with designated agency ethics officials (as defined under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-act" parsable-cite="usc-act/Ethics in Government Act of 1978 /601">section 601</external-xref> of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.), as added by section 3), monitor compliance with that chapter by individuals and agencies.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H677C5E53D1764E9289B57A8B2182BDD1"><enum>5.</enum><header>Revolving door restrictions on financial services regulators moving into the private sector</header> 
<subsection id="H80F93F90F50E4FE4A4480FB7B873E745"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 207 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H7A500E9E6DF945AC81F5CB7C93E18F75"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (e) through (l) as subsections (f) through (m), respectively; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6E70506D59904D9B86B957B4529AD733"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (d) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0B8F3CF6752F4BA5B3563E305B963CC0" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H3404910B166B48C889B6340817F839A3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Restrictions on employment for financial services regulators</header> <paragraph id="H875A0DB441854467954DC04CE8F9BB4A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In addition to the restrictions set forth in subsections (a), (b), (c), and (d), a covered financial services regulator shall not—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3EA34E6591774CDC8CF58CBBEE7E63B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>during the 2-year period beginning on the date on which his or her employment as a covered financial services regulator ceases—</text> <clause id="H72F199E34D0148A9A5A74E174F2E6B5B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>knowingly act as agent or attorney for, or otherwise represent, any other person for compensation (except the United States) in any formal or informal appearance before;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H463E822E1364441DB353C82666BFF5B5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with the intent to influence, make any oral or written communication on behalf of any other person (except the United States) to; or</text></clause> <clause id="H14FD90F12FB94361B264109FF0CBCE30"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>knowingly aid, advise, or assist in—</text> 
<subclause id="H119FFA784F314474BBE85C10CD33A9D2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>representing any other person (except the United States) in any formal or informal appearance before; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="HA8664A3D8B0B4FD891F99F67776950F4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>making, with the intent to influence, any oral or written communication on behalf of any other person (except the United States) to,</text></subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause" indent="subparagraph">any court of the United States, or any officer or employee thereof, in connection with any judicial or other proceeding, that was actually pending under his or her official responsibility as a covered financial services regulator during the 1-year period ending on the date on which his or her employment as a covered financial services regulator ceases or in which he or she participated personally and substantially as a covered financial services regulator; or</continuation-text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3436B3B5CAB34A8D8C48D317A891EAFD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>during the 2-year period beginning on the date on which his or her employment as a covered financial services regulator ceases—</text> <clause id="H96C4FDCD1B744B318337A2F381688544"><enum>(i)</enum><text>knowingly act as a lobbyist or agent for, or otherwise represent, any other person for compensation (except the United States) in any formal or informal appearance before;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDFC8F53F798D4CBB9F7A692B1974C302"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with the intent to influence, make any oral or written communication or conduct any lobbying activities on behalf of any other person (except the United States) to; or</text></clause> <clause id="HA04661E2EB084E7192626610D3C6090C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>knowingly aid, advise, or assist in—</text> 
<subclause id="H6A13E576090C49F5A963253CC6C652FB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>representing any other person (except the United States) in any formal or informal appearance before; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H8737C8E58F2C4DF4AC36EF21B16D7DC2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>making, with the intent to influence, any oral or written communication or conduct any lobbying activities on behalf of any other person (except the United States) to,</text></subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause" indent="subparagraph">any department or agency of the executive branch or Congress (including any committee of Congress), or any officer or employee thereof, in connection with any matter that is pending before the department, the agency, or Congress.</continuation-text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBA0EA43C731648D6ACF40B3328247BC0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>Any person who violates paragraph (1) shall be punished as provided in section 216.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCC70DD299B7F4A46A729F49D4891FC56"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE222BDACA06E42AD8B6345E557C1FDBB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>covered financial services regulator</term> has the meaning given that term in <external-xref legal-doc="usc-act" parsable-cite="usc-act/Ethics in Government Act of 1978 /601">section 601</external-xref> of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE82E361EC31B48D380C62F8A0C104289"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the terms <term>lobbying activities</term> and <term>lobbyist</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 3 of the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1602">2 U.S.C. 1602</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H15D54C573D084802854AA40A3C2F60C0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header> 
<paragraph id="HEC52C145ADB844D0809AEE00A8796BEF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 103(a) of the Honest Leadership and Open Government Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/4702">2 U.S.C. 4702(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 207(e)</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>section 207(f)</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2732BC2581F94F269E27FD2DCFBD86EA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 207 of title 18, United States Code, as amended by subsection (a), is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H88013DFD8EE643A29250886996C400EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (g), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>or (e)</quote> and inserting <quote>or (f)</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCCE08180168B4814B4581415D41F253A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (j)(1)(B), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>subsection (f)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (g)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD6FD8EE51B5C406BB084321527259F66"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (k), as so redesignated—</text> <clause id="H8CD5B68FB57C49E8A956D216CC6F3637"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(B), by striking <quote>(<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450i">25 U.S.C. 450i(j)</external-xref>)</quote> and inserting <quote>(<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5323">25 U.S.C. 5323(j)</external-xref>)</quote>;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9868A2D0B06A4A29849044C359C60D08"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>and (e)</quote> and inserting <quote>(e), and (f)</quote>;</text></clause> <clause id="H47E3B8AB70D1413D99E029E462CAB0FC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>and (e)</quote> and inserting <quote>(e), and (f)</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5DB15D709B4D467DBAE3203B50D7DFED"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in paragraph (7)—</text> <subclause id="H452C94C32D2D443387F27F8642D926B2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>and (e)</quote> and inserting <quote>(e), and (f)</quote>; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HFFC0CF76B0BE432791E4BB1723A7CA2D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)(ii), in the matter preceding subclause (I), by striking <quote>subsections (c), (d), or (e)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (c), (d), (e), or (f)</quote>.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H98E47D0D41494108B10D8BC59EB1E101"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Section 141(b)(4) of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2171">19 U.S.C. 2171(b)(4)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 207(f)(3)</quote> and inserting <quote>207(g)(3)</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H907DF4E3B29844108D8426A26A0EAF39"><enum>(4)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7802">Section 7802(b)(3)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>and (f) of section 207</quote> and inserting <quote>and (g) of section 207</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2153442C7B1A4FEA98E2FB104DCB3A56"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Section 3105(c) of the USEC Privatization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2297h-3">42 U.S.C. 2297h–3(c)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>and (d)</quote> and inserting <quote>and (e)</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H142F2B66674C4294B62B9BAC8C86A9CE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Section 106(p)(6)(I)(ii) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>and (f) of section 207</quote> and inserting <quote>and (g) of section 207</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H210DFD583EA74A9B85D68F7A4805FA5B"><enum>6.</enum><header>Restrictions on Federal examiners and supervisors of financial institutions</header> <subsection id="HCFCBA422F5BC4615A03AF699971AA333"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 10(k) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1820">12 U.S.C. 1820(k)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD8B45CF57C01450297326BCD49CDD115"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the subsection heading—</text> <subparagraph id="H94A17C9BF5814D6C91E350D5FE7FD6EC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">One-Year</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Two-Year</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H12A4D6FBAAB648E69DBEA62027598C1F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Examiners</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Examiners and Supervisors</header-in-text></quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8D48BC55664F452DA87A5ABF49947EF1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE3423BB989C3480293C27EFDEFB3F6F0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (B) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block act-name="" id="H2FDE675573A54F3180C1791C67A6FECB" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H090FAEC2A5CD47F4B6DC31E4BF355512"><enum>(B)</enum><text>served—</text> 
<clause id="HEE5858BBD33645C4B7344D6DDB6D8A59"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not less than 2 months during the final 12 months of the employment of the person with that agency or entity as the senior examiner (or a functionally equivalent position) of a depository institution or depository institution holding company with continuing, broad responsibility for the examination (or inspection) of that depository institution or depository institution holding company on behalf of the relevant agency or Federal reserve bank; or</text></clause> <clause id="H23F0C6BA40AC4CD198D9627836860DA9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>as a supervisor of the senior examiner with responsibility for managing the oversight of not more than 5 depository institutions or depository institution holding companies on behalf of the relevant agency or Federal reserve bank; and</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF3F44B2639F54472967B202211A34F2C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)—</text> <clause id="H9405F6B0DAED4CCB8E58D49423554392"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>1 year</quote> and inserting <quote>2 years</quote>;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HEEDE1B3FB4FD44188E4FF1E8061A22E6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (i)—</text> <subclause id="H7808477F8EAB4E188F4E6D6ABF415610"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>other company</quote> and inserting <quote>other company, firm, or association</quote>; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HAB33B943263747D492023B60CFD2A4D9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HBBBCA3F576864C9B9AE0B2C93DCBDF76"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H70EA7530BDB34D56B36638A27C2F4E81"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block act-name="" id="H29638515EE394AF9801C17A31E74FB2C" style="OLC"> <clause id="HD9D5AD74545742AB9D7475740E845183"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a business entity, firm, or association that represents the depository institution or depository institution holding company for compensation.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE9B42FB39D1647C28FD624E58B73EAD9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (2) through (6) as paragraphs (3) through (7), respectively;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0163150CB2D94D51AA4E79EC46F54FA2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (1) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block act-name="" id="HBD6C40CF707347F58C959005EB35B7A6" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H04305DAAE653492DBCBBFBCC64920195"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application of penalties for supervisors</header><text>A supervisor of a covered financial services regulator, or a supervisor of a senior examiner described in paragraph (1)(B)(i), shall be subject to the penalties described in paragraph (7) if the supervisor knowingly accepts compensation during the 2-year period beginning on the date on which the service of the supervisor is terminated—</text> <subparagraph id="HBB5FAD419E454D3D9AB89C0BEEE54D9F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as—</text> 
<clause id="H7D204FA2527A4A1E8D47BD259F47C94B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an employee;</text></clause> <clause id="H8E801336E7C84C29B59B303835F1BBCC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an officer;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H987DD505A24D4DA1846916E84B23051D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a director; or</text></clause> <clause id="H801DB0A1CB1845ADA359459C6B30F425"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a consultant; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9AB05E2F64154392AFC87422B09FB617"><enum>(B)</enum><text>from—</text> <clause id="H79422F2B48BA4E509B26BDB73A39760E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a depository institution;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H673B3A3F29254D728186EDF5D5D1F9A0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a depository institution holding company that is designated by the Financial Stability Oversight Council as a systemically important financial market utility under section 804 of the Payment, Clearing, and Settlement Supervision Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5463">12 U.S.C. 5463</external-xref>); or</text></clause> <clause id="H0D725E2686FA46818A5E9A1982281A8C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a business entity, firm, or association that represents an institution described in clause (ii) for compensation.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H40A186E94F4146918FF74CA6A9855A4B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), as so redesignated—</text> <subparagraph id="H10DC82D2BB324B1BA34690304A1123C7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (A) and (B) as subparagraphs (B) and (C), respectively; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H687847F877FE46E4876AA6CFCBCD19D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting before subparagraph (B), as so redesignated, the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2A9FFD7D871A44CBA425C04970D5B4F9" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H5C5A449E746842D58CB098517D18F1AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>covered financial services regulator</term> has the meaning given the term in <external-xref legal-doc="usc-act" parsable-cite="usc-act/Ethics in Government Act of 1978 /601">section 601</external-xref> of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.);</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE5F957D36C784AC8B4068B622E1ED6FF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>or other company</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>or other company, firm, or association</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H877E1989D06C41D5A7BCA366520D1FED"><enum>(7)</enum><text>in paragraph (7), as so redesignated—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA3F40DDEA18546BAB81083CEA2BD008E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text> <clause id="HBAA0CCF6ADE645C59DB40E1A2D696531"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>other company</quote> and inserting <quote>other company, firm, or association</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB7F48AFA2C2440CFAE335DF8D4D41838"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (i)(I), by striking <quote>other company</quote> and inserting <quote>other company, firm, or association</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFF27DF1DBDAE438B9FCCF1E379B22FEE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>a company</quote> and inserting <quote>a company, firm, or association</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD7E8F108C34F4130AA08E334D0C7946E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header><text>Section 10(k) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1820">12 U.S.C. 1820(k)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H301EC8CEB4664F1E84F987523387F0B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>paragraph (6)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (7)</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4F4F98D26D884BBAB8CDB61B700C8E14"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)(A), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>paragraph (1)(B)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (1)(B) and (2)</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA015748A29A5401A97CE901C5F69F101"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (7), as so redesignated—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0011A72AA97849F792109ECB263E7076"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text> <clause id="H961BF504A80F46E0BFDFDE763BD0AD1A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subject to paragraph (1)</quote> and inserting <quote>subject to paragraph (1) or (2)</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9EB9C1FF55B84AEB801D7504BF29B1EE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>paragraph (1)(C)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (1)(C) or (2)</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H08D3BE8FA3194EE086C6E670856DB7AE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)—</text> 
<clause id="HDE13DC9F928E438D966A94C3F2A9E887"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>person described in paragraph (1)</quote> and inserting <quote>person described in paragraph (1) or (2)</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="HAB80457C18A340BF81329ED4EFE717F9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the functions described in paragraph (1)(B)</quote> and inserting <quote>the functions or duties described in paragraph (1)(B) or (2)</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section commented="no" id="H122D7F37F6DE48D9900066219BB0EB8F"><enum>7.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act or any amendment made by this Act, or any application of such provision or amendment to any person or circumstance, is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of the provisions of this Act and the amendments made by this Act and the application of the provision or amendment to any other person or circumstance shall not be affected.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

