<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H645056FFEF9E486FBF0A494B29603907" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1843 IH: Clyde-Hirsch-Sowers RESPECT Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1843</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170330">March 30, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000580">Mr. Roskam</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001038">Mr. Crowley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001065">Mr. Holding</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000585">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001158">Mr. Marchant</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001181">Mr. Meehan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000586">Mr. Renacci</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001195">Mr. Smith of Missouri</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000597">Mr. Rice of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001093">Mr. Collins of Georgia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 31, United States Code, to prohibit the Internal Revenue Service from carrying out
			 seizures relating to a structuring transaction unless the property to be
			 seized derived from an illegal source or the funds were structured for the
			 purpose of concealing the violation of another criminal law or regulation,
			 to require notice and a post-seizure hearing for such seizures, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HFD4D8CEF54204953A23F3EAB0172718C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H5CECF7F550FC43FC8CAEC49507B0E66C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Clyde-Hirsch-Sowers RESPECT Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Restraining Excessive Seizure of Property through the Exploitation of Civil Asset Forfeiture Tools Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD18426F3118F48DC940374A922D7792F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Internal Revenue Service seizure requirements with respect to structuring transactions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5317(c)(2) of title 31, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H56AC3C2199E247909EFF57DE91776393"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Any property</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1EA54F1C192541F98C89AD8A3F1A4B05" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HFBB945A1612E45DF87A29CF34BE0782C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any property</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7799B0E267D74A9C9B543C931B313609"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC1B5EF569FC44F66849F2B2EC8849AE0" style="OLC">
					<subparagraph commented="no" id="HB99FBC62CAE34BFFBEA82975C4E575CC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Internal Revenue Service seizure requirements with respect to structuring transactions</header>
 <clause id="H3B2AFE756252489CA7096CB1E0270C4A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Property derived from an illegal source</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Property may only be seized by the Internal Revenue Service pursuant to subparagraph (A) by reason of a claimed violation of section 5324 if the property to be seized was derived from an illegal source or the funds were structured for the purpose of concealing the violation of a criminal law or regulation other than section 5324.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBDB736A7F47142E8A0FAF2B0DB3846BA"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>Not later than 30 days after property is seized by the Internal Revenue Service pursuant to subparagraph (A), the Internal Revenue Service shall—</text>
 <subclause id="H452144D0E5D945A68959159C5D0B51F7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>make a good faith effort to find all persons with an ownership interest in such property; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H35DA7B32D042410D850D197A7CD9EAC4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>provide each such person with a notice of the person’s rights under clause (iv).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H71903AF8E9AF4AC5844F43038FD41F48"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Extension of notice under certain circumstances</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Internal Revenue Service may apply to a court of competent jurisdiction for one 30-day extension of the notice requirement under clause (ii) if the Internal Revenue Service can establish probable cause of an imminent threat to national security or personal safety necessitating such extension.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDBD28CA950BE473D90A6A7B24EECCCBF"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Post-seizure hearing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a person with a property interest in property seized pursuant to subparagraph (A) by the Internal Revenue Service requests a hearing by a court of competent jurisdiction within 30 days after the date on which notice is provided under subclause (ii), such property shall be returned unless the court holds an adversarial hearing and finds within 30 days of such request (or such longer period as the court may provide, but only on request of an interested party) that there is probable cause to believe that there is a violation of section 5324 involving such property and probable cause to believe that the property to be seized was derived from an illegal source or the funds were structured for the purpose of concealing the violation of a criminal law or regulation other than section 5324.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H8321B1AF56F5457D87E184E9FCC17905"><enum>3.</enum><header>Exclusion of interest received in action to recover property seized by the Internal Revenue Service
			 based on structuring transaction</header>
 <subsection id="H745DE6F76EC94FB3AB3F424DB28ADB3E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part III of subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting before section 140 the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HACE50F613DF545E4B777D80825DF6CF2" style="OLC">
					<section id="H250C98AA7DA84EE490A7C7A386087B56"><enum>139G.</enum><header>Interest received in action to recover property seized by the Internal Revenue Service based on
 structuring transaction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Gross income shall not include any interest received from the Federal Government in connection with an action to recover property seized by the Internal Revenue Service pursuant to section 5317(c)(2) of title 31, United States Code, by reason of a claimed violation of section 5324 of such title.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6E1EC5D4E52A440EAD046F87A3AD52F1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for part III of subchapter B of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by inserting before the item relating to section 140 the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1455689D5DBE44BBB1A0BDA831FB9E08" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 139G. Interest received in action to recover property seized by the Internal Revenue Service
			 based on structuring transaction.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB3FD440719AF463B99A5A57013D53A4E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to interest received on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


