<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFF79E6BDF4814221AD052E51BAD1B69C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2788 IH: Health Equity and Access under the Law for Immigrant Women and Families Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2788</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170606">June 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barrag&#225;n</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000535">Mr. Guti&#233;rrez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000486">Ms. Roybal-Allard</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000248">Mr. Serrano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001050">Ms. Hanabusa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. S&#225;nchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To expand access to health care services, including sexual, reproductive, and maternal health services, for immigrant women, men, and families by removing legal barriers to health insurance coverage, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF48D4B9E726E4A629C7FBFDD5DD2BFA3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC3052D8152DF44218FAD69075DA052FD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Health Equity and Access under the Law for Immigrant Women and Families Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or as the <quote><short-title>HEAL for Immigrant Women and Families Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H60341A09348747BC88184FAD94602DCC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; purpose</header> <subsection id="H1D69D5C6ACAF493CABE0C2A9904E0449"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds as follows:</text> 
<paragraph id="H9F6DAFB785C24FE7930E944EDA70D5B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Insurance coverage reduces harmful health disparities by alleviating cost barriers to and increasing utilization of basic preventive health services, especially among low-income and underserved populations, and especially among women.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8903E6A37C8549F6B2232E658C54C13D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Based solely on their immigration status, many immigrants and their families face legal restrictions on their ability to obtain health insurance coverage through Medicaid, CHIP, and Health Insurance Exchanges.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5045C5CCCF4B42B09E4795188A992DDD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Lack of health insurance contributes to persistent disparities in the prevention, diagnosis, and treatment of negative health outcomes borne by immigrants and their families.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB52AE899B2524C40A903C8BBBB426E65"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Immigrant women are disproportionately of reproductive age, low-income, and lacking health insurance coverage. Legal barriers to affordable health insurance coverage therefore particularly exacerbate their risk of negative sexual, reproductive, and maternal health outcomes, with lasting health and economic consequences for immigrant women, their families, and society as a whole.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFB4D8AB5BC3A41EDA60C88F49E002975"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Denying coverage or imposing waiting periods for coverage unfairly hinders the ability of immigrants to take responsibility for their own health and economic well-being and that of their families. To fully and productively participate in society, access to health care is fundamental, which for women includes access to the services necessary to plan whether and when to have a child.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H323FC09041974B749C1395442699DBFB"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The population of immigrant families in the United States is expected to continue to grow. Indeed one in four children in the United States is part of an immigrant family. It is therefore in the Nation’s shared public health and economic interest to remove legal barriers to affordable health insurance coverage based on immigration status.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDC1AB0F315B3451A803B3D290721AD03"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Although Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals (DACA) recipients are authorized to live and work in the United States, they have been unfairly excluded from the definition of lawfully present and lawfully residing for purposes of health insurance coverage by the Department of Health and Human Services, including Medicaid and the Children’s Health Insurance Program (CHIP).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1D186E1F215D43B4B7F55A1DE424D8A2"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Immigration law is constantly evolving and new immigration categories for individuals with federally authorized presence in the United States may be created. </text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H18C25C2551CF473E9E704128204223BB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the purpose of this Act to ensure that all individuals who are granted federally authorized presence are treated as being lawfully present in the United States for purposes of eligibility under all federally funded health care programs.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H150F1A5E942A473181D40BEE9DE7740D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Removing barriers to health coverage for lawfully present individuals</header> <subsection id="HB5EA0D6DA2E747A49384F14F5E80343D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Medicaid</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1903(v)(4) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396b">42 U.S.C. 1396b(v)(4)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF572173ACC7A44038053D33BE117D71A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (A) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H960FA1E564EF4C8A9DB84387A74F567C" style="traditional"> <subparagraph id="HA7CA3EE0855C4F068A57AD2818FB71A5" indent="up2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding sections 401(a), 402(b), 403, and 421 of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996, payment shall be made under this section for care and services that are furnished to aliens, including those described in paragraph (1), if they otherwise meet the eligibility requirements for medical assistance under the State plan approved under this title (other than the requirement of the receipt of aid or assistance under title IV, supplemental security income benefits under title XVI, or a State supplementary payment), and are lawfully present in the United States (including such an individual who is granted deferred action or other federally authorized presence other than as a nonimmigrant).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9CEB8AB6E16A4B549A7A35AD49847499"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text> <subparagraph id="HC1E3F04508364C35BCB5F176AE3FECDC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>a State that has elected to provide medical assistance to a category of aliens under subparagraph (A)</quote> and inserting <quote>aliens provided medical assistance pursuant to subparagraph (A)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H34764C1990294EE0910ECD38B57E875E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>to such category</quote> and inserting <quote>to such alien</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H583745BCC60F44A68FC54F5CCF0A3D07"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD206BB1DABC54BF297FB95B34B540C91"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>an election by the State under subparagraph (A)</quote> and inserting <quote>the application of subparagraph (A)</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC4A1BA7ADD8A4A3C82BD7793A96AC03F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or be lawfully present</quote> after <quote>lawfully reside</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H334276166C504FE4B0E0C0C8147427FF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or present</quote> after <quote>lawfully residing</quote> each place it appears.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H250AAC959C0941C7AD0F3A78A8913C90"><enum>(b)</enum><header>CHIP</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (M) of section 2107(e)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397gg">42 U.S.C. 1397gg(e)(1)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H185EB1E8F02C4327B8196E82770E5911" style="traditional"> 
<subparagraph id="H79F872F583544AF38141304E2D13CB28"><enum>(M)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (4) of section 1903(v) (relating to lawfully present individuals).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H1126A85F339D4B4CBCCF6A9D7AA96BB8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header> <paragraph id="H41AE8155916F408BB89E773058A1E7D3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act and shall apply to services furnished on or after the date that is 90 days after such date of the enactment.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF2C5A494C3E64EDB882DA59FE89685F3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception if state legislation required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a State plan for medical assistance under title XIX, or a State child health plan under title XXI, of the Social Security Act which the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines requires State legislation (other than legislation appropriating funds) in order for the plan to meet the additional requirements imposed by the amendments made by this section, the respective State plan shall not be regarded as failing to comply with the requirements of such title solely on the basis of its failure to meet these additional requirements before the first day of the first calendar quarter beginning after the close of the first regular session of the State legislature that begins after the date of the enactment of this Act. For purposes of the previous sentence, in the case of a State that has a 2-year legislative session, each year of such session shall be deemed to be a separate regular session of the State legislature.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H57B3EFD8283C43B9B27110C44E5CE4E6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Consistency in health coverage for individuals with federally authorized presence, including deferred action</header> <subsection id="H6EA5F077900C4F0BA4A7A1765E0CFB72"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of eligibility under any of the provisions referred to in subsection (b), all individuals granted federally authorized presence in the United States other than as a nonimmigrant shall be considered to be lawfully present in the United States.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H12F7A967C4234511A9D6628BECF07D4F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Provisions described</header><text>The provisions described in this subsection are the following:</text> <paragraph id="HDE1DBCC374BE4C41A9131C304B43123F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exchange eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1311 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18031">42 U.S.C. 18031</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5F1350FFBD8848A6BF1BA6350A40D44F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reduced cost-sharing eligibility</header><text>Section 1402 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18071">42 U.S.C. 18071</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H55BA11739B1349F2BA37AE6721D50B7A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Premium subsidy eligibility</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">Section 36B</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H480F5C8AEA49443E86FAA7DCB123B7DD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Medicaid and CHIP eligibility</header><text>Titles XIX and XXI of the Social Security Act, including under section 1903(v) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396b">42 U.S.C. 1396b(v)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB79793BD60CD41E5846B281A3C23FD43"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header> <paragraph id="H3063B98F9F954234A829C460BB8E1169"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subsection (a) shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2F8676A87DE84A6590DF74468CDA6AB9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transition through special enrollment period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an individual described in subsection (a) who, before the first day of the first annual open enrollment period under subparagraph (B) of section 1311(c)(6) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18031">42 U.S.C. 18031(c)(6)</external-xref>) beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act, is granted federally authorized presence in the United States described in subsection (a) and who, as a result of such subsection, qualifies for a subsidy described in paragraph (2) or (3) of such subsection, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall establish a special enrollment period under section 1311(c)(6)(C) of such Act during which such individual may enroll in qualified health plans through Exchanges under title I of such Act and qualify for such a subsidy. For such an individual who has been granted federally authorized presence in the United States as of the date of the enactment of this Act, such special enrollment period shall begin not later than 90 days after such date of enactment. Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed as affecting the authority of the Secretary to establish additional special enrollment periods under section 1311(c)(6)(C) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18031">42 U.S.C. 18031(c)(6)(C)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

