<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HBBEB7DF73D1F4A4EBFF8B1A31EE58E58" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1813 IH: Border Wall Funding Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1813</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170330">March 30, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000575">Mr. Rogers of Alabama</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001269">Mr. Barletta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000578">Mr. Gaetz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001274">Mr. Brooks of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001048">Mr. Culberson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000388">Mr. Kelly of Mississippi</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001087">Mr. Crawford</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Electronic Fund Transfer Act to impose a fee for remittance transfers to certain
			 foreign countries, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HC41A6D8EFC474B7D97771AE4B72CE139" style="OLC">
 <section id="HD31758647AF44F0B8308913348965D2C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Border Wall Funding Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H35E7290780E64C7BA2E70442A2C9F3F5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Fees for certain remittance transfers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 920 of the Electronic Fund Transfer Act (relating to remittance transfers) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1693o-1">15 U.S.C. 1693o–1</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H499A5461A0724C07B687DEB3A7EB91F8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (g) as subsection (h); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC7CBE6669DC645ACA3FD000B6751A7D7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (f) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HE03DB9E7C8224F7DAF54657058C9960A" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="HC323F2307CD549A3AC778890DA54D7E1"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Border security fee collection</header>
						<paragraph id="HA64BC7D6EE924923B2889C9C826C966A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <subparagraph id="H2914DD9E653A4AB5A52935904D83786E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Fees</header><text>If the designated recipient of a remittance transfer is located in a foreign country described in subparagraph (B), a remittance transfer provider shall collect from the sender of such remittance transfer a remittance fee equal to 2 percent of the United States dollar amount to be transferred (excluding any fees or other charges imposed by the remittance transfer provider). Except as provided in subparagraph (C), such remittance fees shall be submitted to the Treasury to be expended for the purpose of improving border security.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB0D8B25A1034C60918D965623195127"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Foreign countries</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall apply to designated recipients located in Mexico, Guatemala, Belize, Cuba, the Cayman Islands, Haiti, the Dominican Republic, the Bahamas, Turks and Caicos, Jamaica, El Salvador, Honduras, Nicaragua, Costa Rica, Panama, Colombia, Venezuela, Aruba, Curacao, the British Virgin Islands, Anguilla, Antigua and Barbuda, Saint Kitts and Nevis, Montserrat, Guadeloupe, Dominica, Martinique, Saint Lucia, Saint Vincent and the Grenadines, Barbados, Grenada, Guyana, Suriname, French Guiana, Ecuador, Peru, Brazil, Bolivia, Chile, Paraguay, Uruguay, or Argentina.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDBFA209E7D7A495CA4F83BAB7C055EEB"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the 5-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this subsection, a remittance transfer provider may retain up to 5 percent of any remittance fees collected by such remittance transfer provider pursuant to subparagraph (A) to cover the costs of collecting and submitting such remittance fees.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H00EBDC5105C94AF48E7C9FE5825686D8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Fee collection system</header><text>Not later than September 30, 2017, the Bureau, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of the Treasury, and remittance transfer providers, shall develop and make available a system for remittance transfer providers to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7639889DB0BE459DAB02EF8563B88776"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit the remittance fees collected in accordance with paragraph (1)(A) to the Treasury; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20C3460F1A924C96B31F0BF98CAE3ADA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">retain a portion of such remittance fees in accordance with paragraph (1)(C).</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE98BDEAF456E4010AC49DD5A8B87EFFB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Penalties</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H4A9A989A19634D13B0765C7A2655008F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whoever, with the intent to evade a remittance fee to be collected in accordance with this subsection, and who has knowledge that, at the time of a remittance transfer, the value of the funds involved in the transfer will be further transferred to a recipient located in a country listed in paragraph (1)(B), requests or facilitates such remittance transfer to a designated recipient in a country that is not listed in paragraph (1)(B) shall be subject to a penalty of not more than $500,000 or twice the value of the funds involved in the remittance transfer, whichever is greater, or imprisonment for not more than 20 years, or both.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D1C5735C52C45D8B9F214C9A37C596D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any foreign country that, in the joint determination of the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the Secretary of State aids or harbors an individual conspiring to avoid the fee collected in accordance with this subsection shall be ineligible to receive foreign assistance and to participate in the visa waiver program or any other programs, at the discretion of the Secretaries described in this subparagraph.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


