<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H199F4F0EA30C45F99A9CD0725C0E6063" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2028 IH: Healthy Relationships Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2028</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170406">April 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001059">Mr. Hultgren</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000585">Mr. LaHood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001299">Mr. Banks of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000055">Mr. Aderholt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001053">Mrs. Hartzler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001071">Mr. Jody B. Hice of Georgia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administration for
			 Children &amp; Families, to award grants on a competitive basis to public and private entities to provide
			 exclusively education in sexual risk avoidance (meaning avoiding all
			 sexual risk by voluntarily refraining from nonmarital sexual activity).</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H2258A85AEBB94F48B9AA2BF9CF9D3E62" style="OLC">
 <section id="H497E8BB28A9A4913AF085CCCFAF636A3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Healthy Relationships Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H78AE53D29824441DA4B6191411E3F525"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sexual risk avoidance education</header> <subsection id="HB0FEC86BA76E471EA927889DAA514F29"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administration for Children &amp; Families (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), may award grants on a competitive basis to public and private entities for the exclusive purpose of providing qualified sexual risk avoidance (in this section referred to as <quote>SRA</quote>) education to youth and their parents.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4557E3A9F2BF4D64818A1D891AF99FA0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Qualified SRA education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To receive funding for SRA education under this section, an entity shall demonstrate to the Secretary each of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H02866614A2A44C0BBB83B261AB565A97"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The education—</text> <subparagraph id="HC93406B760AF46DA84828AC393DFF6E0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>will be evidenced-based, meaning it will have a clear theoretical framework integrating research findings with practical implementation relevant to the SRA field that matches the needs and desired outcomes for the intended audience; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6AEEA470272456CAAEBC1AAD2CB4429"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if effectively implemented, will give youth improved life and health outcomes.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE10CE41E11E4E06BEE25E7CC79EB4DB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The unambiguous and primary emphasis and context for each topic covered by the education will be the message to middle and high school students that avoiding nonmarital sexual activity offers the best opportunity for optimal sexual health.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD32FBA493BBF4BBB982E1E094766326F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The education will be medically accurate, meaning that information will be referenced to peer reviewed publications by educational, scientific, governmental, or health organizations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7E2F43ABED3443489569FDF96EE24089"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The education will be age-appropriate, meaning it will be appropriate for the general developmental and social maturity of the targeted age group (as opposed to the cognitive ability to understand a topic, or the atypical maturation, of a small segment of the targeted population).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H82547C7ECE4B464994F085109DCAF7EA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The education will thoroughly address each of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HB6C0A3DF93304FB0A81EC7188D816DB4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The holistic individual and societal benefits associated with personal responsibility, self-regulation, goal setting, healthy decisionmaking, and a focus on the future.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF02D7450FFAC4757B427233D9F03DB6A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The research-supported advantage of reserving sexual activity for marriage, in order to improve the future prospects and physical and emotional health of youth, and helping sexually active students return to a risk-free status. In this subparagraph, the terms <term>sexual activity</term> and <term>sexually active</term> refer to any type of genital contact or sexual stimulation for the purpose of arousal, including sexual intercourse.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C5C8DCB172C4E779CF5977BF7579DC2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The increased likelihood of avoiding poverty when youth implement the <quote>success sequence</quote> by achieving three norms in sequence: complete school, secure a full time job, and wait until at least 21 years of age to marry and have children.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF46670BF138341F796B61D205ACC0315"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The skills needed to resist the harms associated with pornography and the pervasive, sex-saturated culture that portrays teenage sexual activity as an expected norm, with few risks or negative consequences.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5D0B3A80603449CA55EB6F1EB9AF051"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The foundational components of healthy relationships and their impact on the formation of healthy marriages and safe and stable families.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D878DF1266142D389862F40B0D1265E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>How to resist and avoid sexual coercion and dating violence, recognizing that even with consent, teen sex remains a youth risk behavior.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC726DDBF45643B6B65F9D08C81AF4F7"><enum>(G)</enum><text>How other youth risk behaviors, such as drug and alcohol usage, increase the risk for teen sex.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H678820B3FE2F465C8EF5AACAFDC4F679"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The education will ensure that any information provided on contraception—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCC69CBF5ADC442A68F0334DE93809B51"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is medically accurate and ensures that students understand that contraception offers only physical risk reduction and not risk elimination; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E9BFECB368141F889320472937EA2D3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include demonstration, simulation, or distribution of contraceptive devices.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7BFC6A2B61174687959DB23577830D6A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under subsection (a), the Secretary shall give priority to applicants proposing programs to provide qualified SRA education that will—</text>
 <paragraph id="H247F82FCCCCD469891E61D27964C366C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>regularly reinforce the SRA message in both the middle and high school grades; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDCD97011A014414B847DC6354F1A0AEA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promote parent-child communication regarding the benefits of avoiding all sexual risk.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC51C6AA844CA4F489486BF3537CD97BC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To seek an application under this section, an entity shall submit an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such assurances as the Secretary may require. At a minimum, the application shall include—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC5E2A35F30FB4A8EB6AAEE88E9CDE988"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assurances satisfactory to the Secretary that each of the conditions listed in subsection (c) will be satisfied;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H59A1D0BF211D442BADA9198278C9E09E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an individualized plan to evaluate the SRA education to be funded through the grant for behavioral impact, or to inform best practices in the provision of such SRA education that are based on research that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDB06C9CE88594EA78D2571CE6804586B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is conducted by independent researchers who have experience in conducting and publishing research in peer-reviewed outlets; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H14D724F565B04BC5A6D6247CDDA84C1D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not part of a national evaluation that is mandated by, contracted for, or conducted by the Department of Health and Human Services; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E2D7AF5CF3049668D5136D4360F95B0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an agreement to expend not more than 20 percent of their overall grant award for such evaluation.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H52B8582050554244AE5A6E132B276C3B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Training and technical assistance</header> <paragraph id="H65C6EAAB55964110A3FB611679AF53C0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may provide training and technical assistance to grantees under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8CF34085B79347B9931BC509CE2C429C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>Any such training and technical assistance shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HF6DFEEDD142D410E8A9E14837D9ED893"><enum>(A)</enum><text>emphasize the practical implementation of SRA in all educational messaging to teens;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4D716190F404DD1BF1582D1D6A58071"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be provided directly to grantees by SRA-credentialed experts;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D5D68239C7440D8AF7C1344608A1513"><enum>(C)</enum><text>cover methodologies and best practices in SRA for teens; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF9B839CF71364368874B08E3255CDD87"><enum>(D)</enum><text>consistently teach in the context of a public health model that stresses risk avoidance or a return to a risk avoidance status.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDFB1EE0048514BAEB3F82BE3D4D91E4C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Settings</header><text>Any such training and technical assistance shall be provided during national and regional conferences, webinars, and one-on-one conversations about funded projects.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HED0525E9F76E44CC8546092E4830BFBD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Qualified organizations</header><text>In addition to training and technical assistance provided by staff of the Department of Health and Human Services, such training and technical assistance shall be provided by qualified organizations that have—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2D6FB5179AB54A4BA395B84AB233FC7F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>sole focus on the development and advancement of SRA education;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEEAE56E25FF2418A8CD9B90839CDE301"><enum>(B)</enum><text>expertise in theory-based SRA program development and implementation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H26CA19CDA93F4C18AC471369C8CA09AE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>direct experience in developing SRA evaluation instruments; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF4C6DDEA50D4B9E95332DF0B0E2D5FD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the ability to offer technical assistance and training on topics relevant to the SRA field.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD93CE82B0A9B4F68A41C0792DC1D3AC9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <paragraph id="H41F59B54D2584867A7341CB619F9C1AC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $100,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022. Amounts authorized to be appropriated by the preceding sentence shall be derived exclusively from amounts made available for the Teen Pregnancy Prevention program of the Department of Health and Human Services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFA55D3CAC169447E9F930CB4CCE090D9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal administrative costs</header><text>Of the amount authorized to be appropriated by paragraph (1) for a fiscal year—</text> <subparagraph id="H5FA15EEB467C45128A6C59C9BE9665FB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>up to $1,000,000 are authorized to be used for the creation of a national media campaign to increase understanding and appreciation for SRA education;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C7F3507B5C2411EBEC7AA5150D4175A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not more than $1,000,000 are authorized to be used for Federal administrative costs; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8BB5F1AC3CAF4A18BA89B556740BD728"><enum>(C)</enum><text>of the amount used by the Secretary for administrative costs, no more than 25 percent shall be used for training and technical assistance.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


