<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H908F43D52DFC47E0BD73C75C58EF3518" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1837 IH: 21st Century Energy Workforce Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1837</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170330">March 30, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Energy to establish a pilot competitive grant program for the
			 development of a skilled energy workforce, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HB0818AF488FF49248780F06F8FF74A52" style="OLC">
 <section id="HAC82E2694E6A4B2B96C0CEE85E00B169" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>21st Century Energy Workforce Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H54D025B0EFD542B081B0A4A5BEF612F7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF4276DAFFBB44EC1BBA26DA253DD011D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the energy sector is the third-largest industry in the United States;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE6DCF19A130A45B0851F67FA0D277DA3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>1,500,000 new skilled workers will be needed in the energy sector over the next 15 years; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDA95182DA7FA4B4B88ECDE27A110DF0F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a skilled workforce is a critical component of ensuring the growth of the energy sector in the United States.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H9E7E59FDEC1F4BDA822F759E62764412"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HA7EDE177A18F4B80BA5AD0A83BAA5855"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Apprenticeship program</header><text>The term <quote>apprenticeship program</quote> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2230FA658DF5412CA7644A0448815B34"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an apprenticeship program registered with the Department of Labor as of the date of enactment of this Act that has a completion rate for participants of not less than 60 percent; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB433D17D13AB4888A66996439F7017F1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an apprenticeship program not registered with the Department of Labor as of the date of enactment of this Act, but that the Secretary determines should be eligible for a grant under section 5.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC22643C0FA564F2EA98C5F480270A5F8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Board</header><text>The term <term>Board</term> means the National Center of Excellence for the 21st Century Workforce Advisory Board established under section 4(a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAFE0AB7BCCB940F58629FEC67150DBD4"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Community college</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>community college</term> means a junior or community college (as defined in section 312(f) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1058">20 U.S.C. 1058(f)</external-xref>)).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6E1C283DDE394B688D043A3064F99073"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The term <term>program</term> means the pilot program established under section 5(a).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0C1C97D0555643339E3B8BA7DE5AE166"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Energy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H281A5B47023C40D48E7C9E119FE80A19"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Veterans service organization</header><text>The term <term>veterans service organization</term> means an organization recognized by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for the representation of veterans under section 5902 of title 38, United States Code.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H7CFB56ADF4654BF09DE280F77C5640A0"><enum>4.</enum><header>National Center of Excellence for the 21st Century Workforce</header>
 <subsection id="H5022102020D5419FA24C17D34D63D7E5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a nationwide advisory board, to be known as the <quote>National Center of Excellence for the 21st Century Workforce Advisory Board</quote>, to foster strategic vision, guidance, and networks for the energy industry.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H7CBEC5B3D2144F0C89247D85540508FB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Representatives</header><text>The members of the Board shall consist of energy sector stakeholders, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE659C6EABAAE4966AAA2AF9F042CE16F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>representatives of relevant industries;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8ED9A4F34D2846418C45463136DD91A1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>experts in labor, economics, and workforce development;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4A5671292A4A411D8EA6223303EACC32"><enum>(3)</enum><text>representatives of States and units of local government;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC53DA256EFA04DDA9E1D34FDC80F34DF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>representatives of elementary and secondary education and postsecondary education; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF1240685C5314862B3551B9BC36CCE7A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>representatives of labor organizations.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H65F0DFD6DDA444B79AA3631F3AD6ADC8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of the Board are—</text>
 <paragraph id="HEC21C2DC4457485983AF6B55FCBB65E8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to support and develop training and science education programs that—</text> <subparagraph id="H43880116D6114D1A897E2722A549BF29"><enum>(A)</enum><text>meet the industry and labor needs of the energy sector; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF248FCED062F4E7BB4429CB2188EE7C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide opportunities for students to become qualified for placement in traditional and clean energy sector jobs;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3517A993F49F425AB27BD70F25273830"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to align apprenticeship programs and industry certifications to further develop succession planning in the energy sector;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1AFEBFD1CCDF44399A9E57A68787F5C3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to integrate educational standards to develop foundational skills for elementary and secondary education and postsecondary education to create a pipeline between education and career; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0EA9ACAE51404F0BA1B6255A7841B2AD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to support the replication of existing model energy curricula.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2ECB6E994E9C45DF996C98FD24C2AE6E"><enum>5.</enum><header>Energy workforce pilot grant program</header> <subsection id="H8D4790D5BD98444E983B4DF33CF71253"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor and the Secretary of Education, shall establish a pilot program to award grants on a competitive basis to eligible entities for job training to obtain an industry-recognized credential.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1B57B23B21DC4B64B2681218C5AC1E6F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an entity shall be a public or nonprofit organization that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4E3D31E41798402C9372D08165544835"><enum>(1)</enum><text>includes an advisory board of proportional participation, as determined by the Secretary, of relevant organizations, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE30248EF0251466C9925A39DC98E9DE6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>relevant energy industry organizations, including public and private employers;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4623D73DC774FC69B7BA489CC25B679"><enum>(B)</enum><text>labor organizations; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB951C8DE34574F2AA2DFBC552448B0B6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>elementary and secondary education and postsecondary education organizations;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D8779D079684788A68F57F81EFE7CF2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>demonstrates experience in implementing and operating job training and education programs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3EAB160F073B40FBA53B8D1F23D6C700"><enum>(3)</enum><text>demonstrates the ability to recruit and support individuals who plan to work in the energy industry in the successful completion of relevant job training and education programs; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBAA309DD7FE4412A8ABA54FB762F8853"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provides students who complete the job training and education program with an industry-recognized credential.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H72B4F9FF1E85461D9BCF33C3A853CA91"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>Eligible entities desiring a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H071B2AAF8F4F46AEB1592E7D31EDBFA2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In selecting eligible entities to receive grants under this section, the Secretary shall prioritize applicants that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H72A99B2D743245818F7F9AD4ECA50354"><enum>(1)</enum><text>house the job training and education programs in—</text> <subparagraph id="HC9440120D5CA4BD1AEE01674FFEEA99A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a community college or institution of higher education that includes basic science and math education in the curriculum of the community college, institution of higher education; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4AA5B9CA272413A8935FEF98BA8EAD8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an apprenticeship program, and with respect to such apprenticeship programs described in section 3(1)(B), the Secretary shall further prioritize such programs that can demonstrate to the Secretary a completion rate for participants of not less than 60 percent;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H023E5E777D2B44C38EA4DA2B2D44B0F4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>work with the Secretary of Defense or veterans organizations to transition members of the Armed Forces and veterans to careers in the energy sector;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8F6B22CFB4014F4383A6D5869011FC9F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>apply as a State or regional consortia to leverage best practices already available in the State or region in which the community college or institution of higher education is located;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H39C9B7EF34E64DDBB330FE2001374305"><enum>(4)</enum><text>have a State-supported entity included in the application;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H62258F198F954646895EEE130AFBBF1D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>include an apprenticeship program as part of the job training and education program;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9DD9A088CA5C4B18832FCDB70E48CDED"><enum>(6)</enum><text>develop a mentorship program for energy professionals and elementary and secondary education students;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAEB1F0888F20462CA350917C9A3C6B40"><enum>(7)</enum><text>provide support services and career coaching;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF3E989619776415AA04623E8AEBABA13"><enum>(8)</enum><text>provide introductory energy workforce development training; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H068C82AF7E09458289C52E3DBFCF3BD7"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide industry-affiliated pre-apprenticeship programs, including intensive skill-building programs and intensive short-term programs.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4824F59179A44AF2B0FBA75B0880CAD0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Additional consideration</header><text>In making grants under this section, the Secretary shall consider regional diversity.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HBDD062DBC7AC403FA9344509206A9F5E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Limitation on applications</header><text>An eligible entity may not submit, either individually or as part of a joint application, more than 1 application for a grant under this section during any 1 fiscal year.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H30A3046053044D9ABF1631E04A8B0B9F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Limitations on amount of grant</header><text>The amount of a grant for any 1 year shall not exceed $1,000,000.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H2365AEC7FCAE41B7B2A168D3C4662204"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Costs</header> <paragraph id="HF84BA2BE7C9A4277A80586AF2D0E3A14"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal share</header><text>The Federal share of the cost of a job training and education program carried out using a grant under this section shall be not greater than 65 percent.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H58051EEC4CDE4715A84CE19F95265090"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Non-Federal share</header>
 <subparagraph id="HF811441B02404175A97A29988304DBF2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The non-Federal share of the cost of a job training and education program carried out using a grant under this section shall consist of not less than 50 percent cash.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H14676645B59A4D2E9D55070575A9EFB7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Not greater than 50 percent of the non-Federal contribution of the total cost of a job training and education program carried out using a grant under this section shall be in the form of in-kind contributions of goods or services fairly valued.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF128ECE61B2C40BAB909B25713450149"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Reduction of duplication</header><text>Prior to submitting an application for a grant under this section, each applicant shall consult with the applicable agencies of the Federal Government and coordinate the proposed activities of the applicant with existing State and local programs.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9595DAE93B994CF3A6A844E3751CA8CD"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary shall provide technical assistance and capacity building to national and State energy partnerships, including the entities described in subsection (b)(1), to leverage the existing job training and education programs of the Department of Energy.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC128D060760D41A1A9190D6B85F947F4"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Secretary shall submit to Congress and make publicly available on the website of the Department of Energy an annual report on the program established under this section, including a description of—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE77E0D4182E2461FB080FF606D7E9B80"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the entities receiving grants;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCBB4EE4488E940EFADEC6F714BE55375"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the activities carried out using the grants;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBC331B57D2C947A49E3910988A64CA0C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>best practices used to leverage the investment of the Federal Government;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H99CC79071BF545FDBE06C83F98B9D13A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the rate of employment for participants after completing a job training and education program carried out using a grant; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC6850570D940496E92803906DB44FDA6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>an assessment of the results achieved by the program.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD556D52C598847DF8AA1EF9C682071AE"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $20,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2020.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


