<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HBD7744628B7640D7A92BD980F2F39416" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1657 IH: Workforce Training Enhancement Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1657</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170321">March 21, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000127">Mr. Nolan</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Trade Act of 1974 to authorize a State to reimburse certain costs incurred by the
			 State in providing training to workers after a petition for certification
			 of eligibility for trade adjustment assistance has been filed, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H4048AB6AA85B4AE3AD75D076E8BB0C3A" style="OLC">
 <section id="HF5EA603ABF9B40CDBA6DB8A4B89DAC10" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Workforce Training Enhancement Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H0FFFEBB0FF3A4A44949458110C23F63A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text>
 <paragraph id="H442E5EF64245444A98FB13B8E3A13381"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The viability of the domestic steel industry is crucial to the United States economy and national security.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0508F77949E3403298048560B3B1C1FF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The steel and taconite iron mining industries have been severely impacted by the foreign dumping and overproduction of steel and are continually faced with unfair trade practices.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H06409610D28B456FB052E102068FDC33"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In 2014, United States imports of steel and steel products increased by 36 percent and captured 28 percent of the total United States steel market. In 2015, United States imports of steel and steel products continued to increase, and captured 29 percent of the total United States steel market.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7BFEE068700441A7BC0E11EBA32B0101"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In 1974, Congress enacted the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2101">19 U.S.C. 2101</external-xref> et seq.), which established the trade adjustment assistance for workers program under chapter 2 of title II of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2271">19 U.S.C. 2271</external-xref> et seq.) to assist workers who have been adversely affected by trade.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBAFD5B8D9CB547259320C129E79074B0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The trade adjustment assistance for workers program provides vital benefits and services to workers whose employment has been adversely affected by foreign trade. Those benefits and services include education and training, income support, relocation assistance, job search assistance, and the health coverage tax credit.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE10ED4A4550346B48E3BACFBA49DEEBD"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Since the inception of the trade adjustment assistance for workers program, more than 5,000,000 United States workers have been certified as eligible for benefits and services under the program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEAA93BD43B3C4C18A23F19BE4F63B908"><enum>(7)</enum><text>As of September 30, 2015, the trade adjustment assistance for workers program had served more than 2,200,000 workers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H103D0E0EB23243368EB75C3045527388"><enum>(8)</enum><text>In fiscal year 2015, the Department of Labor certified 413 petitions for eligibility for the trade adjustment assistance for workers program, which provided access to trade adjustment assistance benefits for 57,631 workers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H89A1D9C518DB4DD79ED6192BC8BFFF29"><enum>(9)</enum><text>In 2015, more than 13,000 new participants were enrolled in the trade adjustment assistance for workers program and the program provided services and benefits to more than 47,000 workers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF8FA22B6E7104205827A33AD16397AE0"><enum>(10)</enum><text>From fiscal year 2012 through fiscal year 2015, the average processing time for a petition under the trade adjustment assistance for workers program was 49.1 days and the average processing time for fiscal year 2015 was 47.2 days.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2D8E8B021FA44AD49E5213582C5ED338"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The trade adjustment assistance for workers program provides vital educational and training services to help trade-affected workers to acquire new skills and prepare for new employment.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE7585C865D0943B4BFDA8078B8CE58EF"><enum>(12)</enum><text>In order to empower workers who have been adversely affected by foreign trade, States should have the option of providing the funding for vital educational and training programs for workers while their petitions for certifications of eligibility for trade adjustment assistance are pending.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HE6D19CD60E6B43A0B83BEE287332F02D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Authorization of States to reimburse certain costs of providing training to workers after a
			 petition for trade adjustment assistance is filed</header>
 <subsection id="H4A067305BCEF4EA18B85E84B0B034639"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 236(a)(6) of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2296">19 U.S.C. 2296(a)(6)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9D08C026B8464C03BEC24FE43F1B2D45" style="OLC">
					<subparagraph id="H4829B5BCD6C049738B9FE8E91B2D91FA" indent="up2"><enum>(C)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB1DB6AEA74054E7DB343841086E3F551"><enum>(i)</enum><text>If the conditions described in clause (ii) are met, a State may use the funds distributed to the State under paragraph (2) to reimburse the costs of providing training to a worker before the worker is approved for training under paragraph (1) paid by—</text>
 <subclause id="H8D8A360C787B4A8B9AE5D8EAEBC0B6B9" indent="up1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the State from funds provided by the State;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H30050B72454E43CC9BB093488F808BA3" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the State or local workforce development areas within the State from funds available under subtitle B of title I of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3151">29 U.S.C. 3151</external-xref> et seq.); or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H45ED35221FDF4C82A63D7642ACA8CC70" indent="up1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>an eligible entity under section 170 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3225">29 U.S.C. 3225</external-xref>) in the State from funds available under that section.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H85A1458AF6744B9CB667FA2838C29ECC" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The conditions described in this clause are met if—</text> <subclause id="HF42B608E68BE4A12B31B71577CE1259F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>as of the date of the reimbursement under clause (i) the worker is covered by a certification for eligibility under subchapter A; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB35F303F2CFC4DBCA1CB56C180C0EC66"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the training the costs of which are being reimbursed—</text> <item id="H37A3EE1EBB844121A1C57096466EE913"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>commenced after the date on which the total or partial separations of the group of workers covered by the certification for eligibility began or threatened to begin; and</text>
 </item><item id="H9ABD3DA3C17F4007AB46A28C3C35FBD8"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>meets the requirements for approval of training under paragraph (1).</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H29AED68DE96A401BA4B72266F20F0EAE"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 236(a)(4)(B) of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2296">19 U.S.C. 2296(a)(4)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>No</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in paragraph (6)(C), no</quote>.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


