<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H69833468257A43949828B235F77E9B9C" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3096 IH: Drug-Free Indian Health Service Act of 2017 </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3096</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170628">June 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000184">Mrs. Noem</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To implement a mandatory random drug testing program for certain employees of the Indian Health
			 Service, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HE59A071EF1A44EE994925AB1C62A3AB1" style="OLC">
 <section id="H819D4B1DEBCF4894A23AF1A22D598B72" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Drug-Free Indian Health Service Act of 2017 </short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H7E964635A2EC43CD920654CAFAC4A7B2" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Mandatory Random Drug Testing of Certain Employees of Indian Health Service</header> <subsection id="H413E8A0AD0BF48FDAF2F97BF7C10791D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Regulations</header> <paragraph id="H8A887650C6694B4A82E686C0B73F147A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall promulgate such regulations as are necessary to implement a mandatory random drug testing program for covered employees of the Indian Health Service. Except as otherwise provided for in this section, the Secretary shall promulgate such regulations in accordance with the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2C67C0E2EA3D495984A6F10F0AD3A21C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The guidelines promulgated on November 25, 2008, titled <quote>Mandatory Guidelines for Federal Workplace Drug Testing</quote> (73 Fed. Reg. 71858).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFDDABDE2556B46EBB9F398BBD5DBF82B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The regulations promulgated under section 264(c) of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320d-2">42 U.S.C. 1320d–2</external-xref> note).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1EF94BA85EB141A9A313CC9706BC21D1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Testing of Certain Drugs</header><text>In carrying out the program required under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall ensure that each covered employee is tested not less than once per year for each of the following drugs:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H76DF5696860C4576A9B0B3497B58BEE5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Marijuana.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8765E55C2CC84557A77A6A1D0CAEC731"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Cocaine.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2DD878EFBDF24E7781FDBDC0261C2B80"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Opiates.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCC56C3DFC7F4B65A0866C219B93E4F8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Amphetamines.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4C5C54ED249410CBA4622A1E837388E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Methamphetamine.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A31C6F7F6864963AD177D1B4315CD7A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Phencyclidine.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1D3E2DA0DE1741699BCC96DFEF4272F6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notice of Mandatory Random Drug Testing Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less than 90 days before implementing the program required under subsection (a), the Secretary shall provide written notice to all covered employees that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4E106BAC7F954239800C66C60D93D0CB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a mandatory random drug testing program will be implemented; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H79A4BFC189C44877AE344160A3585D70"><enum>(2)</enum><text>covered employees will have the opportunity, and reasonable time, to submit medical documentation of lawful use of a drug listed under subsection (a)(2).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAC49170547C240BA8CAC0C9B25593D34"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notification of Selection</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="HF31D3AAEF97A4931B92CC61CA3DC9E2C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>notify a covered employee selected for random drug testing under this section on the same day of, but prior to, such testing; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H07FF5EA44FD7459091100860E160FE74"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include in the notification an assurance that the covered employee was selected randomly and is under no suspicion of illegal drug use.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5C767867183D4441A26FD3B0B27D4A5C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Deferral of Testing</header><text>A covered employee selected for random drug testing under this section may obtain a deferral of testing if the covered employee is—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8DACF5C36D8A48999E569CC5E1C924DE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in a leave status; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA253E8F601324E39BED0CD4BB2B82AF2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in official travel status away from the test site or will embark on official travel that was scheduled prior to the notification of selection under subsection (c).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEE9A534CF342467489211FC779B48D57"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Finding of Illegal Drug Use and Disciplinary Consequences</header>
 <paragraph id="HD25B3E51F5B04ECBA73A7F63B88C4F32"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Finding of Illegal Drug Use</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may determine that a covered employee has engaged in illegal drug use based on any of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6C35E20DA1C6426AA6E32A4341F0DA0E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A verified positive test result from a specimen submitted by the covered employee.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9A29BF9F15F4F83879B710F75ADEBCC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Direct observation by a higher-level supervisor, including observed illegal drug use and the unlawful possession of a drug listed under subsection (a)(2).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8AE663980CBA4E2E813106A1B11674F3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Evidence obtained from an arrest or criminal conviction of the covered employee.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4260B672A2174D78AE6AEE20917DF6E3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The voluntary admission of the covered employee.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EE644EFEAA14E7C8FE7FF939053C1C0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Mandatory Administrative Action</header>
 <subparagraph id="HCC3CBC27F9A84912A9EBA85CE6E03908"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a covered employee is found to have engaged in illegal drug use under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</text>
 <clause id="HC9444D95444B447085E8F5E712BC52BC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>prohibit the covered employee from performing any activity related to providing health care or administrative services to patients; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H50CF6C232F7743F790BA66D03B39C02C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>refer such employee to the Employee Assistance Program of the Department of Health and Human Services.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8A4CA6DD983487EAF4851CBC2018662"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Return to Duty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the discretion of the Secretary, a covered employee may return to performing activities related to providing health care or administrative services to patients after obtaining counseling or rehabilitation through the Employee Assistance Program.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H866BE160CA814BE6A3A7F23390770B0B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Adverse Actions</header>
 <subparagraph id="H0661770C45C94EB69C6F41C42DDB86F7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subsection (g), in addition to carrying out the required actions under paragraph (2), the Secretary may initiate an adverse action, including removal, against a covered employee who is found to have engaged in illegal drug use under paragraph (1).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4BEF5E07F27453F9505F101FC20F478"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Voluntary Admission Exception</header><text>The Secretary may not initiate an adverse action under subparagraph (A) against a covered employee who—</text>
 <clause id="HD5298FE7F48F4529B8857081DA8D4E51"><enum>(i)</enum><text>voluntarily admits to illegal drug use;</text> </clause><clause id="H34BD0F65B15649F785B714245C265648"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ceases such illegal drug use; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9950404BB8BE4863AFEDB28827F9AD8B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>obtains counseling or rehabilitation through the Employee Assistance Program.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H27118E1D3B3141BEB987B8895A99134E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Refusal To Submit to Random Drug Testing and Disciplinary Consequences</header><text>If a covered employee refuses to submit to random drug testing under this section when so required, the Secretary—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA8CA8B1441064DD3BADB227AE1B66F3D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall prohibit the covered employee from performing any activity related to providing health care or administrative services to patients; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC0B9DC231E7941369FF3CFCBD6DE8074"><enum>(2)</enum><text>subject to subsection (g), may initiate an adverse action, including removal, against such employee.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEC1C854CB5064FC0A3EB116D21473EBA"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Due Process</header><text>In carrying out an adverse action under this section against a covered employee, the Secretary shall provide the covered employee with notice and an opportunity to respond.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2EC95115EDD841D1A49506BE4EB3BFF0"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Appeals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered employee subject to an administrative or adverse action under this section may appeal such action to the Merit Systems Protection Board under section 7701 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0DB24981155443D59210D04D84405D34"><enum>(i)</enum><header>No Additional Funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated for the purpose of carrying out this section. This section shall be carried out using amounts otherwise available for such purpose.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8DCDE4CF2E0D4079BC07D699AD02F89B"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section:</text> <paragraph id="HAA0248179CCE4990B3679EB1448C25CA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered Employee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered employee</quote>—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB08AC7438BAB46BF9E7E2472CB45FA47"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means an individual who—</text> <clause id="HD022B4E331594D1AB609DB55139270D6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is employed in a part-time or full-time position at a health care facility of the Indian Health Service (excluding Tribal contract or compact health centers and urban Indian health centers); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB09165D9E72741B38A580599211FD3DA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provides health care or administrative services to patients at such health care facility; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H76AAF6A2ED484900A260C382C37BBB04"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include officers of the Commissioned Corps of the United States Public Health Service.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA69BB86F00E6448281AA45331FD82D77"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Employee Assistance Program</header><text>The term <quote>Employee Assistance Program</quote> means the Employee Assistance Program of the Department of Health and Human Services.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD289F2E60E7A40308B498AEDE9609395"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Illegal Drug Use</header><text>The term <quote>illegal drug use</quote> means the unlawful use of a drug listed under subsection (a)(2) by a covered employee.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H33B00543E5B9437EBE8EE95D14D5BA55"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Random Drug Testing</header><text>The term <quote>random drug testing</quote> means drug testing that is imposed on a covered employee without individualized suspicion that such employee is engaging, or has engaged, in illegal drug use.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H040E386A0967482BAF81F2628B2D2520"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Indian Health Service.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5B84BCB41A9343D7942FD286FE9E8E4A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Specimen</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>specimen</quote> means urine collected from a covered employee for the purpose of random drug testing under this section.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


