<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H836CBFB84DA0409C91B61E658D2991CF" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2901 IH: Volunteer Income Tax Assistance Permanence Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2901</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170615">June 15, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001107">Mr. Curbelo of Florida</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to make permanent the Volunteer Income Tax Assistance
			 matching grant program.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H263CAADE73B6462FA09FD48978978730" style="OLC">
 <section id="H1D6D4DA85DD44975850032C43457C2F9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Volunteer Income Tax Assistance Permanence Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2048A6D425204F6CB4B4A5E4363DC31C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Return preparation programs for low-income taxpayers</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCCA58B44473648B6A43D60A93AFAC25B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/77">Chapter 77</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after section 7526 the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFA49CD668B984C5188420433CAB81579" style="OLC">
					<section id="H607328249A9A47F0916A939D9C010CD5"><enum>7526A.</enum><header>Return preparation programs for low-income taxpayers</header>
 <subsection id="H4D89DCD0538745CC884D147697D16650"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of Volunteer Income Tax Assistance Matching Grant Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, through the Internal Revenue Service, shall establish a Community Volunteer Income Tax Assistance Matching Grant Program under which the Secretary may, subject to the availability of appropriated funds, make grants to provide matching funds for the development, expansion, or continuation of qualified return preparation programs assisting low-income taxpayers and members of underserved populations.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H43BEDDD246234A7DAC04A71450284AAD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header>
 <paragraph id="H5E929845C8E54EA38421D9F6837D4F5F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Qualified return preparation programs may use grants received under this section for—</text> <subparagraph id="HFCA6819765C148F8B2941AABE4614DD7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ordinary and necessary costs associated with program operation in accordance with cost principles under the applicable Office of Management and Budget circular, including—</text>
 <clause id="HD79C07D0750B4B4CA7CB69AFC539EAA8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>wages or salaries of persons coordinating the activities of the program,</text> </clause><clause id="HB077422752BB45B185D8081A3983E3A1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>developing training materials, conducting training, and performing quality reviews of the returns prepared under the program,</text>
 </clause><clause id="H60FB28ADB8B348AC86FECF48661CEF17"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>equipment purchases, and</text> </clause><clause id="H086A459A89904E4EB8C2BF772BBA44EC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>vehicle-related expenses associated with remote or rural tax preparation services,</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D42FF8CB0124C90BB45EA353114F3CE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>outreach and educational activities described in subsection (c)(2)(B), and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H286EF426C3BE45018A1CD71586179C3E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>services related to financial education and capability, asset development, and the establishment of savings accounts in connection with tax return preparation.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B834C191C3648EC87C493CE78FDBAEB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of grants for overhead expenses prohibited</header><text>No grant received under this section may be used for overhead expenses that are not directly related to a qualified return preparation program.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFDC46ADE6F3D4ED5A34436BA6D9DA8BB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header>
 <paragraph id="HCA3E759E830D4CDC9BA640CE483545B7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each applicant for a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may reasonably require.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9D22D8E8A2C74CDF922638A19E79152C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to applications which demonstrate—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8B6883985EC745FA95FB1A48CEF2A802"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assistance to low-income taxpayers, with emphasis on outreach to, and services for, such taxpayers,</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F9E861ECFA1402889A7EA332E8242C4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>taxpayer outreach and educational activities relating to eligibility and availability of income supports available through the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, including the earned income tax credit, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21F350F08E694767969A75452EEBFCFB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>specific outreach and focus on one or more underserved populations.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9D220952CFE4E8B96EFE6AEC6E2DC23"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Amounts taken into account</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining matching grants under this section, the Secretary shall only take into account amounts provided by the qualified return preparation program for expenses described in subsection (b).</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF4E029EF9D5F479DBC7C076A08C02B95"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Accuracy reviews</header>
 <paragraph id="H53B29E4CE67B456F801B475D7D0C441A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish procedures for, and shall conduct, periodic site visits of qualified return preparation programs operating under a grant under this section—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H91D6BDB83F25458EAA8259BBEB4B0682"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to ensure such programs are carrying out the purposes of this section, and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F6FF7FA084645D6B6D9EEFCB0634270"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to determine the return preparation accuracy rate of the program.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H77B9E147D6C240F2A6660081514F7CED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional requirements for grant recipients not meeting minimum standards</header><text>In the case of any qualified return preparation program which—</text> <subparagraph id="H3E59DFF37C7B4BE9889E730F7C68483A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is awarded a grant under this section, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD586B0E566324277883201BACB21370A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is subsequently determined—</text> <clause id="HF03B12816D374318AF09DBEAF40E5874"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to have a less than 90 percent average accuracy rate for preparation of tax returns, or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3D446B435E0343BB8830A9E90AD5B1A5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not to be otherwise carrying out the purposes of this section,</text> </clause></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">such program shall not be eligible for any additional grants under this section unless such program provides sufficient documentation of corrective measures established to address any such deficiencies determined.</continuation-text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H141A0859A1214B1FA49619B216734BE9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section—</text>
 <paragraph id="HEC4E0894BB8440579C3187F5FACA39C1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Qualified return preparation program</header><text>The term <quote>qualified return preparation program</quote> means any program—</text> <subparagraph id="HACA101ED23134B388399684B8958DE5F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>which provides assistance to individuals, not less than 90 percent of whom are low-income taxpayers, in preparing and filing Federal income tax returns,</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7945048B6C0D4EBEA4C29A74FFB6EB4C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>which is administered by a qualified entity,</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H18E623E27C58461489F2C4E0387EAE2F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in which all volunteers who assist in the preparation of Federal income tax returns meet the training requirements prescribed by the Secretary, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC902B72E4C284997BE1AD694C1CAB735"><enum>(D)</enum><text>which uses a quality review process which reviews 100 percent of all returns.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H98C03936E382479A8F6E7149E8223786"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified entity</header> <subparagraph id="H1FE325112000463EA7018280D9D7F629"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>qualified entity</quote> means any entity which—</text>
 <clause id="H7D2A792098A943B78A3B33453A957907"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is an eligible organization,</text> </clause><clause id="H94DBD9AF02F647F688CD63521C4BE291"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is in compliance with Federal tax filing and payment requirements,</text>
 </clause><clause id="H00329AEB6446498099E32BA25A4D56C8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is not debarred or suspended from Federal contracts, grants, or cooperative agreements, and</text> </clause><clause id="HDBD3BB6AC5414D36B8DF81948126026A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>agrees to provide documentation to substantiate any matching funds provided pursuant to the grant program under this section.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H280DF898081B4331A6BABE5A291A43A1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligible organization</header><text>The term <term>eligible organization</term> means—</text> <clause id="H120C33A5461B44C7AF3230E0FBA823EF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an institution of higher education which is described in section 102 (other than subsection (a)(1)(C) thereof) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>), as in effect on the date of the enactment of this section, and which has not been disqualified from participating in a program under title IV of such Act,</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFC63D9725BF2495DBB47F49B5BEC0C92"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an organization described in section 501(c) and exempt from tax under section 501(a),</text> </clause><clause id="H11037DA16B974AD49F1B3739145E814B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a local government agency, including—</text>
 <subclause id="H35400ADFD3DB403691761FAECF3C5E16"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a county or municipal government agency, and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H170A6FF416CD4DB483D6367C3F58A6A3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an Indian tribe, as defined in section 4(13) of the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4103">25 U.S.C. 4103(13)</external-xref>), including any tribally designated housing entity (as defined in section 4(22) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4103">25 U.S.C. 4103(22)</external-xref>)), tribal subsidiary, subdivision, or other wholly owned tribal entity,</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HCD86E1C4D3D447D39480A1DA973979F0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a local, State, regional, or national coalition (with one lead organization which meets the eligibility requirements of clause (i), (ii), or (iii) acting as the applicant organization), or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HED45F3DEFE834A3BA903672B187B01CD"><enum>(v)</enum><text>in the case of a targeted population or community with respect to which no organizations described in the preceding clauses are available—</text>
 <subclause id="HF16859F0251C45F59567E025DBAC5250"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a State government agency, or</text> </subclause><subclause id="HB9C2477FE424414C8A2D79E7931EF66A"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an office providing Cooperative Extension services (as established at the land-grant colleges and universities under the Smith-Lever Act of May 8, 1914).</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3AB77748714741859F1FECB8F5D812CC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Low-income taxpayers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>low-income taxpayer</quote> means a taxpayer whose income for the taxable year does not exceed an amount equal to the completed phaseout amount under section 32(b) for a married couple filing a joint return with 3 or more qualifying children, as determined in a revenue procedure or other published guidance.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0C97820819434086833BEF4D6C4D49B2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Underserved population</header><text>The term <quote>underserved population</quote> includes populations of persons with disabilities, persons with limited English proficiency, Native Americans, individuals living in rural areas, members of the Armed Forces and their spouses, and the elderly.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H95266F114BD443F7A167688A37188C62"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Special rules and limitations</header>
 <paragraph id="HFA90ED42FF7147A1AE4849F5B2818C5B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Duration of grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon application of a qualified return preparation program, the Secretary is authorized to award a multi-year grant not to exceed 3 years.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H55262EF365074CE0A4C8173B2A5E4715"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Aggregate limitation</header><text>Unless otherwise provided by specific appropriation, the Secretary shall not allocate more than $30,000,000 per fiscal year (exclusive of costs of administering the program) to grants under this section.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB9DC7508B3674F64A676FB126AFC556F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Promotion and referral</header>
 <paragraph id="H8F17A2ED02E9472EBA6B5B3CEA40290A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Promotion</header><text>The Secretary shall promote tax preparation through qualified return preparation programs through the use of mass communications, referrals, and other means.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA2E04B6E5B99472F9292187AC93D6CD3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Internal Revenue Service referrals</header><text>The Secretary may refer taxpayers to qualified return preparation programs receiving grants under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7A81E1438D814283972F69D9AE22DB80"><enum>(3)</enum><header>VITA grantee referral</header><text>Qualified return preparation programs receiving a grant under this section are encouraged to refer, as appropriate, to local or regional Low Income Taxpayer Clinics individuals who are eligible for such clinics.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H615DDE78BC184BAAA14481C33412A8BC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for chapter 77 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 7526 the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H67E81AA69E58434B997D8185124F76DF" style="OLC">
					<toc>
						<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">7526A. Return preparation programs for low-income taxpayers.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


