<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H537173552BAF4DF193A71E01825B2CA2" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2227 IH: MGT Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2227</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170428">April 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001073">Mr. Hurd</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001076">Mr. Chaffetz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001105">Mrs. Comstock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000063">Mr. Yoder</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000477">Mr. Taylor</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000377">Ms. Granger</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Appropriations</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To modernize Government information technology, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H7E246947C40E4D6F9AA52270C7199B03" style="OLC">
 <section id="HEC85331F7EE74ACF8B7C5DC202E3FFD2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Modernizing Government Technology Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote>MGT Act</quote>.</text> </section><section id="HEC1207123204496B90F912CF56AA9D77"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; purposes</header> <subsection id="HE3983969449146538148C1C15D897D79"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HED95D152882543908F74DD15310A8C64"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Government spends nearly 75 percent of its annual information technology funding on operating and maintaining existing legacy information technology systems. These systems can pose operational risks, including rising costs and inability to meet mission requirements. These systems also pose security risks, including the inability to use current security best practices, such as data encryption and multi-factor authentication, making these systems particularly vulnerable to malicious cyber activity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2467B6EC8C164C33A5333101A114940B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 2015, the Government Accountability Office (GAO) designated Improving the Management of IT Acquisitions and Operations to its biannual High Risk List and identified as a particular concern the increasing level of information technology spending on operations and maintenance, making less funding available for development or modernization. The GAO also found the Government has spent billions on failed and poorly performing information technology investments due to a lack of effective oversight.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9F5C09D1992A42F8B030F2019A52786C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Government must modernize Federal IT systems to mitigate existing operational and security risks.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF1A21CF3DB2B4E5CBB492DBFE1C6DDC6"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The efficiencies, cost savings, and greater computing power offered by modernized solutions, such as cloud computing, have the potential to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD1AC8CB8E2C74BE08D6CA01C617EB1BC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>eliminate inappropriate duplication and reduce costs;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA9F39EFAE0745A5B67B91F27E88731B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>address the critical need for cybersecurity by design; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDBD9A239BE834C5DB0A8FF4704244E2C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>move the Federal Government into a broad, digital-services delivery model that will transform the ability of the Federal Government to meet mission requirements and deliver services to the American people.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBF63CA6EF55246BDAD95E7AEC858550E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this Act are the following:</text> <paragraph id="H85004FBD8F914AA08785D2D5F90F1B40"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assist the Federal Government in modernized Federal information technology to mitigate current operational and security risks.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H37F64E6C1BC349DC851380DFDC6D7E6C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Incentivize cost savings in Federal information technology through modernization.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H67A433EC14D14D319190C840303370A3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Accelerate the acquisition and deployment of modernized information technology solutions, such as cloud computing, by addressing impediments in the areas of funding, development, and acquisition practices.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H76884BE84E05449590F6C373134023CE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of agency Information Technology Systems Modernization and Working Capital Funds</header>
			<subsection id="HEE1F215440164AC6A705A10ED17C39ED"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Information Technology System Modernization and Working Capital Funds</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HB23472D90389454EBA6E10BC47238F41"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of a covered agency may establish within such agency an information technology system modernization and working capital fund (in this section referred to as the <quote>IT working capital fund</quote>) for necessary expenses described in paragraph (3).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H78171FFB94F54D9DA83CFA8572F468B2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Source of funds</header><text>The following amounts may be deposited into an IT working capital fund:</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H8E6D64C19D21438D9ACAF9AA26778788"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reprogramming and transfer of funds made available in appropriations Acts subsequent to the date of the enactment of this Act, including transfer of any funds for the operation and maintenance of legacy information technology systems, in compliance with any applicable reprogramming law or guidelines of the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HFB1C2D9A8FB446A9AD698042105E3363"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts made available to the IT working capital fund through discretionary appropriations made available subsequent to the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF2A0100B6354EC7A83FA2D32B784D61"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An IT working capital fund established under paragraph (1) may be used, subject to the availability of appropriations, only for the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2AAD9379964D42909827D24043C51E4E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To improve, retire, or replace existing information technology systems in the covered agency to enhance cybersecurity and to improve efficiency and effectiveness.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C86BEA1A5944CE99A63869C82ED1B91"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To transition legacy information technology systems at the covered agency to cloud computing and other innovative platforms and technologies, including those serving more than one covered agency with common requirements.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0A848B605BE43559D71458E052C2C9B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>To assist and support covered agency efforts to provide adequate, risk-based, and cost-effective information technology capabilities that address evolving threats to information security.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5876F534786A4EBFB789DDB6C6245A7B"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To reimburse funds transferred to the covered agency from the Technology Modernization Fund established under section 4, with the approval of the Chief Information Officer of the covered agency.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE9C108CACCC041419C1ADFE958E7E7BC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Existing funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An IT working capital fund may not be used to supplant funds provided for the operation and maintenance of any system within an appropriation for the covered agency at the time of establishment of the IT working capital fund.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HBBB5D87E456D4E998E6804A0B45BF6F7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Prioritization of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of each covered agency shall prioritize funds within the IT working capital fund to be used initially for cost savings activities approved by the Chief Information Officer of the covered agency, in consultation with the Administrator of the Office of Electronic Government. The head of each covered agency may reprogram and transfer any amounts saved as a direct result of such activities for deposit into the applicable IT working capital fund, consistent with paragraph (2)(A).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H9E32C91875EA40C58E771989ED0BFA92"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Return of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any funds deposited into an IT working capital fund shall be available for obligation for three years after the last day of the fiscal year in which such funds were deposited.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF19F73DDCDC042EF823D8EF16A1DC5B4"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Agency CIO responsibilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In evaluating projects to be funded from the IT working capital fund, the Chief Information Officer of the covered agency shall consider, to the extent applicable, guidance issued pursuant to section 4(a)(1) to evaluate applications for funding from the Technology Modernization Fund established under that section that include factors such as a strong business case, technical design, procurement strategy (including adequate use of incremental software development practices), and program management.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H6FCE25AAFE144C92BFE41D144BE0BE27"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H66C09A3DF3A54125960C6BA4C4512121"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every six months thereafter, the head of each covered agency shall submit to the Director the following, with respect to the IT working capital fund for the covered agency:</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H99C5ABEB1ED442CF96355277E8A96525"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A list of each information technology investment funded with estimated cost and completion date for each such investment.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H171C8DA2EB624570B60C226124311451"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A summary by fiscal year of obligations, expenditures, and unused balances.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H04A7EFB2C72D4315A8195E62835B9DA3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Director shall make the information submitted under paragraph (1) publicly available on a website.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6CE8F9AB73AF476D92C6F3DB72C8E31F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Covered agency defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>covered agency</term> means each agency listed in section 901(b) of title 31, United States Code.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H5B0CB7B39E794CD082F7B74F679F6579"><enum>4.</enum><header>Establishment of Technology Modernization Fund and Board</header> <subsection id="H8C862D4CEE4E42FEAAD199028E77AB7B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Technology Modernization Fund</header> <paragraph id="H0634CA5DDDE041E99B0E87AB3FEE2286"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established in the Treasury a Technology Modernization Fund (in this section referred to as the <quote>Fund</quote>) for technology-related activities, to improve information technology, to enhance cybersecurity across the Federal Government, and to be administered in accordance with guidance issued by the Director.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA34E1BD1D9604B688FB36BD18C23A1C8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administration of Fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner of the Technology Transformation Service of the General Services Administration, in consultation with the Chief Information Officers Council and with the approval of the Director, shall administer the Fund in accordance with this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HDFA88D4FABB048BEB49BF22984F7CFA2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner shall, in accordance with the recommendations of the Technology Modernization Board established under subsection (b), use amounts in the Fund for the following purposes:</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HA899AF217C4E48DABBD9E9B9E3A6D4A3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>To transfer such amounts, to remain available until expended, to the head of an agency to improve, retire, or replace existing Federal information technology systems to enhance cybersecurity and improve efficiency and effectiveness.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H879FC1037E8E43059B40320F9CA1856F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>For the development, operation, and procurement of information technology products, services, and acquisition vehicles for use by agencies to improve Governmentwide efficiency and cybersecurity in accordance with the requirements of such agencies.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8C8C0A0433CE48A5A26BED99E9318270"><enum>(C)</enum><text>To provide services or work performed in support of the activities described under subparagraph (A) or (B).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE65CA351DE124335A3A3FF46C3E0A6F5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations; credits; availability of funds</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H25B0D15E6FDB479F98AEB9B4F4F04A52"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Fund $250,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 and 2019.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HDAD48D4011F7499BAA9E8ACAC8410C5C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Credits</header><text>In addition to any funds otherwise appropriated, the Fund shall be credited with all reimbursements, advances, or refunds or recoveries relating to information technology or services provided through the Fund.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H57C348DDEDF243939E40F264860A56EB"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Availability of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts deposited, credited, or otherwise made available to the Fund shall be available, as provided in appropriations Acts, until expended for the purposes described in paragraph (3).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B5717A0E1A2463DA6BA2B74BB6A4CC2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Reimbursement</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H83C448FFAB40420696E45B217D14A588"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Payment by agency</header><text>For a product or service developed under paragraph (3)(B), including any services or work performed in support of such development under paragraph (3)(C), the head of an agency that uses such product or service shall pay an amount fixed by the Commissioner in accordance with this paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HEC280C6AC5C8495CA83FD65635FAD839"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reimbursement by agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of an agency shall reimburse the Fund for any transfer made under paragraph (3)(A), including any services or work performed in support of such transfer under paragraph (3)(C), in accordance with the terms established in a written agreement described in paragraph (6). Notwithstanding any other provision of law, an agency may make a reimbursement required by this subparagraph from any appropriation made available subsequent to the date of the enactment of this Act for information technology activities, consistent with any applicable reprogramming law or guidelines of the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate. An obligation to make a payment under a written agreement described in paragraph (6) in a fiscal year after the date of the enactment of this Act shall be recorded pursuant to section 1501 of title 31, United States Code, in the fiscal year in which the payment is due.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE0E6E3106D8D46FC83925A2D7BA8E4C7"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Prices fixed by Commissioner</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner, in consultation with the Director, shall establish amounts to be paid by an agency and terms of repayment for use of a product or service developed under paragraph (3)(B), including any services or work performed in support of such development under paragraph (3)(C), at levels sufficient to ensure the solvency of the Fund, including operating expenses. Before making any changes to the established amounts and terms of repayment, the Commissioner shall conduct a review and obtain approval from the Director.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1901E161F0F24333950CD098473C2AF6"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Failure to make timely reimbursement</header><text>The Commissioner may obtain reimbursement by the issuance of transfer and counterwarrants, or other lawful transfer documents, supported by itemized bills, if payment is not made by an agency—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H322DF38B6E2A4348BE781A561E70AB29"><enum>(i)</enum><text>within 90 days after the expiration of a repayment period described in a written agreement described in paragraph (6); or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HA6E95D43CC6649F48AE19D13FFE4630C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>within 45 days after the expiration of the time period to make a payment under a payment schedule for a product or service developed under paragraph (3)(B).</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF29BAE3CAFE40838E242C9505B3A5D2"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Written agreement</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H96438616430B4FE2A34DFB2691EC6923"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before the transfer of funds to an agency under paragraph (3)(A), the Commissioner (in consultation with the Director) and the head of the requisitioning agency shall enter into a written agreement documenting the purpose for which the funds will be used and the terms of repayment, which may not exceed five years unless approved by the Director. An agreement made pursuant to this subparagraph shall be recorded as an obligation as provided in paragraph (5)(B).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4D5694DDC46475596DB019F8DCA8922"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirement for use of incremental development practices</header><text>For any funds transferred to an agency under paragraph (3)(A), in the absence of compelling circumstances documented by the Commissioner at the time of transfer, such funds shall be transferred only on an incremental basis, tied to metric-based development milestones achieved by the agency, to be described in a written agreement required under subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H83FD466ACD8D41A2B6FFE7ACFA0908CB"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than six months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director shall publish and maintain a list of each project funded by the Fund on a public website, to be updated not less than quarterly, that includes a description of the project, project status (including any schedule delay and cost overruns), and financial expenditure data related to the project.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9742345017484B9EB684854B3CD8EFD9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technology Modernization Board</header>
 <paragraph id="HB495065628654C39AF93AA8F22450B2D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established a Technology Modernization Board (in this section referred to as the <quote>Board</quote>) to evaluate proposals submitted by agencies for funding authorized under the Fund.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9F862C8A70474DA3808BC325F9A84B79"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>The responsibilities of the Board are the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD8258696237441E5904CAF931385374C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Provide input to the Director for the development of processes for agencies to submit modernization proposals to the Board and to establish the criteria by which such proposals are evaluated, which shall include addressing the greatest security and operational risks, having the greatest Governmentwide impact, and having a high probability of success based on factors such as a strong business case, technical design, procurement strategy (including adequate use of incremental software development practices), and program management.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HCA1991C8CEC94B41A260257EB030D626"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Make recommendations to the Commissioner to assist agencies in the further development and refinement of select submitted modernization proposals, based on an initial evaluation performed with the assistance of the Commissioner.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3D9CB91E265C45A2AE2B40BF8F59BDC8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Review and prioritize, with the assistance of the Commissioner and the Director, modernization proposals based on criteria established pursuant to subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE22001CC934740A6AE59B1AABA986A2C"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identify, with the assistance of the Commissioner, opportunities to improve or replace multiple information technology systems with a smaller number of information technology systems common to multiple agencies.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9E832E330CD14AC3BE9B464D734A5F29"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommend the funding of modernization projects, in accordance with the uses described in subsection (a)(3), to the Commissioner.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8E8D4442317E48A38E5217606357E267"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Monitor, in consultation with the Commissioner, progress and performance in executing approved projects and, if necessary, recommend the suspension or termination of funding for projects based on factors such as failure to meet the terms of a written agreement described in subsection (a)(6).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H409B8DC249A145038EF2D4E91E02D20A"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Monitor operating costs of the Fund.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD5A2015FF9284EB08A1D5AA5E06044FE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Board shall consist of eight voting members.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD5D7ED9D07F24D948061F76F737A2CB4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Chair</header><text>The Chair of the Board shall be the Administrator of the Office of Electronic Government.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4770F3486F5F45009759F67F07C5F48E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Permanent members</header><text>The permanent members of the Board shall be the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H51E353232BC84E788BBD017B3E810AFC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Administrator of the Office of Electronic Government.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HEAA1EF8F85B441ADB3A3F968836D4BDB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A senior official from the General Services Administration having technical expertise in information technology development, appointed by the Administrator of General Services, with the approval of the Director.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5CF6DE9BD3BA45499AD4976CA6C85B1A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Additional members of the Board</header>
 <subparagraph id="H33396C2881B1440582E717E3340706E1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text>The other members of the Board shall be appointed as follows:</text> <clause commented="no" id="HF5592E69131B472981FE08896B5BB48D"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">One employee of the National Protection and Programs Directorate of the Department of Homeland Security, appointed by the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0DACEB7BCD0649DE86E81D049956E3B1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>One employee of the Department of Defense, appointed by the Secretary of Defense.</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H70EA17A034BA4EA4845F9B66784C76CE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Four Federal employees primarily having technical expertise in information technology development, financial management, cybersecurity and privacy, and acquisition, appointed by the Director.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6008DBEB9C494FA995F819465A0786C6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Term</header><text>Each member of the Board described in paragraph (A) shall serve a term of one year, which shall be renewable up to three times, at the discretion of the appointing Secretary or Director, as applicable.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC72727E732D44B9B73EE7A63F7D7C94"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Prohibition on compensation</header><text>Members of the Board may not receive additional pay, allowances, or benefits by reason of their service on the Board.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA947BF96354E483A9BB41D72D26D5AF1"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Staff</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon request of the Chair of the Board, the Director and the Administrator of General Services may detail, on a nonreimbursable basis, any of the personnel of the Office of Management and Budget or the General Services Administration (as the case may be) to the Board to assist the Board in carrying out its functions under this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4EDB71C3A01E4FA78B605EB70FB9774E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Responsibilities of Commissioner</header>
 <paragraph id="HD6C1C3EC906D40E08AB2A1E96C24BF65"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the responsibilities described in subsection (a), the Commissioner shall support the activities of the Board and provide technical support to, and, with the concurrence of the Director, oversight of, agencies that receive transfers from the Fund.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6B1C7E130E36400693171A1D5143305A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The responsibilities of the Commissioner are the following:</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HA14BED2DA87047CABCD0BFCCFCD8380B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Provide direct technical support in the form of personnel services or otherwise to agencies transferred amounts under subsection (a)(3)(A) and for products, services, and acquisition vehicles funded under subsection (a)(3)(B).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE438347A94A0446194147A93B802198B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Assist the Board with the evaluation, prioritization, and development of agency modernization proposals.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H18A62E3D6AC44F838F236AD256C39705"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Perform regular project oversight and monitoring of approved agency modernization projects, in consultation with the Board and the Director, to increase the likelihood of successful implementation and reduce waste.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H87236F934DE74162B858611D8AC285E7"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Provide the Director with information necessary to meet the requirements of subsection (a)(7).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H6BAB028A40C44E6F904976D5621CBA66"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Agency defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given that term in section 551 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HA98B84C3F785434F8981262FB5D02079"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H392B9E6CCB8E42308B78982D025B396D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Cloud computing</header><text>The term <term>cloud computing</term> has the meaning given that term by the National Institute of Standards and Technology in NIST Special Publication 800–145 and any amendatory or superseding document thereto.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H14F7BD0F74BD4293B23468ED7BD14369"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commissioner</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Commissioner</term> means the Commissioner of the Technology Transformation Service of the General Services Administration.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3FD5662F9272404DBCB08847C08B6886"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H88E9F81A113849C6AAA39CC0E5CE7BC6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Information technology</header><text>The term <term>information technology</term> has the meaning given that term in section 3502 of title 44, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE2FB32FFE53A45BF8FF8E85CE8D30F4B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Legacy information technology system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>legacy information technology system</term> means an outdated or obsolete system of information technology.</text> </paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

