<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H701BC7153EC04A5E806C9CB49EE32028" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1697 IH: Israel Anti-Boycott Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1697</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170323">March 23, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000580">Mr. Roskam</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Z000017">Mr. Zeldin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Export Administration Act of 1979 to include in the prohibitions on boycotts against
			 allies of the United States boycotts fostered by international
			 governmental organizations against Israel and to direct the Export-Import
			 Bank of the United States to oppose boycotts against Israel, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H843F8A96BF994DB68C4FB46B7AC9B577" style="OLC">
 <section id="H277E4051D6B1486AB5235AA327E5457C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Israel Anti-Boycott Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H930019410C1D4270AD2DDBB13681FF9C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H3EAA1A9F8C004E0B9EBCAFCCBA1C73FA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United Nations Human Rights Council (in this section referred to as the <quote>UNHRC</quote>) has long targeted Israel with systematic, politically motivated assaults on its legitimacy designed to stigmatize and isolate Israel internationally.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC79AA6A544FF480EA18F45E839E833E4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The UNHRC maintains a permanent agenda item known as <quote>Item 7</quote> to ensure that Israel will be criticized at every gathering of the UNHRC.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H892A8FEA21B04BCAB16C2EBDB778F64D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>At its 31st session on March 24, 2016, the UNHRC targeted Israel with a commercial boycott, calling for the establishment of a database, such as a <quote>blacklist</quote>, of companies that operate, or have business relations with entities that operate, beyond Israel’s 1949 Armistice lines, including East Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5E5EA347116B42B39BCF439CD9397BDA"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At its 32nd session in March 2017, the UNHRC is considering a resolution pursuant to agenda item 7 to withhold assistance from and prevent trade with <quote>territories occupied since 1967</quote>, including East Jerusalem, the West Bank, and the Golan Heights, stating that businesses that engage in economic activity in those areas could face could face civil or criminal legal action.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC746839653E54BF9ADA13DC4F69DF46A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>For a half century, Congress has combated anti-Israel boycotts and other discriminatory activity under the Export Administration Act of 1979 (as continued in effect pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.)), under part VI of title X of the Tax Reform Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/94/455">Public Law 94–455</external-xref>; 90 Stat. 1649) (commonly referred to as the <quote>Ribicoff Amendment</quote>), in free trade agreements with Bahrain and Oman, and in Saudi Arabia’s accession negotiations to the World Trade Organization.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H29538A2D15E643BC88A784DB049DE4D6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The recent action of the UNHRC is reminiscent of the Arab League Boycott, which also called for the establishment of a <quote>blacklist</quote> and promoted a primary, as well as a secondary and tertiary, boycott against Israel, targeting United States and other companies that trade or invest with or in Israel, designed to harm Israel, any business operating in, or doing business with, Israel, or companies that do business with companies operating in Israel.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H84E6179BC38D41B48DD321A25987F3B9"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress recently passed anti-boycott, divestment, and sanctions measures in the Bipartisan Congressional Trade Priorities and Accountability Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/4201">19 U.S.C. 4201</external-xref> et seq.) and section 909 of the Trade Facilitation and Trade Enforcement Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/4452">19 U.S.C. 4452</external-xref>), which establish, among other things—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H898A7A042CA04F34956C9216F908FD88"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the opposition of the United States to actions to boycott, divest from, or sanction Israel;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6B1ABECA5CF435B9012E401598AAE3B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>requirements that the United States utilize trade negotiations to combat state-led or international governmental organization-led actions to boycott, divest from, or sanction Israel; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5EAC0B16930B414DB6AA67FBC1F323E2"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reporting requirements regarding the actions of foreign countries or international organizations that establish barriers to trade or investment for United States companies in or with Israel.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H59C80055B10F426AA8CC4EEC9C5A9191"><enum>3.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress—</text> <paragraph id="H1CD26254581B4F5FB5B169C1584D3533"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">opposes the United Nations Human Rights Council resolution of March 24, 2016, which urges countries to pressure their own companies to divest from, or break contracts with, Israel, and calls for the creation of a <quote>blacklist</quote> of companies that either operate, or have business relations with entities that operate, beyond Israel’s 1949 Armistice lines, including East Jerusalem;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD308F2ED9293404F8764E9B62D4390CC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">views such policies as actions to boycott, divest from, or sanction Israel; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3AE8D70FF33F469B881D8F48C78C5665"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in order to counter the effects of actions to boycott, divest from, or sanction Israel, encourages full implementation of the United States-Israel Strategic Partnership Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/296">Public Law 113–296</external-xref>; 128 Stat. 4075) through enhanced, governmentwide, coordinated United States-Israel scientific and technological cooperation in civilian areas such as with respect to energy, water, agriculture, alternative fuel technology, civilian space technology, and security.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section commented="no" id="H578867FB824A4F3FBA421B5E4FD97F28"><enum>4.</enum><header>Additional prohibitions relating to foreign boycotts under Export Administration Act of 1979</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H3D56A8D9B678441799BC5DC97108E5FB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Declaration of policy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3(5) of the Export Administration Act of 1979 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4602">50 U.S.C. 4602(5)</external-xref>) (as continued in effect pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.)) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H5700C18B44094C4C92C30EF678614FF2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (A) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCFDE0627B1C04CF387B31A7876953F3D" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HC3DE0BC99B1C4DE1B3EAC51E635C0C48"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to oppose—</text>
 <clause id="HEB3C443BE14B47948E122F0818D00EC3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>restrictive trade practices or boycotts fostered or imposed by foreign countries, or requests to impose restrictive trade practices or boycotts by foreign countries, against other countries friendly to the United States or against any United States person; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3C8D57B00C9F421197CC8ECC84C24BFC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">restrictive trade practices or boycotts fostered or imposed by any international governmental organization against Israel or requests to impose restrictive trade practices or boycotts by any international governmental organization against Israel;</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6E594BADEE904A7D95DB9B1037A7800A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>which have the effect</quote> and all the follows and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H26293B51BB96411192CB9E01F5FB2B13" style="OLC"> <text>which have the effect of furthering or supporting—</text><clause id="HF1B8DC5F8E9C42FB8C18E17A3DD0A0F1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">restrictive trade practices or boycotts fostered or imposed by any foreign country, or requests to impose restrictive trade practices or boycotts by any foreign country, against a country friendly to the United States or against any United States person; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8A82689C347745BEB7BCA815A66603AC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">restrictive trade practices or boycotts fostered or imposed by any international governmental organization against Israel or requests to impose restrictive trade practices or boycotts by any international governmental organization against Israel; and</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H2A88950C09FE4B8886EB04F876DC18C5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Foreign boycotts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 8 of the Export Administration Act of 1979 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4607">50 U.S.C. 4607</external-xref>) (as continued in effect pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.)) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFD2DFCCB7F254940883E8E5E96073A95"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1)—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H4A9DA852802C4F7F910BD0F6F32FD390"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the matter preceding subparagraph (A)—</text>
 <clause id="H454B685EEB6B4F7E8B7AC62940BD4483"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, or request to impose any boycott by a foreign country,</quote> after <quote>a foreign country</quote>;</text> </clause><clause id="HC54A3CE57ED14A1195BCCA91F46D5247"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting <quote>, or support any boycott fostered or imposed by any international governmental organization against Israel or request to impose any boycott by any international governmental organization against Israel</quote> after <quote>pursuant to United States law or regulation</quote>;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE36127E458464A6F884B4C7EC9528875"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>or international governmental organization (as the case may be)</quote> after <quote>of the boycotting country</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H175390C6582842CAABFAA9C9750ACF67"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (D)—</text>
 <clause id="H738F9A7E0B59479C9C41EC68D811643C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, or requesting the furnishing of information,</quote> after <quote>Furnishing information</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H240F19F5B4344D2EBC521DFCADBDD134"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or with the international governmental organization (as the case may be)</quote> after <quote>in the boycotting country</quote>; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE10AC44541D24848BAA055E6331EB019"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c)—</text> <subparagraph id="H5081016DEE1D47F1AF356D900FCF1001"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, or requests to impose restrictive trade practices or boycotts by foreign countries,</quote> after <quote>foreign countries</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9D5203703314916AC3FA3A95C0EB0AA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or restrictive trade practices or boycotts fostered or imposed by any international governmental organization against Israel or requests to impose restrictive trade practices or boycotts by any international governmental organization against Israel</quote> before the period at the end.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HB18829B6C4BB46698D9967F51835BCE1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Violations of section <enum-in-header>8(a)</enum-in-header></header><text>Section 11 of the Export Administration Act of 1979 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4610">50 U.S.C. 4610</external-xref>) (as continued in effect pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.)) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HB41C5A85C92149FDAD95632E3CE1AF51"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by inserting <quote>or (j)</quote> after <quote>subsection (b)</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H167D16148F2F44B0B208BB06C5B5A2C9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H890B95B09D1F406A8B0FBEB9456FB0D8" style="OLC">
 <subsection commented="no" id="HDD539FA6351B405A939595408205CFDA"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Violations of section <enum-in-header>8(a)</enum-in-header></header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whoever knowingly violates or conspires to or attempts to violate any provision of section 8(a) or any regulation, order, or license issued thereunder shall be fined in accordance with section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HAFFD34E41CEF44068EC8EE0310F1BB2E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition of international governmental organization</header><text>Section 16 of the Export Administration Act of 1979 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4618">50 U.S.C. 4618</external-xref>) (as continued in effect pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.)) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H47A5235A97434E599574BEF22317245B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (7) and (8) as paragraphs (8) and (9), respectively; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2F027DC5AEE64222A0C3B41F528C3EDC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (6) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HED0B1FDB6F5E4F4F93BF683E2AECF5E9" style="OLC">
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H30F0A9F408B04A2D9E65847B4083C6D9"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the term <term>international governmental organization</term> includes the United Nations and the European Union;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H04064F36C5D44350960655E7B528A9EA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act and apply with respect to actions described in section 8(a) of the Export Administration Act of 1979 (as continued in effect pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.)) taken or knowingly agreed to be taken on or after such date of enactment.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HFD285905E47F4B01B4280F3031BCB2A1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The President shall implement the amendments made by this section by exercising the authorities of the President under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HE43E37C0D9AE4D35A7B51767C1799B08"><enum>5.</enum><header>Policy of the United States relating to boycott of Israel under Export-Import Bank Act of 1945</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2(b)(1)(B) of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/635">12 U.S.C. 635(b)(1)(B)</external-xref>) is amended in the sixth sentence by inserting after <quote>child labor),</quote> the following: <quote>or opposing policies and actions that are politically motivated and are intended to penalize or otherwise limit commercial relations specifically with citizens or residents of Israel, entities organized under the laws of Israel, or the Government of Israel,</quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="H4F29993DD3DC432A85D35BB3D77773ED"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header>
 <subsection id="HA1BFB66E2CED4A2385B572BF80374D66"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HBBECC7CD47B34F15BD1EA5F85451F3C8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Actions to boycott, divest from, or sanction Israel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>actions to boycott, divest from, or sanction Israel</term> has the meaning given that term in section 102(b)(20)(B) of the Bipartisan Congressional Trade Priorities and Accountability Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/4201">19 U.S.C. 4201(b)(20)(B)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCF1E080F3CD84E45A463E86BA9E875C9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>International governmental organization</header><text>The term <term>international governmental organization</term> includes the United Nations and the European Union.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA22403D01C9D41979585FCD6561AC214"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Politically motivated</header><text>The term <term>politically motivated</term> means actions to impede or constrain commerce with Israel that are intended to coerce political action from or impose policy positions on Israel.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H71E25C3708F5475B930A904C3FDDB5F2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to alter the established policy of the United States or to establish new United States policy concerning final status issues associated with the Arab-Israeli conflict, including border delineation, that can only be resolved through direct negotiations between the parties.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


