<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H74988737F487440FBA10D631F3CEA513" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3044 IH: To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to expand supplemental benefits to meet the needs of chronically ill Medicare Advantage enrollees under the Medicare program, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3044</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170623">June 23, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001181">Mr. Meehan</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000567">Mr. Lance</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000379">Mr. Kennedy</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to expand supplemental benefits to meet the needs
			 of chronically ill Medicare Advantage enrollees under the Medicare
			 program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H2E54E153C9C14B7EAB8558D60DCCB619" style="OLC">
		<section id="HCA9354A15C344DBA8F0A7D056DA40BBF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Expanding supplemental benefits to meet the needs of chronically ill medicare advantage enrollees</header>
 <subsection id="H4A855868EA24465FA416935C165C907C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1852(a)(3) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-22">42 U.S.C. 1395w–22(a)(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HDF70F18AF3AF4C6A84AD3121838B82A0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>Each</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to subparagraph (D), each</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6C410428C5254F4D97A66CB85FBF3647"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H57EE64A385EC442E955CDBDB360EE2DD" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H5A9355EDA5ED4257A99503D6209A3641"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Expanding supplemental benefits to meet the needs of chronically ill enrollees</header> <clause id="H569390438458493FB55EA9D82DD6F280"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For plan year 2020 and subsequent plan years, in addition to any supplemental health care benefits otherwise provided under this paragraph, an MA plan may provide supplemental benefits described in clause (ii) to a chronically ill enrollee (as defined in clause (iii)).</text>
							</clause><clause id="H1C9F8A75707E4688B9F8CBDEBF49D6DD"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Supplemental benefits described</header>
 <subclause id="H209DD56374D54A1D9CA0F1C4A4D0896C"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Supplemental benefits described in this clause are supplemental benefits that, with respect to a chronically ill enrollee, have a reasonable expectation of improving or maintaining the health or overall function of the chronically ill enrollee and may not be limited to being primarily health related benefits.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD7D222F90ED3409F8DF7AB37DCC1EDD7"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Authority to waive uniformity requirements</header><text>The Secretary may, only with respect to supplemental benefits provided to a chronically ill enrollee under this subparagraph, waive the uniformity requirement under subsection (d)(1)(A), as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HAC29880D41FF4CBCA3A53F2D809C5F5D"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Chronically ill enrollee defined</header><text>In this subparagraph, the term <quote>chronically ill enrollee</quote> means an enrollee in an MA plan that the Secretary determines—</text> <subclause id="HF245AECA4EDA4101A4981C1FE1B7E42C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>has one or more comorbid and medically complex chronic conditions that is life threatening or significantly limits the overall health or function of the enrollee;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H439E3093F31F43EF9C5E8779FBA9B8AB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>has a high risk of hospitalization or other adverse health outcomes; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="H02560ADED9D84755826F2CADB6FD729A"><enum>(III)</enum><text>requires intensive care coordination.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H792011C29B5C4FAEA3A75A555936C139"><enum>(b)</enum><header>GAO Study and Report</header>
 <paragraph id="H4DAE22D5CC014C01B904CFD3D0E06ECA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Comptroller General</quote>) shall conduct a study on supplemental benefits provided to enrollees in Medicare Advantage plans under part C of title XVIII of the Social Security Act. Such study shall include an analysis of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAF7E237ACC014443805ACA0F9A43BFEC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The type of supplemental benefits provided to such enrollees, the total number of enrollees receiving each supplemental benefit, and whether the supplemental benefit is covered by the standard benchmark cost of the benefit or with an additional premium.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H985F5E3889EC4C64B209DD802A8CAB43"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The frequency in which supplemental benefits are utilized by such enrollees.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC944D3DB6CD7473D814355C5C3497850"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The impact supplemental benefits have on—</text>
 <clause id="HF329BADBCC05462694A9691809EA6313"><enum>(i)</enum><text>indicators of the quality of care received by such enrollees, including overall health and function of the enrollees;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3CBF612FC5BD45D4A063A581D85AA87C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the utilization of items and services for which benefits are available under the original Medicare fee-for-service program option under parts A and B of such title XVIII by such enrollees; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB2C31CF3797A4EAB93A2D7FB286260D4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the amount of the bids submitted by Medicare Advantage Organizations for Medicare Advantage plans under such part C.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4AA22E4920E4E44BCEF5A1C20BB0AD3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit to Congress a report containing the results of the study conducted under paragraph (1), together with recommendations for such legislation and administrative action as the Comptroller General determines appropriate.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


