<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE84A445DE9FE4A91A3969F47BFAE0175" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2904 IH: Restore Honor to Service Members Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2904</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170615">June 15, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barrag&#225;n</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001303">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Brendan F. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001304">Mr. Brown of Maryland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. C&#225;rdenas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001111">Mr. Crist</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001038">Mr. Crowley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001107">Mr. Curbelo of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000598">Mrs. Davis of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000620">Mr. Delaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000293">Ms. Esty of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Al Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001050">Ms. Hanabusa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001064">Mr. Heck</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001038">Mr. Higgins of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000379">Mr. Kennedy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000390">Mr. Kihuen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000380">Mr. Kildee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000586">Mr. Lawson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000563">Mr. Lipinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000480">Mrs. Lowey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001185">Mr. Sean Patrick Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001202">Mrs. Murphy of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000127">Mr. Nolan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000170">Mr. O'Rourke</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000593">Mr. Perlmutter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000602">Miss Rice of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000435">Ms. Ros-Lehtinen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001168">Mr. Sarbanes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001150">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001180">Mr. Schrader</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000248">Mr. Serrano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001170">Ms. Shea-Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001191">Ms. Sinema</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000465">Ms. Tsongas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000799">Mr. Walz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000062">Mr. Yarmuth</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001227">Mr. Brady of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Defense to review the discharge characterization of former members of the Armed Forces who were discharged by reason of the sexual orientation of the member, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF446FF742BCC44BDA4419C4DEF1ED157" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE2BA9176E5224D90AF518B635DB29C7E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Restore Honor to Service Members Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HEFAB355700E34E6FB5C577D828DD3E57"><enum>2.</enum><header>Review of discharge characterization</header> <subsection id="HDAABB27B64B7457199C56D43F81FAE89"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In accordance with this section, the appropriate discharge boards—</text> 
<paragraph id="H807C0D5636D74D9DAB4FF9F049EC7D2C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall review the discharge characterization of covered members at the request of the covered member; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H60FE6798374542FBAA2B7100276F4705"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if such characterization is any characterization except honorable, may change such characterization to honorable.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBF32AC68704C4077B704E6D0C1F54CA0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In changing the discharge characterization of a covered member to honorable under subsection (a)(2), the Secretary of Defense shall ensure that such changes are carried out consistently and uniformly across the military departments using the following criteria:</text> <paragraph id="H643E8C61CD0C4582AB386C3EF29FCBE6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The original discharge must be based on Don’t Ask Don’t Tell (in this Act referred to as <term>DADT</term>) or a similar policy in place prior to the enactment of DADT.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3704683EEEFF4562B024B8EEDF9F02B1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such discharge characterization shall be so changed if, with respect to the original discharge, there were no aggravating circumstances, such as misconduct, that would have independently led to a discharge characterization that was any characterization except honorable. For purposes of this paragraph, such aggravating circumstances may not include—</text> <subparagraph id="HFF89D9F09F564E0FA8AC1960E6BEB47F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an offense under section 925 of title 10, United States Code (article 125 of the Uniform Code of Military Justice), committed by a covered member against a person of the same sex with the consent of such person; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9E5C30E275B94C128AABD57C05BED237"><enum>(B)</enum><text>statements, consensual sexual conduct, or consensual acts relating to sexual orientation or identity, or the disclosure of such statements, conduct, or acts, that were prohibited at the time of discharge but after the date of such discharge became permitted.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H39D40FDF784A499E96D3F1BAD675C1DB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>When requesting a review, a covered member, or their representative, shall be required to provide either—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H245E47DA45D54A169CA07A53B18C6853"><enum>(A)</enum><text>documents consisting of—</text> <clause id="H6B3A490E341F4D308A55D1B92AC2CA92"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a copy of the DD–214 form of the member;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC80FC2E78DAF4572A1ADED909222291F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a personal affidavit of the circumstances surrounding the discharge; and</text></clause> <clause id="HD34ABC2651FB462886CCCDDA417690D1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any relevant records pertaining to the discharge; or</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H29300108A27D40E59011F14B3A57320E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an affidavit certifying that the member, or their representative, does not have the documents specified in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H783D265806E74F96A7AAC281C0081DA1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>If a covered member provides an affidavit described in subparagraph (B) of paragraph (3)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD3F5458D2EB1475DB7694DA30B4FDFC2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the appropriate discharge board shall make every effort to locate the documents specified in subparagraph (A) of such paragraph within the records of the Department of Defense; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7E1974F695C54D9CA164279D40840E62"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the absence of such documents may not be considered a reason to deny a change of the discharge characterization under subsection (a)(2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2CEC8275A1694E3C943BFDE8F37D8B93"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Request for review</header><text>The appropriate discharge board shall ensure the mechanism by which covered members, or their representative, may request to have the discharge characterization of the covered member reviewed under this section is simple and straightforward.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1C3DF90303504548A0105048F24FF49E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Review</header> <paragraph id="H92E5A3531AE84649A5C693CF80AF3295"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>After a request has been made under subsection (c), the appropriate discharge board shall review all relevant laws, records of oral testimony previously taken, service records, or any other relevant information regarding the discharge characterization of the covered member.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6A7FC39A4AFD4FAE9FCA9B7A8DA3FFF9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional materials</header><text>If additional materials are necessary for the review, the appropriate discharge board—</text> <subparagraph id="H24550F917E7F4B7492E6F0019A9505DE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may request additional information from the covered member or their representative, in writing, and specifically detailing what is being requested; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB2EE1B5DC0C847A89EDCF0D829CEA74B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall be responsible for obtaining a copy of the necessary files of the covered member from the member, or when applicable, from the Department of Defense.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6668E43B0742467B8D67CF163F2D949C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Change of characterization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The appropriate discharge board shall change the discharge characterization of a covered member to honorable if such change is determined to be appropriate after a review is conducted under subsection (d) pursuant to the criteria under subsection (b). A covered member, or the representative of the member, may appeal a decision by the appropriate discharge board to not change the discharge characterization by using the regular appeals process of the board.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1CB988A01DF04CEA936914322CDDDD83"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Change of records</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each covered member whose discharge characterization is changed under subsection (e), or for each covered member who was honorably discharged but whose DD–214 form reflects the sexual orientation of the member, the Secretary of Defense shall reissue to the member or their representative a revised DD–214 form that reflects the following:</text> <paragraph id="HF87CD68540B54CB9ADF6A419400D7542"><enum>(1)</enum><text>For each covered member discharged, the Separation Code, Reentry Code, Narrative Code, and Separation Authority shall not reflect the sexual orientation of the member and shall be placed under secretarial authority. Any other similar indication of the sexual orientation or reason for discharge shall be removed or changed accordingly to be consistent with this paragraph.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H049CF658DA93402E95A7C0530B7575DB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each covered member whose discharge occurred prior to the creation of general secretarial authority, the sections of the DD–214 form referred to paragraph (1) shall be changed to similarly reflect a universal authority with codes, authorities, and language applicable at the time of discharge.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H800E229C4E494D89A127617A87E79711"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Status</header> <paragraph id="H4E821304540A417B8ACE143DDDBB6A8C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each covered member whose discharge characterization is changed under subsection (e) shall be treated without regard to the original discharge characterization of the member, including for purposes of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H15131CA9BE934F9EA21C2B4276D2DF3D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>benefits provided by the Federal Government to an individual by reason of service in the Armed Forces; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDD6AB3393CE548A4BFFCC38951F3499F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>all recognitions and honors that the Secretary of Defense provides to members of the Armed Forces.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H036E3BFC59E845A1AE3B230B34CDF200"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reinstatement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out paragraph (1)(B), the Secretary shall reinstate all recognitions and honors of a covered member whose discharge characterization is changed under subsection (e) that the Secretary withheld because of the original discharge characterization of the member.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H781C4273123A4F968EDD126342E1F1F4"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H0FCFC1A60AA64FD0B3A95ED9F10BEDBA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>appropriate discharge board</term> means the boards for correction of military records under section 1552 of title 10, United States Code, or the discharge review boards under section 1553 of such title, as the case may be.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H49F472FF24954398BE54E7A25EECB802"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>covered member</term> means any former member of the Armed Forces who was discharged from the Armed Forces because of the sexual orientation of the member.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8E73149E3D4C442C85F87313FDF08C94"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>discharge characterization</term> means the characterization under which a member of the Armed Forces is discharged or released, including <term>dishonorable</term>, <term>general</term>, <term>other than honorable</term>, and <term>honorable</term>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7D17EF3B099D406D9DC4F016134B4531"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Don’t Ask Don’t Tell</term> means section 654 of title 10, United States Code, as in effect before such section was repealed pursuant to the Don't Ask, Don't Tell Repeal Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/321">Public Law 111–321</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA782C2BB1B7E4531848728179423B721"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <term>representative</term> means the surviving spouse, next of kin, or legal representative of a covered member.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H06215D312A5C42E59BFD4026C4A3D26E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reports</header> <subsection id="HBF66D21D6E7641AAAB8274468939F343"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Review</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall conduct a review of the consistency and uniformity of the reviews conducted under section 2.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H246269C4694441F289C51DCF2AB4D8E1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and each year thereafter for a four-year period, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the reviews under subsection (a). Such reports shall include any comments or recommendations for continued actions.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HB4E53ED113714DB3B5A602B89AB13F27"><enum>4.</enum><header>Historical review</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of each military department shall ensure that oral historians of the department—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7018A7C519E94B9A9F24C20998B5B81D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>review the facts and circumstances surrounding the estimated 100,000 members of the Armed Forces discharged from the Armed Forces between World War II and September 2011 because of the sexual orientation of the member; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H923C442632C14B088BE01347574B38E8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>receive oral testimony of individuals who personally experienced discrimination and discharge because of the actual or perceived sexual orientation of the individual so that such testimony may serve as an official record of these discriminatory policies and their impact on American lives.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

