<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H23CE4E38E13A4095933A47BAA8252053" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 535 IH: Taiwan Travel Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 535</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170113">January 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C000266">Mr. Chabot</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000487">Mr. Royce of California</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To encourage visits between the United States and Taiwan at all levels, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H86BFF053FA824AD5B407CA4EE7B251EE" style="OLC">
 <section id="HB6BE6D4E2EF743709E011F147548F3A5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Taiwan Travel Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HDE3635875781433BB7E7A7D46209BAC7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H68F6C468E8054A86B40A8EF951BFF1E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Taiwan Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/3301">22 U.S.C. 3301</external-xref> et seq.), enacted in 1979, has continued for 37 years to be a cornerstone of relations between the United States and Taiwan and has served as an anchor for peace and security in the Western Pacific area.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7698C092DCCC435C957493DFB35D6A77"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Taiwan Relations Act declares that peace and stability in the Western Pacific area are in the political, security, and economic interests of the United States and are matters of international concern.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5ED720325F2241DAB9F692417954EF54"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The United States considers any effort to determine the future of Taiwan by other than peaceful means, including by boycotts or embargoes, a threat to the peace and security of the Western Pacific area and of grave concern to the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD069D3B602044DCAB23E90CD24AF76AE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Taiwan has succeeded in a momentous transition to democracy beginning in the late 1980s and has been a beacon of democracy in Asia, and Taiwan’s democratic achievements inspire many countries and people in the region.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF17E54CA31CC494F8F8256FDBB23CD81"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Visits to a country by United States cabinet members and other high-ranking officials are an indicator of the breadth and depth of ties between the United States and such country.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H44AD69ECDAAE4E95B4129C1381FEA52A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Since the enactment of the Taiwan Relations Act, relations between the United States and Taiwan have suffered from insufficient high-level communication due to the self-imposed restrictions that the United States maintains on high-level visits with Taiwan.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HE965613467F740A6B4B2CFDD392C951C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress; Statement of policy</header>
 <subsection id="H2594F5D965ED47CEBA845F65B6A200D7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the United States Government should encourage visits between officials from the United States and Taiwan at all levels.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9E2088A4045A47DBABF8ECBA8AF0C554"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text>It should be the policy of the United States to—</text> <paragraph id="HE29523F797224247ACDBCE966C81CEA2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>allow officials at all levels of the United States Government, including cabinet-level national security officials, general officers, and other executive branch officials, to travel to Taiwan to meet their Taiwanese counterparts;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3E502226DF334686965635D70117DD10"><enum>(2)</enum><text>allow high-level officials of Taiwan to enter the United States, under conditions which demonstrate appropriate respect for the dignity of such officials, and to meet with officials of the United States, including officials from the Department of State and the Department of Defense and other cabinet agencies; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2659084486534706A0BD0743F50AC40C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourage the Taipei Economic and Cultural Representative Office, and any other instrumentality established by Taiwan, to conduct business in the United States, including activities which involve participation by Members of Congress, officials of Federal, State, or local governments of the United States, or any high-level official of Taiwan.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


