<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="appropriations" dms-id="ID34BAC14540CB4BC4ADFBFC96EE9D188A" public-private="public"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3355 RH: Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2018</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code> 
<calendar>Union Calendar No. 171</calendar> 
<congress>115th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 3355</legis-num> 
<associated-doc role="report">[Report No. 115–239]</associated-doc> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20170721">July 21, 2017</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001051">Mr. Carter of Texas</sponsor>, from the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSAP00" deleted-display-style="bold-brackets">Committee on Appropriations</committee-name>, reported the following bill; which was committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>Making appropriations for the Department of Homeland Security for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2018, and for other purposes.<pagebreak/></official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body changed="not-changed" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="ID3F54C6107CE743A8878D0BC760C31247" style="traditional-inline"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="ID79993566F894480FBAE9AE6C63CC75EA" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the following sums are appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for the Department of Homeland Security for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2018, and for other purposes, namely:</text> </section> <title id="HA7D846B1C23C4766915D072D6F15B16C" level-type="subsequent"><enum>I</enum><header display-inline="no-display-inline">Departmental management, operations, intelligence, and oversight</header><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="H256D136FA14448C9A6885919107E3472"><header>Office of the secretary and executive management</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H397D19AA58EB48FA870DBD9216CEBDD6"><header>Operations and support</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Office of the Secretary and for executive management for operations and support, $138,997,000: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $30,000 shall be for official reception and representation expenses.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="HEC4E848DE58D45519FFF5F2690A1ECFB"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Management directorate</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H579626B655A34EC9887847972E201A35"><header>Operations and support</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Management Directorate for operations and support, $696,131,000, of which $227,516,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2019: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $2,000 shall be for official reception and representation expenses.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H6E23D26DD8824A43B5B1824A916508CA"><header>Procurement, construction, and improvements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Management Directorate for procurement, construction, and improvements, $27,755,000, to remain available until September 30, 2019.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H4998B24D8FE64AF08DA646A6EF23770F"><header>Research and development</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Management Directorate for research and development, $2,545,000, to remain available until September 30, 2019.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H638B81E048F143A294281C5BC6B6DC9C"><header>Intelligence, analysis, and operations coordination</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H8082A425199E40C09DF95AF404135C8C"><header>Operations and support</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Office of Intelligence and Analysis and the Office of Operations Coordination for operations and support, $252,405,000, of which $77,915,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2019: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $3,825 shall be for official reception and representation expenses.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H70AB92914735436BABB73977C2928AC4"><header>Office of inspector general</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HDD6C2D7A5F8C40BB9FD5BFAC8536659B"><header>Operations and support</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Office of Inspector General for operations and support, $154,830,000: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $300,000 may be used for certain confidential operational expenses, including the payment of informants, to be expended at the direction of the Inspector General.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="HA9375AB41E4C4B1493BC122A7721784C"><header>Administrative provisions</header></appropriations-intermediate> 
<section commented="no" id="HA9A52E2E86BE47D1953DBA77311FB228"><enum>101.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Hereafter, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives, at the time the President's budget proposal is submitted pursuant to section 1105(a) of title 31, United States Code, the Future Years Homeland Security Program, as authorized by section 874 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/454">6 U.S.C. 454</external-xref>).</text></section> <section id="H62B416BD4EED41FB9252760C1FC47C00"><enum>102.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Hereafter, the Chief Financial Officer of the Department of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives a monthly budget and staffing report that includes total obligations of the Department for that month and for the fiscal year at the appropriation and program, project, and activity levels, by the source year of the appropriation, not later than 30 days after the last day of each month.</text></section> 
<section id="H40ED98B5A2BB4F2ABEE412C167C20991"><enum>103.</enum> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H95B7D4BA49714AABB7809C771C7637B3"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 518 of division F of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/113">Public Law 114–113</external-xref>), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit a report not later than October 15, 2018, to the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security listing all grants and contracts awarded by any means other than full and open competition during fiscal years 2017 and 2018.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA3877927B9FC4B6EA41E7C19614F14D8"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Inspector General shall review the report required by subsection (a) to assess departmental compliance with applicable laws and regulations and report the results of that review to the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives not later than February 15, 2019.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H17954413FD10418A8970AADFC76E207E"><enum>104.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall require that all contracts of the Department of Homeland Security that provide award fees link such fees to successful acquisition outcomes, which shall be specified in terms of cost, schedule, and performance.</text></section> <section id="H444076BA2FA7454A9A32F69A825993C1"><enum>105.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall notify the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives of any proposed transfers of funds available under section 9703(g)(4)(B) of title 31, United States Code (as added by <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/102/393">Public Law 102–393</external-xref>) from the Department of the Treasury Forfeiture Fund to any agency within the Department of Homeland Security: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That none of the funds identified for such a transfer may be obligated until the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives are notified of the proposed transfers.</text></section> 
<section commented="no" id="H4D422B1BD95D48EAB06872B2FEE10EC7" changed="not-changed"><enum>106.</enum> 
<subsection id="HE5FEA06023CE4A37B418B46AEA888084" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text>All official costs associated with the use of Government aircraft by Department of Homeland Security personnel to support official travel of the Secretary and the Deputy Secretary shall be paid from amounts made available for the Office of the Secretary.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8983AA767156474C92AD146EA4956DE2"><enum>(b)</enum><text>A travel report of all direct and indirect costs of official and nonofficial travel by the Secretary and Deputy Secretary by appropriation to the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives not later than 30 days after the end of fiscal year 2018.</text></subsection></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4FFC09F3543946B5A0F1B8315D7E7535" section-type="subsequent-section" changed="not-changed"><enum>107.</enum> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H92EBED061DCC47D8BD81BF0AFE70C7C3"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives, the Committees on the Judiciary of the Senate and the House of Representatives, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives, a report for fiscal year 2017 on visa overstay data by country as required by section 1376 of title 8, United States Code: <italic>Provided</italic>, That the report on visa overstay data shall also include—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2ACD9E1A1ABA46DBB19FA3219A7526BA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">overstays from all nonimmigrant visa categories under the immigration laws, delineated by each of the classes and sub-classes of such categories; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H76B13FD19F5A418095C0C7AA58301DC4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">numbers as well as rates of overstays for each class and sub-class of such nonimmigrant categories on a per-country basis.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H1E497F432FBE4674A7887F07F486D787"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall publish on the Department’s website the metrics developed to measure the effectiveness of security between the ports of entry, including the methodology and data supporting the resulting measures.</text></subsection></section> </title> 
<title id="H89091290E5724BC2906D946C93613125"><enum>II</enum><header display-inline="no-display-inline">Security, enforcement, and investigations</header><appropriations-intermediate id="H406D3D12A2E24C28B6EFFC8811BC350E"><header>U.S. customs and border protection</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HC652EB6DC6F24D4793AE0E09BD7D8CBF"><header>Operations and support</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of U.S. Customs and Border Protection for operations and support, including the transportation of unaccompanied minor aliens; the provision of air and marine support to Federal, State, and local agencies in the enforcement or administration of laws enforced by the Department of Homeland Security; at the discretion of the Secretary of Homeland Security, the provision of such support to Federal, State, and local agencies in other law enforcement and emergency humanitarian efforts; the purchase and lease of up to 7,500 (6,500 for replacement only) police-type vehicles; the purchase, maintenance, or operation of marine vessels, aircraft, and unmanned aerial systems; and contracting with individuals for personal services abroad; $11,553,315,000; of which $3,274,000 shall be derived from the Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund for administrative expenses related to the collection of the Harbor Maintenance Fee pursuant to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9505">section 9505(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9505">26 U.S.C. 9505(c)(3)</external-xref>) and notwithstanding section 1511(e)(1) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/551">6 U.S.C. 551(e)(1)</external-xref>); of which $681,441,500 shall be available until September 30, 2019; and of which such sums as become available in the Customs User Fee Account, except sums subject to section 13031(f)(3) of the Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/58c">19 U.S.C. 58c(f)(3)</external-xref>), shall be derived from that account: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $34,425 shall be for official reception and representation expenses: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $15,000,000 may be transferred to the Bureau of Indian Affairs for the maintenance and repair of roads on Native American reservations, as required by the Border Patrol: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $150,000 shall be available for payment for rental space in connection with preclearance operations: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $1,000,000 shall be for awards of compensation to informants, to be accounted for solely under the certificate of the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HE92F408ED9C146A3AB1429AA4B99F8F8"><header>Procurement, construction, and improvements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses for U.S. Customs and Border Protection for procurement, construction, and improvements, including procurement of aircraft and unmanned aerial systems, $2,008,719,000, of which $1,948,944,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2020, and of which $59,775,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2022.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H2798B040609A41838B885BDDE326718E"><header> U.S. immigration and customs enforcement</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H9C2271EF76AD49E5A8732FF268C9FD7E"><header>Operations and support</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement for operations and support, including the purchase and lease of up to 3,790 (2,350 for replacement only) police-type vehicles; overseas vetted units; and maintenance, minor construction, and minor leasehold improvements at owned and leased facilities; $7,002,043,000; of which $6,000,000 shall remain available until expended for efforts to enforce laws against forced child labor; of which $33,700,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2019; of which not less than $4,413,244,000 shall be for enforcement, detention, and removal operations, including transportation of unaccompanied minor aliens: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $11,475 shall be for official reception and representation expenses: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $10,000,000 shall be available until expended for conducting special operations under section 3131 of the Customs Enforcement Act of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2081">19 U.S.C. 2081</external-xref>): <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $2,000,000 shall be for awards of compensation to informants, to be accounted for solely under the certificate of the Secretary of Homeland Security: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $11,216,000 shall be available to fund or reimburse other Federal agencies for the costs associated with the care, maintenance, and repatriation of smuggled aliens unlawfully present in the United States.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H01B88A2D7E4D4EA1BB5A49D2912E31A7"><header>Procurement, construction, and improvements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement for procurement, construction, and improvements, $52,899,000, to remain available until September 30, 2020.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="HDBB1675285724C939BB3C5244442C2D8"><header>Transportation security administration</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H980232AE7942446F880FA6400E46F112"><header>Operations and support</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Transportation Security Administration for operations and support, $7,082,874,000, of which $1,770,719,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2019: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $7,650 shall be for official reception and representation expenses: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That security service fees authorized under section 44940 of title 49, United States Code, shall be credited to this appropriation as offsetting collections and shall be available only for aviation security: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That the sum appropriated under this heading from the general fund shall be reduced on a dollar-for-dollar basis as such offsetting collections are received during fiscal year 2018 so as to result in a final fiscal year appropriation from the general fund estimated at not more than $4,612,874,000.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H4B30ADEA30314EA395939BD14A8EEB49"><header>Procurement, construction, and improvements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Transportation Security Administration for procurement, construction, and improvements, $53,314,000, to remain available until September 30, 2020.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HDEFC875C497B4770A7C00BB76568CED0"><header>Research and development</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Transportation Security Administration for research and development, $20,190,000, to remain available until September 30, 2019.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H6A99BA7F61AB414587811159B919B9D1"><header> Coast guard</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H7D6F875AE2704061B1934E132F6813F7"><header>Operating expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses for the operations and maintenance of the Coast Guard, not otherwise provided for; purchase or lease of not to exceed 25 passenger motor vehicles, which shall be for replacement only; purchase or lease of small boats for contingent and emergent requirements (at a unit cost of not more than $700,000) and repairs and service-life replacements, not to exceed a total of $31,000,000; purchase, lease, or improvement of other equipment (at a unit cost of not more than $250,000); minor shore construction projects not exceeding $1,000,000 in total cost on any location; payments pursuant to section 156 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/97/377">Public Law 97–377</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/402">42 U.S.C. 402</external-xref> note; 96 Stat. 1920); and recreation and welfare; $7,163,464,000; of which $340,000,000 shall be for defense-related activities; of which $24,500,000 shall be derived from the Oil Spill Liability Trust Fund to carry out the purposes of section 1012(a)(5) of the Oil Pollution Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/2712">33 U.S.C. 2712(a)(5)</external-xref>): <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $23,000 shall be for official reception and representation expenses.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H272A890D747D4A0D92E1AE05B3C03706"><header>Environmental compliance and restoration</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses to carry out the environmental compliance and restoration functions of the Coast Guard under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/14/19">chapter 19</external-xref> of title 14, United States Code, $13,397,000, to remain available until September 30, 2022.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HDC148CBCD47442E3B2715F8F32189F08"><header>Reserve training</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Coast Guard Reserve; operations and maintenance of the Coast Guard Reserve Program; personnel and training costs; and equipment and services; $114,875,000.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H81E2807EBEDA45A2A58A038ED733C841"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Acquisition, construction, and improvements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Coast Guard for acquisition, construction, renovation, and improvement of aids to navigation, shore facilities (including facilities at Department of Defense installations used by the Coast Guard), vessels, and aircraft, including equipment related thereto, $1,298,745,000; of which $20,000,000 shall be derived from the Oil Spill Liability Trust Fund to carry out the purposes of section 1012(a)(5) of the Oil Pollution Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/2712">33 U.S.C. 2712(a)(5)</external-xref>); and of which $1,256,655,000 shall be available until September 30, 2022.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H22A2B70420C74881AFCDB9301D6CA099"><header>Research, development, test, and evaluation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Coast Guard for research, development, test, and evaluation; and for maintenance, rehabilitation, lease, and operation of facilities and equipment; $18,641,000; to remain available until September 30, 2020, of which $500,000 shall be derived from the Oil Spill Liability Trust Fund to carry out the purposes of section 1012(a)(5) of the Oil Pollution Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/2712">33 U.S.C. 2712(a)(5)</external-xref>): <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That there may be credited to and used for the purposes of this appropriation funds received from State and local governments, other public authorities, private sources, and foreign countries for expenses incurred for research, development, testing, and evaluation.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H1F206C4472974B6F92AF95183C86DD45"><header>Retired pay</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For retired pay, including the payment of obligations otherwise chargeable to lapsed appropriations for this purpose, payments under the Retired Serviceman's Family Protection and Survivor Benefits Plans, payment for career status bonuses, concurrent receipts, and combat-related special compensation, and payments for medical care of retired personnel and their dependents under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/55">chapter 55</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, $1,673,000,000, to remain available until expended.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H50393E44C36E432287E272A09EF9A7EA"><header>United states secret service</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H2ED0704A259D4196988FB2E8635C8948"><header>Operations and support</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the United States Secret Service for operations and support, including purchase of not to exceed 652 vehicles for police-type use for replacement only; hire of passenger motor vehicles; purchase of motorcycles made in the United States; hire of aircraft; rental of buildings in the District of Columbia; fencing, lighting, guard booths, and other facilities on private or other property not in Government ownership or control, as may be necessary to perform protective functions; conduct of and participation in firearms matches; presentation of awards; conduct of behavioral research in support of protective intelligence and operations; payment in advance for commercial accommodations as may be necessary to perform protective functions; and payment, without regard to section 5702 of title 5, United States Code, of subsistence expenses of employees who are on protective missions, whether at or away from their duty stations; $1,893,215,000; of which $33,692,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2019, of which $6,000,000 shall be for a grant for activities related to investigations of missing and exploited children; and of which not less than $13,869,000 shall be for activities related to training in electronic crimes investigations and forensics: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $19,125 shall be for official reception and representation expenses: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $100,000 shall be to provide technical assistance and equipment to foreign law enforcement organizations in counterfeit investigations.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HD0FEB928C7B545F5942F60730C1F2EB1"><header>Procurement, construction, and improvements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the United States Secret Service for procurement, construction, and improvements, $64,030,000, to remain available until September 30, 2020.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H2983DDC08DAB44DF87A0066CD21E4645"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Research and development</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the United States Secret Service for research and development, $250,000, to remain available until September 30, 2019.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H924CB4B402BB473A8F2CAA7FD3DFE6D3"><header>administrative provisions</header></appropriations-intermediate> <section id="HE811A9893AC54594BA5C2551DDF05172"><enum>201.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 201 of the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2017 (division F of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/31">Public Law 115–31</external-xref>), related to overtime compensation limitations, shall apply with respect to funds made available in this Act in the same manner as such section applied to funds made available in that Act.</text> </section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3F5FF2D2B62940498F0BF81550AD59DC" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>202.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funding made available under the heading <quote>U.S. Customs and Border Protection—Operations and Support</quote> and <quote>U.S. Customs and Border Protection—Procurement, Construction, and Improvements</quote> shall be available for customs expenses when necessary to maintain operations and prevent adverse personnel actions in Puerto Rico in addition to funding provided by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/48/740">48 U.S.C. 740</external-xref>.</text></section> <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H522571860E184AA6A96EBB2A968106B9" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>203.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Hereafter, no U.S. Customs and Border Protection aircraft or other related equipment, with the exception of aircraft that are one of a kind and have been identified as excess to U.S. Customs and Border Protection requirements and aircraft that have been damaged beyond repair, shall be transferred to any other Federal agency, department, or office outside of the Department of Homeland Security without prior notice to the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives.</text></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEBCB4AB4D49C4B6897C4C0B97F79B0B3" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>204.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As authorized by section 601(b) of the United States-Colombia Trade Promotion Agreement Implementation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/42">Public Law 112–42</external-xref>), fees collected from passengers arriving from Canada, Mexico, or an adjacent island pursuant to section 13031(a)(5) of the Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/58c">19 U.S.C. 58c(a)(5)</external-xref>) shall be available until expended.</text></section> <section id="H5B34FD96B560438797A1706F1CA34402"><enum>205.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>U.S. Customs and Border Protection—Operations and Support</quote>, $39,000,000, to remain available until expended, to be reduced by amounts collected and credited to this appropriation in fiscal year 2018 from amounts authorized to be collected by section 286(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1356">8 U.S.C. 1356(i)</external-xref>), section 10412 of the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/8311">7 U.S.C. 8311</external-xref>), and section 817 of the Trade Facilitation and Trade Enforcement Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/125">Public Law 114–125</external-xref>): <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That to the extent that amounts realized from such collections exceed $39,000,000, those amounts in excess of $39,000,000 shall be credited to this appropriation, to remain available until expended.</text></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD51DF415E73D49B1815922708FEA355B" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>206.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available in this Act for U.S. Customs and Border Protection may be used to prevent an individual not in the business of importing a prescription drug (within the meaning of section 801(g) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act) from importing a prescription drug from Canada that complies with the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That this section shall apply only to individuals transporting on their person a personal-use quantity of the prescription drug, not to exceed a 90-day supply: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That the prescription drug may not be—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H455FFB256AD54893B088180FDD44D03E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a controlled substance, as defined in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>); or</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H42B1F0ED00FB4F6091763F37BC4238EE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a biological product, as defined in section 351 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4B64B81A44D6443AB4D9A5C27FD7173D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>207.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, none of the funds provided in this or any other Act shall be used to approve a waiver of the navigation and vessel-inspection laws pursuant to section 501(b) of title 46, United States Code, for the transportation of crude oil distributed from and to the Strategic Petroleum Reserve until the Secretary of Homeland Security, after consultation with the Secretaries of the Departments of Energy and Transportation and representatives from the United States flag maritime industry, takes adequate measures to ensure the use of United States flag vessels for such transportation: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That the Secretary shall notify the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives within 2 business days of any request for waivers of navigation and vessel-inspection laws pursuant to such section with respect to such transportation, and the disposition of such requests.</text></section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H69C0B8028C9C44EC9689531424A7E767" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>208.</enum> 
<subsection id="H363894D52C894387A5B0A2458AC45FEC" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to approve, license, facilitate, authorize, or otherwise allow the trafficking or import of property confiscated by the Cuban Government.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE8BFED10329B4979AC97815E50D8352E"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the terms “confiscated”, “Cuban Government”, “property”, and “traffic” have the meanings given such terms in paragraphs (4), (5), (12)(A), and (13), respectively, of section 4 of the Cuban Liberty and Democratic Solidarity (LIBERTAD) Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2216/6023">2216 U.S.C. 6023</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H0BE64750D0664B5E9424ABD85EDE9997"><enum>209.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Without regard to the limitation as to time and condition of section 503(d), the Secretary may reprogram within and transfer funds to <quote>U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement—Operations and Support</quote> as necessary to ensure the detention of aliens prioritized for removal.</text></section> <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2498AB450C924F1184A2C0C0DFACA44C"><enum>210.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds provided under the heading <quote>U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement—Operations and Support</quote> may be used to continue a delegation of law enforcement authority authorized under section 287(g) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1357">8 U.S.C. 1357(g)</external-xref>) if the Department of Homeland Security Inspector General determines that the terms of the agreement governing the delegation of authority have been materially violated.</text></section> 
<section id="H22569C56BA8A4E5291D071D38C81B1F5"><enum>211.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds provided under the heading <quote>U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement—Operations and Support</quote> may be used to continue any contract for the provision of detention services if the two most recent overall performance evaluations received by the contracted facility are less than <quote>adequate</quote> or the equivalent median score in any subsequent performance evaluation system.</text></section> <section id="H33D36AAD0D894882A3E145A5B1569BB7"><enum>212.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of the House of Representatives and the Senate, including the leadership; the heads of Federal agencies and commissions, including the Secretary, Deputy Secretary, Under Secretaries, and Assistant Secretaries of the Department of Homeland Security; the Attorney General, Deputy Attorney General, Assistant Attorneys General, and United States Attorneys; and senior members of the Executive Office of the President, including the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, shall not be exempt from Federal passenger and baggage screening.</text></section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H37AE2303CC7D40869CE2CCF10BD645AA" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>213.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 44923 of title 49, United States Code, for fiscal year 2018, any funds in the Aviation Security Capital Fund established by section 44923(h) of title 49, United States Code, may be used for the procurement and installation of explosives detection systems or for the issuance of other transaction agreements for the purpose of funding projects described in section 44923(a) of such title.</text></section> <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H15C42A082170458BA8A60B3FE5801DC4" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>214.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available by this Act under the heading <quote>Coast Guard—Operating Expenses</quote> shall be for expenses incurred for recreational vessels under section 12114 of title 46, United States Code, except to the extent fees are collected from owners of yachts and credited to the appropriation made available by this Act under the heading <quote>Coast Guard—Operating Expenses</quote>: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That to the extent such fees are insufficient to pay expenses of recreational vessel documentation under such section 12114, and there is a backlog of recreational vessel applications, personnel performing non-recreational vessel documentation functions under subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/46/121">chapter 121</external-xref> of title 46, United States Code, may perform documentation under section 12114.</text></section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB5604647742A485892C414DC1758FD4D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>215.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Without regard to the limitation as to time and condition of section 503(d), after June 30, up to $10,000,000 may be reprogrammed to or from the Military Pay and Allowances funding category within <quote>Coast Guard—Operating Expenses</quote> in accordance with subsection (a) of section 503.</text></section> <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H75DF60494A2D466ABD6AB979977EAF90" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>216.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Secret Service is authorized to obligate funds in anticipation of reimbursements from Federal agencies and entities, as defined in section 105 of title 5, United States Code, for personnel receiving training sponsored by the James J. Rowley Training Center, except that total obligations at the end of the fiscal year shall not exceed total budgetary resources available under the heading <quote>United States Secret Service—Operations and Support</quote> at the end of the fiscal year.</text></section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDDD9EBCB9006489D8660E6DAB1D9DD57" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>217.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available to the United States Secret Service by this Act or by previous appropriations Acts may be made available for the protection of the head of a Federal agency other than the Secretary of Homeland Security: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That the Director of the Secret Service may enter into agreements to provide such protection on a fully reimbursable basis.</text></section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H382083B1C48340DEB404BAC9B3A3239B" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>218.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of section 503(a)(3) of this Act, up to $15,000,000 may be reprogrammed within <quote>United States Secret Service—Operations and Support</quote>.</text></section> <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB051EFC741DE47EBB31301E796815878" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>219.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funding made available in this Act for <quote>United States Secret Service—Operations and Support</quote> is available for travel of United States Secret Service employees on protective missions without regard to the limitations on such expenditures in this or any other Act if the Director of the United States Secret Service or a designee notifies the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives 10 or more days in advance, or as early as practicable, prior to such expenditures.</text></section></title> 
<title id="H150283C0E38046999EFCCE3E89CAC5D6"><enum>III</enum><header display-inline="no-display-inline">Protection, preparedness, response, and recovery</header><appropriations-intermediate id="HFAF247F9E7CC43DA988E88B8BF3F0323"><header>National protection and programs directorate</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H25873D21103A422E8C57A9C258698536"><header>Operations and support</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the National Protection and Programs Directorate for operations and support, $1,427,062,000, of which $8,912,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2019: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $3,825 shall be for official reception and representation expenses.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H8C11DD96A6CC40688E3509F64E3088EF"><header>Federal protective service</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The revenues and collections of security fees credited to this account shall be available until expended for necessary expenses related to the protection of federally owned and leased buildings and for the operations of the Federal Protective Service.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H20DEB3AC495C4C48BC752C6B53241EB1"><header>Procurement, construction, and improvements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the National Protection and Programs Directorate for procurement, construction, and improvements, $335,033,000, to remain available until September 30, 2019.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H7452877ACF8740ADB8D4BF3ED093811D"><header>Research and development</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the National Protection and Programs Directorate for research and development, $11,126,000, to remain available until September 30, 2019.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="H87EE142011D343AFA835366C3067D7FD"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Office of health affairs</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HA334D1952113455F8D1597347E652BFE"><header>Operations and Support</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Office of Health Affairs for operations and support, $119,319,000, of which $13,520,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2019.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="HEB2701D4009746D99EAD190E7C323266"><header>Federal emergency management agency</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HFCB4974C94B443329C71CEEEF9C7C815"><header>Operations and support</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Federal Emergency Management Agency for operations and support, $1,027,135,000: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $2,250 shall be for official reception and representation expenses.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H60BFC425321242AC84DD5209E0ED5CBC"><header>Procurement, construction, and improvements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Federal Emergency Management Agency for procurement, construction, and improvements, $76,578,000, to remain available until September 30, 2019.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H6363146A93AD4ED4985148EB5F7FDE37"><header>Federal assistance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For activities of the Federal Emergency Management Agency for Federal assistance through grants, contracts, cooperative agreements, and other activities, $3,003,798,000, which shall be allocated as follows:</text> <paragraph id="H57E2B79C2CF14ACCBEA53C824C63A3AD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$467,000,000 for the State Homeland Security Grant Program under section 2004 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/605">6 U.S.C. 605</external-xref>), of which $55,000,000 shall be for Operation Stonegarden: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That notwithstanding subsection (c)(4) of such section 2004, for fiscal year 2018, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico shall make available to local and tribal governments amounts provided to the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico under this paragraph in accordance with subsection (c)(1) of such section 2004.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3D7EB202EECD44AC9FD06E036E81F3AF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$630,000,000 for the Urban Area Security Initiative under section 2003 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/604">6 U.S.C. 604</external-xref>), of which $50,000,000 shall be for organizations (as described under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from tax under section 501(a) of such code) determined by the Secretary of Homeland Security to be at high risk of a terrorist attack.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3CDF36EB6E9147E1BA448D99EBDA7F33"><enum>(3)</enum><text>$100,000,000 for Public Transportation Security Assistance and Railroad Security Assistance under sections 1406 and 1513 of the Implementing Recommendations of the 9/11 Commission Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/1135">6 U.S.C. 1135</external-xref> and 1163), of which $10,000,000 shall be for Amtrak security.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEE5D30E8B3AB47F6B865652E0C27704C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>$100,000,000 for Port Security Grants in accordance with section 70107 of title 46, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBDDA6B05BA014008A996FC5A909FF028"><enum>(5)</enum><text>$690,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2018, of which $345,000,000 shall be for Assistance to Firefighter Grants and $345,000,000 shall be for Staffing for Adequate Fire and Emergency Response Grants under sections 33 and 34 respectively of the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2229">15 U.S.C. 2229</external-xref> and 2229a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA9D5CF98841D413D9A2181EA79FD1DD4"><enum>(6)</enum><text>$350,000,000 for emergency management performance grants under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4001">42 U.S.C. 4001</external-xref>), the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121</external-xref>), the Earthquake Hazards Reduction Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7701">42 U.S.C. 7701</external-xref>), <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/762">6 U.S.C. 762</external-xref>, and Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDE898EB23E504C56A25191CFA08A534A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>$100,000,000 for the National Predisaster Mitigation Fund under section 203 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5133">42 U.S.C. 5133</external-xref>), to remain available until expended.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H527363E8AC3B499C91CCCCC71A2A8FFC"><enum>(8)</enum><text>$177,531,000 for necessary expenses for Flood Hazard Mapping and Risk Analysis, in addition to and to supplement any other sums appropriated under the National Flood Insurance Fund, and such additional sums as may be provided by States or other political subdivisions for cost-shared mapping activities under section 1360(f)(2) of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4101">42 U.S.C. 4101(f)(2)</external-xref>), to remain available until expended.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H61C67C948F5B4ADFAF034066AF7FEB69"><enum>(9)</enum><text>$120,000,000 for the emergency food and shelter program under title III of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11331">42 U.S.C. 11331</external-xref>), to remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed 3.5 percent shall be for total administrative costs.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H926745919FED4AAE911CA3E568A335EB"><enum>(10)</enum><text>$269,267,000 to sustain current operations for training, exercises, technical assistance, and other programs.</text></paragraph></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H2E851CDF433240E78BEDFEF65C848FCC"><header>Disaster relief fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses in carrying out the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121</external-xref> et seq.), $7,327,720,000, to remain available until expended, of which $6,793,000,000 shall be for major disasters declared pursuant to the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121</external-xref> et seq.) and is designated by the Congress as being for disaster relief pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(D) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H57F7764C2F634EA389AEEFB4739BB3BE"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">National flood insurance fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For activities under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4001">42 U.S.C. 4001</external-xref> et seq.), the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4001">42 U.S.C. 4001</external-xref> et seq.), the Biggert-Waters Flood Insurance Reform Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/141">Public Law 112–141</external-xref>, 126 Stat. 916), and the Homeowner Flood Insurance Affordability Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/89">Public Law 113–89</external-xref>; 128 Stat. 1020), $203,500,000, to remain available until September 30, 2019, which shall be derived from offsetting amounts collected under section 1308(d) of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4015">42 U.S.C. 4015(d)</external-xref>); of which $13,573,000 shall be available for mission support associated with flood management; and of which $189,927,000 shall be available for flood plain management and flood mapping: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That any additional fees collected pursuant to section 1308(d) of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4015">42 U.S.C. 4015(d)</external-xref>) shall be credited as offsetting collections to this account, to be available for flood plain management and flood mapping: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That in fiscal year 2017, no funds shall be available from the National Flood Insurance Fund under section 1310 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4017">42 U.S.C. 4017</external-xref>) in excess of—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7FD9B4EBB27A47F8AE769366F04D0701"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$165,224,000 for operating expenses and salaries and expenses associated with flood insurance operations;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD2BF36DBF753489282C2E0F14C963FDE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$1,123,000,000 for commissions and taxes of agents;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4E81AADEB7124E2386D318D03ACA696D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>such sums as are necessary for interest on Treasury borrowings; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA8CEAABB8E9B4ACB896700305A2F23EA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>$175,000,000, which shall remain available until expended, for flood mitigation actions and for flood mitigation assistance under section 1366 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4104c">42 U.S.C. 4104c</external-xref>), notwithstanding sections 1366(e) and 1310(a)(7) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4104c">42 U.S.C. 4104c(e)</external-xref>, 4017):</text><continuation-text commented="no" continuation-text-level="section"> 
<proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That the amounts collected under section 102 of the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4012a">42 U.S.C. 4012a</external-xref>) and section 1366(e) of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 shall be deposited in the National Flood Insurance Fund to supplement other amounts specified as available for section 1366 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968, notwithstanding section 102(f)(8), section 1366(e), and paragraphs (1) through (3) of section 1367(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4012a">42 U.S.C. 4012a(f)(8)</external-xref>, 4104c(e), 4104d(b)(1)–(3)): 
<proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That total administrative costs shall not exceed 4 percent of the total appropriation: 
<proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That up to $5,000,000 is available to carry out section 24 of the Homeowner Flood Insurance Affordability Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4033">42 U.S.C. 4033</external-xref>).</continuation-text></paragraph></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="HA7014FFC5FCA45A0B3509750A4B48663"><header>Administrative provisions</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HEB597733699B4DB19CB99241912853E3"><header>(including transfer of funds)</header></appropriations-small> 
<section id="HF5288747DD8A4560B4DF670742921782"><enum>301.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 2008(a)(12) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/609">6 U.S.C. 609(a)(12)</external-xref>) or any other provision of law, not more than 5 percent of the amount of a grant made available in paragraphs (1) through (4) under <quote>Federal Emergency Management Agency—Federal Assistance</quote>, may be used by the grantee for expenses directly related to administration of the grant.</text></section> <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6A0000228F3E4BC7AFFBDF797585483A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>302.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Applications for grants under the heading <quote>Federal Emergency Management Agency—Federal Assistance</quote>, for paragraphs (1) through (4), shall be made available to eligible applicants not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, eligible applicants shall submit applications not later than 80 days after the grant announcement, and the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall act within 65 days after the receipt of an application.</text></section> 
<section id="H4DBE9218E02841CAB7F3527AB80778AF"><enum>303.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under the heading <quote>Federal Emergency Management Agency—Federal Assistance</quote>, for grants under paragraphs (1) through (4), the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall brief the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives 5 full business days in advance of announcing publicly the intention of making an award.</text></section> <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2CDB91CEDC8C496A97AE22A35851A94E" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>304.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under the heading <quote>Federal Emergency Management Agency—Federal Assistance</quote>, for grants under paragraphs (1) and (2), the installation of communications towers is not considered construction of a building or other physical facility.</text></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H21AE216FE655422A9861063E59A9069E" section-type="subsequent-section" changed="not-changed"><enum>305.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, grants awarded to States along the Southwest Border of the United States under sections 2003 or 2004 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/604">6 U.S.C. 604</external-xref> and 605) using funds provided under the heading <quote>Federal Emergency Management Agency—Federal Assistance</quote> for grants under paragraph (1) in this Act, or under the heading <quote>Federal Emergency Management Agency—State and Local Programs</quote> in <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/4">Public Law 114–4</external-xref>, division F of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/76">Public Law 113–76</external-xref>, or division D of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/6">Public Law 113–6</external-xref> may be used by recipients or sub-recipients for costs, or reimbursement of costs, related to providing humanitarian relief to unaccompanied alien children and alien adults accompanied by an alien minor where they are encountered after entering the United States, provided that such costs were incurred between January 1, 2014, and December 31, 2014, or during the award period of performance.</text> </section> <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC2A00D8E68574045B03F4E4D460DEEF1" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>306.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The aggregate charges assessed during fiscal year 2018, as authorized in title III of the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 1999 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5196e">42 U.S.C. 5196e</external-xref>), shall not be less than 100 percent of the amounts anticipated by the Department of Homeland Security to be necessary for its Radiological Emergency Preparedness Program for the next fiscal year: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That the methodology for assessment and collection of fees shall be fair and equitable and shall reflect costs of providing such services, including administrative costs of collecting such fees: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That such fees shall be deposited in a Radiological Emergency Preparedness Program account as offsetting collections and will become available for authorized purposes on October 1, 2018, and remain available until expended.</text></section></title> 
<title id="H10C9B3C5101140238C7C4C4DE374C86A"><enum>IV</enum><header display-inline="no-display-inline">Research, development, training, and services</header><appropriations-intermediate id="H7576B864AA2E4B6082DB8424E9433A71"><header>U.S. citizenship and immigration services</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H32B70DC725FA4F9C823573926B85BC08"><header>Operations and support</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services for operations and support of the E-Verify Program, $108,856,000.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H23FCA5AFA8914853A23885A3324FCF09"><header>Procurement, construction, and improvements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services for procurement, construction, and improvements of the E-Verify Program, $22,657,000, to remain available until September 30, 2021.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H6077AA5B139A49C88EDDBAA89A561651"><header>Federal law enforcement training centers</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H87E0082AFF054A0882BC5BB7E0B2A86C"><header>Operations and support</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers for operations and support, including the purchase of not to exceed 117 vehicles for police-type use and hire of passenger motor vehicles, and services as authorized by section 3109 of title 5, United States Code, $260,099,000, of which $49,409,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2019: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $7,180 shall be for official reception and representation expenses.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="HBA8130D2908F476D968A5EE4C4B1D572"><header>Science and technology directorate</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H71F4C335A5B5416DB34888BBF498D5C3"><header>Operations and support</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Science and Technology Directorate for operations and support, including the purchase or lease of not to exceed 5 vehicles, $254,618,000, of which $134,795,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2019: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $7,650 shall be for official reception and representation expenses.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H23000D29E9054DA789587E75EDD5152C"><header>Research and development</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Science and Technology Directorate for research and development, $383,482,000, to remain available until September 30, 2020.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H60945449DC3642559FDBC20A7BC2B370"><header> Domestic nuclear detection office</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H73E3E7B67617454F82CFE1B1070E4ACC"><header>Operations and support</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Domestic Nuclear Detection Office for operations and support, $54,664,000: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $2,250 shall be for official reception and representation expenses.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H55B38A504EFB4DCA92D747A74EFD951D"><header>Procurement, construction, and improvements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Domestic Nuclear Detection Office for procurement, construction, and improvements, $87,096,000, to remain available until September 30, 2020.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HA8E5D5DB77FF4AD596EDCB769A82C320"><header>Research and development</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Domestic Nuclear Detection Office for research and development, $144,161,000, to remain available until September 30, 2020.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H7328E441EE6B4977ACA1BAAF6755EA7F"><header>Federal assistance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Domestic Nuclear Detection Office for Federal assistance through grants, contracts, cooperative agreements, and other activities, $44,519,000, to remain available until September 30, 2020.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="HB714FE90518C4670974E3CA9FEA04D0B"><header>Administrative provisions</header></appropriations-intermediate> <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8F90379C90BA43FCA9E5C47B706C476A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>401.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, funds otherwise made available to U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services may be used to acquire, operate, equip, and dispose of up to 5 vehicles, for replacement only, for areas where the Administrator of General Services does not provide vehicles for lease: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That the Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services may authorize employees who are assigned to those areas to use such vehicles to travel between the employees' residences and places of employment.</text></section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA6F90AE96564495CA0FE258F7F8DF3B1" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>402.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available in this Act may be used by U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services to grant an immigration benefit unless the results of background checks required by law to be completed prior to the granting of the benefit have been received by U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services, and the results do not preclude the granting of the benefit.</text></section> <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD4790BD72DB945E48355B56450940504" section-type="subsequent-section" changed="not-changed"><enum>403.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds appropriated by this Act may be used to process or approve a competition under Office of Management and Budget Circular A–76 for services provided by employees (including employees serving on a temporary or term basis) of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services of the Department of Homeland Security who are known as Immigration Information Officers, Immigration Service Analysts, Contact Representatives, Investigative Assistants, or Immigration Services Officers.</text></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H40D33CFEFE7A4DD392B6465590E6B58C" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>404.</enum> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H835BB5F957B74D528B52C2BD851D93CD"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 1356(n) of title 8, United States Code, of the funds deposited into the Immigration Examinations Fee Account, up to $10,000,000 may be allocated by U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services in fiscal year 2018 for the purpose of providing an immigrant integration grants program.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE0F6E7EDA1AF4A8191EBA4A536DC8CEE"><enum>(b)</enum><text>None of the funds made available to U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services for grants for immigrant integration under subsection (a) may be used to provide services to aliens who have not been lawfully admitted for permanent residence.</text></subsection> </section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8B5CAE594D354ED088E99FB0E67E90AF" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>405.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers is authorized to distribute funds to Federal law enforcement agencies for expenses incurred participating in training accreditation.</text></section> <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H905F9089024043409BFAD826F1120899" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>406.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Law Enforcement Training Accreditation Board, including representatives from the Federal law enforcement community and non-Federal accreditation experts involved in law enforcement training, shall lead the Federal law enforcement training accreditation process to continue the implementation of measuring and assessing the quality and effectiveness of Federal law enforcement training programs, facilities, and instructors.</text></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H367BE94CEA5C4E5497C70F53DB5E48C0" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>407.</enum> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA9CC59FFDF604B0981306F4CF6E161A3"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is to be established a <quote>Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers—Procurement, Construction, and Improvements</quote> appropriations account for planning, operational development, engineering, and purchases prior to sustainment and for information technology-related procurement, construction, and improvements, including non-tangible assets of the Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA413063017904DD59CE3FF6B3D0A1AFE"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers may accept transfers to the account established by subsection (a) from Government agencies requesting the construction of special use facilities, as authorized by the Economy Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/1535">31 U.S.C. 1535(b)</external-xref>): <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That the Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers maintain administrative control and ownership upon completion of such facilities.</text></subsection></section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE52105C7F4EF42CFAA2B17408D2E1F1A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>408.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The functions of the Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers instructor staff shall be classified as inherently governmental for the purpose of the Federal Activities Inventory Reform Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/501">31 U.S.C. 501</external-xref> note).</text></section></title> <title id="H2DC190EC93A04673BA9110B355CC0B82" changed="deleted"><enum>V</enum><header display-inline="no-display-inline">General provisions</header><appropriations-small id="HAED3EEBFE7E2492DBDCBEBF0E94E09A3"><header>(including transfers and rescissions of funds)</header></appropriations-small> <section id="H38B51865F10242C2B1F2B6963819FB8E"><enum>501.</enum><text>No part of any appropriation contained in this Act shall remain available for obligation beyond the current fiscal year unless expressly so provided herein.</text></section> 
<section id="HD05C824B08B7469BA13E909B6437F698"><enum>502.</enum><text>Subject to the requirements of section 503 of this Act, the unexpended balances of prior appropriations provided for activities in this Act may be transferred to appropriation accounts for such activities established pursuant to this Act, may be merged with funds in the applicable established accounts, and thereafter may be accounted for as one fund for the same time period as originally enacted.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC936D4BE8F5746CC94E4DF091E4C7A60" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>503.</enum> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HED4FF1C1C6FD4AECA907EC25580E91C1"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds provided by this Act, provided by previous appropriations Acts to the components in or transferred to the Department of Homeland Security that remain available for obligation or expenditure in fiscal year 2018, or provided from any accounts in the Treasury of the United States derived by the collection of fees available to the components funded by this Act, shall be available for obligation or expenditure through a reprogramming of funds that—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H370C0E8062EF4A0086088A74C45583D0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">creates or eliminates a program, project, or activity, or increases funds for any program, project, or activity for which funds have been denied or restricted by the Congress;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFC1746F4A8D94726A8CFCE18F70F393F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contracts out any function or activity presently performed by Federal employees or any new function or activity proposed to be performed by Federal employees in the President's budget proposal for fiscal year 2018 for the Department of Homeland Security;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HADF1DCBA6A464ECC8F32EAB2E398F144"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">augments funding for existing programs, projects, or activities in excess of $5,000,000 or 10 percent, whichever is less;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H32FFCA748F43409B8E19638C76726B0E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>reduces funding for any program, project, or activity, or numbers of personnel, by 10 percent or more;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0B28630E80284E76A075BA1E8C2230D3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>reorganizes components; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBC9F7D8CF0A2435E80E1E419403CE919"><enum>(6)</enum><text>results from any general savings from a reduction in personnel that would result in a change in funding levels for programs, projects, or activities as approved by the Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB176E93BEB1D4342A2F729F6564230C2"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply if the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives are notified at least 15 days in advance of such reprogramming.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H61745985F58E429C8C91F247FE38B6E7"><enum>(c)</enum><text>Up to 5 percent of any appropriation made available for the current fiscal year for the Department of Homeland Security by this Act or provided by previous appropriations Acts may be transferred between such appropriations if the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives are notified at least 30 days in advance of such transfer, but no such appropriation, except as otherwise specifically provided, shall be increased by more than 10 percent by such transfer.</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC6A876A2AB674371937B44298E4D641C"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subsections (a), (b), and (c), no funds shall be reprogrammed within or transferred between appropriations based upon an initial notification provided after June 30, except in extraordinary circumstances that imminently threaten the safety of human life or the protection of property.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H45EC758B3DB84285BCBC9E603F9E2C9E"><enum>(e)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The notification thresholds and procedures set forth in subsections (a), (b), (c), and (d) shall apply to any use of deobligated balances of funds provided in previous Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Acts.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC9792FFB23984956B3ED9EA925735420"><enum>(f)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subsection (c), the Secretary of Homeland Security may transfer to the fund established by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref> note, up to $20,000,000 from appropriations available to the Department of Homeland Security: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That the Secretary shall notify the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives 5 days in advance of such transfer.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H64B66D7705DF49C799DD0B6F4711541E"><enum>504.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 504 of the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2017 (division F of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/31">Public Law 115–31</external-xref>), related to the operations of a working capital fund, shall apply with respect to funds made available in this Act in the same manner as such section applied to funds made available in that Act.</text></section> <section id="H7C312B280A8C42909718C34DF9C49A7E"><enum>505.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise specifically provided by law, not to exceed 50 percent of unobligated balances remaining available at the end of fiscal year 2018, as recorded in the financial records at the time of a reprogramming notification, but not later than June 30, 2019, from appropriations for <quote>Operations and Support</quote> and for <quote>Coast Guard—Operating Expenses</quote>, and salaries and expenses for <quote>Coast Guard—Acquisition, Construction, and Improvements</quote> and <quote>Coast Guard—Reserve Training</quote> for fiscal year 2018 in this Act shall remain available through September 30, 2019, in the account and for the purposes for which the appropriations were provided: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That prior to the obligation of such funds, a notification shall be submitted to the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives in accordance with section 503.</text></section> 
<section id="H95548255E29B435CA5BCFB5B4C292402"><enum>506.</enum><text>Funds made available by this Act for intelligence activities are deemed to be specifically authorized by the Congress for purposes of section 504 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/414">50 U.S.C. 414</external-xref>) during fiscal year 2018 until the enactment of an Act authorizing intelligence activities for fiscal year 2018.</text></section> <section id="H729B3D9BC972400E936A1BF585B05EE7"><enum>507.</enum> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD52C25786EB844EDB322DA63643E228F"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security, or the designee of the Secretary, shall notify the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives at least 3 full business days in advance of—</text> 
<paragraph id="H56119DCA0D274906A34317060CB47524"><enum>(1)</enum><text>making or awarding a grant allocation, grant, contract, other transaction agreement, or task or delivery order on a Department of Homeland Security multiple award contract, or to issue a letter of intent totaling in excess of $1,000,000;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC86A92E22AA942508F5708461C63B9F1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>awarding a task or delivery order requiring an obligation of funds in an amount greater than $10,000,000 from multi-year Department of Homeland Security funds;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H15537E3C73F749E1A9E8ABF83A622E72"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">making a sole-source grant award; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB00C6A15592849DB99EBBEA582668C2B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>announcing publicly the intention to make or award items under paragraph (1), (2), or (3), including a contract covered by the Federal Acquisition Regulation.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H843B9D8FD49D450DA1E048DA9E06EEB5"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary of Homeland Security determines that compliance with this section would pose a substantial risk to human life, health, or safety, an award may be made without notification, and the Secretary shall notify the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives not later than 5 full business days after such an award is made or letter issued.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF19DE5EB48A04D388F925A96E6707268"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A notification under this section—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE80E32F95FD94D27841222A092808908"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may not involve funds that are not available for obligation; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5F608B574CD641E2B688D34B953471C4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall include the amount of the award; the fiscal year for which the funds for the award were appropriated; the type of contract; and the account from which the funds are being drawn.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H32A49CCDA39347479F54D2B5F5F6CF80"><enum>508.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no agency shall purchase, construct, or lease any additional facilities, except within or contiguous to existing locations, to be used for the purpose of conducting Federal law enforcement training without advance notification to the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives, except that the Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers is authorized to obtain the temporary use of additional facilities by lease, contract, or other agreement for training that cannot be accommodated in existing Center facilities.</text></section> <section commented="no" id="H630BE03645B5437EAA06484C5EA634B8"><enum>509.</enum><text>None of the funds appropriated or otherwise made available by this Act may be used for expenses for any construction, repair, alteration, or acquisition project for which a prospectus otherwise required under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/33">chapter 33</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code, has not been approved, except that necessary funds may be expended for each project for required expenses for the development of a proposed prospectus.</text></section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7AD54E007FA64F9F897BCA32B4362061"><enum>510.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sections 520, 522, and 530 of the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2008 (division E of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/161">Public Law 110–161</external-xref>; 121 Stat. 2073 and 2074) shall apply with respect to funds made available in this Act in the same manner as such sections applied to funds made available in that Act.</text></section> <section id="H8B8D59390ADA4847B472691743CAE40F"><enum>511.</enum><text>None of the funds made available in this Act may be used in contravention of the applicable provisions of the Buy American Act: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That for purposes of the preceding sentence, the term <quote>Buy American Act</quote> means <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/41/83">chapter 83</external-xref> of title 41, United States Code.</text></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H73C45D5298A74F199CE35E50B1A71CD8" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>512.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available in this Act may be used to amend the oath of allegiance required by section 337 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1448">8 U.S.C. 1448</external-xref>).</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H19C10D98EF4B41C49EB40FB5E825315F" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>513.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 519 of division F of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/113">Public Law 114–113</external-xref>, regarding a prohibition on funding for any position designated as a Principal Federal Official, shall apply with respect to funds made available in this Act in the same manner as such section applied to funds made available in that Act.</text></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H55B0E54D7A484E539F5B8B5B1CB8667A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>514.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available in this Act may be used for planning, testing, piloting, or developing a national identification card.</text></section> <section id="H5C228A4B23B54E95A63685AC1D1DEFB9"><enum>515.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any official that is required by this Act to report or to certify to the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives may not delegate such authority to perform that act unless specifically authorized herein.</text></section> 
<section id="H2C18E2CF4AE74A408C024AC60D31DC97"><enum>516.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds appropriated or otherwise made available in this or any other Act may be used to transfer, release, or assist in the transfer or release to or within the United States, its territories, or possessions Khalid Sheikh Mohammed or any other detainee who—</text> <paragraph id="H8683818577574E9DBC2B5970690B59E6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is not a United States citizen or a member of the Armed Forces of the United States; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H519B17EF3BE9470DA62B073D6041B0A6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is or was held on or after June 24, 2009, at the United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, by the Department of Defense.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H374716E133114E3391A55D535DB51313"><enum>517.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available in this Act may be used for first-class travel by the employees of agencies funded by this Act in contravention of sections 301–10.122 through 301–10.124 of title 41, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></section> 
<section id="H033C47310DA740559EE987440B1B86CB"><enum>518.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available in this Act may be used to employ workers described in section 274A(h)(3) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a(h)(3)</external-xref>).</text></section> <section id="HF6F961AE2739491EBC55E7940976A796"><enum>519.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, none of the funds appropriated or otherwise made available by this Act may be used to pay award or incentive fees for contractor performance that has been judged to be below satisfactory performance or performance that does not meet the basic requirements of a contract.</text></section> 
<section id="H49A1563C83864ECD924CF8FBF09BF971"><enum>520.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds appropriated or otherwise made available by this Act may be used by the Department of Homeland Security to enter into any Federal contract unless such contract is entered into in accordance with the requirements of subtitle I of title 41, United States Code, or <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/137">chapter 137</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, and the Federal Acquisition Regulation, unless such contract is otherwise authorized by statute to be entered into without regard to the above referenced statutes.</text></section> <section id="H865D08E32B86423AA82BA48948AE9C8A"><enum>521.</enum> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H88E261ED2B5A495BB91D2353DE184639"><enum>(a)</enum><text>For an additional amount for financial systems modernization, $42,233,000, to remain available until September 30, 2019.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H59AF66677B434D7389B83A2F406EE665"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Funds made available in subsection (a) for financial systems modernization may be transferred by the Secretary of Homeland Security between appropriations for the same purpose, notwithstanding section 503 of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9414E5C3099A4952A40A2EA25003B58F"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No transfer described in subsection (b) shall occur until 15 days after the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives are notified of such transfer.</text></subsection></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7E3150DAEDD74D6AB37A1A1C93949475" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>522.</enum> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HCED9577A82EE4831BDCE6CFF46D20729"><enum>(a)</enum><text>None of the funds made available in this Act may be used to maintain or establish a computer network unless such network blocks the viewing, downloading, and exchanging of pornography.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4AD7D9DEFE624E8B9AE019A234DAE8E4"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Nothing in subsection (a) shall limit the use of funds necessary for any Federal, State, tribal, or local law enforcement agency or any other entity carrying out criminal investigations, prosecution, or adjudication activities.</text></subsection></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0D8B6CF8B7D7438CABAF80BBAA7C133E" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>523.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available in this Act may be used by a Federal law enforcement officer to facilitate the transfer of an operable firearm to an individual if the Federal law enforcement officer knows or suspects that the individual is an agent of a drug cartel unless law enforcement personnel of the United States continuously monitor or control the firearm at all times.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC837B50CC4F8460E9919AD69B5F07DDA" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>524.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available in this Act may be used to pay for the travel to or attendance of more than 50 employees of a single component of the Department of Homeland Security, who are stationed in the United States, at a single international conference unless the Secretary of Homeland Security, or a designee, determines that such attendance is in the national interest and notifies the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives within at least 10 days of that determination and the basis for that determination: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That for purposes of this section the term <quote>international conference</quote> shall mean a conference occurring outside of the United States attended by representatives of the United States Government and of foreign governments, international organizations, or nongovernmental organizations: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That the total cost to the Department of Homeland Security of any such conference shall not exceed $500,000.</text></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0967369D35E14292B6B574D48CF2671B" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>525.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available in this Act may be used to reimburse any Federal department or agency for its participation in a National Special Security Event.</text></section> <section id="H4C5B899FFFD0426D8627E1AC718CFA72"><enum>526.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available to the Department of Homeland Security by this or any other Act may be obligated for any structural pay reform that affects more than 100 full-time positions or costs more than $5,000,000 in a single year before the end of the 30-day period beginning on the date on which the Secretary of Homeland Security submits to Congress a notification that includes—</text> 
<paragraph id="H062D5234CC5C423A8E29A9713C3EADEE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of full-time positions affected by such change;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H53F0F202703C4967BE8ED4CE698BDBD7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>funding required for such change for the current year and through the Future Years Homeland Security Program;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0052CB4CA2CB4D84B79C69D418358989"><enum>(3)</enum><text>justification for such change; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC1B11EFFA00C4C05829F6BDD412BF273"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an analysis of compensation alternatives to such change that were considered by the Department.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDD27962949C645A3A90596C1F69200F8" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>527.</enum> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD67C6A3656E14F4EA94AE5BF3DBFC527"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any agency receiving funds made available in this Act shall, subject to subsections (b) and (c), post on the public website of that agency any report required to be submitted by the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives in this Act, upon the determination by the head of the agency that it shall serve the national interest.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD013BF93E6324603B0ECD1B1E16513E2"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) shall not apply to a report if—</text> 
<paragraph id="H33CFE26C5138458F8A6B9D1ED09F00D3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the public posting of the report compromises homeland or national security; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFE4F6EFA48AA4865A1A3EDB0CA81321B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the report contains proprietary information.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H53C87B432A494EAEB09311D6700F02D5"><enum>(c)</enum><text>The head of the agency posting such report shall do so only after such report has been made available to the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives for not less than 45 days except as otherwise specified in law.</text></subsection></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H88C7DD9D1CBB48C2B221D1383E75C138" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>528.</enum> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H5673D2EB44CE48AD911CFD1C1F6FED65"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funding provided in this Act for <quote>Operations and Support</quote> may be used for minor procurement, construction, and improvements.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA90F1ED2A5BE44858BDD427BFFE5988E"><enum>(b)</enum><text>For purposes of subsection (a), <quote>minor</quote> refers to end items with a unit cost of $250,000 or less for personal property, and $2,000,000 or less for real property.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HD940FAD39C3543F2BA656B25EB47812D"><enum>529.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available by this Act may be obligated or expended to implement the Arms Trade Treaty until the Senate approves a resolution of ratification for the Treaty.</text></section> 
<section id="H0931401E1E5046C5952360E8C9D5F74E"><enum>530.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For fiscal year 2018, the Secretary of Homeland Security may provide, out of funds available to the Department of Homeland Security, for the primary and secondary schooling of dependents of Department of Homeland Security personnel who are stationed outside the continental United States and for the transportation of such dependents in the same manner and to the same extent that, pursuant to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/14/544">14 U.S.C. 544</external-xref>, the Secretary may provide, out of funds appropriated to or for the use of the Coast Guard, for the primary and secondary schooling of, and the transportation of, dependents of Coast Guard personnel stationed outside the continental United States.</text></section><appropriations-small id="H1FF9A306EB0440BD9B452701809F8A37"><header>(rescissions)</header></appropriations-small> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H12867090AE914996A1E5C8AFBE380621" section-type="subsequent-section" changed="not-changed"><enum>531.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the funds appropriated to the Department of Homeland Security, the following funds are hereby rescinded from the following accounts and programs in the specified amounts: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That no amounts may be rescinded from amounts that were designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to a concurrent resolution on the budget or the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/99/177">Public Law 99–177</external-xref>):</text> 
<paragraph id="H122281D43A244A249166E3F0EFFC2FFF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$12,928,000 from <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/31">Public Law 115–31</external-xref> under the heading “Transportation Security Administration—Operations and Support”;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCD76AA93C9D84F7A828551F3F5328D3F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$1,785,697 from <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/334">Public Law 108–334</external-xref> under the heading “Coast Guard—Alteration of Bridges”;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H41462DABF0254A2D8AA14471BD721E75"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$1,920,100 from <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/90">Public Law 109–90</external-xref> under the heading “Coast Guard—Alteration of Bridges”;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE413A8578AD94F709B1093819CEC59FA"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$1,791,454 from <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/295">Public Law 109–295</external-xref> under the heading “Coast Guard—Alteration of Bridges”;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAA8DA766708342B69CEC863E747667ED"><enum>(5)</enum><text>$3,221,594 from <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/161">Public Law 110–161</external-xref> under the heading “Coast Guard—Alteration of Bridges”;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB83A5B7045434D0A82063AA9163D0DEF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>$3,680,885 from <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/83">Public Law 111–83</external-xref> under the heading “Coast Guard—Alteration of Bridges”;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3F80836DCF03431CBB7D1A097D133F40"><enum>(7)</enum><text>$25,000,000 from <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/113">Public Law 114–113</external-xref> under the heading “Coast Guard—Acquisition, Construction, and Improvements”; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4C79DDE4F73D401390184EEAAACC351F"><enum>(8)</enum><text>$95,000,000 from <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/31">Public Law 115–31</external-xref> under the heading “Coast Guard—Acquisition, Construction, and Improvements”.</text> </paragraph></section><appropriations-small id="HBF4FC949FB8E47E59012CB2C8F1E3140"><header>(rescissions)</header></appropriations-small> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H27D0B8F265404E95B7B80C7D504F7908" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>532.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From the unobligated balances available in the Department of the Treasury Forfeiture Fund established by section 9703 of title 31, United States Code (added by section 638 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/102/393">Public Law 102–393</external-xref>), $187,000,000 shall be rescinded.</text></section> <appropriations-small id="H2FDF0069B42C4575BE1F9633A8FCC8FA"><header>(rescission)</header></appropriations-small> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3650A47CF1A3499983126AE06470B32A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>533.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the unobligated balances made available to <quote>Federal Emergency Management Agency—Disaster Relief Fund</quote>, $875,575,000 shall be rescinded: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That no amounts may be rescinded from amounts that were designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to a concurrent resolution on the budget or the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985, as amended: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That no amounts may be rescinded from the amounts that were designated by the Congress as being for disaster relief pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(D) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></section> 
<section id="H46A2F4ACC6A24D008B4DBCC7C89FED3F"><enum>534.</enum><text>Not later than 90 days from the date of this Act, the Commissioner of United States Customs and Border Protection shall: (a) conduct a survey of international passenger traffic at the airports listed in section 122.15(b) of title 19, Code of Federal Regulations, and designate any airport as a port of entry if that airport: (1) has scheduled international service by one or more air carriers; and (2) received over 75,000 international passenger arrivals during the most recent calendar year in which federal passenger data is available; (b) ensure a sufficient number of United States Customs and Border Protection officers are available at any airport designated as a port of entry under subsection (a) in order for landing rights requests to be granted in accordance with section 122.14 of title 19, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></section> <section id="HE31E3D9562A0405D8929F17CE0B6C2D7"><enum>535.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds appropriated by this Act for U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement shall be available to pay for an abortion, except where the life of the mother would be endangered if the fetus were carried to term, or in the case of rape or incest: <italic>Provided</italic>, That should this prohibition be declared unconstitutional by a court of competent jurisdiction, this section shall be null and void.</text> </section> 
<section id="HE7D3CB1988254B87A68B0F987AA362C4"><enum>536.</enum><text>None of the funds appropriated by this Act for U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement shall be used to require any person to perform, or facilitate in any way the performance of, any abortion.</text> </section> <section id="HFD14C2C3BED643F380D7CB4F7D21BCC4"><enum>537.</enum><text>Nothing in the preceding section shall remove the obligation of the Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security for U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement to provide escort services necessary for a female detainee to receive such service outside the detention facility: <italic>Provided</italic>, That nothing in this section in any way diminishes the effect of section ____ [preceding section] intended to address the philosophical beliefs of individual employees of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement.</text> </section>
<section id="H0AB9F64478804602A46356100AC24F22"><enum>538.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In fiscal year 2018, nonimmigrants shall be admitted to the United States under section 101(a)(15)(H)(ii)(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)(H)(ii)(a)</external-xref>) to perform agricultural labor or services, without regard to whether such labor is, or services are, of a temporary or seasonal nature. </text></section> <section id="H8663F86D313F4ED3A0207D3A8A300D94" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>539.</enum> <subsection id="HA05CEBE14C154F2DBC1BA97D5CB7733B" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (b) of section 201 of the Immigration and Nationality Act, Christopher William Gard, Constance Rhoda Keely Yates, and Charles Matthew William Gard shall each be eligible for issuance of an immigrant visa or for adjustment of status to that of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence upon filing an application for issuance of an immigrant visa under section 204 of such Act or for adjustment of status to lawful permanent resident.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFAA8B65E67424A989AE890EB305BA4D1"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If Christopher William Gard, Constance Rhoda Keely Yates, or Charles Matthew William Gard enters the United States before the filing deadline specified in subsection (c), he or she shall be considered to have entered and remained lawfully and shall, if otherwise eligible, be eligible for adjustment of status under section 245 of the Immigration and Nationality Act as of the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HCB4D679BE481454095B3E9A1D65AEBAC"><enum>(c)</enum><text>Subsections (a) and (b) shall apply only if the application for issuance of an immigrant visa or the application for adjustment of status is filed with appropriate fees within 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1E5CA9FCF0A74B449D30842058211510"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the granting of an immigrant visa or permanent residence to Christopher William Gard, Constance Rhoda Keely Yates, and Charles Matthew William Gard, the Secretary of State shall instruct the proper officer to reduce by 3, during the current or next following fiscal year, the total number of immigrant visas that are made available to natives of the country of the aliens’ birth under section 203(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act or, if applicable, the total number of immigrant visas that are made available to natives of the country of the aliens’ birth under section 202(e) of such Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9F6CDDF422AA44D48541A845F5AE9F95"><enum>(e)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The natural parents, brothers, and sisters of Christopher William Gard, Constance Rhoda Keely Yates, and Charles Matthew William Gard shall not, by virtue of such relationship, be accorded any right, privilege, or status under the Immigration and Nationality Act.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HB4166FAE351B476AB7CF2E26333ED370"><enum>540.</enum><header>Statue of Limitations</header> 
<subsection id="HE807DC6692C446E9920F9CBD0A3233EA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 705 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5205">42 U.S.C. 5205</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HC32A03272A04425798FFDCC4F9BAA443"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H154A58ED7A034E5CB1C92F922FF9BCE3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Except</quote> and inserting <quote>Notwithstanding section 3716(e) of title 31, United States Code, and except</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7130EAC0C1194A4E83A57A3AF0BB1ABB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>report for the disaster or emergency</quote> and inserting <quote>report for project completion as certified by the grantee</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFDE912C77D5D4C398FC3D43259C6CB77"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <subparagraph id="H8790284AAE9F4631A94E16867A6650D7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1) by striking <quote>report for the disaster or emergency</quote> and inserting <quote>report for project completion as certified by the grantee</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD6A15AB8BE0C4CC7BDC5FB204F0A7ECD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3) by inserting <quote>for project completion as certified by the grantee</quote> after <quote>final expenditure report</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9406D580CE37402AB7324169B50C2947"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header> <paragraph id="HE2F8B15EAD8F4F41973001D3FA40500C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>With respect to disaster or emergency assistance provided to a State or local government on or after January 1, 2004—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H975E0691E88B4F65AD65DA03594981A2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>no administrative action may be taken to recover a payment of such assistance after the date of enactment of this Act if the action is prohibited under section 705(a)(1) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5205">42 U.S.C. 5205(a)(1)</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H41D2FCBB080742EA923756914C4A7608"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any administrative action to recover a payment of such assistance that is pending on such date of enactment shall be terminated if the action is prohibited under section 705(a)(1) of such Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H78FEE8C896C1467CBAA2B171CAA4134F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>This section and the amendments made by this section, may not be construed to invalidate or otherwise affect any administration action completed before the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><appropriations-small id="H099B6B1660024BBD82AF3B7ADE39187F"><header>SPENDING REDUCTION ACCOUNT</header></appropriations-small> <section id="H4264373202594008BF0EA9CB0DFD37E9"><enum>534.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$0.</text></section><appropriations-small id="HD5B1703EAD6E426FA590A8590FDA70F8"><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2018</short-title></quote>.</text> </appropriations-small></title> </legis-body> <endorsement> <action-date date="20170721">July 21, 2017</action-date> <action-desc>Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc> </endorsement> </bill> 

