<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H0BB16C9267684D92B056643245331B52" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2916 IH: Charities Helping Americans Regularly Throughout the Year Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2916</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170615">June 15, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code to extend and modify certain charitable tax provisions.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HF9DB9039E64646969D6157B31FB3890C" style="OLC">
 <section id="HF323DFA16D7A42D480A05E6F21D0FE5F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Charities Helping Americans Regularly Throughout the Year Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H58FD74AA469F462B8244631187462BB4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of the senate relating to the protection of charitable deductions</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6D65893071494A27BD06418BD6D96EC9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Senate makes the following findings:</text>
 <paragraph id="HBF95203207EA4411B04260C5813E0D7E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The deduction for charitable contributions has been an important and effective part of the tax code for almost 100 years.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6CEE190BB5164C488F91F6B9753079D7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The deduction for charitable contributions is unique as it is the only provision that encourages taxpayers to give away a portion of their income for the benefit of others.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H788D832854F446F1BDD45AC04A1D1C54"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In 2012, nonprofit organizations provided 11,400,000 jobs, accounting for 10.3 percent of the country’s private-sector workforce.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H64E66AB38A8B4750B5B35F763E527091"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In 2015, total charitable giving was estimated to be $373,250,000,000 (a 4.1-percent increase from 2014) and accounted for 2.1 percent of the gross domestic product.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4AC1D2532B2C49F4BE813859FC2FFA17"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of the Senate</header><text>It is the sense of the Senate that—</text> <paragraph id="H6AB3BC780486466D947759EA70E07382"><enum>(1)</enum><text>encouraging charitable giving should be a goal of tax reform; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H350CA5156B174919ABEDB873B4131C3D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Congress should ensure that the value and scope of the deduction for charitable contributions is not diminished during a comprehensive reform of the tax code.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2E517A14F17142BA9FAB27F3EFDF0027"><enum>3.</enum><header>Determination of standard mileage rate for charitable contributions deduction</header>
 <subsection id="HEC987EA84D864E20A052838CDC8A4DAC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Determination of standard mileage rate for charitable contributions deduction</header><text>Subsection (i) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/170">section 170</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="H1375DD60E5DE42F28443518F6FA7E815" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HE9829FFA62744087A3C707B1F62A5318"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Standard mileage rate for use of passenger automobile</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of computing the deduction under this section for use of a passenger automobile, the standard mileage rate shall be the rate determined by the Secretary, which rate shall not be less than the standard mileage rate used for purposes of section 213.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H005F652C57DB4C34BFCF33EC051870DB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by this section shall apply to miles traveled after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFF9AF7DC76B64C57BD061D3C0E0E6310"><enum>4.</enum><header>Modification of substantiation requirements for charitable contributions</header>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDB79D0500E054FC6BC2D2BFAE6CDED31"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Paragraph (8) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/170">section 170(f)(8)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking subparagraph (D) and by redesignating subparagraph (E) as subparagraph (D).</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H07C8A5CE51134B7ABA414F54CEBDB24F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to contributions made in taxable years beginning after December 31, 2016.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H43B4A7EF91904323A65ED25CAA9524EB"><enum>5.</enum><header>Mandatory electronic filing for annual returns of exempt organizations</header>
 <subsection id="H00F678D439FD4A45A3E2B68F32388F22"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6033">Section 6033</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by redesignating subsection (n) as subsection (o) and by inserting after subsection (m) the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFCE1CFA91ABA425F86D6C306F9FCC7A7" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H3CDC014FA7E8435AB3E731A8AD0F7EFB"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Mandatory electronic filing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any organization required to file a return under this section shall file such return in electronic form.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCEB53672D02044739E1CFD8095E22DC9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inspection of electronically filed annual returns</header><text>Subsection (b) of section 6104 is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>Any annual return required to be filed electronically under section 6033(n) shall be made available by the Secretary to the public in machine readable format.</quote>.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H121C9DAEF081473E888958CD5827FC8A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header>
 <paragraph id="H3562A347F002405A89CE66A0020F45FD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H0AB8E1D7B1A14BB2A5DC07C09179A8D4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transitional relief</header>
					<subparagraph id="HAFE0F74C94DD447B91A93EDEE3E16834"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Small organizations</header>
 <clause id="HDC33914E3520490ABFBBD0C9B37F9BC4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any small organizations, or any other organizations for which the Secretary determines the application of the amendments made by subsection (a) would cause undue burden without a delay, the Secretary may delay the application of such amendments, but not later than taxable years beginning 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H44079851479443B9A887952984A7688E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Small organization</header><text>For purposes of clause (i), the term <quote>small organization</quote> means any organization—</text> <subclause id="H15411F66F9E447FFB28D19B450DCCFA6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the gross receipts of which for the taxable year are less than $200,000; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HAB9CFFE9E3264FD6BA8F862C4A1B8AC4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the aggregate gross assets of which at the end of the taxable year are less than $500,000.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H190689E3F68F468295133ABB696E559E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Organizations filing form 990–T</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/511">section 511(a)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 which is subject to the tax imposed by section 511(a)(1) of such Code on its unrelated business taxable income, or any organization required to file a return under section 6033 of such Code and include information under subsection (e) thereof, the Secretary may delay the application of the amendments made by this section, but not later than taxable years beginning 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H67A1D38D51EF48A88E8B5C63EB37D881"><enum>6.</enum><header>Modification of rules relating to donor advised funds</header>
			<subsection id="HE940F58BC34C479EB42857DE02D490C3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Allowance of tax-Free charitable distributions from individual retirement accounts</header>
 <paragraph id="H4FD10688A2C34049844D5BCAB93068D1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Clause (i) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/408">section 408(d)(8)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>or any fund or account described in section 4966(d)(2)</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1DDE79CD9D154F888F20FE1DAC2B71E5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this subsection shall apply to distributions made in taxable years beginning after December 31, 2016.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF42021971C664C33A2755A25B78CD581"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Return disclosures</header>
 <paragraph id="H05FFB760D6E949D49CC2977AD0B91266"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Distributions</header><text>Subsection (k) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6033">section 6033</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H4BEA0BC40C4E42DFA60445ABC7288200"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDCA575BA953F4B4083E84CD216E6EA05"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking the period at the end and inserting a comma; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBDA64C413BA6476BA0C0D497629D02A0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9918754468F143729971418AF5E09D45" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H5CDFF0E8E5DC416E99465AF98ACF7B9D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>list the total number of such funds which were in existence for the 36-month period ending at the close of such taxable year,</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7A01A427331F4B6CB920AEA5075F2093"><enum>(5)</enum><text>list the total number of funds described in paragraph (4) which made at least 1 grant during the period described in such paragraph, and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5C2874F191A9482FBD46B9F8D2561C28"><enum>(6)</enum><text>set forth—</text> <subparagraph id="H176C5312EDE1401193D6AE3F96A59E2E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether such organization has a publicly available policy with respect to funds which are inactive, dormant, or do not make distributions during the period described in paragraph (4),</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H16E62826EB1C4258BF6113A3657AB158"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of the organization's policy for responding to funds described in subparagraph (A) or a statement that no such policy is in effect, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D7E8DB174654C62A6469181FA25B5D2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whether such organization regularly and consistently monitors and enforces compliance with the policy described in subparagraph (A) with respect to such funds.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B8E43258C9C46EEB4BCFBD0FF0D756B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this subsection shall apply to returns for taxable years beginning after December 31, 2017.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HFFAF70A627974E31A1E13090A3251D2C"><enum>7.</enum><header>Modification of the tax rate for the excise tax on investment income of private foundations</header>
 <subsection id="H6CDF4D9B852A47EFB56E3981F4CD7FA1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4940">Section 4940(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>2 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>1 percent</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HF810B750635E459BB8B61459BD9785EA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elimination of reduced tax where foundation meets certain distribution requirements</header><text>Section 4940 of such Code is amended by striking subsection (e).</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC460701BFD744A54A1FA2C4DC1A9F373"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H59412F67ACB64F8C9EC3131A4A961ED9"><enum>8.</enum><header>Exception from private foundation excess business holdings tax for certain philanthropic business
			 holdings</header>
 <subsection id="H68273BD80A874844B6441A89D1003154"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4943">Section 4943</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1FBC9E8099D943D68A3695B6839959FB" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H2CDD503F12604F8E88A24FCF14D9E8C1"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Exception for certain philanthropic business holdings</header>
 <paragraph id="H05084CDCAB054988A20640685B44A53C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to the holdings of a private foundation in any business enterprise which for the taxable year meets—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2507D905340A4ED98AB7B6736924857B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the exclusive ownership requirements of paragraph (2),</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22844AFF77914B19B2B86BE165D58BC8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the all profits to charity requirement of paragraph (3), and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4542135AB1AD4563A1E1BCB35187C1BE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the independent operation requirements of paragraph (4).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBDD3D949F66546D1A7150A66EFB5466A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exclusive ownership</header><text>The exclusive ownership requirements of this paragraph are met if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4A2E5A34AD3E41C68E5033B3474637CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>all ownership interests in the business enterprise are held by the private foundation at all times during the taxable year, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H76FD45B9E92947629E3B4E43DEB2EF7C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all the private foundation’s ownership interests in the business enterprise were acquired under the terms of a will or trust upon the death of the testator or settlor, as the case may be.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H084C123506D141E890C2B4598C9BBB32"><enum>(3)</enum><header>All profits to charity</header>
 <subparagraph id="HC6728A88E1A84B0494A2102DD972B37C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The all profits to charity requirement of this paragraph is met if the business enterprise, not later than 120 days after the close of the taxable year, distributes an amount equal to its net operating income for such taxable year to the private foundation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC9AA03E0C004DE1B4704BD2289361C2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Net operating income</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the net operating income of any business enterprise for any taxable year is an amount equal to the gross income of the business enterprise for the taxable year, reduced by the sum of—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="HA324C9F6F9494900A1EE94366ADAC199"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the deductions allowed by chapter 1 for the taxable year which are directly connected with the production of such income,</text>
 </clause><clause id="H854C2044E9B642BDA5280A85E6567247"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the tax imposed by chapter 1 on the business enterprise for the taxable year, and</text> </clause><clause id="HAEB79F15010F4AA3BACC863B23FBBC93"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an amount for a reasonable reserve for working capital and other business needs of the business enterprise.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5879AF60CE5A477EBDB0F7AFBD2315A5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Independent operation</header><text>The independent operation requirements of this paragraph are met if, at all times during the taxable year—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE320C5999B844528B225F5275D545B52"><enum>(A)</enum><text>no substantial contributor (as defined in section 4958(c)(3)(C)) to the private foundation, or family member of such a contributor (determined under section 4958(f)(4)), is a director, officer, trustee, manager, employee, or contractor of the business enterprise (or an individual having powers or responsibilities similar to any of the foregoing),</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD144469F41634C8380B28DCC22B2D57F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>at least a majority of the board of directors of the private foundation are individuals other than individuals who are either—</text>
 <clause id="HA6DBA27FC0444169BE2C7AC1A0D825DD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>directors or officers of the business enterprise, or</text> </clause><clause id="H29007E116DA54AB8A0BD433AEBEF4AD6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>members of the family (determined under section 4958(f)(4)) of a substantial contributor (as defined in section 4958(c)(3)(C)) to the private foundation, and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0DC52A4AC0E4360AC0DE2BDED298666"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">there is no loan outstanding from the business enterprise to a substantial contributor (as so defined) to the private foundation or a family member of such contributor (as so determined).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9791E8620474C7AAF04447FB9AC3D73"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Certain deemed private foundations excluded</header><text>This subsection shall not apply to—</text> <subparagraph id="H0CA165F4813746E4AB44B22DECF3DDD3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any fund or organization treated as a private foundation for purposes of this section by reason of subsection (e) or (f),</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC22AE786302423292EE3B2C88893D4A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any trust described in section 4947(a)(1) (relating to charitable trusts), and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01C3A5FE47EB44019D58D95D5BB61270"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any trust described in section 4947(a)(2) (relating to split-interest trusts).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8256B4F71E56446C9ABDEDD91526A39E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2017.</text> </subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

