<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCCE76FB66D3344E5B660C4F253965A3B" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2426 IH: Secure Government Buildings from Espionage Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2426</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170516">May 16, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the disclosure of beneficial ownership by a foreign person of high-security space leased
			 to accommodate a Federal agency, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H8E01215FAB384A399E69BB3FA7A18E6B" style="OLC">
		<section id="H7E0A4179D8184199A0369E89929A1A5F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; findings</header>
 <subsection id="HAD9013788E77443CA67AF6D3BEA07E3D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Secure Government Buildings from Espionage Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H3F6BE2250EDA4A62AE306568CB0B1862"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HECCB55D7F84349659D81A4A5C55D8117"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Government Accountability Office has reported that the Federal Government often leases high-security space from private sector landlords;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H566AAF4E1F954CEC8B7E4559AFCFE9DC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the General Services Administration and other Federal agencies with leasing authority are not currently required to collect beneficial ownership information and therefore do not know if foreign owners have a stake in the buildings leased by the agencies, even when the leased space is used for classified operations or to store sensitive data; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H12A3B3AB4E8543D78B8A35B2881BC39F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>according to a report of the Government Accountability Office, dated January 2017, that examined the risks of foreign ownership of G<nobreak></nobreak>overnment-leased real estate, <quote>leasing space in foreign-owned buildings could present security risks such as espionage and unauthorized cyber and physical access</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2D30A688ACA64D268A78348A7F61D270"><enum>2.</enum><header>Disclosure of beneficial ownership by foreign persons of high-security space leased for Federal
			 agencies</header>
 <subsection id="HE3B8F822FE7040D7AE8041C61CC282E3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before entering into a lease agreement with a covered entity for the accommodation of a Federal agency in a building (or other improvement) that will be used for high-security leased space, a Federal lessee shall require the covered entity to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H1B2744F06EE7410AB97D38EC40D93561"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify each beneficial owner of the covered entity by—</text> <subparagraph id="H1882426E6696434094B72517A2BD6912"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">name;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7AEFCA448984A06AEF2EDAB49E108C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">current residential or business street address; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05567C3E9E3C42529E67314D32BD5D42"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a unique identifying number from a nonexpired passport issued by the United States or a nonexpired drivers license issued by a State;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H88B044AFB75C4231A952785F16194D6D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>disclose to the Federal lessee any beneficial owner of the covered entity that is a foreign person; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7ED743B122B54DF894602A246D111866"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the Federal lessee is assigning the building (or other improvement) to a Federal tenant, notify the Federal tenant of any disclosure made under paragraph (2).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H47A52340CA2E4199A302671E029E6543"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Timing</header>
 <paragraph id="H548076BCE229473A989C2A48B4EA7606"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A Federal lessee shall require a covered entity to provide the information described in subsections (a)(1) and (a)(2) when first submitting a proposal in response to a solicitation for offers issued by the Federal lessee.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBBCFFFB0D28D4008ACD47E316E03B701"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Updates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Federal lessee shall require a covered entity to update a submission of the information described in subsections (a)(1) and (a)(2) not later than 60 days after the date of any change in—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7FB6D938547C437DAF1B5C702F591CED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the list of beneficial owners of the covered entity; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1AF4F1FDE4B1446CAEA2FC833DE6371E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the information required to be provided relating to each such beneficial owner.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA8A3B0991CF34D7EB8ED8582F4D98008"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the following definitions apply:</text> <paragraph id="H7A0C5A0FE0E94123B25CCA76C9CCA300"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Beneficial owner</header> <subparagraph id="H5F0315AAC8D440A6B414627D3CDB8253"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>beneficial owner</quote> means, with respect to a covered entity, each natural person who, directly or indirectly—</text>
 <clause id="HDE973F1EDEB6497EBC1DC824C3054994"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">exercises control over the covered entity through ownership interests, voting rights, agreements, or otherwise; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H67BAA6A3CFB74015A19899705772650A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has an interest in or receives substantial economic benefits from the assets of the covered entity.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1DECDDD80D64EC8A8380E4E9043673E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>beneficial owner</quote> does not include, with respect to a covered entity—</text>
 <clause id="H2039896F08D84151A3294A4AEEE06CC1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a minor child;</text> </clause><clause id="HA4DF63CB29674C9188B3A5784745639F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a person acting as a nominee, intermediary, custodian, or agent on behalf of another person;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H46B6B216B2864030867CB41F99E357D7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a person acting solely as an employee of the covered entity and whose control over or economic benefits from the covered entity derives solely from the employment status of the person;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB2A99473893B4AEBACF234B2FF0BB358"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a person whose only interest in the covered entity is through a right of inheritance, unless the person also meets the requirements of subparagraph (A); or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H02754A424CB044D0B14CC9470A45FA63"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a creditor of the covered entity, unless the creditor also meets the requirements of subparagraph (A).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C432FCF7B954D85A9A828223A330E46"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Anti-abuse rule</header><text>The exceptions under subparagraph (B) shall not apply if used for the purpose of evading, circumventing, or abusing the requirements of this section.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE5E17B7FD7C74ED1B1BA3053E98D21D7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered entity</quote> means a person, copartnership, corporation, or other public or private entity.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2B3BA794CCEF48C0B8B63F5FB241B9EF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Executive agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Executive agency</quote> has the meaning given the term under section 105 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDE7ED1A840864CE780A5BA1C86D7939F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Federal agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Federal agency</quote> means any Executive agency or any establishment in the legislative or judicial branch of the Government.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4817D14C2C0B4D3A8D1F7C8972A646B0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Federal lessee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Federal lessee</quote> means the Administrator of General Services, the Architect of the Capitol, or the head of any Federal agency, other than the Department of Defense, that has independent statutory leasing authority.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD95C7395CF564D2D85EFC9DC2394F21A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>foreign person</quote> means an individual who is not a United States person or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence into the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCD6A9E3438E043F891B1D855F6324172"><enum>(7)</enum><header>High-security leased space</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>high-security leased space</quote> means a space leased by a Federal lessee that—</text> <subparagraph id="H8A7F8AE872AB4A51AEBE72D7ABA0BC88"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">will be occupied by Federal employees for nonmilitary activities; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1697BB414384B088F2147687C84C733"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has a facility security level of III, IV, or V, as determined by the Interagency Security Committee.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H897A9B3C6F344929AEE92EBCF34232F0"><enum>(8)</enum><header>United States person</header><text>The term <quote>United States person</quote> means a natural person who is a citizen of the United States or who owes permanent allegiance to the United States.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


