<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H0107BF2C59034306AE4627F639ED108B" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1358 IH: Scientific Integrity Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1358</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170302">March 2, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000465">Ms. Tsongas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000563">Mr. Lipinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000287">Mr. Lewis of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000608">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000379">Mr. Kennedy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000015">Mr. Neal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000570">Mr. Ben Ray Luján of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000581">Mrs. Lawrence</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001251">Mr. Butterfield</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001166">Mr. McNerney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000593">Mr. Perlmutter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001050">Ms. Hanabusa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001111">Mr. Crist</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000293">Ms. Esty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To protect scientific integrity in Federal research and policymaking, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H5B00DD406DD74D5A9EB2F656D858C629" style="OLC">
 <section id="H017F32826BE64252A73957C0861C1B82" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Scientific Integrity Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H6FB1A7E2678F4EE3B9B12A2EEC15AAC9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definition of Federal agency</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <quote>Federal agency</quote> has the meaning given the term <quote>agency</quote> in section 551(1) of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </section><section id="H7A63B392572C4C729A0D176B173D41C9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress on scientific integrity</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="H4C975F8B6CE040F58BE4AB4D00A3392A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>science and the scientific process should inform and guide public policy decisions on a wide range of issues, including improvement of public health, protection of the environment, and protection of national security;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2C50B32B20354DFB88D7D28E648CCAA3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the public must be able to trust the science and scientific process informing public policy decisions;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H16D532859D3B4FECAFC50F8553ECB070"><enum>(3)</enum><text>science, the scientific process, and the communication of science should be free from politics, ideology, and financial conflicts of interest; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5A2A63A2264D4A86B6E4F058EC64D8C7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>policies and procedures that ensure the integrity of the conduct and communication of publicly funded science are critical to ensuring public trust.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H524CA64C483649E0B63764F76983F4F1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Public communications</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as provided in section 552(b) of title 5, United States Code, and consistent with privacy and classification standards, the head of each Federal agency that funds or conducts scientific research shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H31AEBC49A3DF496789EE20DBDA8F96A6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promote and maximize the communication and open exchange of data and findings to other agencies, policymakers, and the public of research conducted by a scientist or engineer employed or contracted by a Federal agency that funds or conducts scientific research; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H26C569EE400D4840B22E38BC47ED6991"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prevent the suppression or distortion of the data and findings described in paragraph (1).</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H627448E639654E9AA7FA420D231E4474"><enum>5.</enum><header>Principles</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1009(a) of the America COMPETES Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6620">42 U.S.C. 6620(a)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
			<quoted-block id="H95B322AFDA314E6B86651B3122191369" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="HA56A3ED6E87D44F2A4DAC56F0BCC7301"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Principles</header>
 <paragraph id="H833050510BAC47FDA5B7974507DDFC1D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of the Scientific Integrity Act, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, in consultation with the head of each Federal agency that funds or conducts scientific research, shall develop and issue an overarching set of principles—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H74F85FB1294C4449BA8DBF4241F7A1AD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to ensure the communication and open exchange of data and findings to other agencies, policymakers, and the public of research conducted by a scientist or engineer employed or contracted by a Federal agency that funds or conducts scientific research, while protecting privacy, confidentiality, and national security; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A09B6237D654804ABFF7E52E9ED6F82"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to prevent the suppression or distortion of the data or findings described in subparagraph (A).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF7BF933BD7AC42A7A013749C563F2193"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exchange of data and findings</header><text>In order to promote the sharing of data and findings, as appropriate, the principles shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE3253E068E0C4EA5B9369C11AF27D9E9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>encourage the open exchange of data and findings of research undertaken by a scientist or engineer employed or contracted by a Federal agency that funds or conducts scientific research, while protecting privacy, confidentiality, and national security; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1DEB06806B644439BB7ADE073D8A39A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be consistent with existing Federal laws, including <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/35/18">chapter 18</external-xref> of title 35, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Bayh-Dole Act</quote>).</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="H25B202C7B59F4EE180DE38FA25746F58"><enum>6.</enum><header>Scientific integrity policies</header>
 <subsection id="H37FA348E860B411AA3D20DC4B3AEC088"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1009 of the America COMPETES Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6620">42 U.S.C. 6620</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsection (b) and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HC0259D1677FC4059A52934F67F43F475" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H1EA19F291F84411291661F4D6F5C565F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Scientific integrity policies</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of the Scientific Integrity Act, the head of each Federal agency that funds or conducts scientific research shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H28484A94AF7242CE93B48FC47F3DD408"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop and enforce a scientific integrity policy, including procedures, regarding the release of data and findings to other agencies, policymakers, and the public of research conducted by a scientist or engineer employed or contracted by that Federal agency; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H52E22FEA02794D7EB5FFB9CD718E3828"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit the scientific integrity policy to the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy and Congress.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB11ADF5E8BB74453BADD74F37252B508"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>A scientific integrity policy under subsection (b) shall—</text> <paragraph id="H62FE431BE01E4481BBB2677B1E6B9D5A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be consistent with the principles established under subsection (a);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFCB24FB890744385911B7699BCF46E62"><enum>(2)</enum><text>specifically address what is and what is not permitted or recommended under that policy, including procedures;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0B82A308BFA047BC9DE2164934FFECC3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>be specifically designed for the Federal agency;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB279AED864A64575B3073FEDA0A61C91"><enum>(4)</enum><text>be applied uniformly throughout the Federal agency; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H867EB779817E4E5A8FA704B8830BBBD2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>be publicly accessible and widely communicated to all employees and private contractors of the Federal agency.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H78514B4230AB41B6AF3DC468040DE081"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>At a minimum, each scientific integrity policy under subsection (b) shall ensure that—</text> <paragraph id="H047353FD25A04D07BD7F5A120756A363"><enum>(1)</enum><text>scientific conclusions are not made based on political considerations;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA1CA8B5F47BC4BB9BCC2CC50216774C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the selection and retention of candidates for science and technology positions in the Federal agency are based primarily on the candidate’s expertise, scientific credentials, experience, and integrity;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF1C4D98F3AF842C3BC8983BA6C922C75"><enum>(3)</enum><text>personnel actions regarding scientists and engineers are not made based on political consideration or ideology;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB85221F90B4741F89610904B8E0BF962"><enum>(4)</enum><text>scientists and engineers adhere to the highest ethical and professional standards in conducting their research and disseminating their findings;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H07D70EA8055A43659A48B547E4483370"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the appropriate rules, procedures, and safeguards are in place to ensure the integrity of the scientific process within the Federal agency, including procedures—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB1D82BD2CA3E41B0927E6603DC1A415F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that allow for a scientist to review public release of materials that cite work from that scientist or otherwise claim to represent the scientist’s scientific opinion; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H567CBC08136A440482E981DCCDF195CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to identify, evaluate the merits of, and address instances in which the scientific process or the integrity of scientific and technological information may be compromised;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D3DEC8B45A2405EAF981C447F8B596E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>scientific or technological information considered in policy decisions is subject to well-established scientific processes, including peer review where appropriate;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE85AD020F5C54564AEB472AFFDBF6501"><enum>(7)</enum><text>except as provided in section 552(b) of title 5, United States Code, and consistent with privacy and classification standards, each Federal agency makes publicly available scientific or technological findings that are considered or relied upon in policy decisions and regulatory proposals;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC9A7FB024A384AD8B23207FC55A3167C"><enum>(8)</enum><text>scientific and technical staff are able to ensure the scientific and technical content of scientific documents, reports, press releases, and fact sheets accurately represents the relevant scientific data and conclusions; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H700E49F388234FABAA45E0F42D784FAE"><enum>(9)</enum><text>procedures, including any applicable whistleblower protections, are in place as are necessary to ensure the integrity of scientific and technological information and processes on which the Federal agency relies in its decisionmaking or otherwise uses.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC76B9C67199047729B7B88D128F585F7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Application</header><text>A scientific integrity policy shall apply to each employee or contractor who conducts, handles, communicates, supervises, or manages federally funded scientific research for the Federal agency or for a federally funded research and development center sponsored by the Federal agency.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H74C56CC767714E19AA06BE34ABF04029"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Dissemination of scientific integrity policies and procedures</header><text>The head of each Federal agency that funds or conducts scientific research shall—</text> <paragraph id="H33065EF63B5643B282851CC352710B62"><enum>(1)</enum><text>make the scientific integrity policy available to the public on the Federal agency’s website;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6A108D58474C4602A0C8E971AE797258"><enum>(2)</enum><text>disseminate the scientific integrity policy to each new employee and contractor; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBAB854FF07894A7AA844DAF4521E8FC0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>develop and require training on the scientific integrity policy for each employee or contractor who conducts, handles, communicates, or supervises scientific research for the Federal agency.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9D238F516C3044DEA836A284CA0F2BF4"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definition of federal agency</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>Federal agency</quote> has the meaning given the term <quote>agency</quote> in section 551(1) of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="HC8571182B79144759A30E590C3DAE77C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Existing scientific integrity policies</header><text>Notwithstanding section 1009(b) of the America COMPETES Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6620">42 U.S.C. 6620(b)</external-xref>), as amended by this Act, a scientific integrity policy that was in effect on the day before the date of enactment of this Act may satisfy the requirements of section 1009 of that Act if the head of a Federal agency that funds or conducts scientific research—</text>
 <paragraph id="HAF0DECC099B04D01B720932D41435ED8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>makes a written determination that the policy satisfies the requirements of that section; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H151A5D95B70F4BCA8BA8BD7F42A2F2C0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submits the written determination and the policy to the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy and Congress.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB06FDCB276BB40ED95A103261B1562ED"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall affect the application of United States copyright law.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H0F2565E358B643F4A5BBA1B2C63B58E8"><enum>7.</enum><header>NAPA review</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall enter into an agreement with the National Academy of Public Administration—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9E816BEE309948B4B9CBF5F8B353D1BA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to study the appropriateness of the scientific integrity policies under section 1009 of the America COMPETES Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6620">42 U.S.C. 6620</external-xref>), as added by section 6 of this Act—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5B6015C044F647B3ACBAD3715BE0628A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in promoting the communication and open exchange of data and findings to other agencies, policymakers, and the public of research conducted by scientists employed or contracted by a Federal agency; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBE02E17939F49DC8E3EC794F965D671"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in preventing the suppression or distortion of the data and findings described in subparagraph (A); and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE72DF36C26A74F6081E5F98A96BA3F5F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to recommend any improvements to the scientific integrity policies to achieve the purposes described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1).</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


