<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H44368CB9C68343468D1F56513297B322" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3731 IH: Secret Service Recruitment and Retention Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3731</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170911">September 11, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000566">Mr. Gowdy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000601">Mr. Ratcliffe</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000625">Mr. Donovan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide overtime pay for employees of the United States Secret Service, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H837615A9ABB74A07B5E67A990DF16E00" style="OLC">
 <section id="HEA3975DD6C8249D4BA64B9129E7B3C0A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Secret Service Recruitment and Retention Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H4049057FB20842FBBEC90C872836C6E0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Extension of overtime pay exception through 2018 for protective services</header> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H77F929BE54B74AB29079766B99EFD7A6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Overtime Pay for Protective Services Act of 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/5547">5 U.S.C. 5547</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H66E4F40315FE4E2ABB8BE9BF41FD3D95"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the section heading for section 2, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">2016</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">2016 through 2018</header-in-text></quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0D25736D72E54BCEA81B79CB497B3AFE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>during 2016</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>during 2016 through 2018</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD88A1F98DCDF4C7C9BA13E34C44C57B0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall take effect as if enacted on December 31, 2016.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H3923610A056243EFA773A7602A5D70C2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report on extensions</header><text>Not later than January 30, 2018, and January 30, 2019, the Director of the Secret Service shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on the effects of the amendment made by subsection (a)(2). The report shall include, with respect to the previous calendar year—</text>
 <paragraph id="H20450C6AE6DB46C5BEE502686E595A2A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the total number of United States Secret Service personnel receiving premium pay above the premium pay limitation in subsection (a) of section 5547 of title 5, United States Code;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6425CD3F56DC49F69F6BCCE96F2415E2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total amount of premium pay for that calendar year paid to United States Secret Service personnel above the premium pay limitation in such subsection;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H06E571926D284370B8C05EEA5D955C41"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the mean and median amount of premium pay paid to United States Secret Service personnel above the premium pay limitation in such subsection;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H376A18D36D6E4ECD983C46244A2BF74F"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the greatest amount paid to United States Secret Service personnel above the premium pay limitation in such subsection and the number of employees who received that amount;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H517DBB366CF24A9581878CED920B3E39"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notwithstanding the amendments made by subsection (a), the total number of United States Secret Service personnel who were not fully compensated for service because of the premium pay earnings limitation in section 118 of the Treasury and General Government Appropriations Act, 2001 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/5547">5 U.S.C. 5547</external-xref> note);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBC0C984106DD4856BEDFA3FC4000C182"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total amount of premium pay United States Secret Service personnel would have been paid but for the premium pay earnings limitation in such section; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF2443B200BA247109A0AA03C1890B26F"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of United States Secret Service personnel who, within the calendar year, received premium pay above the premium pay limitation in subsection (a) of section 5547 of title 5, United States Code, and separated from the agency, including the type of separation in each case.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF5D89B2C81044B6FBAD0E59F324E824D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Recruitment and retention efforts</header>
			<subsection id="HB6A7419547A64DE5B61BC466D2A9F647"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Threat assessments</header>
 <paragraph id="H8E1B6FD612D345C88A2921EFEDDEF2B8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Secret Service shall conduct updated threat assessments on all individuals protected by the United States Secret Service and provide such assessments to the appropriate congressional committees. Such threat assessments shall not be conducted for—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0E864085773D46338188432C7FC7754B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the President, the Vice President, or any spouses or children of the President or Vice President; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B5363535C974D36A1DA2E89C4198793"><enum>(B)</enum><text>former Presidents or Vice Presidents.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF77FBC00D9D54F2C9F9E5A2BAB0255B1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement of threat assessments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The threat assessments required under paragraph (1) shall include a description of the costs, including total annual costs, of the protection of each individual.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2510B9BB2ADC449F9CB2E04B22CAA8FB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Recruitment and retention</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Secret Service shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the recruitment and retention efforts of the Secret Service. Such report shall include—</text>
 <paragraph id="H3B7A628490394F5794B33305E181E6B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>data on the overall attrition rate for agency personnel;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H74A041B3727D49ED9530ACA92D2DD509"><enum>(2)</enum><text>information on the causes of employee attrition and issues of low morale;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9E3DFF3428094F0AB14226DAE4D4650A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a strategy for overhauling the agency’s recruitment and hiring process; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5DCF5780865F41419871435A155A675A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a strategy for improving retention of agency personnel.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBD3D01DFC0BA4487A7A571B8887914DD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Extension of protection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the Department of Homeland Security or the United States Secret Service is directed by the President or the Secretary of Homeland Security to extend the protection of an individual beyond the length of time that would otherwise be provided to such individual, and such protection is provided by the United States Secret Service, the Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through the Director of the Secret Service, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a notice of such extension, including an updated threat assessment on such individual.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF5D3087A28574B39A15B5472E2E650D3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Polygraph test questions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 10 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Secret Service shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a list of all questions asked in calendar year 2016 on any polygraph exam the United States Secret Service issued to an applicant for employment in the United States Secret Service.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5F70F6142A2541A4AC4CA0C0DE6098FE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text> <paragraph id="H0E38D0B42A6F44F494782F55506BD19F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3526286C8934424BB533485599F888FE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

