<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1285AC41489645099F5773B01ACDA369" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4009 IH: Smithsonian National Zoological Park Central Parking Facility Authorization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4009</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171011">October 11, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000174">Mr. Sam Johnson of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001053">Mr. Cole</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name>, and in addition to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Board of Regents of the Smithsonian Institution to plan, design, and construct a
			 central parking facility on National Zoological Park property in the
			 District of Columbia.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HB64B33547F2E4D32B4A5CF6EDAA3E3F3" style="OLC">
 <section id="HF13C25C795FB4CA8866A823028526918" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Smithsonian National Zoological Park Central Parking Facility Authorization Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H0D2408B1FD9A4BE484D682BAA8AB40F7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Facility for improved visitor experience and access at the National Zoological Park</header> <subsection id="H7054E826D8D0409684EDD9233AA27D3D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text>In order to improve visitor experience and multi-modal access to the Smithsonian National Zoological Park, the Board of Regents of the Smithsonian Institution is authorized to plan, design, and construct a central parking facility on National Zoological Park property in the District of Columbia.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H383E27358A234687B4157A63C9444773"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Central parking facility</header><text>The facility authorized under this section may include parking, transportation improvements, visitor amenities including restrooms, a pedestrian bridge to a midpoint entry of the National Zoological Park, and ancillary works to accommodate alternative uses of the facility.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8305C3FFD1A6422088E1F35AC2DB9D1C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>Construction of the facility described in this section shall be conducted with funds from nonappropriated sources.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


