<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H33C5B7D2D83343E7A50D6D6F0B21EA53" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2370 RH: Escambia County Land Conveyance Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
		<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 168</calendar>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2370</legis-num>
		<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 115–236]</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20170504">May 4, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000578">Mr. Gaetz</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<action><action-date>July 20, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsor: <cosponsor name-id="B001274">Mr. Brooks of Alabama</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action>
			<action-date>July 20, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc>Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed<pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To authorize Escambia County, Florida, to convey certain property that was formerly part of Santa
			 Rosa Island National Monument and that was conveyed to Escambia County
			 subject to restrictions on use and reconveyance.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H2B76F80F2B1947658980B709DB69F912" style="OLC">
 <section id="H4FEEEA05F0564FC8B2ACD4097DAE0C8C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Escambia County Land Conveyance Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HE2DD1E22B7AF4ECCBF0F1C21B2F8ECCF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="H4EFD6C1FD06D4E49AC07910C8EBA54EF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>County</header><text>The term <term>County</term> means Escambia County, Florida.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H05DD3D182E114976B98AF85DB957A338"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Non-federal land</header><text>The term <term>non-Federal land</term> means the former Santa Rosa Island National Monument land in the State that was conveyed by the United States to the County under the Act of July 30, 1946 (60 Stat. 712, chapter 699), and by deed dated January 15, 1947.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0B482345E8FC40909F9A07B9EBD2EB51"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of Florida.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H8BAB23C1E16D4BB286A2090CAA0D10F7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reconveyance of non-Federal land to Escambia County, Florida</header> <subsection id="H2082B2598B3A433BAB46B16616E6A754"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding the restrictions on conveyance in the Act of July 30, 1946 (60 Stat. 712, chapter 699), and the deed to the non-Federal land from the United States to the County dated January 15, 1947, and subject to subsections (c) through (g), the County may convey all right, title, and interest of the County in and to the non-Federal land or any portion of the non-Federal land, to any person or entity, without any restriction on conveyance or reconveyance imposed by the United States in that Act or deed.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA742E6BA72714B61ADE665F657822116"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effect on leasehold interests</header><text>No person or entity holding a leasehold interest in the non-Federal land as of the date of enactment of this Act shall be required to involuntarily accept a fee interest to the non-Federal land in place of the leasehold interest in the non-Federal land.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H819D62C0B3264C44A5452125A5419BD1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conveyance of land within Santa Rosa County, Florida</header>
 <paragraph id="H0AEC665DCCAB49158A09C42DA81EC613"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a condition of the authority granted to the County to convey the non-Federal land under subsection (a), all right, title, and interest of the County in and to any portion of the non-Federal land that is within the jurisdictional boundaries of Santa Rosa County, Florida, shall be conveyed by the County to Santa Rosa County, Florida, by the date that is 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2F5D608BF5C04CEB947A2E1150F97A49"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A conveyance under paragraph (1) shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HBA9C6B312E5C424385ACB5351CA4798C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be absolute;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49DEFA5631744F3AA190D6117C1A0A96"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">terminate—</text> <clause id="H6DC4CBE4BEDD4582BF1DE8AE9E4D5C64"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any subjugation of Santa Rosa County, Florida, to the County; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC095DB29438D4F29A4B8767EB0E2FBB9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any regulation of Santa Rosa County, Florida, by the County; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HDD9452E382A841798B7AA1058F181707"><enum>(C)</enum><text>be without consideration, except that the County may require Santa Rosa County, Florida, to pay the actual costs associated with the conveyance of the non-Federal land to Santa Rosa County, Florida.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE97F2884485B440B96FCFC84B4E4E677"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Assumption of ownership; imposition of restrictions</header><text>On conveyance of the non-Federal land to Santa Rosa County, Florida, under paragraph (1), Santa Rosa County, Florida—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAEE86253FBCE4835A100D184A1CD1B68"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall assume ownership of the non-Federal land free of the restrictions on the non-Federal land described in subsection (g); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5B70BD4413A4019BC7EE3A968967145"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may establish any lawful restrictions on, or criteria for the reconveyance of, the non-Federal land to any leaseholder of the non-Federal land.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0CB971BE671432A9C9599BC6D3F93F1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reconveyance</header><text>Santa Rosa County, Florida, or any other person to whom Santa Rosa County, Florida, reconveys the non-Federal land may reconvey the non-Federal land or any portion of the non-Federal land conveyed to Santa Rosa County, Florida, under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9432060BAAFD46DBB9DA8701BD27EE77"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Incorporation or annexation</header><text>An owner or leaseholder of the non-Federal land conveyed under this section may pursue incorporation, annexation, or any other governmental status for the non-Federal land, if the owner or leaseholder complies with the legal conditions required for incorporation, annexation, or the other governmental status.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8934689820CB4120BAE4F2BBF9D46AB7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Jurisdiction</header><text>The non-Federal land shall be subject to the jurisdiction of the county or unit of local government in which the non-Federal land is located.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDFD3813B6148499CBDC533D5BEAF91EF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Proceeds</header><text>Any proceeds from the conveyance of the non-Federal land by the County or Santa Rosa County, Florida (other than amounts paid for the direct and incidental costs associated with the conveyance), under this section shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF50F46B81BFD425284D53FE969C46602"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be considered to be windfall profits; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF9DC7AB47AE14515ADEB5C0269521D76"><enum>(2)</enum><text>revert to the United States.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1DA906441CF4429DB050198BF5AEDB6E"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Preservation</header><text>As a condition of the grant of the authority to convey the non-Federal land under subsection (a), the County shall preserve in perpetuity the areas of the non-Federal land that, as of the date of enactment of this Act, are dedicated for conservation, preservation, public recreation access, and public parking, in accordance with any resolutions of the Board of Commissioners of the County.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H38507484FA4048E58D703D084124B1FC"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Determination of compliance</header><text>The County and Santa Rosa County, Florida—</text> <paragraph id="H22D2524A115E49D2917FE5528428450D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>except as provided in subsection (c)(1), shall not be subject to a deadline or requirement to make any conveyance or reconveyance of the non-Federal land authorized under this section; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1569AFFD18BE4FD985FD933FC53FEEE1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may establish terms for the conveyance or reconveyance of the non-Federal land authorized under this section, subject to this Act and applicable State law.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
	<endorsement display="yes">
		<action-date>July 20, 2017</action-date>
		<action-desc>Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill>


