<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC5809BA29F024744A6315A808E2DFE97" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2016 IH: CPI for Seniors Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2016</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170406">April 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000533">Mr. Duncan of Tennessee</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000563">Mr. Lipinski</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To mandate the monthly formulation and publication of a consumer price index specifically for senior citizens for the purpose of establishing an accurate Social Security COLA for such citizens.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC5DE025BAEDD4F34A0F742494464A8BC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HAEE5911DC1E2465E86A7A6D7839D8719" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>CPI for Seniors Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF9FD67411CF5488AB245F9BA80C1F4A3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H9EBD85C1961F430DA8F764C1CB1E83E9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Each year the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor prepares and publishes consumer price indices (the most notable being the Consumer Price Index or <quote>CPI</quote>) that measure the rate of inflation in the economy of the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H08093877285648A4A3B391230C123D48"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A derivative of the CPI is used to determine an annual cost-of-living adjustment (hereinafter referred to as <quote>COLA</quote>) for millions of senior citizens (individuals aged 62 and over) who depend on their respective Social Security benefits.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8CE0E011C4964BBAB10ECE5FB85048D3"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Social Security COLA is calculated using the Consumer Price Index for Urban Wage Earners and Clerical Workers (hereinafter referred to as <quote>CPI–W</quote>), a subset of the population covered by the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers (hereinafter referred to as <quote>CPI–U</quote>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H58B8F10673744170BA69A15FB1CC5A81"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">While the experimental Consumer Price Index for Americans 62 Years of Age and Older (hereinafter referred to as <quote>CPI–E</quote>) is a more accurate measure of the average price of consumer goods and services purchased by senior citizens than the CPI–W, it too is derived from the CPI–U.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H65905DC5592E4D1E90D4C9FCCBE01B71"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to numerous credible authorities, the present methods (CPI–U, CPI–W, and CPI–E to a lesser extent) used to measure inflation are flawed and deficient in measuring the average price of consumer goods and services purchased by senior citizens, and the overall impact of inflation on such citizens.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H72CAEE486E3B46DAA1E26B8A431A9187"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The present sampling regarding senior citizens is too small under the methods referred to in paragraph (5), creating an opportunity for sampling error.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE0970473BF924CB9A593AA6C309E31EA"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prices used under the methods referred to in paragraph (5) are based on geographic areas, retail outlets, and sample items used and purchased by younger consumers and are not necessarily representative of the geographic areas, retail outlets, and sample items used and purchased by senior citizens.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0E83E93D525C4AFFA04B7551BEB30A64"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The locations used under the methods referred to in paragraph (5) are urban locations that do not reflect the economic challenges faced in rural communities, which often have a far larger demographic segment of senior citizens.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC4DFC40B8B5C46F9829C6966B233B19A"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Senior citizens neither have the flexibility or the ability that younger consumers have to substitute necessary purchases in response to changes in prices, nor the same options as younger consumers have to supplement their income.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDBF55589BB02422FB5AD016A78277ADF"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Premium increases for part B of Medicare, part D of Medicare, and other health care costs affecting senior citizens are not adequately considered under the methods referred to in paragraph (5).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAF2E8B24A58E41F2A77B88CE627F07F3"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The cost of taxes on Social Security income is not considered under the methods referred to in paragraph (5), thus putting senior citizens at a greater economic disadvantage each year.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HB9C20C18F51E47AE9749DFE54B2B7A43"><enum>3.</enum><header>Mandate the monthly formulation and publication of a consumer price index for seniors</header> <subsection id="H5847A618398641A895B2309D3CB39B79"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of new CPI</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor shall prepare and publish an index monthly to be known as the <quote>Consumer Price Index for Seniors</quote> (hereinafter referred to as <quote>CPI–S</quote>) that indicates monthly changes in expenditures for consumption that are typical for individuals in the United States who are 62 years of age or older.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HD2900F9BF14142D69EA46BBB51274AB4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Submission to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor shall submit to the Joint Economic Committee a description of the actions taken by such Bureau to meet the requirements of this section not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, and semi-annually thereafter.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE496A786F9AF49AC9D7368FA902DA173"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

