<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H4CB78C321FA649C7862524A247EC37A0" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4388 IH: Forgotten Families Recovery Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4388</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171114">November 14, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000614">Mr. Duffy</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prioritize, in certain substance abuse prevention, treatment, and recovery programs, the
			 treatment and recovery of addicted minors, and individuals responsible for
			 the care of dependent minors who are at risk of entering the foster care
			 system.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H1C7988B467E642DA936764EA7DA616FF" style="OLC">
 <section id="H9C4F2580885345B08100612AA6E48776" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Forgotten Families Recovery Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H1FDD8B84A0DE45FA914BC2A0178FCDCC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress on prioritizing rural families and at-risk youth within substance abuse prevention programs</header> <subsection id="H1B15A291A56B40219A544FDFC17F3711"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>The Congress finds as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="HBCDF9F56D15444FABE847B0B4EC8312E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Behavioral health and detoxification (detox) services are not as readily available in rural communities. For those that are available, their range of services is frequently limited.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEE069D72E02D4931A4E695EEE100864A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Patients who require treatment for substance abuse may need to travel long distances to access these services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA646143F6D5E4E2C8752CD56986D0AA7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Rural first responders or the rural hospital emergency room (ER) staff may have limited experience in providing care to a patient presenting the physical effects of a drug overdose.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2C7400BA7539485D9FC19158128BD725"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Law enforcement and prevention programs may be spread sparsely over large rural geographic areas.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD37B51A690A64F96A5E72889CBD061D7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>According to a 2012 study published by the Maine Rural Health Research Center, alcohol use and binge drinking are more common among rural youth aged 12 to 13 than among urban youth the same age.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB97495FCB57C425D9DB0D8325A327129"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Rural adolescents reported higher rates of binge drinking and driving under the influence (DUI) than urban adolescents.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H93468279C90C4B1EBF46CD58360C93F8"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A 2014 JAMA Psychiatry article concluded that heroin users entering treatment over the past 50 years have demonstrated a changing geographical composition, with an increasing percentage in more recent years arriving from communities outside of large urban areas.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC040287BC0F44FA0B5EEFDF2D4AC4441"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in carrying out substance abuse prevention, treatment, and recovery programs, should prioritize appropriate funding for activities within rural populations, especially those with high rates of substance abuse among families, or high rates of dependent minors at risk of entering the foster care system.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HC04B04BC27E24B838399F1F4E5069F89"><enum>3.</enum><header>Priority for the treatment and recovery of addicted minors, and individuals responsible for the
			 care of dependent minors who are at risk of entering the foster care
 system</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 516(b)(2) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290bb-22">42 U.S.C. 290bb–22(b)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H6455A6845A544C79A2625D511D4B62C3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8F94B1CDBE4F4270BBE513FB1554CA07"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (C) as subparagraph (D); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H71AB5F0CB20A4E75A7B48156E07D1236"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (B) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H072F25D2C0AF4907BC4FB7F7D5EBE63C" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="HF43CAC6BB4EC4C49AF3C4F2D8A169156"><enum>(C)</enum><text>promoting the treatment and recovery of addicted minors, and individuals responsible for the care of dependent minors who are at risk of entering the foster care system; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


