<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H74CE8835F498498D9431C942A260AA88" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2907 IH: Planning for American Energy Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2907</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170615">June 15, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000470">Mr. Tipton</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Mineral Leasing Act to require the Secretary of the Interior to develop and publish an
			 all-of-the-above quadrennial Federal onshore energy production strategy to
			 meet domestic energy needs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HEFD6106231024A07A2748B7003C5A8C5" style="OLC">
 <section id="H73D0C0A141EA4419AA2CB86D15F1C1AE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Planning for American Energy Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HDDBC4A4996504D1C9B12B11FE754A9E2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Onshore domestic energy production strategic plan</header> <subsection id="HFB07342427A5422BA2821A0034B3D617"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Mineral Leasing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/181">30 U.S.C. 181</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by redesignating section 44 as section 45, and by inserting after section 43 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HEC6EDC84943F4AA2996255104290F9A0" style="OLC">
					<section id="H6B796669AE46496C907BC53E7A4077E4"><enum>44.</enum><header>Quadrennial Federal Onshore Energy Production Strategy</header>
 <subsection id="H087F885B5608491EB82FD716C643AD6A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement To publish Quadrennial Federal Onshore Energy Production Strategy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall develop and publish once every 4 years a Quadrennial Federal Onshore Energy Production Strategy.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE73FB44F18F442449861C7A68C263F48"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultations required</header><text>In developing the Strategy, the Secretary shall consult with—</text> <paragraph id="H776493E774CF48ED969C3F8072111448"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration with regard to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H34F2671A5F684B109F8125BE51E0677B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the projected energy demands of the United States for the next 30-year period;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1953E31E2A84492B9DB5C1A06696FB8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the methodology used to arrive at such projection; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8F150E8486B649258C75744155B420D8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>actions to be taken during the next 4-year period with the goal of meeting such demands;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1D3D78A91B848C4A11F5F2D56191F7C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture with regard to lands administered by such Secretary; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H025201945E5E43BDB306C3280938921D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Energy with regard to energy transmission, storage, and distribution infrastructure.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H13F52E57C7A0443AA8A9B5DE5D3030F6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>State, federally recognized Indian Tribes, local government, and public input</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the Strategy, the Secretary shall solicit the input of—</text> <paragraph id="H9C8EDC1BBE374DF7B2447DA05E9A24DA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the State, federally recognized Indian Tribe, or local government where each energy project included in the Strategy is proposed to be located; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEA0838115A7948059E84EEFEB476DA01"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the public.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9D814C539FBC4B3AA6081E28B30728C4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Contents of Strategy</header> <paragraph id="H138A74350EFD4ACEAF7F2E92C5ED7797"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Strategy shall direct onshore Federal land energy development and department resource allocation in order to promote the energy security and national security of the United States in accordance with the principles of multiple use and sustained yield.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4C3C3E5C51C04CA5AFC65E033CA4CB56"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Projected domestic demand for energy resources</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration, shall include in the Strategy an estimate, based upon commercial and scientific data, of the projected domestic demand for energy resources over the 30-year period beginning on the date of the publication of such Strategy. The estimate shall be disaggregated by the energy resource types listed in subparagraphs (A) through (H) of paragraph (3) and expressed in British thermal units or me­ga­watts, as appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA1AE8B7041C64F0B85DB10C6E803E07D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Domestic strategic production objective</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall include in the Strategy a domestic strategic production objective based on the estimate in paragraph (2) for the development of the following energy resource types on Federal onshore lands:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0E59C2BFF2474F5A86882BBBFEABFD58"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Oil and natural gas.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20EBA1AE0721444A8422DFD44E264710"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Coal.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F5FBD27241B48B38BC885649DC4C2EB"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Strategic and critical energy minerals.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDD99B0FC117404EA1DBB7C992913219"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Electricity, in megawatts, from each of wind, solar, biomass, hydropower, and geothermal energy.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B69611F24824509942DD96D7AD1ABFF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Energy from unconventional energy production, such as oil shale.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2BFF7D808272482B85486F5D3C649AEF"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Helium.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H27512E5B09A8489B9DCEF405049C6881"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Oil, natural gas, coal, and other renewable sources from the Tribal lands of any federally recognized Indian Tribe that elects to participate in facilitating energy production on its lands.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0414DE5898D2449BAC75AA7992E72F40"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Other energy production technology sources or advancements in energy, as determined by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD27370334A2B4F799541EF97807A0FC1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the Strategy, the Secretary shall consider—</text> <subparagraph id="HF348887D2BC841DB85E9EECAD98ED982"><enum>(A)</enum><text>how Federal lands will contribute to ensuring national energy security, with a goal for increasing energy independence and production during the next 4-year period;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E5ED40E954C48F098D35E7AD166E6D8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the ability of existing energy transmission, storage, and distribution infrastructure to efficiently utilize energy production from Federal lands; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8C9698E4772E48DE904D17922BA24EF9"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the proportion of total energy production derived from Federal land compared to non-Federal land for each of the energy resources listed in subparagraphs (A) through (H) of paragraph (3).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H75D146A8B2434FA58ED9C538A5933A8A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Tribal objectives</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that federally recognized Indian Tribes may elect to set their own production objectives as part of the Strategy. The Secretary shall work in cooperation with any federally recognized Indian Tribe that elects to participate in achieving its own strategic energy objectives.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H38810D81A2AA4AFE870967DFBD8D61CB"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>The Secretary shall submit a report annually to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H300D385FDEFE48448F78403DE20490CC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">examines the progress made toward meeting the domestic strategic production objective set forth in the Strategy;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE8C486A889A42E0B7E79D0276F4CAEF"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifies projections for production and capacity installations and any problems with leasing, permitting, siting, or production that may prevent meeting the domestic strategic production objective set forth in the Strategy; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H82EF7626C2674911B9E343CE53F95C85"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides suggestions to address any shortfalls in meeting the domestic strategic production objective set forth in the Strategy.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8AE4239EFEF541FCA3ABA210436B37E4"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Congressional review</header><text>At least 60 days before publishing a proposed Strategy under this section, the Secretary shall submit such Strategy to the President and to Congress, together with any comments received from States, federally recognized Indian Tribes, and local governments. Such submission shall state why any specific recommendation of a State, federally recognized Indian Tribe, or local government was not accepted.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9C7191F0D7834D09B10E8F0FD035D135"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H85A98C5BCB7F434D81546FC8422A5900"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Multiple use</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>multiple use</quote> has the same meaning given such term in section 103 of the Federal Land and Policy Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1702">43 U.S.C. 1702</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H46C6871CE5CC4DB78B7CF5FD1F6777E4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of the Interior, unless the context requires otherwise.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H864656C761024C319B32288C155F55B2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Strategy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Strategy</quote> means the Quadrennial Federal Onshore Energy Production Strategy required to be developed and published under subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H44206203F61747A0B6B7968E55D2CEAB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Strategic and critical energy minerals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>strategic and critical energy minerals</quote> means minerals that are necessary for the production of energy and the building and maintaining of the energy infrastructure of the United States, including minerals necessary—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEDD16F411C794C40B98D5541B8A26E4A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for pipelines, refining capacity, electrical power generation and transmission, and renewable energy production;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4632D90E6004F2090C81775CA6AB546"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to support domestic manufacturing, including materials used in energy generation, production, and transportation; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D761AAB854A4422B1AAF48B9DEA36E7"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to ensure the national security of the United States.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB5C4BA53FEF46DB8B6414852FA99024"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Sustained yield</header><text>The term <quote>sustained yield</quote> has the same meaning given such term in section 103 of the Federal Land and Policy Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1702">43 U.S.C. 1702</external-xref>).</text>
							</paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HDAD5E901FE3F429FBAD57C6ADEF7F080"><enum>(b)</enum><header>First Quadrennial Strategy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior shall submit to Congress the first Quadrennial Federal Onshore Energy Production Strategy under the amendment made by subsection (a).</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


