<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H4B892CCC1E8D4B028DCEC2755A35E337" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1982 IH: Mental Health Access and Gun Violence Prevention Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1982</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170406">April 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize funding to increase access to mental health care treatment to reduce gun violence.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H9CEF63E111D049AE817C2C608EC30D6B" style="OLC">
 <section id="H0EC919BC10E244719DA6B668A72AC1D3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Mental Health Access and Gun Violence Prevention Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H1732CC01E1CB4EC780F8EF0EC81F7335"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="H4DAFD5AD54804EA297BF05BA112CEE37"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Suicide is the leading cause of gun related deaths in America. More than 60 percent of deaths by guns in the country are the result of individuals using these weapons as a means to commit suicide. Some of these deaths might have been prevented if there were adequate background checks.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4314626E5C4D43AB85CADAEDAF03E451"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Victims of domestic abuse are more likely to become victims of homicide when a gun is present. Further, individuals who suffer from mental illnesses are more likely to be victims rather than perpetrators of violence.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA80113EC4D5C4C18A2C1A8E0EC3CB838"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Approximately 1 in 4 American adults have a mental illness and nearly half of all adults in America will develop at least one mental illness during their lifetime.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5C417651F24D43BDA2A7353965FB2C10"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Less than half of children and adults with diagnosable mental health problems receive the treatment they need.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H7B939C44637D4556AE622A9C148B8C72"><enum>3.</enum><header>Authorization of funding to increase access to mental health care treatment to reduce gun violence</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Attorney General of the United States, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and the Commissioner of Social Security $500,000,000 for fiscal year 2018 to carry out programs and activities authorized by provisions of law other than this Act—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC279BA24528E40F4810F4A764D7D53C2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to increase access to mental health care treatment and services; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6D5807B073244DFAB21261BA765D0BA3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to encourage and assist the reporting of relevant disqualifying mental health information to the National Instant Criminal Background Check System.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


