<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE3DB19FD89254A7E8D522751ADE98780" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1586 IH: Protecting Our Kids’ Medicine Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1586</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170316">March 16, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000248">Mr. Serrano</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to ensure that liquid over-the-counter
			 medications are packaged with appropriate dosage delivery devices and, in
			 the case of such medications labeled for pediatric use, appropriate flow
			 restrictors, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HFDFFB872133D43F1A2D285B5CBBD49CA" style="OLC">
 <section id="H7CDAA852677A43DFA216A526A5DB0F93" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Our Kids’ Medicine Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HFC5599A5F61A4417BFEC0AE1F46FC432"><enum>2.</enum><header>Dosage delivery devices for liquid OTC drugs and flow restrictors for such drugs labeled for pediatric use</header> <subsection id="HDA8E1FA70FE9491DA63D09FBD8F0A948"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 502 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/352">21 U.S.C. 352</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB5CF8726A72D4F41A52A8BF6FE6E6BEB" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="HFD3D47B834F146F38E9C280110E73EEF"><enum>(ee)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H110BD54184F740C4B53E5818A407A951"><enum>(1)</enum><text>If it is a liquid formulation of a drug that is not subject to section 503(b) and—</text> <subparagraph id="HF8FB0EBBF2DF4E2DBD1CA24AA48510AF" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>it is not packaged with a dosage delivery device in accordance with specifications to be determined by the Secretary by regulation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33748BCDA636418993C58CF8FFF1D63C" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of such a liquid formulation that is labeled for pediatric use, it is not packaged with a dosage delivery device, as described in subparagraph (A), and—</text>
 <clause id="H107D264CE4884CA1B710689E341B5F5D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a flow restrictor; or</text> </clause><clause id="H705E24952AA04B2CA778697C025CB92D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>another mechanism to reduce the frequency and volume of accidental ingestion that provides a level of safety that is equivalent to or greater than the level of safety that would be provided by a flow restrictor, as determined by the Secretary by regulation; or</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE5997B330D4405E8F28C810053C1A16" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>its labeling is in violation of subparagraph (2).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H888E3ED19E064C03B902259006F71B2F" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall require that any measurement in the labeling of a liquid formulation of a drug that is not subject to section 503(b), including any measurement in the labeling of a dosage delivery device packaged with the liquid formulation, be expressed exclusively in metric units. The Secretary may waive the requirement in the preceding sentence with respect to one or more liquid formulations if the Secretary determines that, with respect to such formulations, implementation of such requirement would not benefit the public health.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7867B9915A0845049646A4A0553B7740" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In this paragraph:</text> <subparagraph id="H8881A044D8044B5EB873AC31F1769615"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term <term>dosage delivery device</term>—</text>
 <clause id="HD275FB11584B4B98AAA5AED920039ACF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>means an object that is designed to measure the dosage of a drug in liquid form and deliver that drug to an individual; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H38E8BC23A4C140BB95B12CC8602C1251"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>includes calibrated cups, droppers, syringes, and spoons.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD492992C1BC147DDAE9DFFAD247DF48D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term <term>flow restrictor</term> has such meaning as the Secretary may prescribe by regulation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE4FE0C3C90954660972A3D95BECAFDF3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9103C05C704E48E1A4EEF979CA1E3994"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promulgate a final rule implementing the amendment made by subsection (a); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3878BD700EE24DBCA6AC17BB79AD4DA3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include in such rule a definition of the term <term>flow restrictor</term>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5041D5260269477BBE265952B1B24E98"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) applies beginning on the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


