<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2239432F839349F792E1AD15419FC50D" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4262 IH: Financial Independence for Disabled Veterans Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4262</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171106">November 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000819">Mr. Walker</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize members and former members of the uniformed services who are entitled to veterans
			 disability compensation to continue to participate in the Thrift Savings
			 Plan through the deduction and deposit of a percentage of their veterans
			 disability compensation to the Thrift Savings Fund.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H85B0E0A35DC3438285018A81CE1288AA" style="OLC">
 <section id="H11D46F781559425ABC2638F102BBA9A4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Financial Independence for Disabled Veterans Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HFC86AC2B5BB947E99146ABD8D52A56F8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Disabled veterans continued participation in Thrift Savings Plan</header> <subsection id="H06F8D3DB96FF422A87EB5067BDB3AA21"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Participation authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Executive Director of the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board shall prescribe regulations to permit the continued participation in the Thrift Savings Plan by a member of the uniformed services after the discharge or release of the member from service in the uniformed services if the member or former member is entitled to veterans disability compensation.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0497EC992FC246DCABE052A7DD4D4ABA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contributions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of section 8432 of title 5, United States Code, the monthly veterans disability compensation of a member or former member of the uniformed services shall be deemed to be basic pay for a monthly pay period.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEBB307E7D8754362A5CC7210B16672F6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Matching contributions prohibited</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The deduction and deposit in the Thrift Savings Fund of a percentage of the veterans disability compensation of a member or former member of the uniformed services does not require or authorize Government contributions under section 8432 of title 5, United States Code, or any other provision of law.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H56D2F55713EB468DBE6495C41D62B5FE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Veterans disability compensation defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>veterans disability compensation</quote> has the meaning given the term <quote>compensation</quote> in section 101(13) of title 38, United States Code.</text> </subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

