<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1575CAA8308B48D0A99EBB41C5F3413D" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1800 IH: To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to transfer certain Federal land to facilitate scientific research supporting Federal space and defense programs.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1800</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170330">March 30, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001250">Mr. Bishop of Utah</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to transfer certain Federal land to facilitate scientific
			 research supporting Federal space and defense programs.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H8AFE6A3C99A749D7ABC7EEE4B5B5E56B" style="OLC">
		<section id="HD29969D4408C4A3AB8A596255BFBB3BA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Land conveyance, Wasatch-Cache National Forest, Rich County, Utah</header>
 <subsection id="H136C295E3AAA4668801D0874233670C1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Land conveyance authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary of Agriculture shall convey, without consideration, to the Utah State University Research Foundation, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to a parcel of real property consisting of approximately 80 acres, including improvements thereon, located outside of the boundaries of the Wasatch-Cache National Forest, Rich County, Utah, within Sections 19 and 30, in Township 14 North, Range 40 East of the Salt Lake Base and Meridian.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H335C6312545F49C7ABA0FD9D56AFC286"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Description of property</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The exact acreage and legal description of the property to be conveyed under subsection (a) shall be determined by a survey satisfactory to the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H819947596BA74FEC8EB63F45D1BABEDF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional terms and conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Agriculture may require such additional terms and conditions in connection with the conveyance under subsection (a) as the Secretary considers appropriate to protect the interests of the United States.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


