<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCB64EC96EBBC4B719AC5FA542AC6F732" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2240 IH: U.S.-Israel Joint Missile Defense Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2240</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170428">April 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001199">Mr. Mast</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of Defense to carry out a test of the Arrow 3 missile defense system
			 with the Government of Israel, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H719492FAF32048E18557E209B8EE9AD1" style="OLC">
 <section id="HF97B444A591446BAA0938DAAD6FAB6D5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>U.S.-Israel Joint Missile Defense Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HA04976FE055F4D7CA377FB269E7FBBB8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HB543D9FD2CFC49549B5328D8170B3DF0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Israel faces grave threats from Iran, Hezbollah, and Hamas, each of which are increasing their capabilities and strength.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7653749ABD3049BA86FC681E8DF04A68"><enum>(2)</enum><text>On March 9, 2016, Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps successfully launched two <quote>Qadr H</quote> ballistic missiles at a target in southeastern Iran approximately 870 miles away, in violation of United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6E95EDB80568471389154A7C87B67D08"><enum>(3)</enum><text>According to Iran’s official news agency, the missiles were inscribed with the slogan, <quote>Israel should be wiped off the earth.</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCC6A25A4C8C946EFA115F3030B24A458"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Iranian Brigadier General Ami Ali Hajizadeh stated, <quote>The reason we designed our missiles with a range of 2,000 kilometers is to be able to hit our enemy the Zionist regime from a safe distance.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB6B7753C62A643ACBE89EDFE9E11C1E7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Tel Aviv is approximately 987 miles from Tehran and likely within the operational capabilities of Iran’s current missile technology.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H40586688D2DE49518FAFE40571E414AD"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Iran conducted another test in January 2017.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H178DE6712D754442ABB7DA19EF49C16D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Hezbollah, designated by the Department of State as a terrorist organization, has an arsenal of approximately 120,000 to 150,000 rockets aimed at Israel.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8558687C983042A9B1C35CD35F87502A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Israel, with the August support of the United States, developed the Arrow 3 missile defense system to intercept and destroy long-range exo-atmospheric intercontinental ballistic missiles.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8D365AF7D2DC46C8ACE3313658FB99C5"><enum>(9)</enum><text>On January 18, 2017, Israel placed into service the first Arrow 3 interceptor after nearly a decade of development.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA19D159C8B0D41489E68E189D99C4813"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Further testing will be required to improve the system, ensure accuracy, and validate the system’s capabilities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD42640586DE64A068FC63CE80E8E3779"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Israel and the United States plan to conduct a test during 2018 in the United States that will cost approximately $105,000,000.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HC4934E9E595D47A395F1981B3C96EFEC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Test of Arrow 3 missile system</header>
 <subsection id="H8F54A809299D46D08DC3081884774B5B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense may conduct a test of the Arrow 3 missile defense system, in conjunction with the Government of Israel, to validate the capabilities of the system and improve the performance of the system.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC5763B41A7CF41919BE69E8AFCD7622B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to any funds authorized to be appropriated by section 1690 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>) or otherwise made available to the Secretary of Defense for the Arrow 3 missile defense system, there is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary an additional $105,000,000 for fiscal year 2018 to provide assistance to the Government of Israel to carry out the test specified in subsection (a) in the United States.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


