<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HEA2192C972A1458CA0FAE8AA27178700" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4294 IH: Prevention of Private Information Dissemination Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4294</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171108">November 8, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000392">Mr. Kustoff of Tennessee</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Financial Stability Act of 2010 to provide a criminal penalty for unauthorized
			 disclosures of certain individually identifiable information by officers
			 or employees of a Federal department or agency.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H7FE845BA153B44D988989E791FA51517" style="OLC">
 <section id="HB87859BBBE8346C097B17812EF28099D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prevention of Private Information Dissemination Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HA3E8FAEF25704B6ABA8BA39806BAFF19"><enum>2.</enum><header>Criminal penalty for unauthorized disclosures</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 165 of the Financial Stability Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5365">12 U.S.C. 5365</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE90B786615DC43C38AAE38FFE7D40961" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="HF49ADD9239B84ECFBB719E75CC1EF56B"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Criminal penalty for unauthorized disclosures</header>
 <paragraph id="HBC4A89727BBA4E77A124C34899787052"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any officer or employee of a Federal department or agency, who by virtue of such officer or employee’s employment or official position, has possession of, or access to, agency records which contain individually identifiable information submitted pursuant to the requirements of this section, the disclosure of which is prohibited by Federal statute, rule, or regulation, and who knowing that disclosure of the specific material is so prohibited, willfully discloses the material in any manner to any person or agency not entitled to receive it, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and fined not more than $5,000.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9E62B4A83381444B832BD9BF407E6ED3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Obtaining records under false pretenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person who knowingly and willfully requests or obtains information described under paragraph (1) from a Federal department or agency under false pretenses shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and fined not more than $5,000.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFBF9B2E9D00C445982116FABCCC49617"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Treatment of determinations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, a determination made under subsection (d) or (i) based on individually identifiable information submitted pursuant to the requirements of this section shall be deemed individually identifiable information, the disclosure of which is prohibited by Federal statute.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


