<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H087843CDBAF742B19A0687A4A3057BD7" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4120 IH: Grid Cybersecurity Research and Development Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4120</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171025">October 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000563">Mr. Lipinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000608">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for a comprehensive interdisciplinary research and development initiative to strengthen
			 the capacity of the electricity sector to neutralize cyber attacks.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H982F883FCA084D1992305923C829D467" style="OLC">
 <section id="H44616B58DB48416E9B8D2D427B7B7FA8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Grid Cybersecurity Research and Development Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H73A113B7C1A945AE9DBFB9C70A976842"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HBE19A4A218C342DD8D8CF9C4C99AC04A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Nation, and every other critical infrastructure sector, depends on reliable electricity.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H644BB4A3975E4C8D976A3C5704ECB361"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Industrial control systems used in the electricity sector are essential to maintain reliable operations of the electric grid.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H15E0BD26EA8C4174AD82A6AE303D030E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The cybersecurity threat landscape is constantly changing and attacker capabilities are advancing rapidly, requiring ongoing modifications, advancements, and investments in technologies and procedures to maintain security.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3AD553B6D9C14196B11518AE438581F7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>There are substantial and important differences between cybersecurity approaches needed to protect information technology systems and industrial control systems.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDB455D866C204A06B3E5D9BD912EDF84"><enum>(5)</enum><text>It is in the national interest for Federal agencies to invest in industrial control system cybersecurity research that facilitates private sector investment and the ability of the private sector to develop cybersecurity tools and products for control systems.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4069E510F7624800BDEE3757DBFBF2EC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The number of elements connecting to the electric grid is increasing, and designing cybersecurity into communication, data, and control systems when they are built is more effective than modifying products after installation to meet cybersecurity goals.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5915D2A682374131B664606109503397"><enum>(7)</enum><text>An understanding of human factors can be leveraged to understand the behavior of cyber threat actors, develop strategies to counter threat actors, improve industrial control system cybersecurity training programs, optimize the design of human-machine interfaces and cybersecurity tools, and increase the capacity of the electrical sector workforce to prevent attacks from gaining entry to industrial control systems.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H191FCDEF27B14EBFBA7844D1FE13D933"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H004691E5665846CB826D998AE70B7706"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Critical electric infrastructure information</header><text>The term <term>critical electric infrastructure information</term> has the meaning given that term in section 215A(a)(3) of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824a-1">16 U.S.C. 824a–1(a)(3)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0B6D23D7BB5B4452ABC348E514AAB9E0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cybersecurity</header><text>The term <term>cybersecurity</term> means a set of preventative measures to protect information from a digital device or system, including a device or system used to manage the electric grid, from being stolen, compromised, or used to carry out an attack.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H90DCF149C1E54F088E9CD7F32F5AF4DA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Electricity Subsector Coordinating Council</header><text>The term <term>Electricity Subsector Coordinating Council</term> means the self-organized, self-governed council consisting of senior industry representatives to serve as the principal liaison between the Federal Government and the electric power sector and to carry out the role of the Sector Coordinating Council as established in the National Infrastructure Protection Plan for the electricity subsector.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3382AD51D3564C198C2E82D2932B2BB7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Energy Sector Government Coordinating Council</header><text>The term <term>Energy Sector Government Coordinating Council</term> means the council consisting of representatives from relevant Federal Government agencies to provide effective coordination of energy sector efforts to ensure a secure, reliable, and resilient energy infrastructure and to carry out the role of the Government Coordinating Council as established in the National Infrastructure Protection Plan for the energy sector.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H076F7EF7EC9B43F5B8C8FF3B593BD10A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Human factors research</header><text>The term <term>human factors research</term> means research on human performance in social and physical environments, and on the integration of humans with physical systems and computer hardware and software.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H94F7D64C612E49C08AC7150387827BA3"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Human-machine interfaces</header><text>The term <term>human-machine interfaces</term> means technologies that present information to an operator about the state of a process or system, or accept human instructions to implement an action, including visualization displays such as a graphical user interface.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0697728E0A814F61B262A1646DECC9B4"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Energy.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB05AC84278064145B5199FC352571932"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Transient devices</header><text>The term <term>transient devices</term> means removable media, including floppy disks, compact disks, USB flash drives, external hard drives, mobile devices, and other devices that utilize wireless connections for limited periods of time.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H7322CD69828D44BEBABC8E2C556CA9DC"><enum>4.</enum><header>Electricity sector cybersecurity research, development, and demonstration program</header>
 <subsection id="H661977902DEE4EFDB0FEACDC4DAAF8FE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with appropriate Federal agencies, the Electricity Subsector Coordinating Council, State, tribal, local, and territorial governments, private sector vendors, and other relevant stakeholders, shall carry out a research, development, and demonstration initiative to harden and mitigate the electric grid from the consequences of cyber attacks by increasing the cybersecurity capabilities of the electricity sector and accelerating the development of cybersecurity technologies and tools.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA9C1B1031D814C68A38DEE3BF2DF652C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Department of Energy</header><text>As part of the initiative described in subsection (a), the Secretary shall carry out activities to—</text> <paragraph id="H942B13CEAB894E7D8B4035ABFB824856"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify cybersecurity risks to the communication and control systems within, and impacting, the electricity sector;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H24370BC458B9463DA9E4AF8B7833E769"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop methods and tools to rapidly detect cyber intruders and cyber incidents, including the use of data analytics techniques to validate and verify system behavior using multiple data streams reflecting the state of the system;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF79D6E0BBA754622B0E2355D9B331815"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assess emerging energy technology cybersecurity capabilities, and integrate cybersecurity features and protocols into the design, development, and deployment of emerging technologies, including renewable energy technologies;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4364369113174B8A8AADF81A1CA44AEB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>develop secure industrial control system protocols and identify vulnerabilities in existing protocols;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2C98068622E940A3BF7BFED95F8CE1DD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>work with manufacturers to build or retrofit security features and protocols into—</text> <subparagraph id="HB3EABAC2CF924F959E7867F8510EA51A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>communication and network systems and management processes;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17EC723F375840A9AEC2A7B7E833A58F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>industrial control and energy management system devices, components, software, firmware, and hardware, including distributed control and management systems and building management systems;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10D4038879CD48A4A60C51A8115C9A1C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>data storage systems and data management and analysis processes;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7521ED753B424F3980CDD5AEF5AC4450"><enum>(D)</enum><text>generation, transmission, distribution, and energy storage technologies;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E958A7F671C43C9B2D0463C2183821F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>automated and manually controlled devices and equipment for monitoring or managing frequency, voltage, and current;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE7CD65BF7254F5DB442EA1202D10CCA"><enum>(F)</enum><text>technologies used to synchronize time and develop guidance for operational contingency plans when time synchronization technologies are compromised;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80CF2CFA01B741ABA245F5D25A335247"><enum>(G)</enum><text>end user elements that connect to the grid, including—</text> <clause id="H85DA89A516D7465A839D9A5DAED6B426"><enum>(i)</enum><text>meters, synchrophasors, and other sensors;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF57EC1979DAF4D2E96538617BD5FBAF6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>distribution automation technologies, smart inverters, and other grid control technologies;</text> </clause><clause id="H5543AE4DF7E84F9D94801758C10B13B7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>distributed generation and energy storage technologies;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4ED6875C94E244AEB02BFAA0A24FF19E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>demand response technologies;</text> </clause><clause id="HB3DE33C7422146B8A85BEFD53872B55E"><enum>(v)</enum><text>home and building energy control systems;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBA1499FCCB644CDBBD1FB0A306D16D39"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>electric and plug-in hybrid vehicles; and</text> </clause><clause id="H2F7C8A8315B64B569DC3B85F6477F412"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>other relevant devices, software, firmware, hardware, and distributed energy technologies; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5B22957DF8943D9B0D3D009BACD93B6"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the supply chain of electric grid management system components;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C721A79AE514068B838F7CE643091E4"><enum>(6)</enum><text>improve the physical security of communication technologies and industrial control systems, including remote assets;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0D3F05C5E124426D87A8FC6D3ABE4132"><enum>(7)</enum><text>integrate human factors research into the design and development of advanced tools and processes for dynamic monitoring, detection, protection, mitigation, and response;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4A7C18BB5B38414B8F98FFE1D2ED6D25"><enum>(8)</enum><text>advance the capabilities and use of relevant interdisciplinary mathematical and computer simulation modeling and analysis methods;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF0F2B04AD6EB4826B74A5D9C5A1FD2F7"><enum>(9)</enum><text>evaluate and understand the potential consequences of practices used to maintain the cybersecurity of information technology systems on the cybersecurity of industrial control systems;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H21DB6745C010467185C4A9A75AE6540F"><enum>(10)</enum><text>increase access to and the capabilities of existing cybersecurity test beds to simulate impacts of cyber attacks on industrial control system devices, components, software, and hardware; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4C6CE7B57AAC4169A688D46953814EB5"><enum>(11)</enum><text>reduce the cost of implementing effective cybersecurity technologies and tools in the electricity sector.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H630683560CCF4DA28C46375FD4BC8583"><enum>(c)</enum><header>National Science Foundation</header><text>The National Science Foundation shall—</text> <paragraph id="H3A7BB9DA2B2644729F612799F85DF270"><enum>(1)</enum><text>support fundamental research to advance cybersecurity applications, technologies, and tools for industrial control systems, including incorporating interdisciplinary research in—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAB096DAF0F6D4E06B915AFC94035FD10"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evolutionary systems, theories, mathematics, and models;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8099A266CBA54CEBA8B0E963DF99177D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>economic and financial theories, mathematics, and models; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A49EC06C6014E57ABF98DBFAC796571"><enum>(C)</enum><text>big data analytical methods, mathematics, computer coding, and algorithms; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC7C976C0AE84BBA827AAC090CB5E26C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>support education and training for the industrial control system cybersecurity workforce, including through the Advanced Technological Education program, graduate research fellowships, and other appropriate programs.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAB77FD96A810450BB49DAB084769417E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Department of Homeland Security Science and Technology Directorate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Science and Technology Directorate of the Department of Homeland Security, in collaboration with the Department of Energy, experts in the private sector with the necessary clearances, and other relevant stakeholders, shall assess existing cybersecurity technologies and tools used in the defense industry and—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA95962536FE3447D8D73FCFA93321ED7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify technologies and tools that could be applied to meeting evolving civilian energy sector cybersecurity needs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6C935F8D14EB4610B79C8EC116DDB22B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop a research strategy that incorporates human factors research findings to guide the modification of defense industry cybersecurity tools for use in the civilian sector;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC6E7425943C348EB9F1BD4DB148B3FA8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>develop a strategy to accelerate efforts to bring modified defense industry cybersecurity tools to the civilian market; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2D5EF9AD7DFD40B78CE6090BB5DAB692"><enum>(4)</enum><text>carry out other activities the Secretary of Homeland Security considers appropriate to meet the goals of this subsection.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD1CC865DFFCB4738B2244BEB04123E50"><enum>5.</enum><header>Technical standards and guidance documents for electricity sector cybersecurity research</header>
 <subsection id="HE49E93EF3E464045BC142A7AFE409D19"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in coordination with appropriate Federal agencies, the Electricity Subsector Coordinating Council, standards development organizations, State, tribal, local, and territorial governments, private sector vendors, and other relevant stakeholders, shall coordinate the development of guidance documents for research and demonstration activities to improve the cybersecurity capabilities of the electricity sector through participating agencies. As part of these activities, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H19E9110E49DC4C02A2B4918C7D535BA7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>facilitate stakeholder involvement to update—</text> <subparagraph id="HDBD4163A970342B7A69020DA9E509759"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Roadmap to Achieve Energy Delivery Systems Cybersecurity (published in September 2011);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6164FBDEE7F4E568A1481ADFAC11CA1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Cybersecurity Procurement Language for Energy Delivery Systems (published by the Energy Sector Control Systems Working Group in April 2014), including developing guidance for—</text>
 <clause id="H1E5F046B96174E538538EA84B19D70D2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>contracting with third parties to conduct vulnerability testing for industrial control systems;</text> </clause><clause id="HF510C33868FC4F8DAC7EEA5347166F18"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>contracting with third parties that will utilize transient devices to access industrial control or information technology systems; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H703BFAFEF2574CEA817B844A4437635C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>managing supply chain risks; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7B7AF902EA14239ADE557A8F7667872"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Electricity Subsector Cybersecurity Capability Maturity Model (published by the Department of Energy in February 2014), including the development of—</text>
 <clause id="H333081159385443D88E123E09B9EA9DB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>metrics to measure changes in cybersecurity capabilities and assess the potential for metrics to drive unexpected behavioral changes that would reduce security; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3016DA65EBE5485DB6D513A03593718C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an analysis of incentive mechanisms and their potential to increase investments in cybersecurity;</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF713A080F5DC425B843D85BB3CC89107"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop voluntary guidance to improve forensic analyses capabilities, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5176B8A6B59B49D6AB865CCA5ADF9634"><enum>(A)</enum><text>developing standardized terminology and monitoring processes;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4496876B76714FD192C69FA1A177A9EB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identifying minimum data needed; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H187FE3CAF53247A69CF4F304412AD9CB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>utilizing human factors research to develop more effective procedures for logging incident events; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C8364A4E3CC4B7E8000197DB3F0AD8F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>work with the National Science Foundation, Department of Homeland Security, National Institute of Standards and Technology, and stakeholders to develop a mechanism to anonymize, aggregate, and share the testing results from cybersecurity industrial control system test beds to facilitate technology improvements by public and private sector researchers.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF5B24884C8E74E829CE6A747DBACFCFC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Critical electric infrastructure information</header><text>Information provided to Federal agencies for the purposes of carrying out subsection (a) shall be considered critical electric infrastructure information and provided the protections established in section 10.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD760CAE4E7464E44847476CD5491D0AD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Standards</header><text>The Secretary, in collaboration with the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology and other appropriate Federal agencies, shall convene relevant stakeholders and facilitate the development of—</text>
 <paragraph id="H58C955BD336545588A5ED8231C73EEE0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>voluntary, consensus-based technical standards to improve cybersecurity for—</text> <subparagraph id="HFD92FCBD7124409EB17B292E2585E751"><enum>(A)</enum><text>emerging energy technologies;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD819858282DC4FE79A5292266301FA56"><enum>(B)</enum><text>distributed generation and storage technologies, and other distributed energy resources;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5978FA2BE114C51AEC25656995A32D6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>electric vehicles; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA53C924854147F48B4DBB3ED1256EC8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>other technologies and devices that connect to the electric grid that can affect voltage stability;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2FA4E37D03BD40179B3EE2DB0E97527C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommended cybersecurity features and requirements that can be used by the private sector to design and build interoperable cybersecurity features into—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD9A53C10B5E94C65A403BE1C021004EF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>devices and components;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD0021D5AB8440E99E5FCF9070C82323"><enum>(B)</enum><text>software and hardware; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55F08637D8D24387B277E95CC947B9ED"><enum>(C)</enum><text>other technologies that connect to the electric grid; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA3F7F3FCAAF8499CA27F85A53821193D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>voluntary standards for test beds and test bed methodologies that will enable reproducible testing of industrial control system devices, components, software, and hardware across test beds.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB9A42B06636A4796AB048B7A82BA28F7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulatory authority</header><text>Subsection (c) shall not be construed to authorize regulatory actions that would duplicate or conflict with regulatory requirements, mandatory standards, or related processes under any other provision of Federal law.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HA3C0EF0C2A7242B99F826302D4BDD95C"><enum>6.</enum><header>Vulnerability testing and technical assistance to increase cyberresilience</header>
 <subsection id="HA77053752DE9406E95B75518B1690704"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="H850B5B9560114DD9B3FE3861EB514175"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collaborate with electricity sector asset owners and operators in the private sector, leveraging the research facilities and expertise of the National Laboratories, to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H642DC17C005C46AA9E30D19A25B8D896"><enum>(A)</enum><text>utilize a range of methods, including voluntary vulnerability testing and red team-blue team exercises, to identify vulnerabilities in physical and cyber systems;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEFA5A92980E242D38ED1F59FE8787E96"><enum>(B)</enum><text>develop cybersecurity risk assessment tools and provide confidential analyses and recommendations to participating stakeholders;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBAA0E0656BD1488ABD0D4B167A44629D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>work with stakeholders to develop methods to share anonymized and aggregated results in a format that enables the electricity sector, researchers, and the private sector to advance cybersecurity efforts, technologies, and tools; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC47811C868C471DA561DB33FEC24BE5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>leverage the unique strengths and expertise of the National Laboratories and Federal agencies;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3F53DD3EA954D60B86D1729E4599A2F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>collaborate with relevant stakeholders to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H02114A44F6C04477947AC88A0AB11FAA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify information, research, staff training, and analysis tools needed to evaluate industrial control system cybersecurity issues and challenges in the electricity sector; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA8C798C6E1C4C7884D06CEF32ADF9B7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>facilitate the sharing of information and the development of tools identified under subparagraph (A);</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C9AF8C1DE554369964E2C03FBE717AF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>collaborate with and support electricity sector trade organizations and their research agencies to improve the cybersecurity of industrial control systems used by members and stakeholders; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H88B3D5A3164540A6925FDA4C0A978A65"><enum>(4)</enum><text>collaborate with tribal governments to—</text> <subparagraph id="H93458B4D104B45F18FCAB9987873846E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify information, research, and analysis tools needed by tribal governments to increase the industrial control system cybersecurity of electricity assets within their jurisdiction; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0F800D5296048A5BBFD07E4D8714477"><enum>(B)</enum><text>facilitate the sharing of information and the development of tools needed to ensure the cybersecurity of tribal electricity assets and systems.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB5DBA9925B7842F089E5994887515B79"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Critical electric infrastructure information</header><text>Information provided to Federal agencies for the purposes of carrying out subsection (a)(1)(C) shall be considered critical electric infrastructure information and provided the protections established in section 10.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H2BC06161EA5A491A9655B8D3D2961A97"><enum>7.</enum><header>Education and workforce training research and standards</header>
 <subsection id="H7E9E943D14D1482599911BCB11833B7E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Department of Energy</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="HC219EC38B1484B20B265B73EDECB45A3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>utilize human factors research and other methods to identify core skills used by electricity sector industrial control systems cybersecurity professionals; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA1808AB0AFEB41B78A3134B633BA01A2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop assessment methods and tools to identify existing personnel that show competence in the core skills identified under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4BD5D545CA534C99964CD0372B0FE2F5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>National Institute of Standards and Technology</header><text>The Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall—</text> <paragraph id="HF11D260504A949789CFDAB0039B57943"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop voluntary, innovative industrial control systems cybersecurity training and retraining standards, lessons, and recommendations for the electricity sector that minimize duplication of cybersecurity compliance training programs; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA5B3DE8AB2B34DAB81724C59BAD13086"><enum>(2)</enum><text>maintain a public database of industrial control systems cybersecurity education, training, and certification programs.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8E1675BAFB1B46C69367E360C4F47DFE"><enum>8.</enum><header>Interagency coordination and Strategic Plan for electricity sector cybersecurity research</header>
 <subsection id="HB34B1DC8650D44C3B8A4019B46D55AD8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Energy Sector Government Coordinating Council shall—</text> <paragraph id="H7676C2F436A142478C4B55607480D48C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>review the most recent version of the Roadmap to Achieve Energy Delivery Systems Cybersecurity and identify crosscutting energy grid cybersecurity research needs and opportunities for collaboration among Federal agencies and between Federal agencies and other relevant stakeholders;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC93BBE862BE34929BCA6F254121EEC8A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify interdisciplinary research, technology, and tools that can be applied to industrial control system cybersecurity challenges in the electricity sector;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3C3177A0ADA14F27814C4139C33AC40D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identify technology transfer opportunities to accelerate the development and commercial application of novel industrial control system cybersecurity technologies, systems, and processes; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEA4258576A9D4374BB84CCF6465C32AE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>develop a coordinated Interagency Strategic Plan to advance cybersecurity capabilities for industrial control systems used in the electricity sector that builds on the Roadmap to Achieve Energy Delivery Systems in Cybersecurity.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7887D8D112AC42D6B367F17022F5E846"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Strategic plan</header>
 <paragraph id="H0D6CD4026872449CA68E0D4C294A1774"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Submittal</header><text>The Interagency Strategic Plan developed under subsection (a)(4) shall be submitted to Congress within 12 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFC1F81C98FF64D7D87ABDDFBB7377083"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The Interagency Strategic Plan shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="HA081535E5F7B4282A8589E22DC4D7382"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an analysis of how existing cybersecurity research efforts conducted by member agencies are coordinated and can complement and advance the goals of the Roadmap to Achieve Energy Delivery Systems Cybersecurity;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F4A12071EF94A72B38DE091A874D090"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommendations for prioritized research efforts that could contribute to advancing the cybersecurity of electricity sector industrial control systems;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5DE0510869645B8AB62A33352588EFB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of how existing and proposed public and private sector research efforts address the topics described in paragraph (3); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H47B7AD88BF824988A7E7F668A1B35A8C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a description of needed support for workforce training in this area.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC418973E9A1E4E29A351CAB85E990F56"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>In developing the Interagency Strategic Plan, the Energy Sector Government Coordinating Council shall consider—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC841061548194F96A6AD7880118760C7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>opportunities for human factors research to improve the design and effectiveness of cybersecurity devices, technologies, tools, processes, and training programs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A268C5D68AE4FEEB4EF40ECCA9340F8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>contributions of other disciplines to the development of innovative cybersecurity protocols, devices, components, technologies, and tools;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H038986AEFD5B47B4B79396798235BFC5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>opportunities for Small Business Innovation Research (SBIR) and other technology transfer programs to facilitate private sector development of industrial control system cybersecurity protocols, devices, components, technologies, and tools;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB16E3F17B804B22ADB076D9FF1B468C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>broader applications of the work done by relevant Federal agencies to advance the cybersecurity of industrial control systems used by other sectors; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4EB050977DB4A4B87F311FB585EC2B0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>activities called for in the Federal cybersecurity research and development strategic plan required by section 201(a)(1) of the Cybersecurity Enhancement Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/7431">15 U.S.C. 7431(a)(1)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H620EA7732CF24DE496547D2761283C5E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>For the purposes of carrying out this section, the Energy Sector Government Coordinating Council shall include representatives from Federal agencies with expertise in industrial control systems cybersecurity, information technology cybersecurity, cyber physical systems, engineering, human factors research, human-machine interfaces, high performance computing, big data and data analytics, or other disciplines considered appropriate by the Council Chair. The Chair shall consider including at least one employee designated by the head of each of the following agencies:</text>
 <paragraph id="H02FD70C058B446CA93E2728BC372346C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In the Department of Energy—</text> <subparagraph id="HCEB03432554449C8A586BF1839C7EACA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Office of Electricity Delivery and Energy Reliability;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D523A4839FE4EC7A94E2DA7C386F392"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Office of Science’s Advanced Scientific Computing Research program;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8F46F7CAA7A46E091C129C42AFBAE30"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Office of Small Business Innovation Research/Small Business Technology Trans­fer programs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4D06C1251BA4D63B382D6DF734598A5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Office of Technology Transitions; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5EB9DE0D39D435CA9C38B434EF210CD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>other offices considered appropriate by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8DA3B4ADC08A40519B49DBC219151B6E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The National Science Foundation.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEF4831BF8E104842ADDC9ED750DC4715"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Department of Homeland Security’s Science and Technology Directorate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8D71F21A24674E769FE6753FEDFB3468"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The National Institute of Standards and Technology.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4EC8C07AE6DB4AC494668C07285200BB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The National Aeronautics and Space Administration’s Human Research Program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6D012DB4948E4CA5BA212B7368050224"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Office of Science and Technology Policy.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE5A57D93B18F45C38D1F3D38E6AA7589"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Federal Energy Regulatory Commission.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA8E8BF7F528B406FBFA654AE5631F07B"><enum>9.</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header>
			<subsection id="HE4A5AED95CD04BF19E83C8C36A33B7EE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Identification of common factors in cyber attacks</header>
 <paragraph id="H7A82C672C3D843A38D32B23DB68A472A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in collaboration with the Secretary of Homeland Security, other appropriate Federal agencies, and energy sector stakeholders, shall conduct a study to analyze cyber attacks on electricity sector industrial control systems and identify cost-effective opportunities to improve cybersecurity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H229BF12A1B8E46F9BE1A4E675F08583C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Critical electric infrastructure information</header><text>Incident data provided to Federal agencies for the purposes of carrying out this subsection shall be considered critical electric infrastructure information and provided the protections established in section 10.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1BA4AE43EFBD422EBA4392F1F1EEC106"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Content</header><text>The study shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HE7A48E194FCB41B79C52501580945610"><enum>(A)</enum><text>summarize cyber incident data provided to the Secretary by relevant Federal agencies and energy sector stakeholders;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BCE12E283FB4F2B80485BE3AB708841"><enum>(B)</enum><text>analyze processes, operational procedures, and other factors common among cyber attacks;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D1A6ABD33F84DD5AFD11BDC3A1538A3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identify the points where human behavior played a critical role in maintaining or compromising the security of the system;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63EC669DC8A64E0581C9D82D1B940932"><enum>(D)</enum><text>recommend—</text> <clause id="H9294AFCAFA7B4D40BE8C833021E0BF8D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>changes to the design of devices, human-machine interfaces, technologies, and tools to optimize security that do not require a change in human behavior;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H90E10B00557149FF9AEF464CE6F4BDB0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>changes to processes or operational procedures that do not require a change in human behavior; and</text> </clause><clause id="H21D7735E6DA7443DB7DBC51D1D2F176A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>training techniques to increase the capacity of employees to actively identify, prevent, or neutralize the impact of cyber attacks; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H11CBB496D20D471087A660ADD0773538"><enum>(E)</enum><text>evaluate existing engineering and technical design criteria and guidelines that incorporate human factors research findings, and recommend criteria and guidelines for industrial control system cybersecurity tools that can be used to develop procurement guidance, including guidance for alarms, displays, and layouts.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E004BF2FC1F426EB72D32B0982336CD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In conducting the study, the Secretary shall consult with electricity sector stakeholders, professionals with expertise in human factors research, private sector industrial control system vendors, and other relevant parties.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H577BF8B5BBC34983BA100E3F76A49C59"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 24 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report on the results of the study, including the findings of the Secretary on each of the items described in paragraph (3).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6C7E7C7F8EB24B64A4663A65D9ECF1C9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Balancing risks, security, and modernization of industrial systems</header>
 <paragraph id="HC153FAC4266C48E48F90EEC7EA4165E0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Secretary, in collaboration with the National Institute of Standards and Technology, other Federal agencies, and electricity sector stakeholders, shall examine the risks associated with increasing penetration of digital technologies in operational networks.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8589EF451B7343D7A18093F2F2D82446"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Content</header><text>The study shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H653B6D1213C04482BD38C7B791C93CB7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluate the relative qualitative risks and benefits of various design and architecture options for electricity sector industrial control systems, including consideration of—</text>
 <clause id="HED2E8F287DAB4CDB80AAB388604B5EA8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>designs that include both digital and analog control devices and technologies;</text> </clause><clause id="H12429CEB7D984F4DAEA05F0099C71BDB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>different communication technologies used to move information and data between control system devices, technologies, and system operators;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDF93BE4DDACC4FC8ABAA9421ACA0B349"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>automated and human-in-the-loop devices and technologies;</text> </clause><clause id="HBE42C9BBEA954205984D7086B9E42338"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>programmable versus non­pro­gram­ma­ble devices and technologies; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H461C09F86DFE4ED8BD3D2A63F1DA5A63"><enum>(v)</enum><text>increased redundancy using dissimilar cybersecurity technologies;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF823F07EDB58464D8CDDDD862A057A3E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommend methods or metrics to document changes in risks associated with system designs and architectures;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E17AD6F28E84A518257A53399946580"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide recommendations for research, development, demonstration, and commercial application activities to address issues raised in subparagraphs (A) and (B); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4DA5F1F34C8842C7B5378F6B33ECBDC3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>recommend guidance to minimize overall system risks.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A15A9E39E0E4499915255BB4094705F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In conducting the study, the Secretary shall consult with electricity sector stakeholders, academic and private sector researchers, private sector industrial control system vendors, and other relevant parties.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC2AFC59CCB8346CCB3A9DD0A4945CD78"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 24 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report on the results of the study, including the findings of the Secretary on each of the items described in paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6798A26467AD48B693DC1AC751CF0423"><enum>10.</enum><header>Protection of critical electric infrastructure information</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Any Federal agency that produces information or has information made available to it in the course of carrying out this Act shall determine whether to designate any such information as critical electric infrastructure information. Critical electric infrastructure information—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC228683B34384F679362CE577588D6C5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall be exempt from disclosure under section 552(b)(3) of title 5, United States Code; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8A43789DAC604D3BB6B8D207D3AF5820"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall not be made available by any Federal, State, political subdivision, or tribal authority pursuant to any Federal, State, political subdivision, or tribal law requiring public disclosure of information or records.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H069029D802864C1DA5BFEA71CD746914"><enum>11.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this Act—</text> <paragraph id="HDFF76CDBDCD84063A21BFA338FAE5C03"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$65,000,000 for fiscal year 2018;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEC2ABC8E0E784060B895EDADF2D0DB89"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$68,250,000 for fiscal year 2019;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5F657535AB7F4D66A5CE43CF22ABAE53"><enum>(3)</enum><text>$71,662,500 for fiscal year 2020;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5CE37E7D586F4487ABFA3F618B38CC8D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>$75,245,625 for fiscal year 2021; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4126221FF0A24785BDFA3D2BFA9542F4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>$79,007,906 for fiscal year 2022.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


