<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HEA3F74F259E7400C9B7D0BBB2C9FA4A8" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2396 IH: Privacy Notification Technical Clarification Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2396</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170504">May 4, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000475">Mr. Trott</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001049">Mr. Clay</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act to update the exception for certain annual notices provided by
			 financial institutions.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H99D3AA2F04044430BE3BFF3EEF39951E" style="OLC">
 <section id="HEA573620FCB7458D9A2757206B0C1345" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Privacy Notification Technical Clarification Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HF0B0733DC51944E1A6924F6AE3CB6594"><enum>2.</enum><header>Exception to annual notice requirement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 503(f) of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/6803">15 U.S.C. 6803(f)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H2ACA732667CC4011A7CD35FF47B3CEA2" style="OLC">
 <text>or—</text><paragraph id="HE775D217BA454E74BC8FD6A117278717"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A financial institution that—</text> <subparagraph id="HCBB885D2A3714956996094CC4BE1C7EC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has not changed its policies and practices with regard to disclosing nonpublic information from the policies and practices that were disclosed in the most recent disclosures sent to consumers in accordance with this section, shall not be required to provide an annual disclosure under this section until such time as the financial institution has changed its policies and practices with regard to disclosing nonpublic information from the policies and practices that were disclosed in the most recent disclosures sent to consumers in accordance with this section, provided,</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78C58C06EEFC4961829AC9F8E832B3A8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the financial institution makes its current policy available to consumers on its website and via mail upon written request sent to a designated address identified for the purpose of requesting the policy or upon telephone request made using a toll free customer service telephone number; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F4F7249A32A4159AA0740DC83B741EC"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the financial institution conspicuously notifies customers of the availability of the current policy including a message on or with each periodic billing statement for customers who are entitled to periodic billing statements. For customers and consumers who are not entitled to periodic billing statements, the financial institution shall conspicuously notify customers and consumers of the availability of the current policy through other reasonable means such as on its website or with other written communication, including electronic communication, sent to the consumer.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CB85F43B17A45BCB93F9FB4BF1952F7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>If a financial institution maintains more than one policy that varies depending on the consumer’s account status or state of residence, the financial institution may comply with the website posting requirement in subparagraph (B) by posting all of its notices to the public section of its website with instructions for choosing the applicable notice.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


