<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H551EC554CA4A4734863DE0052970BF1C" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4149 IH: To amend title 38, United States Code, to make certain improvements to the use of educational assistance provided by the Department of Veterans Affairs for flight training programs.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4149</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171026">October 26, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000815">Mr. Wenstrup</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to make certain improvements to the use of educational
			 assistance provided by the Department of Veterans Affairs for flight
			 training programs.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HA0B94550CBD24C40BFAD9C586C817724" style="OLC">
		<section id="H289A320A449B46B98E3B55166BD2F9D8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Improvements to assistance provided for certain flight training and other programs of education</header>
 <subsection id="HD625D38919EE40988EF8ABC163E66571"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Use of entitlement for private pilot’s licenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3034(d) of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HF01293F1DAFD429DA5F185ED86BF50FB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1) by striking the semicolon and inserting the following: <quote>and is required for the course of education being pursued (including with respect to a dual major, concentration, or other element a degree); and</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H21165244EA6049D9BF9FCB724F18311D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF220CCB073664C28A61DAD955F2FAC02"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (3) as paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5711F10434B8478992322FA04ED5968D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Accelerated payments for flight training</header><text>Section 3313 of such title is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8CF180DD43094DE18AD045BA0BE15A99" style="USC"> <subsection id="H10F3F73CC5D9471E9AD041D4DB46491A"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Accelerated payments for certain flight training</header> <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDFF81DB609D54D02BAA86D2115565E2F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Payments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual enrolled in a program of education pursued at an institution of higher learning in which flight training is required to earn the degree being pursued (including with respect to a dual major, concentration, or other element of such a degree) may elect to receive accelerated payments of amounts for tuition and fees determined under subsection (c). The amount of each accelerated payment shall be an amount equal to twice the amount for tuition and fee so determined under such subsection, but the total amount of such payments may not exceed the total amount of tuition and fees for the program of education. The amount of monthly stipends shall be determined in accordance with such subsection (c) and may not be accelerated under this paragraph.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1641EA1712144923B324E37F11AAB834"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Educational counseling</header><text>An individual may make an election under paragraph (1) only if the individual receives educational counseling under section 3697A(a) of this title.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC6969F40A2E84366BB5413F64C77BC08"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Charge against entitlement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of months of entitlement charged an individual for accelerated payments made pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be determined at the rate of two months for each month in which such an accelerated payment is made.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9612EE9B36F7479B9E2A89C2A2673C9D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Flight training at public institutions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (c)(1)(A) of such section 3313 is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HBA11A51A66484EBE96FACA497C322A61"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (i)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB08B7E4391364F31812CCDD0A5B1D241"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subclauses (I) and (II) as items (aa) and (bb), respectively;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1FCAA5C42F324934BB6208D85ABA853C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>In the case of a program of education pursued at a public institution of higher learning</quote> and inserting <quote>(I) Subject to subclause (II), in the case of a program of education pursued at a public institution of higher learning not described in clause (ii)(II)(bb)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6AA95A8D771C4A18B9A7A7AA96FE56A1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subclause:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAF24EFEFCD324535835283A463EDAADF" style="USC"> <subclause id="H049760A7E20846D7BA181A825ECC9D65" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining the actual net cost for in-State tuition and fees pursuant to subclause (I), the Secretary may not pay for tuition and fees relating to flight training.</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFAFB46A507904BCCB3E052ADF1E599F0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (ii)—</text> <subparagraph id="HB314FBBF2B4746BBBA800D8980EAA09B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subclause (I), by redesignating items (aa) and (bb) as subitems (AA) and (BB), respectively;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83130C7C83E94D3793FB91BF4A5E69BF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subclause (II), by redesignating items (aa) and (bb) as subitems (AA) and (BB), respectively;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AF86B23F4C2497E9DDA2402984D09D5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating subclauses (I) and (II) as items (aa) and (bb), respectively;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BC399B1AB674CE494CE15686CBA77C9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by striking <quote>In the case of a program of education pursued at a non-public or foreign institution of higher learning</quote> and inserting <quote>(I) In the case of a program of education described in subclause (II)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCAAAF8DE5B874E94ADDCCC2088F1705A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subclause:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H90168BC2E06C4E9DA360492E6309DD3A" style="USC"> <subclause id="HFFF0407B93E0454BB871EDE355DB47FF" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A program of education described in this subclause is any of the following:</text>
 <item id="H9D01B6F068124E44B5018622345FFADD"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A program of education pursued at a non-public or foreign institution of higher learning.</text> </item><item id="H3CD4FE9F95474ECBB93D6ACF61502ABF"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>A program of education pursued at a public institution of higher learning in which flight training is required to earn the degree being pursued (including with respect to a dual major, concentration, or other element of such a degree).</text></item></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H6046FD140659424CADA77D4492C60D4B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Certain programs of education carried out under contract</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3313(c)(1)(A)(ii)(II) of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (c)(2)(E), is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H089EB001F3F54EC9B5BDF2EAA1F889F3" style="OLC">
 <item commented="no" id="H64CD44058EF04FCD8112695F71E6BBED" indent="up1"><enum>(cc)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A program of education pursued at a public institution of higher learning in which the public institution of higher learning enters into a contract or agreement with an entity (other than another public institution of higher learning) to provide such program of education or a portion of such program of education.</text></item><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H3A2BA5A483CD404DAB1D8C375B098956"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Application</header>
 <paragraph id="HE8F4B9BB2F9A4C828D2AB1BE4BC02D70"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided by paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to a quarter, semester, or term, as applicable, commencing on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H20DDFD18267C49D7B173F10BB56D830F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rule for current students</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an individual who, as of the date of the enactment of this Act, is using educational assistance under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/33">chapter 33</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, to pursue a course of education that includes a program of education described in item (bb) or (cc) of section 3313(c)(1)(A)(ii)(II) of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsections (c) and (d), respectively, the amendment made by such subsection shall apply with respect to a quarter, semester, or term, as applicable, commencing on or after the date that is two years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


