<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H15F9EB7C3A514A8688AAE682934D191D" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1396 IH: Restoring Statutory Rights and Interests of the States Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1396</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170307">March 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Maxine Waters of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001050">Ms. Hanabusa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001185">Mr. Sean Patrick Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To restore statutory rights to the people of the United States from forced arbitration.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H28082E85207D404ABC6F5AA6910B74DC" style="OLC">
 <section id="H114837576D7749179D9D39FB9F8D8BC1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Restoring Statutory Rights and Interests of the States Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H333792F0C5874CB787A5A847F0591F98"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and intent</header> <subsection id="HD3BF3943E8F5461F86B178677E7D264F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H6F6F5052EFCB4E4083BEEC4893A277AF"><enum>(1)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/9/1">Chapter 1</external-xref> of title 9, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Federal Arbitration Act</quote>), represented an exercise of legislative power that required courts to recognize private voluntary agreements to arbitrate commercial disputes at a time when the courts were refusing to do so on grounds that arbitration represented a usurpation of the authority of the courts to resolve legal disputes.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H984CC7F592E24E4F823F2980D3037E03"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Federal Arbitration Act did not, and should not have been interpreted to, supplant or nullify the legislatively created rights and remedies which Congress, exercising its power under article I of the Constitution of the United States, has granted to the people of the United States for resolving disputes in State and Federal courts.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H08416ADB371F4AB48F041036C2D01C06"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Recent court decisions, including AT&amp;T Mobility v. Concepcion, 563 U.S. 333 (2011) and American Express Co. v. Italian Colors Restaurant, 133 S.Ct. 2304 (June 20, 2013), have interpreted the Federal Arbitration Act to broadly preempt rights and remedies established under substantive State and Federal law. As a result, these decisions have enabled business entities to avoid or nullify legal duties created by congressional enactment, resulting in millions of people in the United States being unable to vindicate their rights in State and Federal courts.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H611C9B7428424A51AE578630DEFD550B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>States have a compelling interest in enacting rights and remedies to protect the welfare of their citizens, and the Federal Arbitration Act should not be, and should not have been, interpreted to preempt State legislation that enacted rights and remedies to protect the welfare of their citizens.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC2A85018A87C4C88A197F30678BB3A71"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Intent of Congress</header><text>In enacting this Act, it is the intent of Congress—</text> <paragraph id="HE8503C4548F14465BC5DF3B0A846AA8D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to restate and reinstitute the primacy of congressional and State legislative bodies as the creators of the rights and remedies available to all the people of the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H06813E49ED4147268C09B78790C67A41"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to clarify that congressionally established rights and remedies may not be waived prior to the institution of a dispute by the party intended to be protected by such statute; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4AF5985849364ADD84115A447002BA86"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to reinstate and reaffirm existing rights and remedies of the people of the United States enacted since the enactment of the Federal Arbitration Act regarding access to the courts that have, or may have been, abrogated or diminished.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H4188F2EB747B4E949EC95514F5478ACB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Arbitration of Federal statutory causes of action</header>
 <subsection id="HA87D970EF39D42B8A272AF4C5E3E343F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Adjudication of Federal statutory rights of action</header><text>Section 2 of title 9, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HF6A149BB8D384217AC6743918F75BD9B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>A written</quote> and inserting <quote>(a) <header-in-text level="subsection" style="USC">In general</header-in-text>.—Except as provided in subsection (b), a written</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H63F9C8D4258B488B8B322730E51D1A96"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2C67E2FB2D124EB5A541FFC5CDBD05C1" style="USC"> <subsection id="H0560DB0AE6DF4C09A6C81A312AD241EF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply to a written provision that requires arbitration of a claim for damages or injunctive relief brought by an individual or small business concern (as defined in section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>)), in either an individual or representative capacity, arising from the alleged violation of a Federal or State statute, the Constitution of the United States, or a constitution of a State, unless the written agreement to arbitrate is entered into by both parties after the claim has arisen and pertains solely to an existing claim.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0CE8C9172218475FBF5A8C79D12DA58F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Interaction with State law</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a), the phrase <term>grounds as exist at law or in equity for the revocation of a contract</term> shall include a Federal or State statute, or the finding of a Federal or State court, that prohibits the agreement to arbitrate on grounds that the agreement is unconscionable, invalid because there was no meeting of the minds, or otherwise unenforceable as a matter of contract law or public policy.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEDC3C4CA94C34F789EBDC7FAD364548E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Validity and enforceability</header><text>A de­ter­mi­na­tion as to whether this chapter applies to an agreement to arbitrate shall be made by a court, rather than an arbitrator, irrespective of whether the party resisting arbitration challenges the agreement to arbitrate specifically or in conjunction with other terms of the contract containing such agreement.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HBED8BFB2F0D34CA881316FD4E49574BB"><enum>4.</enum><header>Vacating an award made in violation of section 2 of title 9, United States Code</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 10(a) of title 9, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HC0D0E333A4E6455F9C979494572133C6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAEC0105870DA4498BF9341CD1BB20A59"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF8F09ED3CA9740BAB312444BD1469ED8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6BC2A1F08BC046E4AC3B78E76C2A2F0B" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HECB6A3EF0920467E84376E34B6B92C41"><enum>(5)</enum><text>where the arbitration took place in violation of section 2.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></section><section id="H6557C5C1DA204EC19856233B6443F748"><enum>5.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act, and the amendments made by this Act, shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act and shall apply with respect to any dispute or claim that arises on or after such date of enactment.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


