<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB716F9511CE7438F8C8A0DCA6C75034B" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2819 IH: Political Intelligence Transparency Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2819</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170607">June 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="D000533">Mr. Duncan of Tennessee</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000799">Mr. Walz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 to require the disclosure of political intelligence
			 activities, to amend title 18, United States Code, to provide for
			 restrictions on former officers, employees, and elected officials of the
			 executive and legislative branches regarding political intelligence
			 contacts, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HD05A0D0B38A944B09EF6707187FCF020" style="OLC">
 <section id="H3719C077FE414F748B6ECCFEA6D97DB4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Political Intelligence Transparency Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H789479C4E43C401EB82EC2EDF56A928B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Disclosure of political intelligence activities under lobbying disclosure act</header> <subsection id="H0B3A8517A4364A6A92DFB769B00521F2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Section 3 of the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1602">2 U.S.C. 1602</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6DC2A6B1DB964372BFDD9B9AF3CB2F51"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> <subparagraph id="HF561780FBF5441DD881BBE5BF8A6851A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting after <quote>lobbying activities</quote> each place that term appears the following: <quote>or political intelligence activities</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2F8DA24895F4B5DB4CC31B951EE5C82"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after <quote>lobbyists</quote> the following: <quote>or political intelligence consultants</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H060D282B658348CCA0AC90ADEC19CC01"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H4C59C9F232F54C30AB426F5AE63C4333" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H663933AB85CC4662B16BE48556999236"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Political intelligence activities</header><text>The term <term>political intelligence activities</term> means political intelligence contacts and efforts in support of such contacts, including preparation and planning activities, research, and other background work that is intended, at the time it is performed, for use in contacts, and coordination with such contacts and efforts of others.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="HCF71D7F898E043D8BBA22379F5235187"><enum>(18)</enum><header>Political intelligence contact</header>
 <subparagraph id="H1E267104CBB0497E8C98A6BAB1A98C1A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>political intelligence contact</term> means any oral or written communication (including an electronic communication) to a covered executive branch official or a covered legislative branch official, the information derived from which is for use in analyzing the markets for securities, commodities for future delivery, swaps, or security-based swaps, or in informing investment decisions in any such market, and which is made on behalf of a client with regard to—</text>
 <clause id="HF878BCF266B74749AA02A0FAE0E33480"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the formulation, modification, or adoption of Federal legislation (including legislative proposals);</text>
 </clause><clause id="H814E065972FD4631A0679D21CB9DD828"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the formulation, modification, or adoption of a Federal rule, regulation, Executive order, or any other program, policy, or position of the United States Government;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA72317E8895443589F7D9995D8321F2A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the administration or execution of a Federal program or policy (including the negotiation, award, or administration of a Federal contract, grant, loan, permit, or license); or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8D293ED1F2AC424583C7417FAB0CFAE8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the nomination or confirmation of a person for a position subject to confirmation by the Senate.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H30C75D98A6194052888194B8B047D594"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>political intelligence contact</term> does not include a communication that is—</text>
 <clause id="HD61F42665CE943BDB42955F992BBA94A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">made by a representative of a media organization (as such term is defined in this subsection) if the purpose of the communication is gathering and disseminating news and information to the public;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H56C299D45C724DA6BFA936ABBDAFE523"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>made in a speech, article, publication or other material that is distributed and made available to the public, or through radio, television, cable television, or other medium of mass communication;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3A00E56F49A447A28A6592DF4F55DB37"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>made on behalf of a government of a foreign country or a foreign political party and disclosed under the Foreign Agents Registration Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/611">22 U.S.C. 611</external-xref> et seq.);</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5D28B3CA5A1D4732A2CB0584C7FEC54C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a request for a meeting, a request for the status of an action, or any other similar administrative request, if the request does not include an attempt to influence a covered executive branch official or a covered legislative branch official;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H78B1B5664982427D9404188E4D019E20"><enum>(v)</enum><text>made in the course of participation in an advisory committee subject to the Federal Advisory Committee Act;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H163ABCABABDF42AF85C129C5C09982A1"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>testimony given before a committee, subcommittee, or task force of the Congress, or submitted for inclusion in the public record of a hearing conducted by such committee, subcommittee, or task force;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6EC39BD287FA41A1B4150AB409B755D8"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>information provided in writing in response to an oral or written request by a covered executive branch official or a covered legislative branch official for specific information;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H22F037C12B0F46F49F79D9A006F3DDC7"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>required by subpoena, civil investigative demand, or otherwise compelled by statute, regulation, or other action of the Congress or an agency, including any communication compelled by a Federal contract, grant, loan, permit, or license;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H065C016304554E43B9EA1D5C4FC63985"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>made in response to a notice in the Federal Register, Commerce Business Daily, or other similar publication soliciting communications from the public and directed to the agency official specifically designated in the notice to receive such communications;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEE31BDE95909418387B1217878F1173B"><enum>(x)</enum><text>not possible to report without disclosing information, the unauthorized disclosure of which is prohibited by law;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6C2F35BFF9F547A5ACFA428C342BCB30"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>made to an official in an agency with regard to—</text> <subclause id="HD500F48533274C6DAB37EEA2BC162325"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a judicial proceeding or a criminal or civil law enforcement inquiry, investigation, or proceeding; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H75C6C5C31DE047A58BF184D4E72B753A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a filing or proceeding that the Government is specifically required by statute or regulation to maintain or conduct on a confidential basis, if that agency is charged with responsibility for such proceeding, inquiry, investigation, or filing;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H3ABC9115592A41A2BDFEFD3881EAD87F"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>made in compliance with written agency procedures regarding an adjudication conducted by the agency under section 554 of title 5, United States Code, or substantially similar provisions;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFEA73560E69D4158BE645EE13FA46C6D"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>a written comment filed in the course of a public proceeding or any other communication that is made on the record in a public proceeding;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBB8F9FBAC0E04D8D8A2CCDA4572D98C7"><enum>(xiv)</enum><text>a petition for agency action made in writing and required to be a matter of public record pursuant to established agency procedures;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC6F42B210EC04F3EB84A9B9268EC9F3E"><enum>(xv)</enum><text>made on behalf of an individual with regard to that individual's benefits, employment, or other personal matters involving only that individual, except that this clause does not apply to any communication with—</text>
 <subclause id="H69C7B5BC41A54077AE83A0611FC27EC2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a covered executive branch official; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="H878409BE1053469D94A8FB225DE983F6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a covered legislative branch official (other than the individual's elected Members of Congress or employees who work under such Members' direct supervision), with respect to the formulation, modification, or adoption of private legislation for the relief of that individual;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HA2150FD7A558473384FF5A5B12C8BEB4"><enum>(xvi)</enum><text>a disclosure by an individual that is protected under the amendments made by the Whistleblower Protection Act of 1989, under the Inspector General Act of 1978, or under another provision of law;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H224605D1954A42EEA04A154BA27DD8C1"><enum>(xvii)</enum><text>made by—</text> <subclause id="H8F5E9F31B80D4F55B1E9D26AFF5FE89C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a church, its integrated auxiliary, or a convention or association of churches that is exempt from filing a Federal income tax return under paragraph (2)(A)(i) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6033">section 6033(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H3CD5F5C2042346D0BFAEA412E3578C2A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a religious order that is exempt from filing a Federal income tax return under paragraph (2)(A)(iii) of such section 6033(a); and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H86D290DCFC934B30A9A56AF109171063"><enum>(xviii)</enum><text>between—</text> <subclause id="H9276C6EC4F3A4852A51423ED6F56A8A7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>officials of a self-regulatory organization (as defined in section 3(a)(26) of the Securities Exchange Act) that is registered with or established by the Securities and Exchange Commission as required by that Act or a similar organization that is designated by or registered with the Commodities Future Trading Commission as provided under the Commodity Exchange Act; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HF8C80D2B1F1343D986EC244B5DD8B003"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Securities and Exchange Commission or the Commodities Future Trading Commission, respectively,</text> </subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">relating to the regulatory responsibilities of such organization under that Act.</continuation-text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5C6AFE196E9431CB184D24BC5FC604D"><enum>(19)</enum><header>Political intelligence firm</header><text>The term <term>political intelligence firm</term> means a person or entity that has one or more employees who are political intelligence consultants to a client other than that person or entity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFEAB3FA6371F491DB1BBAAFCE26D25BD"><enum>(20)</enum><header>Political intelligence consultant</header><text>The term <term>political intelligence consultant</term> means any individual who is employed or retained by a client for financial or other compensation for services that include one or more political intelligence contacts, including an individual who provides brokerage and research services under section 28(e) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4BE7F05971C648E1B8A9E5E945B9B89F"><enum>(21)</enum><header>Security</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>security</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3(a)(10) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)(10)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9462A5CE155A4D2DAF1D826E5C2095E0"><enum>(22)</enum><header>Security-based swap</header><text>The term <term>security-based swap</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3(a)(68) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)(68)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H860D7F64640441C692E5E9A6A3E237D7"><enum>(23)</enum><header>Commodity</header><text>The term <term>commodity</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1a(9) of the Commodity Exchange Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1a">7 U.S.C. 1a(9)</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB9F9AE2B79F44548A690B2FC1A0F74C2"><enum>(24)</enum><header>Swap</header><text>The term <term>swap</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1a(47) of the Commodity Exchange Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1a">7 U.S.C. 1a(47)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H58DA301303084305B42DE6C623455F1E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Registration requirement</header><text>Section 4 of the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1603">2 U.S.C. 1603</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H1A777D9C7EEF4645816BCACD8904A2DB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4665B9FDF1FE4FF9955D006298777316"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by amending paragraph (1) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBD0BD143386C432B8023010DCB70EBFE" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H3C0BE8C50D144FC6A5DDED794501C73B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>General rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A lobbyist or a political intelligence consultant (or, as provided under paragraph (2), the organization employing such lobbyist or consultant), shall register with the Secretary of the Senate and the Clerk of the House of Representatives—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4646D917F30E48929031D99DB214CD20"><enum>(A)</enum><text>no later than 45 days after—</text> <clause id="H2B0DD60634C94C3C9F36AC8CFAFAAEA1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the lobbyist first makes a lobbying contact or is employed or retained to make a lobbying contact, whichever is earlier; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H490D27E67109499E89B738CEF9251CAC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the political intelligence consultant first makes a political intelligence contact or is employed or retained to make a political intelligence contact, whichever is earlier; or</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD3025F0316554D1388D144C95DF48E68"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on the first business day after such 45th day if the 45th day is not a business day.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A7FE40915B94282B8497860DFC70C45"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by inserting after <quote>lobbyists</quote> each place that term appears the following: <quote>or political intelligence consultants</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F273C47064642DA8E65C1C1676F3B44"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(A)—</text> <clause id="HF0F2410149994AFF8D3CFF115EC5204D"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause (i)—</text>
 <subclause id="H10256E5495A447A6866DF2064455B0BE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by inserting after <quote>lobbying activities</quote> the following: <quote>and political intelligence activities</quote>; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H565FB9A7E9DD49F2A93130AAA5C65BC5"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after <quote>lobbying firm</quote> the following: <quote>or political intelligence firm</quote>; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HC86C79741B5E41B184780D46EAB5A4F8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (ii)—</text> <subclause id="H808BD4E225C84F6096B47138DD355DEA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by inserting after <quote>lobbying activities</quote> the following: <quote>and political intelligence activities</quote>; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H8D6E4A3FB9C24B379F7C8EE782CCA0A5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by inserting after <quote>lobbying activities</quote> the following: <quote>or political intelligence activities</quote>;</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4391A1B0D4484471AB11B9892CF7852F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H324465D6E7104047B5605286CFB09ACE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by inserting after <quote>lobbying activities</quote> each place that term appears the following: <quote>or political intelligence activities</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF613ABC8A054F8894FB7D9CE660D135"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text>
 <clause id="H88B6ACFA491E4F258A206FFA6E866D9E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by inserting after <quote>lobbying activities</quote> the following: <quote>or political intelligence activities</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="HA207F25DC9F34C7A8908CAA8B9812723"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by inserting after <quote>lobbying activity</quote> the following: <quote>or political intelligence activity</quote>;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9937D2934165467994439A117EF8C92C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by inserting after <quote>lobbying activities</quote> each place that term appears the following: <quote>or political intelligence activities</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D508338719D4C93B665FD093FF762E5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in the matter following paragraph (6), by inserting <quote>or political intelligence activities</quote> after <quote>such lobbying activities</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7649EE75FE7742C2951649A8CA82CE94"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text> <subparagraph id="H1A0EEA6541A14C6FA21B1C5DCC0E694A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting after <quote>lobbying contacts</quote> the following: <quote>or political intelligence contacts</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB5369C93E6C4C08A6DDE91A99297AE3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> <clause id="HED51C700F67F4A9A9AD0086E0BBB4F42"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting after <quote>lobbying contact</quote> the following: <quote>or political intelligence contact</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H222100F8C5AE4EF48A8F790A73D28404"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting after <quote>lobbying contacts</quote> the following: <quote>and political intelligence contacts</quote>; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H767A1F2742E848D4B277C41B3F14C0DC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2), the following new paragraph:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA2CE84C9A23C41DDBC4F572BDCBCDFA8" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HFEB690D9DF9F4DD0A9F8F964B7983C02"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any threshold dollar amount or percentage described in subsection (b) relates to the sum of the income, contributions, or percent equitable ownership related to lobbying activities plus the income, contributions, or percent equitable ownership related to political intelligence activities.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H745601EC50C5479B8A70EB305B8097F1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (d), by inserting after <quote>lobbying activities</quote> each place that term appears the following: <quote>or political intelligence activities</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB8F5BCB31A564977AE1A6621F1B2D0DD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports by registered political intelligence consultants</header><text>Section 5 of the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1604">2 U.S.C. 1604</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H84572D993FD143FA86705C0AA55CA9E9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by inserting after <quote>lobbying activities</quote> the following: <quote>and political intelligence activities</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4AE361C7F7D24A7984536C20B96333EC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC9941D957C504422B2F4131F1FE0A0FF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> <clause id="HE549915F8F4441B28CE21C88CBF387A0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by inserting after <quote>lobbying activities</quote> the following: <quote>or political intelligence activities</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1DEFEFD05F784C4285E0AAA2B28BFDD6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text> <subclause id="H507BB4C6CD4544EB99245B09626600FF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by inserting after <quote>lobbyist</quote> the following: <quote>or political intelligence consultant</quote>; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA71DF0963D71480B929BA14AE83920F2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by inserting after <quote>lobbying activities</quote> the following: <quote>or political intelligence activities</quote>;</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HB80C21A177024909A753FAF72081996D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by inserting after <quote>lobbyists</quote> the following: <quote>and political intelligence consultants</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H803DE8B17B9048569414EA12F22C8127"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by inserting after <quote>lobbyists</quote> the following: <quote>or political intelligence consultants</quote>;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9FA09F6FF1AA40839AB37E730162BAD9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text>
 <clause id="H3558F196A7C64CA6ABA35BA052E1A1E3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting after <quote>lobbying firm</quote> the following: <quote>or political intelligence firm</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H7DAD216D83074E908F36DFC27CE625D0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting after <quote>lobbying activities</quote> each place that term appears the following: <quote>or political intelligence activities</quote>; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD858B0DD60AA4D738AC3366BD3D005A2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by inserting after <quote>lobbying activities</quote> each place that term appears the following: <quote>or political intelligence activities</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF67AC067E064E9DA68C47D6033D160F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(1), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>or a political intelligence consultant</quote> after <quote>a lobbyist</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5942B8EA2DCF4EFD96DC018BA3F76F96"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Disclosure and enforcement</header><text>Section 6(a) of the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1605">2 U.S.C. 1605</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HCD6D5F1A29CF47F18FFDD0C1630A0675"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(A), by inserting after <quote>lobbying firms</quote> the following: <quote>, political intelligence consultants, political intelligence firms,</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H936D26A61E59431F973D6CD7350F87FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (7), by striking <quote>or lobbying firm</quote> and inserting <quote>lobbying firm, political intelligence consultant, or political intelligence firm</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB4FB271AEAF94879B5D13A0D14B55A5B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (8), by striking <quote>or lobbying firm</quote> and inserting <quote>lobbying firm, political intelligence consultant, or political intelligence firm</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD3A52D7BCB264B95B5D72A25794E9127"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text>Section 8(b) of the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1607">2 U.S.C. 1607(b)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>or lobbying contacts</quote> and inserting <quote>lobbying contacts, political intelligence activities, or political intelligence contacts</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H5A1C3020B12A48BAB67D0CB4C2E48369"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Identification of clients and covered officials</header><text>Section 14 of the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1609">2 U.S.C. 1609</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2BAF707E08A64EAC859E765142BD7E62"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="H182BD4DFA68E47169CBDA38FEDD10E82"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">or Political Intelligence</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Lobbying</header-in-text></quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7986F33EFD5405CA95C0A41CC50C38E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or political intelligence contact</quote> after <quote>lobbying contact</quote> each place that term appears; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2C986139A6244B1A0EE604B0A8EF784"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by inserting <quote>or political intelligence activity, as the case may be</quote> after <quote>lobbying activity</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDAC3117A28F4448C995E685BAC1536D9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <subparagraph id="H9AD7858D478D4A5395D13392BAF6FF77"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">or Political Intelligence</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Lobbying</header-in-text></quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBEAA48215E6443498207C8357AE2D10"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or political intelligence contact</quote> after <quote>lobbying contact</quote> each place that term appears; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3E926DC2BA84B6EB1A7CBC05BDF2793"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by inserting <quote>or political intelligence activity, as the case may be</quote> after <quote>lobbying activity</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8BD10E9F80348429F02CCA0E12739E7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by inserting <quote>or political intelligence contact</quote> after <quote>lobbying contact</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0617B41B6C27432DBE69B287D775DDBB"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Annual audits and reports by comptroller general</header><text>Section 26 of the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1614">2 U.S.C. 1614</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H971FAB4E59B242ABB06CEE6F0FD2120A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="H40E8C8AA3AC24A11ABA25DF526CDDEF3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>political intelligence firms, political intelligence consultants,</quote> after <quote>lobbying firms</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6D3B66AE1B24714A6C7500428170D35"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>lobbying registrations</quote> and inserting <quote>registrations</quote>;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H27B982F8AA774F53A753EB3422ECFA52"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1)(A), by inserting <quote>political intelligence firms, political intelligence consultants,</quote> after <quote>lobbying firms</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1AF48FB485BB48B38D0299529B71B595"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by inserting <quote>or political intelligence consultant</quote> after <quote>a lobbyist</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HDBEBAEF75D224A5DA290FA87381D99A4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Restrictions on former officers, employees, and elected officials of the executive and legislative branches regarding political intelligence contacts</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 207 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HBB645CBA293441BCB67918AD3253E9BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="H18434150505446289A639BCB4B783064"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting after <quote>with the intent to influence,</quote> the following: <quote>or with the intent to gain information for use in analyzing securities or commodities markets, or in informing investment decisions in securities or commodities markets,</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8950AA0A9974CD5858BB8D32E2B283D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by inserting after <quote>with the intent to influence,</quote> the following: <quote>or with the intent to gain information for use in analyzing securities or commodities markets, or in informing investment decisions in securities or commodities markets,</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H289F202AFAE9427F9AFB36E404E6554E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c)(1), by inserting after <quote>with the intent to influence,</quote> the following: <quote>or with the intent to gain information for use in analyzing securities or commodities markets, or in informing investment decisions in securities or commodities markets,</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE0B15F14A7014877B90B2DEB39D8D342"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (d)(1), by inserting after <quote>with the intent to influence,</quote> the following: <quote>or with the intent to gain information for use in analyzing securities or commodities markets, or in informing investment decisions in securities or commodities markets,</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H97D03094BF1545E583C6DA99D253CD77"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (e), by inserting after <quote>with the intent to influence,</quote> each place it appears the following: <quote>or with the intent to gain information for use in analyzing securities or commodities markets, or in informing investment decisions in securities or commodities markets,</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H63102A9501054F718B763A0071048283"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (i)(1), by inserting after <quote>with the intent to influence,</quote> each place it appears the following: <quote>or with the intent to gain information for use in analyzing securities or commodities markets, or in informing investment decisions in securities or commodities markets,</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDE334D2C59D24DD69CAFBB3B712FE986"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in subsection (j), by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE854FE5E970E40CBAB2AF17E4E83DC89" style="USC"> <paragraph id="H94BDDA23EE754948BA8FB071215993C1"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Representative of a media organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The restrictions contained in this section relating to a communication made with the intent to gain information for use in analyzing securities or commodities markets, or in informing investment decisions in securities or commodities markets shall not apply to a communication made by a representative of a media organization (as such term is defined in section 3 of the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1602">2 U.S.C. 1602</external-xref>)), if the purpose of the communication is gathering and disseminating news and information to the public.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H9D043D0C7A6C4A10B6340DF803B34B61"><enum>4.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments made by this Act shall apply with respect to any political intelligence contact (as defined in section 3 of the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1602">2 U.S.C. 1602</external-xref>), as added by section 2 of this Act) that is made on or after the 90th day after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


