<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H41D4B270085F4BDCA9F3408EDD5FA1F0" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4334 IH: Improving Oversight of Women Veterans’ Care Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4334</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171109">November 9, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000598">Mrs. Davis of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001303">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000371">Mr. Aguilar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001200">Mr. McEachin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000410">Mr. Gene Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Brendan F. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000565">Mr. Loebsack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001050">Ms. Hanabusa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000258">Mr. Peterson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000171">Mr. O'Halleran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000799">Mr. Walz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for certain reporting requirements relating to medical care for women veterans provided
			 by the Department of Veterans Affairs and through contracts entered into
			 by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs with non-Department medical
			 providers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H8B2DB9F7111145008C29F7F715C499F7" style="OLC">
 <section id="H9DB85B17707C47009BFD0FAF74DD8B87" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Improving Oversight of Women Veterans’ Care Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H61211D321BFC47CAAB8E8F52F588593A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Annual report on veteran access to covered sex-specific services under community care contracts</header> <subsection id="HE8F5A8AE557A4600B73EF7B3D9BD1BC8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Under Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the House of Representatives an annual report on the access of women veterans to covered sex-specific medical care under contracts with non-Department medical providers entered into by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for the provision of hospital care or medical services to veterans eligible for enrollment in the patient enrollment system of the Department of Veterans Affairs maintained under section 1705 of title 38, United States Code. Such report shall include data and performance measures for the availability of covered sex-specific medical care, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDC53A5EA0DFE4A46B714A0FA64CD178B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the average wait time between the veteran’s preferred appointment date and the date on which the appointment is completed;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA5EA6B2AE5EA44CD8095DB1E93ABC738"><enum>(2)</enum><text>driving time required for veterans to attend appointments; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3DED5EFB714E463CBED223C0BBD41280"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reasons why appointments could not be scheduled with non-Department medical providers.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD21C9E4CB5BE447EBFBC22B66D6CD4CC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered sex-Specific medical care</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>covered sex-specific medical care</quote> means mammography, maternity care, and gynecological care.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H83BA14DCF5204E0DA761748522DCE40E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reporting on Veterans Health Administration environment of care standards for women veterans</header> <subsection id="H71CE6857EA154FBA9E9D9F5E22625932"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Medical facility reporting</header><text>Each medical facility of the Department shall submit to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs a quarterly report on the compliance and noncompliance of the facility with the environment of care standards for women veterans. Each such report shall include the name of each person associated with such facility who is responsible for such compliance and the specific role or responsibility assigned to each such person.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H03B798915466471CB538DDA8CF8F3846"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report on the plan of the Secretary to strengthen the environment of care standards for women veterans at Department of Veterans Affairs medical facilities. Such report shall include—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7A8C82FFAEA34A479CF9EBEF79EBF8C6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the process established to verify that noncompliance information reported under subsection (a) is accurate and complete; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H307ACDC3022B42818819437D56BB54C5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of the method by which the Secretary will—</text> <subparagraph id="H126266C28EB54189827AE81365FFD95E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure that all patient care areas of each Department medical facility are inspected as required; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF3ADEC65DB9461AB35CF81C09F9DB7C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>expand the list of items that facility staff inspect for compliance to align with the women’s health handbook of the Veterans Health Administration.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB7E0F6EB87364140822DE7777306BDC1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Environment of care standards for women veterans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>environment of care standards for women veterans</quote> has the meaning given that term in Veterans Health Administration Directive 1330.01(1).</text> </subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

