<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1A993F8D367B4490A26DB2F11F12029B" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1144 IH: Inclusive Prosperity Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1144</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170216">February 16, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000127">Mr. Nolan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000486">Ms. Roybal-Allard</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001168">Mr. Sarbanes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To impose a tax on certain trading transactions to invest in our families and communities, improve
			 our infrastructure and our environment, strengthen our financial security,
			 expand opportunity and reduce market volatility.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H43A129F5ABF34B4D85EA7F4F6EC6045F" style="OLC">
 <section id="H66E5FDFFB1EA49EE8216C95F30B39C31" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Inclusive Prosperity Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H31E60FC38F974845B163D94915526C89"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HA44343BF7B944D7BB0DCE7ADAC0752B6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The global financial crisis cost Americans $19 trillion in lost wealth.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC486F975E9FE429786198B26ACED9183"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The global financial crisis was caused by financial firms taking great financial risks without disclosing those risks to their investors or their regulators and by regulatory failures to adequately police the financial services markets for crime, unfair or deceptive practices, fraud, lack of transparency, and mismanagement.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6D3B5DCE436A4AD2BDE28FA26F04A856"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Deceptive, illegal, and speculative financial practices have harmed public confidence in the integrity and fairness of many United States financial institutions and threaten the basic strengths of the United States economic system.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H67CF8931EA564EF5AD17198E8E71624C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>American citizens provided the money to stabilize the financial sector, making $600 billion available to 800 financial institutions, automakers, and insurance companies.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD928EF1570574BFF9D3D8DD793BEAEEF"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The global financial crisis, along with the wars, unabated and unaddressed climate change, unsustainable tax cuts, and a continuing unemployment crisis, if unaddressed, will deprive a generation of a meaningful role in the larger economy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2B6538DC7A6644CFB4F21F3F18B72681"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nurses, teachers, public safety officers, and other public sector workers have faced drastic funding cuts, harming our long-term public safety and prospects for economic growth.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF576F3A83F3C436A94A580FF0EFA7C24"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Extreme weather events rooted in climate change, including flood, drought, fire, super storms like Sandy, as well as <term>slow-onset</term> events like sea level rise, are wreaking havoc in the United States and across the globe resulting in climate change impacts that jeopardize the lives and livelihoods of Americans, causing large-scale food and energy insecurity in developing countries, and extolling untold economic costs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEE9DF957B5EB402E908176360D796FA6"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to economists, a small tax on transfer of ownership of every financial trade could generate hundreds of billions annually in revenue, which when invested could help create sufficient jobs in both the public and private sectors to replace the 8 million jobs lost in the recent recession and add even more jobs on an ongoing basis, as well as provide urgently needed funding for programs to combat climate change and address global health and development issues.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H58DDE6C85ACF4DFABA4C4DBDC355C3DA"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A transactions tax will help limit high frequency trading which may be as high as 70 percent of the market and results in declining market stability through extreme price volatility, distorted market prices, and structural vulnerability to speculation far in excess of the liquidity needs of commercial hedgers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H100F437E80034E8185B252F1CE6E77D9"><enum>(10)</enum><text>A securities transfer tax would have a negligible impact on the average investor.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H58AC8A80706940A9BDA1476981BA0B63"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The United States had a transfer tax from 1914 to 1966: The Revenue Act of 1914 (Act of Oct. 22, 1914 (ch. 331, 38 Stat. 745)) levied a 0.2 percent tax on all sales or transfers of stock which was doubled in 1932 to help overcome the budgetary challenges during the Great Depression.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H82FE60EF016A411788C8B3F9AB78FB97"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Forty nations have or have had some form of a financial transactions tax; it is endorsed by more than 1,000 economists; and 11 European countries are moving forward on implementing a coordinated financial transactions tax after European Union finance ministers signaled approval in January 2013.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD7DD51AAAAD24ED8B439E8E34E0F67E1"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Revenue generated by this tax will be available to—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HE751D5952EF14EACA1F3AA78A214E04D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>strengthen financial security and expand opportunity for low- and moderate-income families, including strengthening the social safety net and expanding resources for child care, Social Security, and savings incentives; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF998F7AB396F4382897BBA6CE551DDBD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expand resources for State and Federal investments that protect our health and environment, investing in water and wastewater infrastructure, rebuild our crumbling physical infrastructure, and create good paying jobs by—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H2D763876789F4FA3961142A00F1C0747"><enum>(i)</enum><text>expanding and improving Medicare and Medicaid;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H5EE93AEE34C947CAB4BA563AEF960B07"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>investing in education, student debt relief, job training, public sector jobs, and green jobs;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HFC35E2AB4F0347A5971DFAF26051EC37"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>providing housing assistance to low-income households;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HFD64CAD2884D4B2ABDDA56EF91409932"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>investing in transportation including public mass transit and an infrastructure bank that promotes environmentally responsible domestic manufacturing and construction industries; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H1D3C3CA7C6DF4DF591AA4F7EA79BA9E4"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">protecting our environment and building a clean energy economy, including efforts to combat climate change and build resilience to its effects in the United States and in developing countries; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0E1D63D89BE8471E915EA7E56BE4E8C9"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">fund international sustainable prosperity programs such as health care investments, AIDS treatment, research and prevention programs, climate change adaptation and mitigation efforts by developing countries, and international assistance.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HCC5527A281E5447CB79233A0BDFE0EC8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Transaction tax</header>
 <subsection id="H6527629F083544B48CBF23025B4076AD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/36">Chapter 36</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after subchapter B the following new subchapter:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H69E681A8CF6E4AF8963116C30033E696" style="OLC">
					<subchapter id="H7A6569ED1186462697782ADC22ED1870"><enum>C</enum><header>Tax on Trading Transactions</header>
						<toc container-level="subchapter-container" idref="H7A6569ED1186462697782ADC22ED1870" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
							<toc-entry idref="HD7A4C0C98A204BDAA27242A447834DDC" level="section">Sec. 4475. Tax on trading transactions.</toc-entry></toc>
						<section id="HD7A4C0C98A204BDAA27242A447834DDC"><enum>4475.</enum><header>Tax on trading transactions</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H579E4B0EC7BB4E6F9F901A83770686A1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Imposition of tax</header><text>There is hereby imposed a tax on the transfer of ownership in each covered transaction with respect to any security.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4D1A84669ED94662ABCE686968265BD5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rate of tax</header><text>The tax imposed under subsection (a) with respect to any covered transaction shall be the applicable percentage of the specified base amount with respect to such covered transaction. The applicable percentage shall be—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8785178A9F06428A8D54EECE797EEEBE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>0.5 percent in the case of a security described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of subsection (e)(1),</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDFC7BB555E504B2C9DEB9F2A16E35051"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">0.10 percent in the case of a security described in subparagraph (C) of subsection (e)(1), and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0BB5F3107E68483C8063814D0ACBEEF7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">0.005 percent in the case of a security described in subparagraph (D), (E), or (F) of subsection (e)(1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA031E9C9E21043B1BB0BFA7B101E4FBB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Specified base amount</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>specified base amount</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="H32DDBCFF58D348DC975A06D724653DD1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>except as provided in paragraph (2), the fair market value of the security (determined as of the time of the covered transaction), and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H97348260B639496BBFCA430FE53228B1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of any payment described in subsection (h), the amount of such payment.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAD0EE558C5924836B3FCA13EE9246ADE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Covered transaction</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>covered transaction</term> means—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFA1AE2FC46F248A88177482E4DF8C137"><enum>(1)</enum><text>except as provided in paragraph (2), any purchase if—</text> <subparagraph id="HF9D320BB5DD645778DC9F8DEE8F6886E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such purchase occurs or is cleared on a facility located in the United States, or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7EC8067267604BDC92B1CE47BF04B691"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the purchaser or seller is a United States person, and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E014B5A1983497A956D89D0CD805B7D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any transaction with respect to a security described in subparagraph (D), (E), or (F) of subsection (e)(1), if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H56EA402D0B174CFF8B33EA2C82F97840"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such security is traded or cleared on a facility located in the United States, or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2684DAC51CF4B5993B978626E5D89BD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any party with rights under such security is a United States person.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H89D2B89A6C074680B72B266BF8339C15"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Security and other definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H99BAFA8F0D1D45FD933D4B8420181D5E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>security</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD08D02ADC3D44892A8AA3B58CBB7047A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any share of stock in a corporation,</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H16DECB17ACA44268843DBB8B9117D950"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any partnership or beneficial ownership interest in a partnership or trust,</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD74472BD1F34378AAB23576DF033669"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any note, bond, debenture, or other evidence of indebtedness, other than a State or local bond the interest of which is excluded from gross income under section 103(a),</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBAD173FFCF3D449DBF1F5A884AC8C93E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any evidence of an interest in, or a derivative financial instrument with respect to, any security or securities described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C),</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H30AD9E9500D54735A31C4FF232033C74"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any derivative financial instrument with respect to any currency or commodity including notional principal contracts, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB0E20BDB69D45BAAE49DFB0F26F1710"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any other derivative financial instrument any payment with respect to which is calculated by reference to any specified index.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H83DCC591DE1C43ACAC85AE3F025AF3CA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Derivative financial instrument</header><text>The term <term>derivative financial instrument</term> includes any option, forward contract, futures contract, notional principal contract, or any similar financial instrument.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB27B447B8A2E4F938E041BE561CBAECE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Specified index</header><text>The term <term>specified index</term> means any one or more of any combination of—</text> <subparagraph id="HD7F1CA6D4A0A49D5B678A50C3A82F8F9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a fixed rate, price, or amount, or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B0D8BF11A5442E99F7C05E278927BE9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a variable rate, price, or amount, which is based on any current objectively determinable information which is not within the control of any of the parties to the contract or instrument and is not unique to any of the parties’ circumstances.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B7C53E269C64D9CAD9ED52D86F19B59"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Treatment of exchanges</header>
 <subparagraph id="H3556CE38C43E4715BC58EE588A236875"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An exchange shall be treated as the sale of the property transferred and a purchase of the property received by each party to the exchange.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA96208EB12F44B5785CCBAB3856849D2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Certain deemed exchanges</header><text>In the case of a distribution treated as an exchange for stock under section 302 or 331, the corporation making such distribution shall be treated as having purchased such stock for purposes of this section.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3F8953EF2DB74C3AA75AED6C446E7731"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Exceptions</header>
 <paragraph id="H102E3EC714CC46DB828BD6BAE36A71D5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exception for initial issues</header><text>No tax shall be imposed under subsection (a) on any covered transaction with respect to the initial issuance of any security described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of subsection (e)(1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFCE1C5DEFAB74784ABE37B494599398B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for certain traded short-term indebtedness</header><text>A note, bond, debenture, or other evidence of indebtedness which—</text> <subparagraph id="H08B16A9A12C64842BF9010651019A1EB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is traded on a trading facility located in the United States, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D16442A5128423CACF65E8F60B4D864"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has a fixed maturity of not more than 60 days,</text> </subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">shall not be treated as described in subsection (e)(1)(C).</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9BF8FCB8E22D456B8ED7D71E09654693"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception for securities lending arrangements</header><text>No tax shall be imposed under subsection (a) on any covered transaction with respect to which gain or loss is not recognized by reason of section 1058.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF96E8B2FC5F34950ADF2365B57DD7A0A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>By whom paid</header>
 <paragraph id="HF9AC46B940834B8D8F75A1C5FB6941EA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The tax imposed by this section shall be paid by—</text> <subparagraph id="HBBCF92835880403EBFA3E38CACFE229F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a transaction which occurs or is cleared on a facility located in the United States, such facility, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7ADB92313B8645BFAE8C0D951B89FFFB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a purchase not described in subparagraph (A) which is executed by a broker (as defined in section 6045(c)(1)), the broker.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1FCDAD5EA3841468B8F8D03D7651469"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rules for direct, etc., transactions</header><text>In the case of any transaction to which paragraph (1) does not apply, the tax imposed by this section shall be paid by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H504E70585738488DA8A0ECF1AF75FF4A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a transaction described in subsection (d)(1)—</text> <clause id="H2EE81ECFC188450A95E613C70FBFDDD0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the purchaser if the purchaser is a United States person, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H57F2BE4884CB4906BA9E323E5EF5BEE1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the seller if the purchaser is not a United States person, and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE82F027D27443B29833223756393CAB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a transaction described in subsection (d)(2)—</text>
 <clause id="HB620BE25B07B4A519C500A553F472BE2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the payor if the payor is a United States person, and</text> </clause><clause id="H639F8E910B3B413A98E9E566409A98FF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the payee if the payor is not a United States person.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5B08FE13A9094CEAAC48CD353E742180"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Certain payments treated as separate transactions</header><text>Except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, any payment with respect to a security described in subparagraph (D), (E), or (F) of subsection (e)(1) shall be treated as a separate transaction for purposes of this section, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFD8AD12B82C04325B2D377A619C87BA1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any net initial payment, net final or terminating payment, or net periodical payment with respect to a notional principal contract (or similar financial instrument),</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7D314A61B53543F7942BD68F1D0339AF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any payment with respect to any forward contract (or similar financial instrument), and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEBE1648EB8C743A2943DDA4E73DA299C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any premium paid with respect to any option (or similar financial instrument).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H28EC0FDF53224DE8AB35BA3F6A3576C0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out this section in consultation with the Securities and Exchange Commission and the Commodity Futures Trading Commission.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCC77626BFD424F23B59534B21AEABB93"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Guidance; regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="H68C491970D0144EBA245D50C79B3852B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide guidance regarding such information reporting concerning covered transactions as the Secretary deems appropriate, including reporting by the payor of the tax in cases where the payor is not the purchaser, and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB310DEE730F54E10AA34D81E6E879812"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prescribe such regulations as are necessary or appropriate to prevent avoidance of the purposes of this section, including the use of non-United States persons in such transactions.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC5B4ECD7D0E94971BEBF8F726F9A26F4"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Whistleblowers</header><text>See section 7623 for provisions relating to whistleblowers.</text></subsection></section></subchapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H4946D048AE274669A166BA365BA908A0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Penalty for failure To include covered transaction information with return</header><text>Part I of subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/68">chapter 68</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after section 6707A the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H814C67D7A93843AE8B7C5AD54F0920A8" style="OLC">
					<section id="H856539CA6195493F89786611F35788BE"><enum>6707B.</enum><header>Penalty for failure to include covered transaction information with return</header>
 <subsection id="H02B7692FAEED4F6CA78F6BD854B9D306"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Imposition of penalty</header><text>Any person who fails to include on any return or statement any information with respect to a covered transaction which is required pursuant to section 4475(j)(1) to be included with such return or statement shall pay a penalty in the amount determined under subsection (b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA439CD3CF532486187DF877E1FAEDF76"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amount of penalty</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the amount of the penalty under subsection (a) with respect to any covered transaction shall be determined by the Secretary.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEEAB9D1D2E5C4D3298D2098162BA9957"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Covered transaction</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>covered transaction</term> has the meaning given such term by section 4475(d).</text> </subsection><subsection id="HC9C333FE5B9042988A6712A583508148"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authority To rescind penalty</header> <paragraph id="H4DB716C80F5144E4BFA532D4621BA17B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commissioner of Internal Revenue may rescind all or any portion of any penalty imposed by this section with respect to any violation if rescinding the penalty would promote compliance with the requirements of this title and effective tax administration.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDE774AB7C25E4F92938D061CAE424CE5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No judicial appeal</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any determination under this subsection may not be reviewed in any judicial proceeding.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9C2C747DF4B24A6DB7AB81AAE91FC75D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Records</header><text>If a penalty is rescinded under paragraph (1), the Commissioner shall place in the file in the Office of the Commissioner the opinion of the Commissioner with respect to the determination, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H387BBB9F013644259A232F0799E32A42"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a statement of the facts and circumstances relating to the violation,</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD055146ECAF0498FB0FD8219A039621F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the reasons for the rescission, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H887090378DED45A6BE5C4489FCDA746D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the amount of the penalty rescinded.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC0FB9FBB6F8E4D28A91E4959960279B0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Coordination with other penalties</header><text>The penalty imposed by this section shall be in addition to any other penalty imposed by this title.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H2A3C7E50DB3447DD878C950A0C40FD16"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="H354FFF30254541BDA452532E235AC05A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for part I of subchapter B of chapter 68 of such Code is amended by inserting after item relating to section 6707A the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2344F58AAD6B4ABBAF4FFB6C6728C6D5" style="OLC">
						<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="H814C67D7A93843AE8B7C5AD54F0920A8" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
							<toc-entry idref="H856539CA6195493F89786611F35788BE" level="section">Sec. 6707B. Penalty for failure to include covered transaction information with return.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H198265B9C413447FA38C91B6994C0AD5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The table of subchapters for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/36">chapter 36</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after the item relating to subchapter B the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8A870A4DBAAF4C8683705D5FB2F084CE" style="OLC">
						<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="H69E681A8CF6E4AF8963116C30033E696" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
							<toc-entry idref="H7A6569ED1186462697782ADC22ED1870" level="subchapter">Subchapter C. Tax on Trading Transactions</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9E9AB9ABA3BC4AB1A0119B791A5200FC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to transactions after December 31, 2017.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H790EA1ED05B1473AA8035F8DF0636CB2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Offsetting credit for financial transaction tax</header> <subsection id="H462EE8EC7F5245929A5AD330216BEE44"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart A of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (relating to nonrefundable personal credits) is amended by inserting after section 25D the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H49AC96757B734BFBB729ADB00D5705D1" style="OLC">
					<section id="H3E702A388EA840B1BDD045781C142F4E"><enum>25E.</enum><header>Financial transaction tax payments</header>
 <subsection id="H7F7AE935B2CB4DF5866E2522745178C8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Allowance of credit</header><text>In the case of an individual, there shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by this chapter for the taxable year an amount equal to the tax paid during the taxable year under section 4475.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="HFE8E28BB13774102B55B67723BAAE4B6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation based on modified adjusted gross income</header>
 <paragraph id="H77707D19577F44FFA0026F70AF10A914"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply to a taxpayer for the taxable year if the modified adjusted gross income of the taxpayer for the taxable year exceeds $50,000 ($75,000 in the case of a joint return and one-half of such amount in the case of a married individual filing a separate return).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6CD88FFA22514B3685A8E667DAA7C7EA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Modified adjusted gross income</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), the term <term>modified adjusted gross income</term> means adjusted gross income—</text> <subparagraph id="HB730683753534C78A209CA3CC6B65F4A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determined without regard to sections 86, 893, 911, 931, and 933, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0CD89B1D6764AC9B6923598DAB52DA2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>increased by the amount of interest received or accrued by the taxpayer during the taxable year which is exempt from tax.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A7CB30C74424C7C831DD14EE9D687CE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header>
 <subparagraph id="H5B44EF47F5AD469A9E84BB717989E3EA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any taxable year beginning after 2016, each dollar amount referred to in paragraph (1) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</text>
 <clause id="HAF7028DC61F249C299A6A67ED4992FEE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such dollar amount, multiplied by</text> </clause><clause id="HDD8F08BD0D444B2FB663D99E097DD313"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section (1)(f)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 for the calendar year in which the taxable year begins, by substituting <quote>2017</quote> for <quote>1992</quote>.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H017386E609654896BC75B1E25270069F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rounding</header><text>If any amount as adjusted under clause (i) is not a multiple of $50, such amount shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $50.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H39D969107BF643488602A8E59C2ACC27"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible individual</header>
 <paragraph id="H65789F8A48E141FB8E7BB391558D5002"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>eligible individual</term> means, with respect to any taxable year, an individual who—</text> <subparagraph id="H1AF0A053F86D40CBB7AFBF81BCD58C58"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has attained the age of 18 as of the last day of such taxable year, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB0884028B9A4F71A9C22C6D434AB213"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is a citizen or lawful permanent resident (within the meaning of section 7701(b)(6)) as of the last day of such taxable year.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H60816E18DD4544C7A21A87E0D07D4A6C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certain individuals not eligible</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), an individual described in any of the following provisions of this title for the preceding taxable year shall not be treated as an eligible individual for the taxable year:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3B8509BE33FD4F5CAD2AC0C4B5393F19"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An individual who is a student (as defined in section 152(f)(2)) for the taxable year or the immediately preceding taxable year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF73C42BD5B2A421B9B6252F59CB576B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An individual who is a taxpayer described in subsection (c), (d), or (e) of section 6402 for the immediately preceding taxable year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62B6965E50174A498303338E8BFACDAA"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A married individual who files a separate return for the taxable year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="HF21DD33FBD1645A0A19F862701805644"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subpart A of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 25D the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H76D7BA08965447B7B40E7AF2C00A2630" style="OLC">
					<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="H49AC96757B734BFBB729ADB00D5705D1" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
						<toc-entry idref="H3E702A388EA840B1BDD045781C142F4E" level="section">Sec. 25E. Financial transaction tax payments.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0C657E3328384AB6AB0CC20F21FBA35E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2017.</text> </subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

