<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H6C4BCB755D8E45BBBD964879CBB1F54A" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4150 IH: Innovate America Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4150</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171026">October 26, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000619">Mr. Rodney Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To support innovation, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H172DD83D8A024A25B5CE4233AFDFC099" style="OLC">
		<section id="H2D46E500ABF143B8BD60A1A943494059" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="H4E7F7EF09632498BB74DB3A14A7739E6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Innovate America Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HEE7ABB7882AF4B4498CBC623161C2F9B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc>
					<toc-entry idref="H2D46E500ABF143B8BD60A1A943494059" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H47C91F0DEB1748E49EDABC621A06E244" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H5396E5F226D647618056243931D53ABA" level="title">TITLE I—Education</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H3A302214E2BF40618C2E4DCF1D74DF0A" level="section">Sec. 101. Definitions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H8A2B7EF1BA964BA3BCB57BF0EF0AAA64" level="section">Sec. 102. Increasing funding for STEM secondary schools.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HB10623ED8852404B95BEF8CB78B1DC8D" level="section">Sec. 103. Report on STEM secondary schools.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H93540B6A0BE842E19DB7F7E2C0F16D93" level="section">Sec. 104. Study and report on retaining STEM students.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HB42D0BDE7C61447486A2B7F73D1CCEFA" level="section">Sec. 105. Expanding undergraduate research opportunities.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HA88FEFDBD1EF4F5DA1641358D7213579" level="section">Sec. 106. Technology Commercialization Awards Pilot Program.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H4F37B9AFACC040A3A2DDE433935C93F2" level="section">Sec. 107. Computer science in the Robert Noyce teacher scholarship program.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H405A66A6342F476FB40C92D99E334B66" level="title">TITLE II—Manufacturing and export promotion</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H4C900C0AB740439F9BCCF698D2BAFA13" level="section">Sec. 201. Manufacturing assistance program for small- and medium-sized manufacturers in the United
			 States.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H2986069C756648C181A7A24EAFA45540" level="section">Sec. 202. Removing barriers for exporting industries in the United States.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H5781E5AA223D4DE18F6FE22ACD8DC9F8" level="title">TITLE III—Offsets</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H9E7823C1C50F459D8B780E7C755668E7" level="section">Sec. 301. Limitation on Government printing costs.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HD69C626FC2BF484C82BF622EAC7AEB8E" level="section">Sec. 302. Eliminating bonuses for poor performance by Government contractors.</toc-entry></toc>
 </subsection></section><section id="H47C91F0DEB1748E49EDABC621A06E244"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="H39AE20512AA7484DB0AA149668FFBB7D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Innovation has historically been a catalyzing force in the economy of the United States, driving the production of game-changing technologies, the creation of millions of jobs and the opening of countless new avenues for growth. In an increasingly competitive global economy, our Nation’s continued leadership and prosperity will hinge on progress in key innovative areas, most notably exporting, entrepreneurship, research and development, and education in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (referred to in this section as <quote>STEM</quote>), including computer science.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC937AC6223724C05AE63CF7EC2887533"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Technology-based startups play a critical role in driving innovation. Increasing the flow of capital to these firms would bridge the gap that often exists between their initial startup costs and their long-term capital needs, giving the firms the resources necessary to research, develop, and commercialize new products.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF1DB99B3922A48559C616B87A1D240DE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Simplifying, expanding, and stabilizing the tax credits that businesses and institutions of higher education rely on to offset the cost of research and would promote greater clarity in the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and deliver a powerful incentive for private sector innovation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3155490F6F7648A48C491ED18EB96BDF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Increasing the emphasis on STEM education in high schools and institutions of higher education would ensure that more students have the skills and training to not only compete for jobs in a 21st century economy, but also to create the startup companies and revolutionary technologies that will sustain American prosperity for centuries to come.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFC14FAC8938A4B4D8DB68C1B98142D39"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Bureau of Labor Statistics predicts that in the year 2020, of the 9,200,000 STEM jobs there will be in the United States, half of them will be in computing. With more than 150,000 job openings expected annually in computing, it is one of the fastest growing occupations in the United States. Increasing the teaching and learning of computer science in schools would strengthen the workforce of the United States by helping our students gain the skills and training necessary to fulfill new computer programming jobs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H18E909975ED145F2AFD12DF2F15F516F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>An effective regulatory climate should protect consumers and promote transparency without overburdening the businesses that create jobs. Federal agencies with rulemaking authority should be vigilant in assessing the impact of new regulations on innovation and job creation, particularly in anchor industries like manufacturing.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB05040784FB0450E9D4DC0890F38053D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The economic impact of a new product or technology is often dependent on its commercial success. To ensure American products can be bought and sold in markets around the world, the Federal Government should identify and remove over burdensome regulations that create barriers for United States exporting companies.</text>
			</paragraph></section><title id="H5396E5F226D647618056243931D53ABA"><enum>I</enum><header>Education</header>
 <section id="H3A302214E2BF40618C2E4DCF1D74DF0A"><enum>101.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text> <paragraph id="H7C8D445D068442F195EC04297E0EB88C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the National Science Foundation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDEC27003DCC6460E945AF0E87AF8025E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE3F8DB7F6961416C88237BA367F76F00"><enum>(3)</enum><header>STEM</header><text>The term <term>STEM</term> means the subjects of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics, including other subjects based on science, technology, engineering, or mathematics, such as computer science.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBB3FB692DA584A12AB7FD37B2645A084"><enum>(4)</enum><header>STEM secondary school</header><text>The term <term>STEM secondary school</term> has the meaning given the term by the Secretary of Education, in coordination with the Director, not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7FD99196A3A94136A205BA03814FFE24"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State educational agency</header><text>The term <term>State educational agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph></section><section id="H8A2B7EF1BA964BA3BCB57BF0EF0AAA64"><enum>102.</enum><header>Increasing funding for STEM secondary schools</header>
 <subsection id="H7DF70785C8AB4F299DD108858DD5FD13"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this section is to increase the number of STEM secondary schools in the United States from approximately 100 to approximately 200.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="H329302721FB84F50BB4313499A28EAA9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program authorized</header>
 <paragraph id="H0C64640B74794141AC85AC8ED38788ED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From amounts appropriated under subsection (e), the Secretary of Education, in coordination with the Director, shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to State educational agencies to enable the State educational agencies to carry out the purposes of this section by establishing or expanding STEM secondary schools.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1260BD3381B94B9F8D494ED6DCDD7108"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Geographic distribution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall award grants under this section in a manner that ensures geographic diversity, including awarding grants to State educational agencies serving rural areas.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD890AE401B7C412D9DC7B7BB8E5804E8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>A State educational agency desiring to receive a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary of Education at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE816DECEEF6A49B7BF88FD308ACFA836"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State educational agency receiving funds under this section shall use such funds to award subgrants, on a competitive basis, to local educational agencies in the State to enable the local educational agencies to establish and maintain new STEM secondary schools, which may include repurposing an existing secondary school to become a STEM secondary school.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6A07AF53EFC64080A2596F466BF84FAF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2027.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="HB10623ED8852404B95BEF8CB78B1DC8D"><enum>103.</enum><header>Report on STEM secondary schools</header>
 <subsection id="H0AE67BBA9F284A52A914F47E54D17434"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Database</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Education, in coordination with the Director, shall develop a database to identify existing STEM secondary schools.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5D9849608C4E4A98BA0F8BA7A2E02184"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Education, in coordination with the Director, shall submit a report to Congress with recommendations on how to replicate existing successful STEM secondary schools.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H93540B6A0BE842E19DB7F7E2C0F16D93"><enum>104.</enum><header>Study and report on retaining STEM students</header>
 <subsection id="H062A995BEF3F4F64A8DAFA3B30312A95"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director shall conduct a study, in coordination with the Secretary of Education, to make recommendations to Congress on how to improve retention rates of students in STEM programs at institutions of higher education. The study should include an analysis of existing successful retention programs at institutions of higher education.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF02C280CB7E042B7922528FA787F60F1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall submit to Congress a report on the study conducted under subsection (a).</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="HB42D0BDE7C61447486A2B7F73D1CCEFA"><enum>105.</enum><header>Expanding undergraduate research opportunities</header>
 <subsection id="HAD44000DC4D1461EB1C83CB6A062F224"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than June 1, 2018, the President shall ensure that not less than 15 percent of all Federal funds available for a fiscal year for undergraduate research opportunities at 2-year and 4-year degree-granting institutions of higher education shall be used to fund research opportunities for postsecondary students, with an emphasis on undergraduate research opportunities occurring during the first 2 academic years of postsecondary education.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H86521BDE9E8248A68A24CFDDD630494D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of the Congress that each Federal agency should restructure the agency's undergraduate student research opportunities for students attending 2-year or 4-year degree-granting institutions of higher education, in order to provide more research opportunities for postsecondary students during the students’ first 2 academic years of postsecondary education.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6413854A788849E39133275065746F71"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Identification of research programs</header><text>Not later than December 31, 2017, the head of each Federal agency shall submit to the President—</text> <paragraph id="H9FFB507DCB744766B20F5AB96F35626F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a list of all programs and funds available for undergraduate student research under the jurisdiction of the agency; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD0EAA0607C904E87933616FD0764F72C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommendations regarding how the agency can best fulfill the requirements of subsection (a).</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA88FEFDBD1EF4F5DA1641358D7213579"><enum>106.</enum><header>Technology Commercialization Awards Pilot Program</header> <subsection id="HAF355C4DC88B40518F683F9CEEBD2B20"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director, through the Partnerships for Innovation Program of the National Science Foundation, shall administer a Technology Commercialization Awards Pilot Program through which promising technology advances derived from National Science Foundation research grants shall be eligible for follow-on funding—</text>
 <paragraph id="H501BBFC2BF0241148438D5897B697148"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to move the technology through prototype and demonstration phases;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBA798B0999A844248C9805CE18777D83"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for training for researcher participants in business plan development, technology transfer, and commercialization; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H19511806C37D4524B755B3DAA1D668F5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>for establishing start-up firms based on the technologies developed.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCEC511855054490E95A3463CC535369C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Competitive selection</header><text>The Director shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2739EFF5894A4244B7C71654B737B3EC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>seek from National Science Foundation offices and divisions recommendations on outstanding research funded by the National Science Foundation with clear promise that such research can be advanced close to commercialized in a 3- to 5-year period;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC17E6E05EE414E548455763AD9CCA0C8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>solicit applications from National Science Foundation award grantees who believe that they have qualifying technologies eligible for commercialization; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H703C7DBBB2D54313B29679B6067B51B0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>award grants to such National Science Foundation award grantees based on a merit-based, competitive selection process.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC374EC32E28E4B698C2002243D177191"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Advisory Committee</header><text>The Director shall form an Advisory Committee of experts on technology and the technology commercialization process to advise the National Science Foundation on the Technology Commercialization Awards Pilot Program.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDB06D11060D5435CBDF47EA7BAE59840"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the first grant is awarded under this section, the Director shall—</text> <paragraph id="HAD324FB2DDBE4BAEB30DC523E37EB161"><enum>(1)</enum><text>report to the relevant committees of Congress on the results of the Technology Commercialization Awards Pilot Program; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC693CBEC68144E418FC1C4055E01C67B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make recommendations on whether and how such a technology commercialization fund could be adopted by other Federal research and development agencies.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H01E11A651AF645178788B2E07AE690A3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $10,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2018 through 2022.</text>
 </subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4F37B9AFACC040A3A2DDE433935C93F2"><enum>107.</enum><header>Computer science in the Robert Noyce teacher scholarship program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 10 of the National Science Foundation Authorization Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1862n-1">42 U.S.C. 1862n–1</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H44B4A1EBA4E547D6A346F1122ECA6EB2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and mathematics</quote> and inserting <quote>mathematics, informatics, and computer science</quote> each place the term appears;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5CC16004EC8A45779A4E5D0F400BC88B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1)(D)(i), by striking <quote>or mathematics</quote> and inserting <quote>mathematics, informatics, or computer science</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6913A0E60EAD433D9E0915242004D50E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text> <subparagraph id="H4C1DD6468E4647B1B3128A6553C263FC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(A), by striking <quote>or mathematics</quote> and inserting <quote>mathematics, informatics, or computer science</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0C3D008BBD14AD0A737949FF0B17251"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>mathematics or</quote> and inserting <quote>mathematics, informatics, computer science, or</quote>;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1BFB458B3CB4C609203A1527440321B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(4), by striking <quote>mathematics or</quote> and inserting <quote>mathematics, informatics, computer science, or</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE8F6D8EAE9D84C34B3BBF7C60282F811"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subsection (i)—</text> <subparagraph id="HEA135066EE37428292C15ACB9FCA290F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking <quote>or mathematics</quote> and inserting <quote>mathematics, or computer science</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEFC83E2A47614CBD8297F63C69DFBB00"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (7), by striking <quote>or mathematics,</quote> and inserting <quote>mathematics, informatics, or computer science,</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></section></title><title id="H405A66A6342F476FB40C92D99E334B66"><enum>II</enum><header>Manufacturing and export promotion</header> <section id="H4C900C0AB740439F9BCCF698D2BAFA13"><enum>201.</enum><header>Manufacturing assistance program for small- and medium-sized manufacturers in the United States</header> <subsection id="H4CCAB7B8AEF147E1BACFECF164B02F74"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
 <paragraph id="HA64D17B18AF64144BA440D6E7A670D01"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Commerce.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7D998E0AE9A44FB9A5E2C193B90AC02A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Small- and medium-sized domestic manufacturers</header><text>The term <term>small- and medium-sized domestic manufacturers</term> means businesses—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD63F26E7A5F345CF88C68B301909972C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with not more than 500 employees; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H99F79107E5D649BA82E95735E079E3BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with facilities located in the United States that mechanically, physically, or chemically transform materials, substances, or components into new goods, including component parts.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC8AEBF628C15437FB7DF65463A58E75C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish a manufacturing assistance program for small- and medium-sized domestic manufacturers for the purposes of promoting the manufacturing of goods in the United States and enabling those manufacturers to be competitive in the global economy by—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDF58B492BBAF4112AF49AB50D33839FE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifying and reducing regulatory burdens on those manufacturers under subsection (c); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H024F32CE42A84907AC54C620B8C7F240"><enum>(2)</enum><text>providing those manufacturers with information and other assistance under subsection (d).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H97D429F3F9814F58B1B6210CE2C46DBA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reduction of regulatory burdens</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="H37313DBE8C06474CAA5669C357F8134B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify any regulatory requirements applicable to small- and medium-sized domestic manufacturers that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE83E0FB693C24AC49B77E8C5A1215F60"><enum>(A)</enum><text>impose an unnecessary burden on those manufacturers; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H30028C590D5D4CE0B236F944464D04DE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may be eliminated or reduced in order to promote the manufacture of goods in the United States;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8278C98ADE094351854613AE58001A93"><enum>(2)</enum><text>take appropriate action to eliminate or reduce the regulatory requirements identified under paragraph (1); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA43BF88BFC2E475A91F8E2190B78309A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date on which the Secretary establishes the program required by subsection (b), submit to Congress a report that makes recommendations with respect to action by Congress that may be necessary to eliminate or reduce the regulatory requirements identified under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HE42FDA438F124F70AE20234015C7F825"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Assistance</header><text>The Secretary shall assist small- and medium-sized domestic manufacturers by providing those manufacturers with information with respect to—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H39035D85ED5042F9A65729AFA16C580B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>how small- and medium-sized domestic manufacturers can comply efficiently with regulations applicable to those manufacturers;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC0900958F8D74C869B54B4D852EC2725"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recently proposed and recently prescribed regulations likely to have an effect on small- and medium-sized domestic manufacturers; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7562818796EE4A1A8F2F7D821F44EBFD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>how small- and medium-sized domestic manufacturers can express their views and provide input with respect to any policy developments relating to the manufacture of goods in the United States.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8804D17323B64FB8B32138D61A2AF03A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report on effectiveness of program</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Hollings Manufacturing Extension Partnership of the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall submit to Congress a report on the program established under subsection (b) that includes—</text>
 <paragraph id="HAB53E86D3D6A42D6871F48C108202240"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an assessment of the extent to which the program has been effective—</text> <subparagraph id="H081AF445481143FCAE097A92AB5AAC8B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in identifying and reducing regulatory burdens on small- and medium-sized domestic manufacturers under subsection (c);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A771289EFA44AB0A5917EB7AB0FC69F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in providing information and other assistance to small- and medium-sized domestic manufacturers under subsection (d); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96D477AD40F7476DB0D5A8C70C8326B6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in promoting the manufacturing of goods in the United States and enabling small- and medium-sized domestic manufacturers to be competitive in the global economy;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H54B51FBF5176467CA72F4CE85BE467D0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>detailed information with respect to the nature, location, and duration of any jobs created as a result of the program established under subsection (b) and a description of the methodology used to compile that information; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5829986B42A94A3FBEE2C49524997496"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any recommendations with respect to continuing or improving the program established under subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7A39ABFFA7E94259A9F658863619E843"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $15,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2018 through 2022 to carry out the program established under subsection (b).</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H2986069C756648C181A7A24EAFA45540"><enum>202.</enum><header>Removing barriers for exporting industries in the United States</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Under Secretary for International Trade of the Department of Commerce shall submit to Congress a report—</text>
 <paragraph id="H08DEBF7B21BA4FADA0BEBC45E2FEAC44"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifying the 20 industries in the United States that export the most goods or services;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0B3934BFBDBD4E5BAF7A61714F497FED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>evaluating the competitiveness of those industries in global markets compared to competitors manufacturing outside the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H896C73C4259944C98D9BA31FD24E6D19"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifying domestic regulatory and policy barriers to increasing exports by those industries;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HACD58FD0AAF04B97A183BC05D8B39775"><enum>(4)</enum><text>identifying measures imposed by foreign governments that impede the access of those industries to foreign markets; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDD1742D3F1C94D86BA1ADE3E078AA132"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">making recommendations with respect to legislative action that could be taken by Congress to reduce barriers identified under paragraph (3) and improve the global competitiveness of those industries in foreign markets.</text>
				</paragraph></section></title><title id="H5781E5AA223D4DE18F6FE22ACD8DC9F8"><enum>III</enum><header>Offsets</header>
 <section id="H9E7823C1C50F459D8B780E7C755668E7"><enum>301.</enum><header>Limitation on Government printing costs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall coordinate with the heads of Federal departments and independent agencies to—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF5FE5998F6F24B4B98F2787709907C90"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determine which Government publications could be available on Government websites and no longer printed and to devise a strategy to reduce overall Government printing costs over the 10-year period beginning with fiscal year 2018, except that the Director shall ensure that essential printed documents prepared for Social Security recipients, Medicare beneficiaries, and other populations in areas with limited internet access or use continue to remain available;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEA5183BAE9B54E13AF1F3953839D5028"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish Governmentwide Federal guidelines on employee printing;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC7FBAB9FF45546259D8EF912C8CB4BFE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>issue on the Office of Management and Budget's public website the results of a cost-benefit analysis on implementing a digital signature system and on establishing employee printing identification systems, such as the use of individual employee cards or codes, to monitor the amount of printing done by Federal employees; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC59E90FAB0174EFC9AB6F1135AE85017"><enum>(4)</enum><text>ensure that Federal employee printing costs unrelated to national defense, homeland security, border security, national disasters, and other emergencies do not exceed $860,000,000 annually.</text>
				</paragraph></section><section id="HD69C626FC2BF484C82BF622EAC7AEB8E"><enum>302.</enum><header>Eliminating bonuses for poor performance by Government contractors</header>
 <subsection id="H38B79C8C09E0463684889FCAE4A075BC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Guidance on linking of award and incentive fees to outcomes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, each Federal department or agency shall issue guidance, with detailed implementation instructions (including definitions), on the appropriate use of award and incentive fees in department or agency programs.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3CEA08FF9AEE41AC91287B608788BACA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The guidance under subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph id="HB09D7C11F3904BA48D8C1FC9861DC7C2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>ensure that all new contracts using award fees link such fees to outcomes (which shall be defined in terms of program cost, schedule, and performance);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H618B940E78CD4CCCB73BBC63A4AC6695"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish standards for identifying the appropriate level of officials authorized to approve the use of award and incentive fees in new contracts;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H875C10F5CFE9467CAEFA519A5BEB13C7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide guidance on the circumstances in which contractor performance may be judged to be excellent or superior and the percentage of the available award fee which contractors should be paid for such performance;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7742285067774A83881E9E549EB7020A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establish standards for determining the percentage of the available award fee, if any, which contractors should be paid for performance that is judged to be acceptable, average, expected, good, or satisfactory;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H17319675489A4C9D84BD07452B6C3D79"><enum>(5)</enum><text>ensure that no award fee may be paid for contractor performance that is judged to be below satisfactory performance or performance that does not meet the basic requirements of the contract;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H80D99F43C697483C80F84BE961E386EA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>provide specific direction on the circumstances, if any, in which it may be appropriate to roll over award fees that are not earned in one award fee period to a subsequent award fee period or periods;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE1383ECB0D5B46FA9BA39E72D5AEF262"><enum>(7)</enum><text>ensure that the Department or agency—</text> <subparagraph id="H4489553AFD5440C88D9CD29C8B260E0E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>collects relevant data on award and incentive fees paid to contractors; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D61D34AA00F4F0787E2C81C592B094E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has mechanisms in place to evaluate such data on a regular basis; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC273E41580114AD68A47DFF8BF71C5B9"><enum>(8)</enum><text>include performance measures to evaluate the effectiveness of award and incentive fees as a tool for improving contractor performance and achieving desired program outcomes.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4F4FECBA89FA490FB7717A56DD25EE4F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Return of unearned bonuses</header><text>Any funds intended to be awarded as incentive fees that are not paid due to contractors' inability to meet the criteria established by this section shall be returned to the Treasury.</text>
				</subsection></section></title></legis-body></bill>


