<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H5BBF799B01214BC1BC7648F6855288EB" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 82 IH: Criminal Alien Deportation Enforcement Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 82</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170103">January 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To withhold Federal financial assistance from each country that denies or unreasonably delays the
			 acceptance of nationals of such country who have been ordered removed from
			 the United States and to prohibit the issuance of visas to nationals of
			 such country.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H7F05959C880A4182ABACAF33DBB67946" style="OLC">
 <section id="H1E57401C50D7443395479F14BD8F058A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Criminal Alien Deportation Enforcement Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H3B88A5096FC84CE7A3F82750F03C8034" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on Federal financial assistance to countries that deny or unreasonably delay the acceptance of nationals who have been ordered removed from the United States</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Chapter 1 of part I of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151">22 U.S.C. 2151 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="HCA1F15C0B84548A7B814EBBE2FAB3804" style="OLC">
				<section id="H90D75C4217BF4EEF860E70038C0E2093"><enum>137.</enum><header>Prohibition on Federal financial assistance to countries that deny or unreasonably delay the
			 repatriation of nationals who have been ordered removed from the United
			 States</header>
 <subsection id="HA6459291FAB7489795B045D64AE17C20"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text>Except as otherwise provided under this section, funds made available under this Act may not be dispersed to a foreign country that refuses or unreasonably delays the acceptance of an alien who—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9F74F32A7DAB402AB67CFEFE029E08AD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is a citizen, subject, national, or resident of such country; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB3CADDBE341A45D2AB7A768E85692E8E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has received a final order of removal under chapter 4 of title II of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1221">8 U.S.C. 1221 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF9D3FA10178945289CCAC81A44503653"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Defined Term</header><text>In this section and in section 243(d) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1253">8 U.S.C. 1253(d)</external-xref>), a country is deemed to have refused or unreasonable delayed the acceptance of an alien who is a citizen, subject, national, or resident if the country does not accept the alien within 90 days of receiving a request to repatriate such alien from an official of the United States who is authorized to make such a request.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB35BFE7CA0084DF8AC292D8E3F7F0DC4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Quarterly Reports</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this section, and every 3 months thereafter, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit a report to the Senate and the House of Representatives that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H059A5AF4E0A14C449E9AE7768D0D30E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>lists all the countries which refuse or unreasonably delay repatriation (as defined in subsection (b)); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H03D8AD5433454FE085D7BDD925FAFAEE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes the total number of aliens who were refused repatriation, organized by—</text> <subparagraph id="H92088E2ADAD74C779E96AF6088DD7B5C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>country;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BBAD07424F34BD59342B54C182CA39C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>detention status; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE6588619A814036B3B9D54B985361DE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>criminal status.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB42C2C25D4D14B2A8D936B37E9742E44"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Issuance of Travel Documents</header><text>If a country is listed in a report submitted under subsection (c), the country shall be subject to the sanctions described in subsection (a) and in section 243(d) of the Immigration and Nationality Act unless the country issues appropriate travel documents—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE85F6D85966647969FEBC2F716EB7644"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than 100 days after the submission of such report on behalf of all aliens described in subsection (a) who have been convicted of a crime committed while in the United States; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEBB616A6C2B241E4A544EACF211EE371"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 200 days after the submission of such report on behalf of all other aliens described in subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4B8EBAB9BCA6472980C38C95A505D612"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Standing</header><text>A victim or an immediate family member of a victim of a crime committed by any alien described in subsection (a) after such alien has been issued a final order of removal shall have standing to sue in any Federal district court to enforce the provisions of this section and the provisions of section 243(d) of the Immigration and Nationality Act. No monetary judgments may be awarded in a suit filed under this subsection.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="HA9DCE33F0F0940E0A8E8CCACC9024856"><enum>3.</enum><header>Discontinuing granting visas to nationals of country denying or delaying accepting aliens</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 243(d) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1253">8 U.S.C. 1253(d)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
			<quoted-block id="HF5F0FC19D06F4D6F9D090660C0810D49" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="HFBCD5EE0BFE1481BBEEBB1EEDFEF1306"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Discontinuing Granting Visas to Nationals of Country Denying or Delaying Accepting Aliens</header>
 <paragraph id="HDEA1261565874E0D8FCE6B7A35AD418C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a country is listed on the most recent report submitted by the Secretary of Homeland Security to Congress under section 137(c) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, no visa may be issued to or status under the immigration laws provided to a subject, national, or resident of such country unless the country is in full compliance with section 137(d) of such Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H17FB7869547C428EB710EDF96E79F675"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect of unauthorized issuance</header><text>Any visa issued or status provided in violation of this paragraph shall be null and void.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD21A9447D210483E88DD5E2D9F8E1A74"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Standing</header><text>A victim or an immediate family member of a victim of a crime committed by any alien described in section 137(a) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 after such alien has been issued a final order of removal shall have standing to sue in any Federal district court to enforce the provisions of this subsection. No monetary judgments may be awarded in a suit filed under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


