<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB3D37ECF9FE245A69B91C4FC03AF91D9" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3705 : Veterans Fair Debt Notice Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3705</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date date="20171109">November 9, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to require the use of certified mail and plain language
			 in certain debt collection activities.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H0AE655C42FAA4C31B9793FA870090FF2" style="OLC">
 <section id="H3E275064231348EEA2F1167FA1E5520A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Fair Debt Notice Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H63CB78607156492D8C9781123B9EFF39" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs notice relating to debt collection activities</header> <subsection id="HE3FEE8AC95D44769B3D8945BD0F71DAF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Debt notification letters</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall collaborate with veterans service organizations to write a standard letter to be provided to individuals who the Secretary determines owe debts to the Department of Veterans Affairs. Such letter shall be written in plain language and shall include a notice of the debt and a clear explanation of—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD2054E43DA9A4F87903F28BB172DBA83"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">why the individual owes money to the Department of Veterans Affairs; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBEBFF0DFB34A43D6A0CD98549F4353B7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the options available to the individual.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD28510190589478EACC7AFDB54716C00"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Delivery of letters</header><text>The Secretary shall develop a method by which individuals may elect to receive debt notification letters by electronic means and shall ensure, to the extent practicable, that the letter developed under subsection (a) is delivered to intended recipients who have made such an election by both standard mail and by electronic means and to intended recipients who have not made such an election only by standard mail.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HE8D4B9352D53483A9F12F8AC3E6AC026"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notice to Congress</header>
 <paragraph id="H93EAFAB7A85F4EC0B9812F00CC7675C4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice of completion</header><text>Upon completion of the letter required under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to Congress notice of the completion of the letter.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H45799F237F9248F29D42F3FA3F88B2F1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Progress reports</header><text>If the Secretary has not submitted the notice required by paragraph (1) by the date that is 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H620C2783BC044F8D87900F3FF6A0AD09"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit to Congress a report describing the progress of the Secretary toward implementing subsection (a) and an explanation for why the letter has not been completed; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1B84BADDCF242588587DCC875B6AA56"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">every 30 days thereafter until the submittal of the notice required by paragraph (1), submit to Congress an update to the report under subparagraph (A) that includes an additional explanation for the failure to complete the letter.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6C993231C22341508F3ADE7A3F980420"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Study; report</header>
 <paragraph id="HA0049B8983A04540862040712811CEFE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall conduct a study on the process by which the Department of Veterans Affairs notifies veterans of debt collection efforts. Such study shall include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9911BE2C13894C8587339D612D49F689"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an analysis of the scope of the problem of veterans not receiving debt collection notices;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08C16227B7674E7C8455F6F3F4DC5268"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of any non-legislative actions the Secretary could take to reduce the number of incorrect or unknown addresses of veterans in the databases of the Department and a timeline for adopting such actions; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H090D45EC77624C4E8DCB700F934ADFBE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an estimate of the costs associated with sending debt collection notices by certified mail.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0142CCDA2F2144EABABD24B17E5484E4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 12 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the study conducted under paragraph (1).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
	<attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20171108">Passed the House of Representatives November 8, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill>


