<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H3EB9E2B8408C4FDDBCFDC6CDAC37CB39" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3213 IH: To direct the Joint Committee on the Library to accept a statue depicting Pierre L’Enfant from the District of Columbia and to provide for the permanent display of the statue in the United States Capitol.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3213</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170712">July 12, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Joint Committee on the Library to accept a statue depicting Pierre L’Enfant from the
			 District of Columbia and to provide for the permanent display of the
			 statue in the United States Capitol.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HFE8A731385D9427FA60FA3BEB5A8010B" style="OLC">
 <section id="H9F323FCF657D4ED8941C7305150A9A2B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="H8BB10BA5FE194C8F9896D2F6B5A03632"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pierre L’Enfant was born in France in 1754, and traveled to the United States to serve with the United States in the Revolutionary War.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBE038E9B6ADF46AFAE8C3979B71C0AD8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Pierre L’Enfant was an engineer and architect, and in 1791 he developed the unique and exceptional design for the Nation’s capital that laid the framework for the modern-day District of Columbia that is followed and maintained until today.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBB0F226B02E147D997AD83F5E01F0030"><enum>(3)</enum><text>L’Enfant’s remarkable design envisioned a distinguishable Federal and residential city with diagonal streets propelling from Congress and the President’s home, beautiful boulevards on local streets and neighborhoods, and open spaces for monuments, memorials, and historical structures, all of which largely remain intact, protected as a historical treasure.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAAE30504FF0C4C5889EF197420429BC5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The United States Capitol does not currently appropriately recognize the contributions of Pierre L’Enfant.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H5CAFA14A94574A31998FD0DEB494C819"><enum>2.</enum><header>Acceptance of statue of Pierre L’Enfant for placement in United States Capitol</header>
 <subsection id="HB071DA242C9E4F229493F32E1DB4B452"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Acceptance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Joint Committee on the Library shall accept from the District of Columbia the donation of a statue depicting Pierre L’Enfant, subject to the terms and conditions that the Joint Committee considers appropriate.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF25F8767275A41DA998D63CBBA338BD2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Placement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Joint Committee shall place the statue accepted under subsection (a) in a suitable permanent location in the United States Capitol.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


