<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCDF848AD10684D2985F6528D79775A4E" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 274 IH: Modernizing Government Travel Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 274</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170104">January 4, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001073">Mr. Hurd</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001187">Mr. Meadows</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001286">Mrs. Bustos</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for reimbursement for the use of modern travel services by Federal employees traveling
			 on official Government business, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H37B45DCBF7024565952DCFD9F7BD49AE" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE3EE19CF8AE540F081E0C4EBC046A98E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Modernizing Government Travel Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HF5B5CEE0A1C24B07A9C32B4E7635094C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Federal employee reimbursement for use of modern travel services</header> <subsection id="HFCEEFC0E1EC64D59AB214CDABA55A9CB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of General Services shall prescribe regulations under section 5707 of title 5, United States Code, to provide for the reimbursement for the use of a transportation network company or innovative mobility technology company by any Federal employee traveling on official business under subchapter I of chapter 57 of such title, except that the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall prescribe such regulations with respect to employees of the judicial branch of the Government.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H830F5589A3C947679878BC745952BF63"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H2DF7B296FC484CC982056A682600410F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Innovative mobility technology company</header><text>The term <quote>innovative mobility technology company</quote> means an organization, including a corporation, limited liability company, partnership, sole proprietorship, or any other entity, that applies technology to expand and enhance available transportation choices, better manage demand for transportation services, and provide alternatives to driving alone.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H68961A6C0F914B14A55478E4292A653E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transportation network company</header><text>The term <quote>transportation network company</quote>—</text> <subparagraph id="HFB447D99C8FC444B9CBC570A5BE02101"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a corporation, partnership, sole proprietorship, or other entity, that uses a digital network to connect riders to drivers affiliated with the entity in order for the driver to transport the rider using a vehicle owned, leased, or otherwise authorized for use by the driver to a point chosen by the rider; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H891DACC09EC449A38F37E5BC45609605"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include a shared-expense carpool or vanpool arrangement that is not intended to generate profit for the driver.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF32D0E58359B4A1EA2FE67E1B7BB468C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report on transportation costs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5707(c) of title 5, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7CB2CB68F0054B4882D9F0E114AAC1BC" style="USC"> <subsection id="H9E122A0CE24D48BF8B8F8802CE6DD1A6"><enum>(c)</enum> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HBF8FA24689AB465F8135A7B982A385DC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than November 31 of each year, the head of each agency shall submit to the Administrator of the General Services, in a format prescribed by the Administrator and approved by the Director the Office of Management and Budget—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5F021B83FD1B44818483E7BD95A0950A" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">data on total agency payments for such items as travel and transportation of people, average costs and durations of trips, and purposes of official travel;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6943D6A057B8413D8C83C6C7830B0B0E" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">data on estimated total agency payments for employee relocation; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC375D47D6F3548A28B5669D3F2E0CA46" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of the total costs of transportation service by type, and the total number of trips utilizing each transportation type for purposes of official travel.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8AC55543F3304DC68EAD7681CB22345B" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the General Services shall make the data submitted pursuant to paragraph (1) publically available upon receipt.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC4520B57DA894C36A84230D49C67311C" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than January 31 of each year, the Administrator of the General Services shall submit to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Homeland Security and Government Affairs of the Senate—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H68C93CCC420A4A9EA23705F9D0A13650"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of the data submitted pursuant to paragraph (1) for the agencies listed in section 901(b) of title 31 and a survey of such data for each other agency; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3702E09E7AA140558735C4DD7BC9BBE5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of any new regulations promulgated or changes to existing regulations authorized under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


