<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H8181606AD4F544F19D46782D0DC9E596" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1867 IH: Alaska Native Veterans Land Allotment Equity Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1867</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170403">April 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young of Alaska</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act to provide for equitable allotment of land to
			 Alaska Native veterans.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H265E08616E0D44ABB2964A5A4023728E" style="OLC">
 <section id="HAB9C052E6C944E98BBF42939D97B7124" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Alaska Native Veterans Land Allotment Equity Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HE1EB0CD0CA3A4098AACCA790C87B9F4E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Open season for certain Alaska native veterans for allotments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 41 of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1629g">43 U.S.C. 1629g</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H443590F617024FB584E55E686EC1BE42"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="HB77F3851DB3D402CAB648FB6FFA14EA6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">In General</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Alaska Native Veteran Allotments</header-in-text></quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D3182AC262B4B44B1507989C0BB314D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking paragraphs (1) through (4) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HB41C523C775B4366A55D86F3DCE9F04F" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H4E737FEE35B54C48A33A70A64D11EB8A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Allotments</header> <subparagraph id="HCE8FAC0380B34AB48751088BE3C01FA4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Eligible recipients</header><text>Any person described in paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (b) shall be eligible to receive an allotment under the Act of May 17, 1906 (34 Stat. 197, chapter 2469) (as in effect before December 18, 1971), of not more than 2 parcels of Federal land, the total area of which shall not exceed 160 acres. Any person described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (b) who, prior to the date on which the Secretary promulgates regulations pursuant to section 3 of the Alaska Native Veterans Land Allotment Equity Act, received an allotment that has a total area of less than 160 acres shall be eligible to receive an allotment under the Act of May 17, 1906 (34 Stat. 197, chapter 2469) (as in effect before December 18, 1971), of not more than 1 parcel of Federal land, the total area of which shall not exceed the difference in acres between 160 acres and the total area of the allotment that the person previously received under the Act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H11D5EA7A046140F38F1C961CFA362736"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>The civil action styled <quote>Shields v. United States</quote> (698 F.2d 987 (9th Cir. 1983), cert. denied (104 S. Ct. 73 (1983))) shall not be construed to diminish or modify the eligibility of any person described in paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (b).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0031472C0B344DC2B682E3FA9183E369"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Filing deadline</header><text>An allotment shall be filed for an eligible recipient not later than 3 years after the date on which the Secretary promulgates regulations pursuant to section 3 of the Alaska Native Veterans Land Allotment Equity Act.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H81609105307045AEA50F50514C42BA98"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Land available for allotments</header>
 <subparagraph id="HB73D050A461C49ECA69ABF617A38A78C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (C), an allotment under this section shall be selected from land that is—</text> <clause id="HAC1455FFA7174806AFC04C1E37E62757"><enum>(i)</enum> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0C3B96872A424F6F8F94ACFDF7D95AB5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>vacant; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H210DD797F9044E1C8814FF33475504CB" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>owned by the United States;</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H438927A7C83640D2ACF42B1F47FE1F91"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>selected by, or conveyed to, the State of Alaska, if the State voluntarily relinquishes or conveys to the United States the land for the allotment; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCD560425362B4DEA82C98F1A777C5318"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>selected by, or conveyed to, a Native Corporation, if the Native Corporation voluntarily relinquishes or conveys to the United States the land for the allotment.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BD35FAFE31D45C89A25FD76674A5F97"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Relinquishment by native corporation</header><text>If a Native Corporation relinquishes land under subparagraph (A)(iii), the Native Corporation may select appropriate Federal land, as determined by the Secretary, the area of which is equal to the area of the land relinquished by the Native Corporation, to replace the relinquished land.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8182587EC191460B9971FFAF194BB3AD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>An allotment under this section shall not be selected from land that is located within—</text> <clause id="H2D8E6DB51EEF4BD5B02E17A94FA5B3FD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a right-of-way of the TransAlaska Pipeline;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA7C03B814176407B9AB3CB435AD93682"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an inner or outer corridor of such a right-of-way; or</text> </clause><clause id="HC726DB005380485ABCEE28D3F5C33ACF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a unit of the National Park System, a National Preserve, or a National Monument.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7D552514D9F24E10BE1CFC5F05055BF7"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>The civil action styled <quote>Shields v. United States</quote> (698 F.2d 987 (9th Cir. 1983), cert. denied (104 S. Ct. 73 (1983))) shall not be construed to limit the land that is eligible for allotment under this paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H816F8CBCF97D44EA94BDDAEFD1FF00F4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Alternative allotments</header><text>A person described in paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (b) who qualifies for an allotment under this section on land described in paragraph (2)(C) may select an alternative allotment from land that is—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4D91302BD78145A69E0F139F6B2FB747"><enum>(A)</enum><text>located within the boundaries of land described in paragraph (2)(C);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H40ACFFCAA67141DCAF26F331D7E57BA8"><enum>(B)</enum> <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H5815FE4A499D4B98B27E989BAD1DA39A"><enum>(i)</enum> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HAAB97D280BC74CB5AB7989CE6FB8C4A4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>withdrawn under section 11(a)(1)(C); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA9238E505F7943158FE9199B996ABD6F" indent="up2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>not selected, or relinquished after selection, under section 11(a)(3);</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HAC46F13A3AAE43248389F84DB79A6035" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>contiguous to an outer boundary of land withdrawn under section 11(a)(1)(C); or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5A5474BD2D7B4735B979657F78ED05F3" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>vacant, unappropriated, and unreserved; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2AE9E228D0DF4F448BFD3103C5AFDFEA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not a unit of the National Park System, a National Preserve, or a National Monument.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H257DA3516B84452DB82D1FA2168D435F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (5) and (6) as paragraphs (4) and (5), respectively;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3F6F6CEBBA84069981EB98CA6EFE360"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3851E1E0BCA8400886CCA104CA9EB362"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking subparagraph (B) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HD4D17581DB664C3D91220D9E76970D2C" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H139E92CC4C46488FAF20D00C7658412B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is a veteran who served during the period beginning on August 5, 1964, and ending on May 7, 1975.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H908B3C8831714F98B257075A612AF752"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HD2BC1157C5A043839AE67CE905699C8F" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HB43B81318478414C832A762AFE53F848"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deceased persons</header><text>If an individual who would otherwise have been eligible for an allotment under this section dies before applying for an allotment, an heir of the person may apply for, and receive, an allotment under this section, on behalf of the estate of the person.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H91D5B0E461FD484C96402C20305D072F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (3) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H04D85D87087D4D26BDB5A3393A897671" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H8535A74A69A046F7846EA3ECB85D17C2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>No person who received an allotment or has a pending allotment under the Act of May 17, 1906, may receive an allotment under this section, other than—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H34C6945968834A9390E598125DC63B7E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an heir who applies for, and receives, an allotment on behalf of the estate of a deceased person under paragraph (2); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H842B6FF5FEC94902BEC532F81328189D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a person who, prior to the date on which the Secretary promulgates regulations pursuant to section 3 of the Alaska Native Veterans Land Allotment Equity Act, received an allotment under the Act of May 17, 1906 (34 Stat. 197, chapter 2469), that has a total area of less than 160 acres.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H31C7EEB29C7E4F8B9B5178C3CC90CC0D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (d) and (e) as subsections (f) and (g), respectively;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H415AE3650C1E4AF58669C3FFC197AB10"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (c) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H48413A32590C4C94AC75F2BEC326E5E2" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H146C3282CF7A4F08A4DEEBE7CE841EB3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Approval of allotments</header>
 <paragraph id="H39D2CBE4DBCD46EDB4850939A47668CE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to any valid right in existence on the date of enactment of the Alaska Native Veterans Land Allotment Equity Act, and except as provided in paragraph (3), not later than 5 years after the date of the enactment of the Alaska Native Veterans Land Allotment Equity Act, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2E0BD394DFCA4C9A91AEB44F8EFF3C9E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>approve any application for an allotment filed in accordance with subsection (a); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5B4F36BE8FC4EB5B5618D34545AE9B2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>issue a certificate of allotment under such terms, conditions, and restrictions as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C98AF842EA1479594A318B333294E03"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of the Alaska Native Veterans Land Allotment Equity Act, on receipt of an application for an allotment under this section, the Secretary shall provide to any person or entity that has an interest in land described in subsection (a)(2) that is potentially adverse to the interest of the applicant a notice of the right of the person or entity, by not later than 90 days after the date of receipt of the notice—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H845453CD275A4947A58FB8637BAECE7D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to initiate a private contest of the allotment; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83173D724343437B98E0EC8943E8993F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to file a protest against the allotment in accordance with procedures established by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE761F56BBFB4482ABE9930FBB23B4A83"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Action by secretary</header><text>If a private contest or protest relating to an application for an allotment is initiated or filed under paragraph (2), the Secretary shall not issue a certificate for the allotment under paragraph (1)(B) until a final determination has been made with respect to the private contest or protest.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H66C639EB41BA4918AD12F104CA4F8ADE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reselection</header><text>A person that selected an allotment under this section may withdraw that selection and reselect land in accordance with this section after the date of enactment of the Alaska Native Veterans Land Allotment Equity Act, if the land originally selected—</text>
 <paragraph id="H05872AF7B3F848CEB5E56B615517675E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>was selected before the date of enactment of the Alaska Native Veterans Land Allotment Equity Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3AD7D007A61C469A90827E8061120BD2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>as of the date of enactment of that Act, was not conveyed to the person.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1D349AFBD3B545DB9197DBCE600D07CA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by striking subsection (f), as designated by paragraph (3) and inserting:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HA52621A4096344EE914EC4E5A00E69C8" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H7C259E0736E64AAF9F4304D02F3F6A73"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For the purposes of this section:</text> <paragraph id="H03430FE546964BE4A534A908341F5E4F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>veteran</quote> means a person who served in the active military, naval, or air service, and who was discharged or released therefrom.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H275520BDFA4442B79A34104BDBF9A5BD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>Vietnam era</quote> has the meaning given the term by paragraph (29) of section 101 of title 38.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></section><section id="H847EA86BE98042158AD7BE76FF0B0B7E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior shall promulgate, after consultation with Alaska Native organizations, final regulations to carry out the amendments made by section 2. During the consultation process, the Secretary shall, in coordination with Alaska Native organizations and to the greatest extent possible, identify persons who are eligible to receive an allotment under the amendments made by section 2. Upon promulgation of the final regulations, the Secretary shall contact each of these persons directly to provide an explanation of the process by which the person may apply for an allotment under the amendments made by section 2.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


