<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H0EA3E177721D47459E6CBFD1A1AE0E44" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4193 IH: To deauthorize a portion of the project for navigation, Milwaukee Harbor, Milwaukee, Wisconsin.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4193</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171031">October 31, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To deauthorize a portion of the project for navigation, Milwaukee Harbor, Milwaukee, Wisconsin.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HBDA41B969F384705A96D1E23FA2D5F55" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE2FF1C8495E64584A08C4D8E6B02A5A0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Project for navigation, Milwaukee Harbor, Milwaukee, Wisconsin</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The portion of the project for navigation, Milwaukee Harbor, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, authorized by the first section of the Act of March 3, 1843 (5 Stat. 619; chapter 85), consisting of the navigation channel within the Menomonee River that extends from the 16th Street Bridge upstream to the upper limit of the authorized navigation channel and described as follows is no longer authorized beginning on the date of enactment of this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="HC4A63022E19E4C4FB3DF811234D09BA8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Beginning at a point in the channel just downstream of the 16th Street Bridge, N383219.703, E2521152.527.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD8E7E592D60245B08BF39B90D0BCD159"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Thence running westerly along the channel about 2,530.2 feet to a point, N383161.314, E2518620.712.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAA51CEDD388B495DAF092AD4A17446CE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Thence running westerly by southwesterly along the channel about 591.7 feet to a point at the upstream limit of the existing project, N383080.126, E2518036.371.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H07272A7989074998BEE56F0CB60D2086"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Thence running northerly along the upstream limit of the existing project about 80.5 feet to a point, N383159.359, E2518025.363.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5CDBEA58D025446196ADA560DEDC44BD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Thence running easterly by northeasterly along the channel about 551.2 feet to a point, N383235.185, E2518571.108.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB4A661DD90354B83886C45F3D51E11D1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Thence running easterly along the channel about 2,578.9 feet to a point, N383294.677, E2521150.798.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H72621986AA9F48FBBF0632AFEC156C53"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Thence running southerly across the channel about 74.3 feet to the point of origin.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


