<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HAC4A3527820744A7AE0979B95EB31FB4" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2420 IH: To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for tax preferred savings accounts for individuals under age 26, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2420</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170511">May 11, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for tax preferred savings accounts for
			 individuals under age 26, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HFE68B96C73D64EB5B56F8BBEE72A6CAD" style="OLC">
		<section id="HEEC348C9EEC74A9E943C6A91526D11AA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Young savers accounts</header>
			<subsection id="H5C138556BDCF44C793D7CF44BED17ABE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of accounts</header>
 <paragraph id="HF32B9A5372F44D5A9D97ED31B4A0BF6B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/408A">Section 408A</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (relating to Roth IRAs) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA98D0B05C6CE42D4A76B795FB9DFEDC0" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="HC5367AB8BEE9434A98286DFDF742B7F0"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Young savers account</header>
 <paragraph id="H352E048F933E487BB3DD437D56E7B08A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in this subsection, a young savers account shall be treated in the same manner as a Roth IRA.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H37A5DCBEB3AE4EE4B79C513FD19D1EE8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Young savers account</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>young savers account</quote> means, with respect to any taxable year, a Roth IRA which is established and maintained on behalf of an individual who has not attained age 26 before the close of the taxable year.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="HFB2997D3AF574F669B475D105843706A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contribution limits</header>
 <subparagraph id="HF14D16FBEAE54872B8B9F0F45FDE17E6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Limit on accounts with respect to individual</header><text>In the case of any contributions for any taxable year to one or more young savers accounts established and maintained on behalf of an individual, the amount determined with respect to such individual under subsection (c)(2)(A) shall be treated as the amount in effect for the taxable year under section 219(b)(5) (determined without regard to subparagraph (B) thereof).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0FCEEFB56EEB4D569F03C0A5B5CA5A0E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limit on contributors</header><text>The aggregate amount of qualified young saver contributions an individual may make for any taxable year to all young savers accounts shall not exceed the deductible amount in effect for the taxable year under section 219(b)(5) (determined without regard to subparagraph (B) thereof).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD56CC3EA2B7B48ED92E30D025961AAFC"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Special rule for recontribution of amount distributed for higher education expenses</header><text>In the case of a young savers account from which an individual receives a distribution to which section 72(t)(2)(E) applies (or would have applied had such distribution been includible in gross income), subparagraphs (A) and (B) shall not apply to any contribution made by such individual to a Roth IRA of such individual (and there shall not be taken into account under subsection (c)(2) any such contribution) to the extent such contribution does not exceed the excess (if any) of—</text>
 <clause id="HCB18A606BD464502995D3422BBADCF07"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the aggregate amount of such distributions made during the 20-year period ending on the date of the contribution to which this subparagraph is applied, over</text>
 </clause><clause id="H08B38F2456404D9BB794959CE29AAD66"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the aggregate amount of contributions to which this subparagraph applies for all taxable years.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB03CA0393104D0E9116D6B31DF32571"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Qualified contributions</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>qualified young saver contribution</quote> means a contribution by an individual (with respect to whom a young savers account is not established and maintained during the taxable year) to a young savers account established and maintained on behalf of another individual.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2AD14167B3B14B02A5E419B6C1B44F31"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2017.</text> </subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

