<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE2555A2E157547BBB6672BD5CA8BFC1A" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4648 IH: Home Mortgage Reporting Relief Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4648</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171214">December 14, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000294">Mr. Emmer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001059">Mr. Hultgren</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To delay the effective date of certain regulations relating to home mortgage disclosures, to
			 suspend certain data sharing requirements, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H6954C218F7C5428896599DBC96449ECD" style="OLC">
 <section id="H69619607CBC8447CB81A5ED5AB8F6653" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Home Mortgage Reporting Relief Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H5FB905A9C24F4367B358792AA5FD7F58"><enum>2.</enum><header>Delayed effective date of amendments to regulation relating to home mortgage disclosure</header> <subsection id="HBD9F91D80EAA437B9EA01F151D5DDB9F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Compilation of reportable data</header><text>Compliance with the amendments made to section 1003.4 of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations, by the final rule issued by the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection entitled <quote>Home Mortgage Disclosure (Regulation C)</quote> (80 Fed. Reg. 66310 (October 28, 2015)) and the final rule issued by the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection entitled <quote>Home Mortgage Disclosure (Regulation C)</quote> (82 Fed. Reg. 43132 (September 13, 2017)) prior to January 1, 2019, may not serve as the basis of a supervisory or enforcement action taken against any depository institution, and no suit may be filed against any depository institution for a violation of such requirements occurring before such date.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6FA605932C854863A577B577A8DC3934"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Compliance with the amendments made to section 1003.5 of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations, by the final rules described in subsection (a) prior to January 1, 2020, may not serve as the basis of a supervisory or enforcement action taken against any depository institution, and no suit may be filed against any depository institution for a violation of such requirements occurring before such date.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H9045592E0E864754B990DB7781F88D64"><enum>3.</enum><header>Suspension of data sharing requirements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, including the final rules described in section 1—</text> <paragraph id="H6D32472C7CA84B1CA7B0177237BFC65E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">depository institutions shall not be required to publish, disclose, or otherwise make available to the public, pursuant to the Home Mortgage Disclosure Act of 1975 (or regulations issued under such Act) any data, other than data that will be compiled in aggregate form as described under section 310 of such Act, that was not required to be published, disclosed, or otherwise made available pursuant to such Act (or regulations issued under such Act) on the day before the date of the enactment of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD515BBFB903D45B492EB9E2C589609F1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection and the Financial Institutions Examination Council shall not publish, disclose, or otherwise make available to the public any data received from depository institutions pursuant to the Home Mortgage Disclosure Act of 1975 (or regulations issued under such Act), other than data that will be compiled in aggregate form as described under section 310 of such Act, that was not required to be reported by depository institutions on the day before the date of the enactment of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HF6D14CF7AFB445B7B067E9EED182ECD7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Depository institution defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act, the term <quote>depository institution</quote> has the meaning given such term under section 303 of the Home Mortgage Disclosure Act of 1975 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/2802">12 U.S.C. 2802</external-xref>).</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


