<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE734EAB3DD1345C7B48667A86FC9FA87" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2851 IH: SITSA Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2851</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170608">June 8, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000602">Miss Rice of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000289">Mr. Goodlatte</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000566">Mr. Gowdy</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Controlled Substances Act to clarify how controlled substance analogues are to be
			 regulated, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HEDAB63B4A4294EFE8B08DAF903449B13" style="OLC">
 <section id="H44629E324E594296A3998D07891BE6B3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop the Importation and Trafficking of Synthetic Analogues Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote>SITSA Act</quote>.</text> </section><section id="H45EB2A8FA42445B395D75098E6EC5C96"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of Schedule A</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 202 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/812">21 U.S.C. 812</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H63D7D0940F30432A9A4846E1A4DBC875"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>five schedules of controlled substances, to be known as schedules I, II, III, IV, and V</quote> and inserting <quote>six schedules of controlled substances, to be known as schedules I, II, III, IV, V, and A</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC4266117344142DB8D7479F57A82E70D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HADAA09F08FEA4FE583976868C807C1AB" style="OLC">
					<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H13BD56CCD4E4452E9F9E5EAF0F9F81FD" indent="up1"><enum>(6)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Schedule A</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9555F902374D4AE4968B85508F00E059"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The drug or substance—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0CA970ED24F946BD93EADF0F08F87B77"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3BE004E2A6F840A287A8EFC402643E8F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a chemical structure that is substantially similar to the chemical structure of a controlled substance in schedule I, II, III, IV, or V; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H786BED8FE72F42C7AD173BA567BE6988"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an actual or predicted stimulant, depressant, or hallucinogenic effect on the central nervous system that is substantially similar to or greater than the stimulant, depressant, or hallucinogenic effect on the central nervous system of a controlled substance in schedule I, II, III, IV, or V; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB57A34958BA74AEFAD6629FD9D29CADD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is not—</text> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2AE030657BC449D58859C900FC0BC840"><enum>(I)</enum><text>listed or otherwise included in any other schedule in this section or by regulation of the Attorney General; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H520ACE5ABEC44F30ADF19AD7C77CD2CB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>with respect to a particular person, subject to an exemption that is in effect for investigational use, for that person, under section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355</external-xref>) to the extent conduct with respect to such substance is pursuant to such exemption.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA2C6FB6A5585412FB8252BF04CEF72EC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Predicted stimulant, depressant, or hallucinogenic effect</header><text>For purpose of this paragraph, a predicted stimulant, depressant, or hallucinogenic effect on the central nervous system may be based on—</text>
 <clause id="HAFDFD0DC6EEE4E1C97E88BCDB80ED745"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the chemical structure, structure activity relationships, binding receptor assays, or other relevant scientific information about the substance;</text>
							</clause><clause id="H2A78075CAE584524AAA235CDEC63EF4E"><enum>(ii)</enum>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H6AEEF2A844284837840A8028AE33A056"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the current or relative potential for abuse of the substance; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HE2E89C678DCA43569B1235D319E50F00" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the clandestine importation, manufacture, or distribution, or diversion from legitimate channels, of the substance; or</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H3045D615755F42E0A82BDAFDB459E3F2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the capacity of the substance to cause a state of dependence, including physical or psychological dependence that is similar to or greater than that of a controlled substance in schedule I, II, III, IV, or V.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HABF73FB5BB31452A8F585E5E5CE006B5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text> <subparagraph id="HF55E40D6D90D4E758A26D9CAB547B9DE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding schedule I, by striking <quote>IV, and V</quote> and inserting <quote>IV, V, and A</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7C8EFDA78AE4F46A4A4AF3087D352FC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBB28959183BB47E89A2CAA00D82CB7C3" style="traditional"> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD8970F38435043EB8951D967B3305829" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><header>Schedule A</header><text>(a) Unless specifically excepted or unless listed in another schedule, any of the following substances, as scheduled in accordance with section 201(k)(5):</text>
 <paragraph id="H4CA34F34F33D4E9585CF86F66DC2C218"><enum>(1)</enum><text>4-fluoroisobutyryl fentanyl.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6A50D935195C425A9EC8DDA0218800FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Valeryl fentanyl.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9B318C6A4483485E933C5568455AFE05"><enum>(3)</enum><text>4-methoxybutyryl fentanyl.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2E272DE1100F4F708BF1AD471AEC8E48"><enum>(4)</enum><text>4-methylphenethyl acetyl fentanyl.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA670AB5350584B3B96F00D7BA2F2E5FD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>3-furanyl fentanyl.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFDC0997DC72744CF9AD3182FBEC11C0C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Ortho-fluorofentanyl.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H27F7FC937EC0466B94F340EBF5B96742"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Tetrahydrofuranyl fentanyl.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6BE3191F2236461685CF2C400653B0AD"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Ocfentanil.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0124DFF543DE4B52BC715DA1DD63B1C4"><enum>(9)</enum><text>4-fluorobutyryl fentanyl.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H90EC203F889243B5A87E71C766BBA68C"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Methoxyacetyl fentanyl.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB2F3F8E7984F49CBB957D402FBB5431E"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Meta-fluorofentanyl.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H25B076E2F5F24520ADBB8AA26BE48C52"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Isobutyryl fentanyl.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB40498D55D9748F1AA3CCA343A6DE117"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Acryl fentanyl.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HA8EF66C8E1004201B5CF9854E970B0A7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Temporary and permanent scheduling of schedule A substances</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 201 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/811">21 U.S.C. 811</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H226E3AEB8EDD46D1897E5024768A447C" style="traditional">
				<subsection id="H0311D17F212F467B926C2A7510137B47"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Temporary and permanent scheduling of schedule A substances</header>
 <paragraph id="HD7AB10D142A14CABB2C4A63FE44FFE65"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Attorney General may issue a temporary order adding a drug or substance to schedule A if the Attorney General finds that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5734810487D7491BBC0D43C2A99208FC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the drug or other substance satisfies the criteria for being considered a schedule A substance; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0310BC6880964518827A05AA578991DF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>adding such drug or substance to schedule A will assist in preventing abuse or misuse of the drug or other substance.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F579102116242718A47990F12EB5E35"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A temporary scheduling order issued under paragraph (1) shall not take effect until 30 days after the date of the publication by the Attorney General of a notice in the Federal Register of the intention to issue such order and the grounds upon which such order is to be issued. The temporary scheduling order shall expire not later than 5 years after the date it becomes effective, except that the Attorney General may, during the pendency of proceedings under paragraph (5), extend the temporary scheduling order for up to 180 days.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEBEC67764B78432196050CB00D7AAD05"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A temporary scheduling order issued under paragraph (1) shall be vacated upon the issuance of a permanent order issued under paragraph (5) with regard to the same substance, or upon the subsequent issuance of any scheduling order under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HAFBE16A730414A3AA5550141C97002B6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A temporary scheduling order issued under paragraph (1) shall not be subject to judicial review.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF9183D2A4634496E841D819B2E9CABC0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Attorney General may, by rule, issue a permanent order adding a drug or other substance to schedule A if such drug or substance satisfies the criteria for being considered a schedule A substance. Such rulemaking may be commenced simultaneously with the issuance of the temporary scheduling order issued under paragraph (1) with regard to the same substance.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7E8FDC74B02C4198B33661A4DD28C9AD"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Before initiating proceedings under paragraph (1) or (5), the Attorney General shall transmit notice of an order proposed to be issued to the Secretary of Health and Human Services. In issuing an order under paragraph (1) or (5), the Attorney General shall take into consideration any comments submitted by the Secretary of Health and Human Services in response to a notice transmitted pursuant to this paragraph.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section commented="no" id="H08B67F24905944BAA352D8E65A18A75B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Penalties</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="HCDE2870AA0BB4F458E75C00FB1CE18B9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Controlled Substances Act</header><text>The Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/801">21 U.S.C. 801</external-xref> et seq.) is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HFC0DBF2618CA401E9A3E620CC1BAFCDD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 401(b)(1) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/841">21 U.S.C. 841(b)(1)</external-xref>), by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA6FEC829A3FD478EA4D1562F5C19432F" style="OLC">
						<subparagraph id="H4142463B61C04223B54CCE43C5E2180E" indent="up2"><enum>(F)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD6397EDC41E447B892F054087B2EE6EC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>In the case of any controlled substance in schedule A, such person shall be sentenced to a term of imprisonment of not more than 10 years and if death or serious bodily injury results from the use of such substance shall be sentenced to a term of imprisonment of not more than 15 years, a fine not to exceed the greater of that authorized in accordance with the provisions of title 18, United States Code, or $500,000 if the defendant is an individual or $2,500,000 if the defendant is other than an individual, or both.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD74DDAC1866748328ED2F630B90F7F92" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>If any person commits such a violation after a prior conviction for a felony drug offense has become final, such person shall be sentenced to a term of imprisonment of not more than 20 years and if death or serious bodily injury results from the use of such substance shall be sentenced to a term of imprisonment of not more than 30 years, a fine not to exceed the greater of twice that authorized in accordance with the provisions of title 18, United States Code, or $1,000,000 if the defendant is an individual or $5,000,000 if the defendant is other than an individual, or both.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6D72AF66D1CD4601A068891F8072E6FB" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Any sentence imposing a term of imprisonment under this subparagraph shall, in the absence of such a prior conviction, impose a term of supervised release of not less than 2 years in addition to such term of imprisonment and shall, if there was such a prior conviction, impose a term of supervised release of not less than 4 years in addition to such term of imprisonment.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HAFC56B5FAD784508A8C1E7C1252312E9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 403(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/843">21 U.S.C. 843(a)</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HA95517ED56304882AE1885C4028DFFC2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (8), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H08C3C25C2D314DF9963F61357F08F0AA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (9), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4A5B9596605C4923BCF5E98F8B24F6DC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (9) the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD1A9D4F1B1F14EB0BEA9D0165C7DAE89" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HEAD362FD017E4F579932602C46FC6985"><enum>(10)</enum><text>to export a substance in violation of the controlled substance laws of the country to which the substance is exported.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H0643BE92858146C7BB51E9E1401F71DF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 404 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/844">21 U.S.C. 844</external-xref>), by inserting after subsection (a) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA5E6383940494321BABD4B93C15BE0C8" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H962FE300012B44D08243413409323333"><enum>(b)</enum><text>A person shall not be subject to a criminal or civil penalty under this title or under any other Federal law solely for possession of a schedule A controlled substance.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HBBADD8916EEB47F9B87F761B4AFCF843"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Controlled Substances Import and Export Act</header><text>Section 1010(b) of the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/960">21 U.S.C. 960(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2A88BC5000DC44098A8A5A78EE1989B7" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HFB536BA612D44D1AB030CA2C4627BA25" indent="up1"><enum>(8)</enum><text>In the case of a violation under subsection (a) involving a controlled substance in schedule A, the person committing such violation shall be sentenced to a term of imprisonment of not more than 20 years and if death or serious bodily injury results from the use of such substance shall be sentenced to a term of imprisonment of not less than 20 years and not more than life, a fine not to exceed the greater of that authorized in accordance with the provisions of title 18, United States Code, or $1,000,000 if the defendant is an individual or $5,000,000 if the defendant is other than an individual, or both. If any person commits such a violation after a prior conviction for a felony drug offense has become final, such person shall be sentenced to a term of imprisonment of not more than 30 years and if death or serious bodily injury results from the use of such substance shall be sentenced to life imprisonment, a fine not to exceed the greater of twice that authorized in accordance with the provisions of title 18, United States Code, or $2,000,000 if the defendant is an individual or $10,000,000 if the defendant is other than an individual, or both. Notwithstanding section 3583 of title 18, United States Code, any sentence imposing a term of imprisonment under this paragraph shall, in the absence of such a prior conviction, impose a term of supervised release of not less than 3 years in addition to such term of imprisonment and shall, if there was such a prior conviction, impose a term of supervised release of not less than 6 years in addition to such term of imprisonment. Notwithstanding the prior sentence, and notwithstanding any other provision of law, the court shall not place on probation or suspend the sentence of any person sentenced under the provisions of this paragraph which provide for a mandatory term of imprisonment if death or serious bodily injury results.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H78D78B6363AC4433AAFDE78E90FA4A8E"><enum>5.</enum><header>False labeling of schedule A controlled substances</header>
 <subsection id="H96F92DCE5AB54818BF8D6C73D61C8435"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 305 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/825">21 U.S.C. 825</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAAEB93500C6E417A9DCD881D6724513B" style="OLC">
					<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6A9C85DB20B742D4BF6A33CE83990BD6"><enum>(f)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">False labeling of schedule A controlled substances</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H72EE3353C6884B199A6F2B05624CE8EC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be unlawful to import, export, manufacture, distribute, dispense, or possess with intent to manufacture, distribute, or dispense, a schedule A substance or product containing a schedule A substance, unless the substance or product bears a label clearly identifying a schedule A substance or product containing a schedule A substance by the nomenclature used by the International Union of Pure and Applied Chemistry (IUPAC).</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H88AACC27D69E46718534282A1B5D67C9"><enum>(2)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0501107319B74098998042C1DCD37B5D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A product described in subparagraph (B) is exempt from the International Union of Pure and Applied Chemistry nomenclature requirement of this subsection if such product is labeled in the manner required under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC680BBCE623A4A07907F71F84CF60EA5" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A product is described in this subparagraph if the product—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HBF880E575750407C971594E9E2388ED0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is the subject of an approved application as described in section 505(b) or (j) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H73F254FDD66844B4A53BD9B314CFDBFA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is exempt from the provisions of section 505 of such Act relating to new drugs because—</text> <subclause commented="no" id="HA9CF1506B6794B399D3EF91957B9323D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>it is intended solely for investigational use as described in section 505(i) of such Act; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H8E84AA61647F4EE0B50E52157167F7D6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>such product is being used exclusively for purposes of a clinical trial that is the subject of an effective investigational new drug application.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1310DF7676204F8CB912631EB22F365D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>Section 402 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/842">21 U.S.C. 842</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H91001479DC6F4A6892B1205EE92B8D2E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(16), by inserting <quote>or subsection (f)</quote> after <quote>subsection (e)</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA0DF7C7DB1264C678C468709546B0E80"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(1)(D), by inserting <quote>or a schedule A substance</quote> after <quote>anabolic steroid</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H51248574964A44EBBA6DC12EABEF5628"><enum>6.</enum><header>Registration requirements for handlers of schedule A substances</header> <subsection id="H8DD4C83F18EA4728BA238B50274C54B7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Controlled Substances Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 303 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/823">21 U.S.C. 823</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H05A04EC2677443088B4ECEB4498267F3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (f), in the undesignated matter following paragraph (5)—</text> <subparagraph id="H24204ED38F2F431B9B1195AD73375766"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or A</quote> after <quote>schedule I</quote> each place it appears; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9458BFE32EE49009ADB3367C96F3A88"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: <quote>A separate registration for engaging in research with a controlled substance in schedule A for practitioners already registered under this part to engage in research with controlled substances in schedule I shall not be required. The Secretary shall determine the merits of the research protocol submitted by the practitioner registering to engage in research with a controlled substance in schedule A, and the Attorney General may deny or revoke the registration only on a ground specified in section 304.</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA67658E5E014C9381FC26FCD27C41CD"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFFD0B4528BE247E09E51E2C3C7BCC3D2" style="OLC"> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H294D4F50BA8041EC9921C7EAA3A97E88"><enum>(k)</enum> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H2982587DD2E74CDE948AFD71C9D8D63F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall register an applicant to manufacture schedule A substances if—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H29405C6867784219AD2F8C355629B7B6" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the applicant demonstrates that the schedule A substances will be used for research, analytical, or industrial purposes approved by the Attorney General; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HED8A3B2A077B4DE893529C154AF8DF8B" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Attorney General determines that such registration is consistent with the public interest and with the United States obligations under international treaties, conventions, or protocols in effect on the date of enactment of this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE7ABD4DD2C254F03967660510DDF92F9" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining the public interest under paragraph (1)(B), the Attorney General shall consider—</text> <subparagraph id="HB4E32D155B5D44E0A5ECC46A7642E3A8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>maintenance of effective controls against diversion of particular controlled substances and any controlled substance in schedule A compounded therefrom into other than legitimate medical, scientific, research, or industrial channels, by limiting the importation and bulk manufacture of such controlled substances to a number of establishments which can produce an adequate and uninterrupted supply of these substances under adequately competitive conditions for legitimate medical, scientific, research, and industrial purposes;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82A3BB2237E84E15B7ABFDB6783A0F20"><enum>(B)</enum><text>compliance with applicable State and local law;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3467159120D4441F8F2CA69D4682099F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>promotion of technical advances in the art of manufacturing substances described in subparagraph (A) and the development of new substances;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H867573DB4E84489A9330A98D6E46DF25"><enum>(D)</enum><text>prior conviction record of applicant under Federal and State laws relating to the manufacture, distribution, or dispensing of substances described in paragraph (A);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9BD983340D0B419C87F1E5C9DA2838DA"><enum>(E)</enum><text>past experience in the manufacture of controlled substances, and the existence in the establishment of effective control against diversion; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9FE79FE86E0541C980C49AD6D37EBC94"><enum>(F)</enum><text>such other factors as may be relevant to and consistent with the public health and safety.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F4B3CFA55B04D8C9996A4110985907F" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>If an applicant is registered to manufacture controlled substances in schedule I or II under subsection (a), the applicant shall not be required to apply for a separate registration under this subsection.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFF2E784725244003BC442EA2CD1436DD"><enum>(l)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE07C2BADDFD2408D97FDAB46E96B70C8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall register an applicant to distribute schedule A substances—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8CB8C8A56C844B8589A4257C5EDFF56E" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if the applicant demonstrates that the schedule A substances will be used for research, analytical, or industrial purposes approved by the Attorney General; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9BDB9D4F5652463A890554BCCBF88AA9" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">unless the Attorney General determines that the issuance of such registration is inconsistent with the public interest.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCCC44A911C774278869CC109C54A9CF3" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining the public interest under paragraph (1)(B), the Attorney General shall consider—</text> <subparagraph id="HD70AAAAE682243C5B00BE9CC95E4D9E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>maintenance of effective control against diversion of particular controlled substances into other than legitimate medical, scientific, and industrial channels;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A410F82BCB840DAB58F9C2B988D15EE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>compliance with applicable State and local law;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H59CF70BE3A9A42A4838F78F6C9E053EE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>prior conviction record of applicant under Federal or State laws relating to the manufacture, distribution, or dispensing of substances described in subparagraph (A);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H15D1EDA2EC5441E1AB79C587B43C31E4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>past experience in the distribution of controlled substances; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC367114FD284EA48BA477530F95AC3A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>such other factors as may be relevant to and consistent with the public health and safety.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF187097394F467AA74BECA50584B0D0" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>If an applicant is registered to distribute a controlled substance in schedule I or II under subsection (b), the applicant shall not be required to apply for a separate registration under this subsection.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HB6DE26221B4E410D9B1AF2E90347C749"><enum>(m)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H9E5D249A79614535B4281AD68E354E38"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Not later than 90 days after the date on which a substance is placed in schedule A, any practitioner who was engaged in research on the substance before the placement of the substance in schedule A and any manufacturer or distributor who was handling the substance before the placement of the substance in schedule A shall register with the Attorney General.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H74D009DF931940C19E693E350F36660E" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H92105A062183474AA837685D6017AC63"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Not later than 60 days after the date on which the Attorney General receives an application for registration to conduct research on a schedule A substance, the Attorney General shall—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H8A96B6EFF5334F3DA9C5E6EF961B4CBF" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>grant, or initiate proceedings under section 304(c) to deny, the application; or</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HE7623BF20DF64D79BA9B1C2763A753AA" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>request supplemental information from the applicant.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5496261F857D44A3A84E39CC47106DA1" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Attorney General receives supplemental information requested under subparagraph (A)(ii) in connection with an application described in subparagraph (A), the Attorney General shall grant or deny the application.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC7FF68D8BB7D481BA7D4E17DB822879A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Controlled Substances Import and Export Act</header><text>Section 1008 of the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/958">21 U.S.C. 958</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA11D2FA51FEE45A58B5383029FF99618" style="OLC">
					<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8BB076558F6448C3947E920FA29F1191"><enum>(j)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H351A65B0CEA3490298610C3043D61949"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall register an applicant to import or export a schedule A substance if—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD110F54972F14FE89F59000755BA96AA" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the applicant demonstrates that the schedule A substances will be used for research, analytical, or industrial purposes approved by the Attorney General; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H835EBF0569454910B046A6FEAA16F5E8" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Attorney General determines that such registration is consistent with the public interest and with the United States obligations under international treaties, conventions, or protocols in effect on the date of enactment of this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H389B351C150D4B2CA697002AA16F9721" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining the public interest under paragraph (1)(B), the Attorney General shall consider the factors described in subparagraphs (A) through (F) of section 303(k)(2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2CCF279FBB6E4E96889F5283A1B6963C" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>If an applicant is registered to import or export a controlled substance in schedule I or II under subsection (a), the applicant shall not be required to apply for a separate registration under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H955339D5EF9D4A7D94C1BB75ADCEE203"><enum>7.</enum><header>Additional conforming amendments</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H9686790544564FD9B185D35E2EEB6892"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Controlled Substances Act</header><text>The Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/801">21 U.S.C. 801</external-xref> et seq.) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H86147B4D56A84C3E8CA08C1834645EF9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 303(c) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/823">21 U.S.C. 823(c)</external-xref>)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H294C54E79FCA4AA586C8F091C8333220"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subsections (a) and (b)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (a), (b), (k), or (l)</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8329535CE304D11B93DCD866469AE47"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>schedule I or II</quote> and inserting <quote>schedule I, II, or A</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB513E0746A7B4900B006421ADF95CA78"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 306 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/826">21 U.S.C. 826</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph id="H806B190F81DD41E5935BC58B99940F22"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), in the first sentence, by striking <quote>schedules I and II</quote> and inserting <quote>schedules I, II, and A</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A252F8799A546B4BB7E5A335C0638DE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b), in the second sentence, by striking <quote>schedule I or II</quote> and inserting <quote>schedule I, II, or A</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H286D18803FFB45D8937EB3CC5AC8153B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (c), in the first sentence, by striking <quote>schedules I and II</quote> and inserting <quote>schedules I, II, and A</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CC69E572A534B8ABF7CAE8EC8C2EBE0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subsection (d), in the first sentence, by striking <quote>schedule I or II</quote> and inserting <quote>schedule I, II, or A</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB29011ACCC24C579FCF6407AF5C0118"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in subsection (e), in the first sentence, by striking <quote>schedule I or II</quote> and inserting <quote>schedule I, II, or A</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF37E6F7FDE2F476190F5B7CF81DFE9D7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>in subsection (f), in the first sentence, by striking <quote>schedules I and II</quote> and inserting <quote>schedules I, II, and A</quote>;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF57DF4AE3130408593B1A6591CE3C8A3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 308(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/828">21 U.S.C. 828(a)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>schedule I or II</quote> and inserting <quote>schedule I, II, or A</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H699BE05DE1CA4BCA9F293036A9F006F8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in section 402(b) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/842">21 U.S.C. 842(b)</external-xref>), in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>schedule I or II</quote> and inserting <quote>schedule I, II, or A</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA58012A771EB481388AE8F4B5FF0E550"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in section 403(a)(1) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/843">21 U.S.C. 843(a)(1)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>schedule I or II</quote> and inserting <quote>schedule I, II, or A</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF20F201B10974CEDA22EFB20CBE2A75B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in section 511(f) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/881">21 U.S.C. 881(f)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>schedule I or II</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>schedule I, II, or A</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H759B9A20481F4AC4B089B40DC012D475"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Controlled Substances Import Export Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Controlled Substances Import and Export Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/951">21 U.S.C. 951</external-xref> et seq.) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H63B43050A1B24543A15B24923A8DFD08"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 1002(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/952">21 U.S.C. 952(a)</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph id="H58D8B5418F8D44B49DA4E72EEF2642CD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>schedule I or II</quote> and inserting <quote>schedule I, II, or A</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFD25C12B9974806951E0EE84B28BBF0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>schedule I or II</quote> and inserting <quote>schedule I, II, or A</quote>;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7CFB2C372084597B21266E249BB311A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 1003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/953">21 U.S.C. 953</external-xref>)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H88C354A4F6E148DDA48A6F115E266F30"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (c), in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>schedule I or II</quote> and inserting <quote>schedule I, II, or A</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D0EA9EFB4284EBBA274400283DD0403"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (d), by striking <quote>schedule I or II</quote> and inserting <quote>schedule I, II, or A</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H350B17C4B1CC417F876578A810504DDD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 1004(1) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/954">21 U.S.C. 954(1)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>schedule I</quote> and inserting <quote>schedule I or A</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC7D5F07CA6134C5393044FE6236DF593"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in section 1005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/955">21 U.S.C. 955</external-xref>), by striking <quote>schedule I or II</quote> and inserting <quote>schedule I, II, or A</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCBB09E3F1CB84106A6DADA685F98389E"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 1009(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/959">21 U.S.C. 959(a)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>schedule I or II</quote> and inserting <quote>schedule I, II, or A</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HCD018B58380A463BB5208414814B5F42"><enum>8.</enum><header>Controlled substance analogues</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H49D427F3532F4E219840343A6BAB4E18"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), by striking <quote>or V</quote> and inserting <quote>V, or A</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5C259A2CB5C04085A8DB49F84892A316"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (14)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H25823B8E601240D58BA7DA851982F6CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>schedule I(c) and</quote> and inserting <quote>schedule I(c), schedule A, and</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF71449804E5447D7BEFE682CDA2460FB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>schedule I(c),</quote> and inserting <quote>schedule I(c) and schedule A,</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E6D0F1ABAFF47FF8FD6C63B3E9AC33C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (32)(A), by striking <quote>(32)(A)</quote> and all that follows through clause (iii) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6787546D36C247209B9D3E2D569F1B65" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H472473CD06AB46A695D1A38594A533DA" indent="up1"><enum>(32)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0A05D83DA3574C6B97C455E694C14841"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (C), the term <term>controlled substance analogue</term> means a substance whose chemical structure is substantially similar to the chemical structure of a controlled substance in schedule I or II—</text>
 <clause id="H5381A1A38F5147F992C91A8C211C79F6" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>which has a stimulant, depressant, or hallucinogenic effect on the central nervous system that is substantially similar to or greater than the stimulant, depressant, or hallucinogenic effect on the central nervous system of a controlled substance in schedule I or II; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0C6E8AE9B41F45F7880A99CAC86CBAC8" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect to a particular person, which such person represents or intends to have a stimulant, depressant, or hallucinogenic effect on the central nervous system that is substantially similar to or greater than the stimulant, depressant, or hallucinogenic effect on the central nervous system of a controlled substance in schedule I or II.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section commented="no" id="H1E3A643D7B4445B89398DFA430E6F095"><enum>9.</enum><header>Amendment to the sentencing guidelines</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2D1.1 of the Federal Sentencing Guidelines is amended, in Application Note 6 (Analogues and Controlled Substances Not Referenced in this Guideline) of the Commentary, by striking <quote>In determining the most closely related controlled substance, the court shall, to the extent practicable, consider the following:</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H25B476823D214F98A6F1659B8ECC31C2" style="OLC">
 <text>In determining the most closely related controlled substance and the applicable guideline or drug equivalence, the court shall—</text><subparagraph id="H4F3EE053A62B454882229F739F6DA639"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if Attorney General has provided guidance on the appropriate sentencing equivalency or ratio to a controlled substance that is referenced in the guidelines through publication in the Federal Register (whether such guidance is included in or separate from any notice of proposed temporary or permanent scheduling of such substance under section 201 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/811">21 U.S.C. 811</external-xref>)), apply any such sentencing equivalency or ratio; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE01356336AFC42779174018F9FD8326F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the absence of guidance with respect to a substance or group of substances as described in paragraph (A), use equivalencies for the following structural classes of substances as if they were included on the Drug Equivalency Tables:</text>
					<table align-to-level="section" blank-lines-before="1" colsep="1" frame="topbot" line-rules="hor-ver" rowsep="0" rule-weights="4.4.4.0.0.0" table-template-name="Generic: 2 text, even cols" table-type="">
						<tgroup cols="2" grid-typeface="1.1" rowsep="0" thead-tbody-ldg-size="10.10.12"><colspec coldef="txt" colname="column1" colwidth="163pts" min-data-value="150" rowsep="0"></colspec><colspec coldef="txt-no-ldr" colname="column2" colwidth="163pts" min-data-value="150" rowsep="0"></colspec><thead>
								<row><entry align="center" colname="column1" morerows="0" namest="column1" rowsep="1">Drug Class</entry><entry align="center" colname="column2" morerows="0" namest="column2" rowsep="1">Marihuana Equivalency of 1 gm of subject substance</entry></row></thead>
							<tbody>
								<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" leader-modify="force-ldr" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">Synthetic Opioids</entry><entry align="left" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr" rowsep="0">1 gm = 10 kg</entry></row>
								<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" leader-modify="force-ldr" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">Synthetic Cannabinoids</entry><entry align="left" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr" rowsep="0">1 gm = 167 gm</entry></row>
								<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" leader-modify="force-ldr" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">Synthetic Cathinones</entry><entry align="left" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr" rowsep="0">1 gm = 380 gm</entry></row>
								<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" leader-modify="force-ldr" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">Tryptamine</entry><entry align="left" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr" rowsep="0">1 gm = 80 gm</entry></row>
								<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" leader-modify="force-ldr" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">Phenethylamines</entry><entry align="left" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr" rowsep="0">1 gm = 2.5 kg</entry></row>
								<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" leader-modify="force-ldr" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">Piperazines</entry><entry align="left" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr" rowsep="0">1 gm = 2 kg</entry></row>
								<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" leader-modify="force-ldr" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">Benzofurans</entry><entry align="left" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr" rowsep="0">1 gm = 500 gm</entry></row>
								<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" leader-modify="force-ldr" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">Arylcyclohexylamines (PCP-like substances)</entry><entry align="left" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr" rowsep="0">1 gm = 1 kg</entry></row>
								<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" leader-modify="force-ldr" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">Methylphenidate analogs</entry><entry align="left" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr" rowsep="0">1 gm = 100 gm</entry></row>
								<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" leader-modify="force-ldr" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">Benzodiazepines</entry><entry align="left" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr" rowsep="0">1 <quote>unit</quote> (as defined in Note (F) to the Drug Quantity Table in 2D1.1) = 0.0625 gm</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table>
				</subparagraph><quoted-block-continuation-text quoted-block-continuation-text-level="paragraph">In the case of a substance for which paragraphs (A) and (B) above are not applicable, the court
			 shall determine an equivalency or ratio by considering the following
			 factors, to the extent practicable:</quoted-block-continuation-text><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="HE0E814BE75204FB596CB07EA93242854"><enum>10.</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act, or the amendments made by this Act, may be construed to limit—</text> <paragraph id="H6B43E7B1359D45F291F7023F17DD62D3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the prosecution of offenses involving controlled substance analogues under the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/801">21 U.S.C. 801</external-xref> et seq.); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCAD124528319454D914774EA7AAF9A76"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the authority of the Attorney General to temporarily or permanently schedule, reschedule, or decontrol controlled substances under provisions of section 201 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/811">21 U.S.C. 811</external-xref>) that are in effect on the day before the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


