<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HA13A94EF35EF4B609449E9D5876E329D" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3428 IH: Advancing and Promoting Programming</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3428</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170726">July 26, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000294">Mr. Emmer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a website for Federal Government apps, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HD25B105F9DAA49C9AA677451261BD77C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H81460ED4CE384385A8395CA3BAA8D91E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Advancing and Promoting Programming</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>APP Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H9012F73040A94DC499541BE46CDA737C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; sense of Congress</header> <subsection id="H39BF70190D3A403EA0A6660B091AA19F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HB8B328D01FC14577895825BA4C539868"><enum>(1)</enum><text>84 percent of leading app makers are outside Silicon Valley, and 83 percent are small businesses.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC17482DF379747F3815C63EBCEAC7709"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Millions have participated in the Hour of Code, which teaches the fundamental components of computer programming.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H29985C96B66748D6860E72AEBED3815E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Congressional App Challenge is an officially sanctioned competition to promote computer science education and demonstrate the value of coding to the next generation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H37721BB617924812B8AA4582FC4AFF7E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Computer Science majors earn 40 percent more than the average college graduates.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFA03C2980172446B816AACBBE7416DB3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In 2016, China surpassed the United States in app store revenue.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1331F22E7B854BBC9DB14FFB7F327405"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The current extent of a Federal mobile app directory exists as a text list on a General Services Administration website.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA2E9F8879EA54803A736BD97ED89BAEC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="H7DFBCBDF674E414682DB0DC508862F59"><enum>(1)</enum><text>computer science skills are critical to a burgeoning technology industry, and will provide high-quality jobs for America’s future workforce;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE80A9263FBA415FB53C165B1EAF98FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Federal Government has an obligation to provide information and services through a means that meets the technology demands of our changing society; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC35B8CB217DD466E8E2BAEB5E0C238FA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>among other fields, computer programming jobs are a way to ensure America keeps the highest-quality jobs and remains a world economic leader.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H17BBC100D79F411A80145D1FA590438D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Federal Government website for apps</header>
 <subsection id="H4FA737D01DBD48F49CF0E09D11DE57A6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of website</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of General Services shall establish a publicly available website that includes a database of Federal funding opportunities for the creation of apps, allows the public to download a Federal Government app that has been made available to the public, and includes the following:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H8DF8A8C9C2E347F69DA35E6DDF81BFA5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A list of each funding source (including grants and prizes) for the creation and maintenance of Federal Government apps and how an applicant may apply for such funding, including resources such as grants.gov, challenge.gov, and the Small Business Innovation Research program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H36686F6507A14CBDA7734021EEA92CB4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The ability for the public to rate and review any such Federal Government app.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4E7B61384B2D48588CD4F7BCC07B2585"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A page that prominently displays apps that have been recently updated or that receive a high user review average under paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBD079847BD054D9B8B51E7BC894827E0"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A page that features Government projects that provide application developers with tools to improve private apps, such as data.gov and developer.epa.gov.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7A9387DA806E48CEB1B0376B578C837D"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Resources for education and training related to the creation of apps.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA861567925914E938CDAA47471B8D6A7"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A page that features outstanding, educational, computer science programs, determined by the Administrator of General Services and the Director of the National Science Foundation, and resources to replicate such programs.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H32F16006D1BA4D9DA6CD94F3FBDF66E1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review and removal of outdated apps</header><text>The Administrator of General Services shall review any app for which an update has not been released in more than 2 years and shall remove any app from the website described in subsection (a) that is no longer functional or compatible.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H98A2C7AE3A6348A8A0541A8F8197B0BA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>App defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>app</term> means a software application that enables the performance of a specific task that may be run on a computer, a mobile device, the Internet, or any other electronic device.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HD6D7DCD2061C4A24A78B0BBD5700E58C"><enum>4.</enum><header>No additional funds authorized</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to carry out the requirements of this Act. Such requirements shall be carried out using amounts otherwise authorized.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


