<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H301ECBDE3D7F4C6E8A228DAFE0711CD2" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3506 IH: Article I Restoration Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3506</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170727">July 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000599">Mr. Posey</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To sunset new Federal regulatory rules after 3 years, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H8F2DBD3BDEC9494C98291486DEC5D476" style="OLC">
 <section commented="no" id="H751342F50E7E4BEC8CE0AEF89A96A1AD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Article I Restoration Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H93664694CC344967A28865965A216CCB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sunset of Federal regulations after 3 years</header> <subsection id="H7CB105028CFE4159B38892FFFD5EB0E5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>Any covered rule issued by an agency after the date of the enactment of this Act shall sunset on the date that is three years after the effective date of such covered rule, unless specifically reauthorized by an Act of Congress.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H462E3A373B044926AB98D642AEAF6838"><enum>(b)</enum><header>After sunset</header><text>An agency may not reissue, enforce, revise, or take other regulatory action related to a covered rule that has sunset under subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H65A835EC88E44357B79F7E0B3B687FC5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Oversight by OMB and heads of agencies</header><text>The Director of the Office of Management and Budget or the head of the relevant agency may oversee the sunset of covered rules under subsection (a).</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HA017EE6337A041E0AF5F83FFCDE1E5E8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Submission of request for reauthorization to Congress</header>
 <subsection id="HD31519C4C3FD458D9BFE9E444E6E270F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Request for reauthorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the head of an agency that issues covered rules wants to request a reauthorization for such rules, such head shall, not later than the December 1 that is one year before the date on which the covered rule is scheduled to sunset, submit to Congress and any appropriate committee of Congress a report containing such request that includes—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD401F4B4491945159FAECC6CBF758077"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a justification for the reauthorization of each covered rule;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC8687A32CBE44BD8BA5E310B29DBE7C1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any related covered rules; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEDD49FB0CB14431D850F5DCF53966121"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any recommendation or request made by the chair or ranking member of an appropriate committee of Congress.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H51CB63EE00B44237A19298BFFD3CDD07"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Single submission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of an agency submitting a request for reauthorization under subsection (a) shall make every effort to bundle multiple requests for reauthorization in a single submission.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H077C8853EAEC4F4594498EA882383953"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public availability of reports</header><text>Any report submitted by the head of an agency under subsection (a) shall be published on the public website of the agency.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HDD7FAA8C5B284F08A05D860493FEEFB7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Relationship to the administrative procedure</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to supersede the provisions of chapter 5, 6, or 7 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </section><section id="H04501AADAA1F44DCBECD72B93ABFC809"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H4B166F3497E443B5BA5C7B31B3CB0F75"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given that term in section 551 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2308DE87109045B5AE3FA63A06E7D476"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs in the Office of Management and Budget.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H039F4065ADC247CFAFE607D7C247E3C4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered rule</term> has the meaning given the term <term>rule</term> in section 551 of title 5, United States Code, but does not include a rule—</text> <subparagraph id="HE2E980F55088472986D8652E97ACD7DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>issued in accordance with the formal rulemaking provisions of sections 556 and 557 of title 5, United States Code;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE332E7DFDF54CC09C660A34D72FD0C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>issued with respect to a military or foreign affairs function of the United States;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E624BED04424B51A15073A56893B285"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that the Administrator certifies in writing is necessary for the enforcement of Federal criminal laws;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82DB4FDAD7234121B0B7025AC950C20A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>that is limited to agency organization, management, or personnel matters; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73488157D3F04C25938641AE03CCCC17"><enum>(E)</enum><text>that is necessary due to an imminent threat to human health or safety or any other emergency.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD55363CC9E7247A99104073FA03AAE3F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The term <term>sunset</term> means to have no force or effect.</text> </paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

