<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H9AB992F8B00B4307ABC25CA8D29C10FD" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2117 IH: Multi-Employer Pension Plan Partnership Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2117</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170425">April 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to permit multiemployer plans in
			 critical status to modify plan rules relating to withdrawal liability, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HF01128B488DF42F8B0F1A07367653132" style="OLC">
 <section id="HD5F2BFC4A92340C1B4F05564F72A0E72" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Multi-Employer Pension Plan Partnership Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H06A1D7C0A3894614BB703262D879B626"><enum>2.</enum><header>Alternative method of withdrawal liability payments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 4224 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1404">29 U.S.C. 1404</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4F8DF6D3FE174B5C87663A1CEF187675"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>A multiemployer plan</quote> and inserting <quote>(a) A multiemployer plan</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE73599B6DC9645238E20472116A4B75A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE1B6F2AADB8743D689E71F864EB7D7D0" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H58BED6A13A8F4909B1F3EA08ACAB62EB"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any contrary provisions of this part, in the case of a multiemployer plan that is in critical status within the meaning of subsection (b)(2) of section 305 and whose plan sponsor determines pursuant to subsection (e)(3)(A)(ii) of such section that the plan cannot be reasonably expected to emerge from critical status by the end of the rehabilitation period, such plan may adopt rules for the purpose of forestalling or avoiding insolvency that provide for other terms and conditions for the computation of the amount of an employer's withdrawal liability (not to exceed the amount that would otherwise be determined without regard to this subsection). Any such rule shall become effective at the end of a 90-day period that begins on the date of adoption of the rule unless the corporation disapproves the rule before the end of the 90-day period (except that such 90-day period shall be tolled during any period in which a request by the corporation for additional information is pending). The corporation may disapprove a rule under this subsection only if it reasonably determines that the rule creates an unreasonable risk of loss to plan participants and beneficiaries or to the corporation.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


