<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H0888196D096B4782B5A457F4A13F6925" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1925 IH: At-Risk Youth Medicaid Protection Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1925</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170405">April 5, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000568">Mr. Griffith</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to protect at-risk youth against termination of
			 Medicaid eligibility while an inmate of a public institution.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H151F956902EE4F8C908E654B717C74FA" style="OLC">
 <section id="H88DCA5C175A94E02892202EB0F9CDDBF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>At-Risk Youth Medicaid Protection Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H49A9C4FA9C244F9598BFBD9E939D0CD1"><enum>2.</enum><header>At-risk youth Medicaid protection</header> <subsection id="H9EDF7F8E95894FEE8E610E7DF8034B0C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1902 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2EFE817E4B494E04AA5823DFEFEE8CC2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="H807CD70612DD45A5BE19ABD650D30C88"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (82);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6FDF47E74F574D09A2F5E16EF7753C92"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of paragraph (83) and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6591878A6B8425585C543411F2CAFDF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (83) the following new paragraph:</text>
						<quoted-block id="H8C1A4EB46C8D4D1BB4D008C82F909CE2" style="OLC">
 <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCAF63C022638446495C3614F4365868E"><enum>(84)</enum><text>provide that—</text> <subparagraph id="H13331EA0513B461B83CCB913F6D00B9E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the State shall not terminate eligibility for medical assistance under a State plan for an individual who is an eligible juvenile (as defined in subsection (nn)(2)) because the juvenile is an inmate of a public institution (as defined in subsection (nn)(3)), but may suspend coverage during the period the juvenile is such an inmate;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8CC25389B2F48A49D820358E85A18F2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the State shall restore coverage for such medical assistance to such an individual upon the individual’s release from any such public institution, without requiring a new application from the individual, unless (and until such date as) there is a determination that the individual no longer meets the eligibility requirements for such medical assistance; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H741ADDB062054834988B49350D67F1AA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the State shall process any application for medical assistance submitted by, or on behalf of, a juvenile who is an inmate of a public institution notwithstanding that the juvenile is such an inmate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0A3115DBAA9424482CEAFAF53D73681"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE95F571E9AF54E98833DE6F7202633D2" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H892101825758422884A0AC125E495BBC"><enum>(nn)</enum><header>Juvenile; eligible juvenile; public institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (a)(84) and this subsection:</text>
 <paragraph id="HA9C06E62BEEB408DBA9A56721E551C00"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Juvenile</header><text>The term <term>juvenile</term> means an individual who is—</text> <subparagraph id="H2FA9C89F93814DFC9C8DB4BF1554A0B4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>under 21 years of age; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13844BC3B3B54521B3BE1594BA1917D0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is described in subsection (a)(10)(A)(i)(IX).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H405C708F37EA4E4E98607547A17554FA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible juvenile</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible juvenile</term> means a juvenile who is an inmate of a public institution and was eligible for medical assistance under the State plan immediately before becoming an inmate of such a public institution or who becomes eligible for such medical assistance while an inmate of a public institution.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6470D773FC6C49BBA2CA7A051EA81EEE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Inmate of a public institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>inmate of a public institution</term> has the meaning given such term for purposes of applying the subdivision (A) following paragraph (29) of section 1905(a), taking into account the exception in such subdivision for a patient of a medical institution.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HF0B7D6D6C14543A6934921D279DB6C0C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No change in exclusion from medical assistance for inmates of public institutions</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed as changing the exclusion from medical assistance under the subdivision (A) following paragraph (29) of section 1905(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d(a)</external-xref>), including any applicable restrictions on a State submitting claims for Federal financial participation under title XIX of such Act for such assistance.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2766F03F07BA4CBD933BD2E203E24AC4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No change in continuity of eligibility before adjudication or sentencing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to mandate, encourage, or suggest that a State suspend or terminate coverage for individuals before they have been adjudicated or sentenced.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H3194A66CCE5F49EB9C0878546F3C9605"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header>
 <paragraph id="H48B1AE0113794FD5B689FDD9C5617B73"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendments made by subsection (a) shall apply to eligibility of juveniles who become inmates of public institutions on or after the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H522878B015F84AC0AAB9984A28417F9A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule for changes requiring state legislation</header><text>In the case of a State plan for medical assistance under title XIX of the Social Security Act which the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines requires State legislation (other than legislation appropriating funds) in order for the plan to meet the additional requirements imposed by the amendments made by subsection (a), the State plan shall not be regarded as failing to comply with the requirements of such title solely on the basis of its failure to meet these additional requirements before the first day of the first calendar quarter beginning after the close of the first regular session of the State legislature that begins after the date of the enactment of this Act. For purposes of the previous sentence, in the case of a State that has a 2-year legislative session, each year of such session shall be deemed to be a separate regular session of the State legislature.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


