<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HBAC206BEBD1E487EAF0014DC6E0E30EB" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2696 IH: Executive Office of Environmental Justice Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2696</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170525">May 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001200">Mr. McEachin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Office of Environmental Justice in the Executive Office of the President, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HF4A49FFCC0B8426F8E167A5565107D75" style="OLC">
 <section id="HF03CC519527844B0ADBAA04E11064FFE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Executive Office of Environmental Justice Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H11B708DAF3BE4AFBBBC613731A4826C8" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Office of Environmental Justice</header> <subsection id="H9D99A543841642CC9E0EDFE1CB3564BA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of Office; duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established in the Executive Office of the President an Office of Environmental Justice, which shall have the following duties:</text>
 <paragraph id="H77136BE85BF34EBE9D4D6F1091836C9B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Liaise with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6BCE6EBCF16F47309FB0F837B516E533"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Complete an environmental justice assessment of each Executive order, to be made public on the White House website.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDAEB44287C414ED99C0B1FC1A22FD05D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Discuss an assessment with the President before an Executive order is signed. Any such assessment shall be made available to the public not later than 15 days after the Executive order is signed.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC0C273360DE04BD7B12FD77DCA64BDF7"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Attend the Interagency Working Group meetings established under Executive Order 12898 (50 Fed. Reg. 7629; relating to Federal actions to address environmental justice in minority populations and low-income populations) and meet, not less frequently than annually, with the members of the Interagency Working Group described in section 1–102 of such Executive order to review progress being made on implementing the environmental justice goals of the Interagency Working Group within the applicable agency or office.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H99712CC80F064C9ABDE72F2380532018"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Coordinate roundtables with stakeholders and hold public meetings.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H365F85DFFEF340B2A53E02FCBC457859"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ensure that the goals of Executive Order 12898 (59 Fed. Reg. 7629; relating to Federal actions to address environmental justice in minority populations and low-income populations) are being actively implemented through science-based regulations in the White House and the Environmental Protection Agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H427E6ED52298499CAD68D1D7C72A7AE8"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Represent the executive branch in the community and regularly engage in frontline communities, including communities of color, low income communities, people with limited English proficiency, indigenous peoples, and people living with disabilities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H94480FC6A5F840E3A3B2A1C668AB2492"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Serve as a member on the Domestic Policy Council, established by Executive Order 12859 (58 Fed. Reg. 44101; relating to establishment of the Domestic Policy Council).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H94A91BCD900E47AFBB252397331D15E7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Director</header>
 <paragraph id="H7FE31652D23842DFA7040E6E2C99001A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There shall be a Director of the Office of Environmental Justice who shall head the Office.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H060A863807A34F189096C06BAD35195F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. The first such appointment shall not be later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDE2654647C33422D9B8158D175DF1351"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Director shall serve as the liaison with the Office of Environmental Justice of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H79DC9D09FA9244BEAF6FFFAA01C5D84E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Pay</header><text>The annual rate of basic pay for the Director shall be the rate payable under level III of the Executive Schedule (section 5314 of title 5, United States Code).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9E8944D393224888B5C820E461FBE7BC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 5314 of such title is amended by inserting after the item relating to <quote>Director of the Office of Emergency Planning</quote> the following new item:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD52ADF42BA29406993AABE510DCEBEA6" style="OLC"> <quoted-block-continuation-text quoted-block-continuation-text-level="paragraph">Director of the Office of Environmental Justice.</quoted-block-continuation-text><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

