<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H63209FC4C83F4704BCC73D2342E676A5" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4457 IH: Veterans Empowerment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4457</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171121">November 21, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001187">Mr. Meadows</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to establish the Veterans Accountable Care Organization and
			 to provide veterans access to private health insurance plans, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H30B1F577EF344455B52C70FC2793FCA6" style="OLC">
		<section id="HF999AE431D154736AFD015B356BB7A26" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Empowerment Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H12690CA506D549888328873F68CEC6CE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of Veterans Accountable Care Organization</header> <subsection id="H22505838A3D5435EA9B0E9DA33AF629B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header> <paragraph id="H3FDD589982F64A9AAADF34D13A10E0D9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/3">Chapter 3</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDA9DEF6E802D436EB6499FE1728EF9BA" style="USC">
						<section id="HE5FCFCF15CEA45E29B985BE5677D0CB2"><enum>323.</enum><header>Veterans Accountable Care Organization</header>
							<subsection id="H63EB5E4546E34AEC96C22E3789A74B93"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H68B543E943A74445AB75AA988CA8E349"><enum>(1)</enum><text>There is established the Veterans Accountable Care Organization (in this section referred to as the <quote>Corporation</quote>).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H39B9E6CF497D4E80AA508AAEA601C9D9" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Corporation is a federally chartered corporation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDC290179E16A43A3B7B4BC851B65D46A" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Corporation shall be incorporated and domiciled in the District of Columbia, or another nearby State, as determined by the board of directors of the Corporation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H539AF356A71E4BD8BDACF28CB95C08A6" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Corporation shall be a charitable and nonprofit corporation.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1ADA3F43762E44FAAB02C7AA72EA7718" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Except as otherwise provided, the Corporation shall have perpetual existence.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE56AA3EA07B14E479652DED3F014F1B6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the Corporation is to furnish high-quality hospital care, medical services, and other health care (excluding nursing home care and domiciliary care) to individuals eligible for such care and services under laws administered by the Secretary.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="H1B4A676A9B454E278FE65FF6FD235DD3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Board of Directors</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H8D11E8490B1A426589A6E96DE9623C9A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The powers of the Corporation shall be vested in a Board of Directors that governs the Corporation.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEA095869B8E14A27A1E754A34B6B4448" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Board of Directors shall be composed of the following members:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H912E2E595D6647138ED38DAABA7A7ADA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81061DC6196A40F18B056988293B7607"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Two members appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, at least one of whom shall be a veteran.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF3A18073A57490783D802AA9E74E767"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Two members appointed by the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives, at least one of whom shall be a veteran.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5AFD0ED1949649C68AD54532F7578BF5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Two members appointed by the Majority Leader of the Senate, at least one of whom shall be a veteran.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96C62F3ABE974468BB6E16D19FC64BD4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Two members appointed by the Minority Leader of the Senate, at least one of whom shall be a veteran.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3040E33FC8D740D4999A4E7A72EE7481"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Two members appointed by the President, at least one of whom shall be veterans.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H24BB807B12684A5C83F2D8AD7E2BEDAF" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall designate a member of the Board of Directors to serve as Chairperson of the Board. The Board shall select a Vice Chairperson from among its members.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="H97FBBFDFE04A45338C99320323FDE9A8" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H2528848B5A1C429094C74D1B07FC2FE6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A member of the Board of Directors shall serve for a term of five years, except that the members first appointed shall be appointed for staggered terms as the President considers appropriate to ensure that the terms of no more than three members expire in the same year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF7D83355C45440EAC53AD573F27CB2A" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring before the expiration of the term for which the member’s predecessor was appointed shall be appointed only for the remainder of that term. A member may serve after the expiration of that member’s term until a successor has taken office. A vacancy on the Board shall not affect its powers, but shall be filled in the same manner in which the original appointment was made.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C3C9595B3A848D8A74E07C47FB27AA8" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term of each member may be renewed for an additional term, except that in no case shall any member serve more than two consecutive terms exceeding ten years.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0E01F274F1D14244B614C2B93B4FF7D8" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the absence or disability of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs or in the event of a vacancy in the office of Secretary, the Acting Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall serve as the member of the Board of Directors specified in paragraph (2)(A).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD765816DC8ED4E0499C981502E5272EA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>In carrying out subsection (b), the Corporation shall—</text> <paragraph id="H23FBC5FE993847699FEBE09E83A17D5C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">transfer personnel and assets of the Department of Veterans Affairs to the Corporation pursuant to subsection (b) of section 2 of the <short-title>Veterans Empowerment Act</short-title>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDD0A1FEE94C3485292A0DD0DDA18F1B6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish priorities, milestones, and time­lines, in consultation with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, for the termination of functions of the Veterans Health Administration directly related to the furnishing of hospital care, medical services, and other health care (excluding nursing home care and domiciliary care) pursuant to subsection (c) of such section 2;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB87806CFDB5244D79BD61C1B0A1FF8A3"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to centers of excellence relating to service-connected injuries and other medical issues—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3BDD2533B6AF4BA78B6B418BF68A994B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">continue to administer such centers previously established by the Secretary; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB58725681D144F0B860D9E36AFE0A95D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establish and administer additional such centers as the Board of Directors determines appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8B99AA60E6648D9ABA2641C9F6CDB4A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in consultation with the Secretary, carry out such other actions necessary to carry out this section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9F219E816BBB4EF3B87B3D45C3F720EB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Powers</header><text>The Corporation shall—</text> <paragraph id="H63E3A79D6FDF4CB7BECB0B8A7F62AD3A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>appoint employees; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H160BEB2A8A184B17B00ED27FBDF70FD9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">adopt a Constitution and bylaws consistent with the purpose set forth under subsection (b).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE64039756C274BEF86C6353E636D0A00"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Duty To maintain corporate and tax-Exempt status</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB618188DC2D04F2ABF5E3391A318DDE6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Corporation shall maintain its status as a corporation incorporated under the laws of the District of Columbia or another nearby State, as determined by the Board of Directors.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9BFF1921D6D544F7A0ED3A636CBD4860" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Corporation shall maintain its status as an organization exempt from the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2D0A6D362A9F4231BF0256E25EC10914"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Veterans Accountable Care Organization Fund</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H4879F368379F41FFA51B8543F4C712E6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is in the Treasury a fund to be known as the Veterans Accountable Care Organization Fund (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Fund</quote>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE65841EF10FC41CBA3B1983236E87ABB" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Amounts recovered or collected under chapter 26 of this title shall be deposited in the Fund.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2331ABA3807F457AA19C962CCD534FB8" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts in the Fund shall be available, without further appropriation and without fiscal year limitation, to establish and administer centers of excellence described in subsection (d)(3) and for health care or medical services furnished to a veteran at a facility operated by the Corporation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBD51A2B147694C1EA2134019A30A63F4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 3 of such title is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 322 the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2FB97FF074434EC999E9D0268F630F4F" style="OLC">
						<toc>
							<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">323. Veterans Accountable Care Organization.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1D52841B2A3F4BB7843BFE707E40FBD1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transfer of personnel and assets</header>
 <paragraph id="H4A3FBEEE1EF04E4D85954AA651D7A805"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Transfer</header><text>All of the personnel, property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds employed, used, held, available, or to be made available in connection with the direct furnishing of hospital care, medical services, and other health care (excluding nursing home care and domiciliary care) to individuals eligible for such care and services under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs are transferred to the Veterans Accountable Care Organization established under section 323 of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H153E2E0BB6624F238CA996B8CF1139E3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reduction in force</header><text>The Secretary may implement a reduction in force in carrying out paragraph (1).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2AAA2B3D66954632809FCF63BAEF0D59"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Termination of functions</header> <paragraph id="HAA32BDF544534E0399C3EE823BFC9A44"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided by paragraph (2), all of the functions of the Veterans Health Administration directly relating to the furnishing of hospital care, medical services, and other health care (excluding nursing home care and domiciliary care) to individuals eligible for such care and services under laws administered by the Secretary shall terminate one year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H187D797CAC76483DA2104BC55B44ABF5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Extensions</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs may make not more than two 90-day extensions to the termination date specified in paragraph (1) if the Secretary notifies Congress of such extensions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8A1257456A3343E59EEB7754B1EC6BD1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Certification of termination date</header><text>The Secretary shall certify to Congress the date on which paragraph (1) is carried out.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6CFF7489F57942B6B77AAE74E8B9D860"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Recommendations for statutory amendments</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that contains recommendations for technical and conforming amendments to Federal statutes to carry out this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H2BEEE21AC59E4D889F70D77E1E40CC1B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of Veterans Health Insurance Program</header>
 <subsection id="H7BE541E745544C1C8FCB63985D563612"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/73">Chapter 73</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7B07777F91AA4EFB8C39F734F801A882" style="USC">
					<section id="H308D91E7E3334494A56E60C27A82EA7E"><enum>7309A.</enum><header>Veterans Health Insurance Program</header>
 <subsection id="H9BEE342D2A5A44E5A40A7388AFF08FB2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the Veterans Health Administration the Veterans Health Insurance Program (in this section referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5F19DB2333FB4E6E99515958769CC55A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>Under the Program, the Secretary shall administer the provision of health insurance support to veterans under chapter 26 of this title.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H22866C0AE6624839BDEF2916E7A93ACC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 73 of such title is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 7309 the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H91795A63CF4249A7B976219912BAF665" style="USC">
					<toc>
						<toc-entry idref="H308D91E7E3334494A56E60C27A82EA7E" level="section">7309A. Veterans Health Insurance Program.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H89C44826A2664E1B83703D448C5A76A0"><enum>4.</enum><header>Designation of existing authorities for hospital care, medical services, and other health care</header>
 <subsection id="H2A1EA2FEB3CD45F59D5B1A3FA9CAD82A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/17">chapter 17</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/1701">section 1701</external-xref> the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H27544F60324F4E5A93C3EAEA87DEA086" style="USC">
					<section id="HBEC3EA23B161481F95F193681B6833EE"><enum>1701A.</enum><header>VetsCare Federal program: designation of authorities for hospital care, medical services, and other
			 health care as program</header>
 <subsection id="HDA73812B509047BEAABF07E0DFC16851"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Effective as of the date described in section 2(c)(3) of the <short-title>Veterans Empowerment Act</short-title>, the authorities for the provision of hospital care, medical services, and other health care (other than nursing home care and domiciliary care) in subchapter II of this chapter and under any other law administered by the Secretary may be referred to as the <quote>VetsCare Federal program</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H597F48A6658B48E7B6F52C724A34E007"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designation of recipients</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective as of the date described in section 2(c)(3) of the <short-title>Veterans Empowerment Act</short-title>, any eligible individual who receives hospital care, medical services, and other health care (excluding nursing home care and domiciliary care) in accordance with the authorities referred to in subsection (a) after such date may be referred to in the receipt of such care or services as participating in the <quote>VetsCare Federal program</quote>.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="HDF82DC479FC7425BBAB4AE5734B863A8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Secondary payer</header>
 <paragraph id="HE05B8953172841D9A331B8B51CCFE170"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any health plan (including the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395</external-xref> et seq.) or a State plan under title XIX of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396</external-xref> et seq.) and the TRICARE program under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/55">chapter 55</external-xref> of title 10) under which an eligible individual is covered shall be responsible for the payment of costs for any health care received by an eligible individual for a non-service connected disability up to the maximum amount allowable under such plan before the VetsCare Federal program is responsible for any such costs, if applicable.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD77D90CC39704916B16864BE19D3DEA3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Defense, or any other head of a relevant department or agency of the Federal Government shall notify the Secretary of Veterans Affairs of an eligible individual being covered under a health plan described in paragraph (1).</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6EC041C17E894B0C83C3D68993C4866D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Treatment of employer-Sponsored health plans</header>
 <paragraph id="HEF6A4D1838C44E48BCFF2F80B1FE7832"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The provisions of section 1862(b)(3)(C) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395y">42 U.S.C. 1395y(b)(3)(C)</external-xref>) shall apply with respect to financial or other incentives for an employee who is an eligible individual not to enroll (or to terminate enrollment) under a health plan that would (in the case of such enrollment) be responsible under subsection (c) for the payment of costs for hospital care, medical services, or other health care received by the eligible individual for a non-service connected disability in the same manner as such section 1862(b)(3)(C) applies to financial or other incentives for an individual entitled to benefits under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395</external-xref> et seq.) not to enroll (or to terminate enrollment) under a group health plan or a large group health plan which would (in the case of enrollment) be a primary plan (as defined in section 1862(b)(2)(A) of such Act).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD886B628578445E5ABB2B4B59BEB9CCA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary may by regulation adopt such additional exceptions to the prohibition described in paragraph (1) as the Secretary considers appropriate and such paragraph shall be implemented taking into account the adoption of such exceptions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0E31C0E40705406CA9B9510AC4C2CCE4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Veterans Accountable Care Organization and the Secretary of Health and Human Services may enter into agreements to carry out this subsection. Any such agreement shall provide that any expenses incurred by the Secretary of Health and Human Services pertaining to carrying out this subsection shall be reimbursed by the Veterans Accountable Care Organization.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1C96A2A271E042CAB15EFE8754123C3C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Group health plan defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>group health plan</term> means a group health plan (as that term is defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5000">section 5000(b)(1)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 without regard to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5000">section 5000(d)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCB083862404E4363901DD3061A8D6C58"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Eligible individuals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual is eligible to participate in the VetsCare Federal program if such individual was enrolled in the system of annual patient enrollment established and operated by the Secretary under section 1705(a) of this title as of the date described in section 2(c)(3) of the <short-title>Veterans Empowerment Act</short-title>.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1F1D86134EA4462D86CB71AB0F29818C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 1701 the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HBA30C022262C4577A1633A0E45A83691" style="OLC">
					<toc>
						<toc-entry idref="HBEC3EA23B161481F95F193681B6833EE" level="section">1701A. VetsCare Federal program: designation of authorities for hospital care, medical services,
			 and other health care as program.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="HB6B94BFD7DBD495AA764A5B8B4D78494"><enum>5.</enum><header>Health insurance support for new veterans and veterans electing health insurance support in lieu of
			 eligibility for hospital care, medical services, and other health care
			 under existing authorities</header>
 <subsection id="H219E6C37F436408DB95AAA59C1E97894"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Part II of title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting after chapter 24 the following new chapter:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3A60C8183E8947999EA2A4F7E20E31CD" style="USC">
					<chapter id="H7DE83536AD5548E4B8E7905346B330A9" style="OLC"><enum>26</enum><header>Veterans Independence in Health Care</header>
						<toc container-level="chapter-container" idref="H7DE83536AD5548E4B8E7905346B330A9" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
							<toc-entry idref="HD08B526C366E44229AE05D1BA4F3880D" level="subchapter">Subchapter I—Veterans Generally</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H51E9B424512341D7B6E11E829FD84D6C" level="section">2601. VetsCare Choice program: designation of recipients.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H1C8CACA98029457B89E22D68E33EBFFE" level="section">2602. Eligibility.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H090930D409ED46678DDC3F2DA4F1616C" level="section">2603. Qualifying health insurance.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H9E0638D6E7F348779A3A9E417803B544" level="section">2604. Health insurance support.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="HB6184C6F4D324CB9AD4D7E6F88768192" level="section">2605. Treatment of other health plans.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H8B83F64A53D146BC9C331D36502B7226" level="section">2606. Receipt of health care through the Department.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H0037DAA47E6C482096DFEC23B73D1F65" level="section">2607. Pharmacy benefits.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="HD8811E506E85423F8A03F270E96AD09E" level="subchapter">Subchapter II—Medicare-Eligible Veterans</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H6469BA6906684E49B51C1C9D26244D13" level="section">2611. VetsCare Senior program: designation of recipients.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="HC24027056C064426AF281BFCCCEAEE3A" level="section">2612. Medicare support.</toc-entry></toc>
						<subchapter id="HD08B526C366E44229AE05D1BA4F3880D" style="OLC"><enum>I</enum><header>Veterans Generally</header>
							<section id="H51E9B424512341D7B6E11E829FD84D6C"><enum>2601.</enum><header>VetsCare Choice program: designation of recipients</header>
 <subsection id="H969D722CED764471A1561F5F4B411FC0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The authorities for the provision of health insurance support under this subchapter may be referred to as the <quote>VetsCare Choice program</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDC822EB81AAD4A32BF56F333E8745CC2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designation of recipients</header><text>Any veteran who receives health insurance support under this subchapter may be referred to in the receipt of support as participating in the <quote>VetsCare Choice program</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H5657DE1893CA41E2938DDF8BD0F45A59"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Relationship to care by Veterans Accountable Care Organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Health insurance support under this subchapter is in addition to any health care or medical services furnished to a veteran at a facility operated by the Veterans Accountable Care Organization.</text>
								</subsection></section><section id="H1C8CACA98029457B89E22D68E33EBFFE"><enum>2602.</enum><header>Eligibility</header>
 <subsection id="H4196DF5292224A36B9C946E3E507B0A1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsections (c) and (d), the following veterans shall be provided health insurance support under this subchapter:</text>
 <paragraph id="HEC292E7A65834B1486C2E46A05B10F69"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Veterans who first enroll in the system of annual patient enrollment established and operated by the Secretary under section 1705(a) of this title on or after the date described in section 2(c)(3) of the <short-title>Veterans Empowerment Act</short-title>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAE5DF8BAE7404D8C875CB6DD70B1875B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Veterans enrolled in such system as of the date described in section 2(c)(3) of the <short-title>Veterans Empowerment Act</short-title> who elect health insurance support under this subchapter in lieu of eligibility for hospital care, medical services, and other health care (excluding nursing home care and domiciliary care) under the VetsCare Federal program under chapter 17 of this title or any other law administered by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0AF3583DBFC0433A82E959DF05F9D190"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enrollment</header><text>The Secretary shall administer—</text> <paragraph id="HB23E196928F249468EEFD0EFBD6CEC5E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an open enrollment period for the VetsCare Choice program that corresponds to the open enrollment period for the Federal Employees Health Benefits program described in section 8905(g); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA83792216DF447EA96AA533885E442A4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>special enrollment periods based on qualifying life events of veterans similar to such events under the Federal Employees Health Benefits Program, except that the change of priority group shall also be treated as a qualifying life event.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF1E5CDCAAA5E488B984B219B5E6946C0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effect of election</header><text>While an election under subsection (a)(2) of a veteran described in that subsection is in effect, the veteran is not eligible for hospital care, medical services, and other health care (excluding nursing home care and domiciliary care) under chapter 17 of this title or any other law administered by the Secretary.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4947C2DF6CAC497A86269D5FE8FAB383"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>The following veterans are not eligible for health insurance support under this subchapter:</text> <paragraph id="HF822B656796B48E8AB2EDABAC42A7893"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Any veteran eligible for care under the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HECD4DDD00F5F41619A65BFF8EDF9AA8A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any veteran who—</text> <subparagraph id="H2A97986963664C8F81D48D1B6599284E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">first enrolls in the system of annual patient enrollment established and operated by the Secretary under section 1705(a) of this title on or after the date described in section 2(c)(3) of the Veterans Act; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8FB8D2099274203A361B635B7DB2FC2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is in priority group 7 or priority group 8.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7890AFDE1AB945BB959B4949452E1644"><enum>(e)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Commencement of availability of support</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Health insurance support under this subchapter shall commence being available as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="HDF8062F09EB54A8DB243EB77274A378D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>With respect to veterans in priority group 1, 2, or 3, on the first day of the first month that begins on or after the date described in section 2(c)(3) of the <short-title>Veterans Empowerment Act</short-title>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H00400D566D19442A8725E9892D34F13F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to veterans in a priority group other than 1, 2, or 3, on the first day of the first month that begins on or after the date that is 180 days after the commencement date under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3272D27BD8EE41CDB01F10F4583EF26F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Priority group defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>priority group</term> means the priority groups established by the Secretary for purposes of the enrollment of veterans in the patient enrollment system under section 1705(a) of this title.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H090930D409ED46678DDC3F2DA4F1616C"><enum>2603.</enum><header>Qualifying health insurance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Health insurance support may be provided under this subchapter only for health plans that—</text> <paragraph id="H9C020F956CD942D8B3667C4CB80EEE37"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include the types of health care authorized under section 1079 of title 10, United States Code; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H43B9D0D83CE649C4BFA1C746945F5D8A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide such additional elements of coverage as the Secretary shall prescribe for purposes of this subchapter.</text>
								</paragraph></section><section id="H9E0638D6E7F348779A3A9E417803B544"><enum>2604.</enum><header>Health insurance support</header>
 <subsection id="HBCA2131DCA8747ADAFF4307EEC510DCB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide health insurance support to veterans eligible for such support under this subchapter through premium support under subsections (b) and (c), cost-sharing support under subsection (d), and alternative support under subsection (e) by paying or reimbursing such veterans for the costs associated with such health insurance support. The Secretary shall make such payments or reimbursements in a manner similar to the manner in which the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services make similar payments and reimbursements.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2357EA6F46BD4BE08BDF661BD89825BA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Premium support generally</header><text>The premium support provided by the Secretary under this subsection is as follows:</text> <paragraph id="HCE67D7D220A54388A5678C037668CDD9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Tier 1</header><text>To any veteran with a service-connected disability rated as 100 percent disabling, health insurance support sufficient to provide benefits to the veteran under a health plan that are actuarially equivalent to 100 percent of the full actuarial value of the benefits provided under the health plan. A health plan under this paragraph may be referred to as a <quote>Tier 1 Plan</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD9B6D24C832948288D114307678E5E12"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Tier 2</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To any veteran in priority group 1 not covered by paragraph (1) and any veteran in priority group 2, health insurance support sufficient to provide benefits to the veteran under a health plan that are actuarially equivalent to 90 percent of the full actuarial value of the benefits provided under the health plan. A health plan under this paragraph may be referred to as a <quote>Tier 2 Plan</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5663559602AA48DC96266CA18D887EFB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Tier 3</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To any veteran in priority group 3 or priority group 4, health insurance support sufficient to provide benefits to the veteran under a health plan that are actuarially equivalent to 80 percent of the full actuarial value of the benefits provided under the health plan. A health plan under this paragraph may be referred to as a <quote>Tier 3 Plan</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBBE5F68F03AD46D5B09BC4737DB1C853"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Tier 4</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To any veteran in priority group 5 or priority group 6, health insurance support sufficient to provide benefits to the veteran under a health plan that are actuarially equivalent to 70 percent of the full actuarial value of the benefits provided under the health plan. A health plan under this paragraph may be referred to as a <quote>Tier 4 Plan</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB71C40A66E2F4549BABB2ECCE7653A5F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Tier 5</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To any veteran not in a priority group covered by paragraphs (1) through (4) and not ineligible for such support under section 2602(d)(2) of this title, health insurance support sufficient to provide benefits to the veteran under a health plan that are actuarially equivalent to 60 percent of the full actuarial value of the benefits provided under the health plan. A health plan under this paragraph may be referred to as a <quote>Tier 5 Plan</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC6083429E3A042BBBB755203F03765BC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional premium support based on need</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The premium support provided by the Secretary under this subsection is as follows:</text> <paragraph id="H1916F778125347F2A087F25BE7B40608"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To any veteran with an annual gross household income that is less than 133 percent of the poverty line, health insurance support sufficient to cover any costs of such monthly premium that are more than 2 percent of the monthly gross household income of the veteran.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE40625093CB84D9995D5ACE60859DAB2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To any veteran with an annual gross household income that is between 133 percent and 150 percent of the poverty line, health insurance support sufficient to cover any costs of such monthly premium that are more than 3 percent of the monthly gross household income of the veteran.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H339E777B702A42F5AF7BC6648A25BC36"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To any veteran with an annual gross household income that is between 150 percent and 200 percent of the poverty line, health insurance support sufficient to cover any costs of such monthly premium that are more than 4 percent of the monthly gross household income of the veteran.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFAB291D189EE455BAC2498ECF6ABE03A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To any veteran with an annual gross household income that is between 200 percent and 250 percent of the poverty line, health insurance support sufficient to cover any costs of such monthly premium that are more than 6.3 percent of the monthly gross household income of the veteran.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H51AE0188600144019C99D303288C80F1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>To any veteran with an annual gross household income that is between 250 percent and 300 percent of the poverty line, health insurance support sufficient to cover any costs of such monthly premium that are more than 8.05 percent of the monthly gross household income of the veteran.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA139141FEAAF4E3A8F7A04B0B4557CA5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>To any veteran with an annual gross household income that is between 300 percent and 400 percent of the poverty line, health insurance support sufficient to cover any costs of such monthly premium that are more than 9.5 percent of the monthly gross household income of the veteran.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H124A5EEF3B294934BF0C9454E3057E64"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Cost-Sharing support</header><text>The cost-sharing support provided by the Secretary under this subsection is as follows:</text> <paragraph id="HF004F1392FBE4E63804684E5AD713A01"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To any veteran with an annual gross household income that is less than 150 percent of the poverty line, health insurance support sufficient to cover cost-sharing in order to ensure that the effective minimum actuarial value of the benefits provided under the health plan of the veteran is not less than 94 percent.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5342B180ED584884B5C9D8D7A2934A13"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To any veteran with an annual gross household income that is between 150 percent and 200 percent of the poverty line, health insurance support sufficient to cover cost-sharing in order to ensure that the effective minimum actuarial value of the benefits provided under the health plan of the veteran is not less than 87 percent.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0BC37FA7042A4547A6E49E15FFCA500A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To any veteran with an annual gross household income that is between 200 percent and 250 percent of the poverty line, health insurance support sufficient to cover cost-sharing in order to ensure that the effective minimum actuarial value of the benefits provided under the health plan of the veteran is not less than 73 percent.</text>
									</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H81406DB24A2E41589781C7269690564D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Alternative support for veterans with certain health insurance</header>
 <paragraph id="H65BFE3F93AFE4BADB33384BBCDC14CFF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, upon the election of a veteran eligible for health insurance support under this subchapter who obtains a high deductible health plan that includes a health savings account under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/223">section 223</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, the Secretary shall contribute an amount calculated under paragraph (2) into such health savings account on behalf of the veteran.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB9A4242826B04F998E0FFCF7863ACF55"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amount calculated</header><text>The amount calculated under this paragraph is an amount equal to the difference between—</text> <subparagraph id="H5F8B5ED561264E1EB3323637125CCE0E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amount of health insurance support the veteran would otherwise have received under the subsection of this section applicable to the veteran; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA9CF7792A5C4C13AA183A9FB77D1DC0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount payable by the veteran in connection with the high deductible health plan described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H68DC234F4A094935A6557493F402F291"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Determinations based on cost of plans</header><text>In making determinations under this section with respect to the amount of health insurance support to provide to a veteran, the Secretary shall make such determinations based on the costs associated with the second-least-costly health plan available to the veteran in the area in which the veteran resides.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H001438EA0FE241E2B07671FF85B48EF5"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HBA3E5BEDA02841E2B8D8CB26E7A0D468"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>cost-sharing</term>, in connection with the receipt of health care and treatment under a health plan, means any copayments, deductibles, or other charges imposed, collected, or otherwise required by a health insurance provider or health care provider in connection with the receipt of health care and treatment under such health plan.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE25A2AFFBFFE47799D15D6E184ECDE73"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>poverty line</term> means the poverty line (as defined in section 673(2) of the Community Services Block Grant Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9902">42 U.S.C. 9902(2)</external-xref>) applicable to a family of the size involved.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H789A48A028F84807AE48F5022711AAB9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>high deductible health plan</term> has the meaning given that term in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/223">section 223(c)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF40B238455AC4361BF1AACB3AA7B5D79"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>priority group</term> means the priority groups established by the Secretary for purposes of the enrollment of veterans in the patient enrollment system under section 1705(a) of this title.</text>
									</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB6184C6F4D324CB9AD4D7E6F88768192"><enum>2605.</enum><header>Treatment of other health plans</header>
								<subsection id="H99467B620EDC4918B74A6B3242AFE097"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Secondary payer</header>
 <paragraph id="H75765A5A976D435CB896485D84536ECC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any health plan (including a State plan under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396</external-xref> et seq.) and the TRICARE program under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/55">chapter 55</external-xref> of title 10) under which a veteran is covered that is not a health plan for which health insurance support is provided under this subchapter shall be responsible for the payment of costs for any health care received by an eligible individual for a non-service connected disability up to the maximum amount allowable under such plan before any health plan for which health insurance support is provided under this subchapter is responsible for any such costs, if applicable.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2B42456FF41D4F7381069A37CBF6BABF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Defense, or any other head of a relevant department or agency of the Federal Government shall notify the Secretary of Veterans Affairs of an eligible individual being covered under a health plan described in paragraph (1).</text>
									</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2681140B5F0B43B9B433F059742165C7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment of employer-Sponsored health plans</header>
 <paragraph id="HD987396E161E40BC8B6E6D68974ED575"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The provisions of section 1862(b)(3)(C) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395y">42 U.S.C. 1395y(b)(3)(C)</external-xref>) shall apply with respect to financial or other incentives for an employee who is a veteran not to enroll (or to terminate enrollment) under a health plan that is not a health plan for which health insurance support is provided under this subchapter and that would (in the case of such enrollment) be responsible under subsection (a) for the payment of costs for health care received by the veteran in the same manner as such section 1862(b)(3)(C) applies to financial or other incentives for an individual entitled to benefits under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395</external-xref> et seq.) not to enroll (or to terminate enrollment) under a group health plan or a large group health plan which would (in the case of enrollment) be a primary plan (as defined in section 1862(b)(2)(A) of such Act).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBECDF1054AC743FBB9C467439C325CE2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary may by regulation adopt such additional exceptions to the prohibition described in paragraph (1) as the Secretary considers appropriate and such paragraph shall be implemented taking into account the adoption of such exceptions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3547B6CB73DD4193B68C0CAC6628A100"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Agreements</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Health and Human Services may enter into agreements to carry out this subsection. Any such agreement shall provide that any expenses incurred by the Secretary of Health and Human Services pertaining to carrying out this subsection shall be reimbursed by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA0A19358485449FB94833468194262BE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Group health plan defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>group health plan</term> means a group health plan (as that term is defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5000">section 5000(b)(1)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 without regard to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5000">section 5000(d)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986).</text>
									</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8B83F64A53D146BC9C331D36502B7226"><enum>2606.</enum><header>Receipt of health care through the Department</header>
 <subsection id="H87030DFB2C8344BFBD5E53205F5F77B4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Contracts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any health insurance provider that provides a health plan for which health insurance support may be provided under this subchapter or subchapter II may enter into a contract with the Veterans Accountable Care Organization under which the medical personnel and facilities of the Veterans Accountable Care Organization may be treated as a designated provider for purposes of such health plan.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H36C96F23ED324123BC4B086F60900749"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Cost of care</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The cost, including any copayments, of any health care or treatment provided to a veteran by the Veterans Accountable Care Organization under a contact under subsection (a) shall be determined by the Veterans Accountable Care Organization.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCD6F5C2A21D0426291BF341F4355AB57"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Mechanism</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board of Directors of the Veterans Accountable Care Organization shall establish a mechanism through which the Veterans Accountable Care Organization enters into contracts with health insurance providers under subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H0037DAA47E6C482096DFEC23B73D1F65"><enum>2607.</enum><header>Pharmacy benefits</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A veteran who is enrolled in the VetsCare Choice program or the VetsCare Senior program may fill prescriptions at pharmacies of the Department.</text>
							</section></subchapter><subchapter id="HD8811E506E85423F8A03F270E96AD09E" style="USC"><enum>II</enum><header>Medicare-Eligible Veterans</header>
							<section id="H6469BA6906684E49B51C1C9D26244D13"><enum>2611.</enum><header>VetsCare Senior program: designation of recipients</header>
 <subsection id="H75CF715A848847A1A59732B962D8AEF7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The authorities for the provision of health insurance support under this subchapter may be referred to as the <quote>VetsCare Senior program</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA0AC6A11672F42C583381C7F17B7B463"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designation of recipients</header><text>Any veteran who receives health insurance support under this subchapter may be referred to in the receipt of support as participating in the <quote>VetsCare Senior program</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HD81E14D3FE3543CB93EB7103FEC48FE0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Relationship to care by Veterans Accountable Care Organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Health insurance support under this subchapter is in addition to any health care or medical services furnished to a veteran at a facility operated by the Veterans Accountable Care Organization.</text>
								</subsection></section><section commented="no" id="HC24027056C064426AF281BFCCCEAEE3A"><enum>2612.</enum><header>Medicare support</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H55042CF3AB43483D87D4BCE7A229BAFE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide health insurance support to each covered veteran equal to the costs incurred by such veteran for Medicare premiums and cost-sharing under parts A, B, C, and D of title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395</external-xref> et seq.) and for premiums and cost-sharing for Medicare supplemental policies under section 1882 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ss">42 U.S.C. 1395ss</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H62047913D31049ECAF8F7B995EF06C58"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Relationship with VetsCare Federal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, if a covered veteran is enrolled in the VetsCare Federal program under section 1701A of this title, the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395</external-xref> et seq.) (or a Medicare supplemental policy under section 1882 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ss">42 U.S.C. 1395ss</external-xref>)) shall be responsible for the payment of costs for any health care received by an eligible individual for a non-service connected disability up to the maximum amount allowable under such program (or supplemental policy) for such health care before the VetsCare Federal program is responsible for any such costs, if applicable.</text>
								</subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H54E51E82F49446578A7A535FBD86841B"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Availability of payment or reimbursement</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD30AAC55F1C9417EB87E30D718A1F686"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commencement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Health insurance support under this subchapter shall commence being available as follows:</text> <subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA4E3F872B4A949DF9DE1C6E44A74E887"><enum>(A)</enum><text>With respect to covered veterans in priority group 1, 2, or 3, on the first day of the first month that begins on or after the date described in section 2(c)(3) of the <short-title>Veterans Empowerment Act</short-title>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94FAD7F675AD4657AD57BFF3515452B2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to covered veterans in a priority group other than 1, 2, or 3, on the first day of the first month that begins on or after the date that is 180 days after the commencement date under paragraph (1).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC9C67A85095E45C4B36EE5D514B992A4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exclusion of certain veterans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered veteran is not eligible for health insurance support under this section if such veteran—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H290E9669D329418BB6AF8AF7AB575299"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">first enrolls in the system of annual patient enrollment established and operated by the Secretary under section 1705(a) of this title on or after the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H273800BE39CB4BB4A7478AA9A90151FF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is in priority group 7 or 8.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H560AD537E3B142788CD6A0753E04359D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3DDF38135A164416829159EC989DF011"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>cost-sharing</term>, in connection with the receipt of health care and treatment under the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395</external-xref> et seq.) or Medicare supplemental policies under section 1882 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ss">42 U.S.C. 1395ss</external-xref>), means any copayments, deductibles, or other charges imposed, collected, or otherwise required by a health insurance provider or health care provider in connection with receipt of health care and treatment under such program or supplemental policies.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H67EFF638574B433FB04311E4C4E30CEB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>covered veteran</term> means a veteran receiving benefits under the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H593A68B5B38044AD9C1E3C0FF10D2412"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>priority group</term> means the priority groups established by the Secretary for purposes of the enrollment of veterans in the patient enrollment system under section 1705(a) of this title.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></subchapter></chapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5924762EF11A44F6B244F54720F0831B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of chapters at the beginning title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to chapter 24 the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H194919E3F886400EAF14D1A72011FE43" style="OLC">
					<toc>
						<multi-column-toc-entry bold="off" level="section"><toc-enum>Chapter 26.</toc-enum><level-header level="section">Veterans Independence in Health Care</level-header><target>2601</target></multi-column-toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H8F31550DE2B940658EC6E40D54ECE158"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="HAA3D5909C9F44A0388B66E7881B4891E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Minimum essential coverage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5000A">Section 5000A(f)(1)(A)(v)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>or 18</quote> and inserting <quote>, 18, or 26</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0CAF3C103319401CA280238972FD4F1C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Medicare part B</header> <subparagraph id="HABDD18A425D84E90A57335E342894D85"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Non-application of late enrollment penalty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1839(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395r">42 U.S.C. 1395r(b)</external-xref>) is amended, in the second sentence, by inserting <quote>or months for which the individual can demonstrate that the individual was enrolled in the VetsCare Senior program under subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/26">chapter 26</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code</quote> after <quote>an individual described in section 1837(k)(3)</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HECB0CAFDB9A84DE991BE600BBFD7C5F9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Special enrollment period</header><text>Section 1837 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395p">42 U.S.C. 1395p</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H667EBA9EE40441C795C04C736DA0971F" style="OLC">
							<subsection commented="no" id="HD33CD427664C4CBBB2C78006787FD689"><enum>(m)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H21A7A9AC1CB149BA8A862876DCA9FE86"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any individual who is enrolled in the VetsCare Senior program under subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/26">chapter 26</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code at the time the individual is entitled to part A under section 226 or section 226A and who is eligible to enroll but who has elected not to enroll (or to be deemed enrolled) during the individual’s initial enrollment period, there shall be a special enrollment period as specified by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD6C6123EF3144DB4914A094195659E31" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In the case of an individual who enrolls during the special enrollment period provided under paragraph (1), the coverage period under this part shall begin on such date specified by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HFFD9A2C485A9499E930FD17CD006C97F" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An individual may only enroll during the special enrollment period provided under paragraph (1) one time during the individual’s lifetime.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3636169D14834FA280662E8D6CA614E9" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall collaborate with the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Commissioner of Social Security to provide for the accurate identification of individuals described in paragraph (1). The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall provide such individuals with notification with respect to this subsection. The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall collaborate with the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Commissioner of Social Security to ensure appropriate follow up pursuant to any notification provided under the preceding sentence.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H775FD39E722642FA8A1B1D2300E6834C"><enum>6.</enum><header>Coordination between VetsCare Choice program and eligibility to make contributions to health
			 savings accounts</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="HEAD1704EDA9C4A4DB6C8D831223CA77B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/223">Section 223(c)(1)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of clause (ii), by striking the period at the end of clause (iii) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new clause:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H112A5E05EB504883AED561FAF4EDE9ED" style="OLC"> <clause commented="no" id="HC2CEF52FEEC647F3878489378E6F8673"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>coverage for health insurance support under the VetsCare Choice program under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/26">chapter 26</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF764616BB3AD45E29CBD3903B20E40FF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Denial of deduction for amounts not includible in gross income</header><text>Subsection (b) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/223">section 223</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block act-name="" id="H42B9B8B0B88448A4B3C13973281B6F05" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HC953613B73FC4768818A594E6B168475"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Amounts not includible in gross income</header><text>No amount paid to a health savings account of an individual shall be taken into account under subsection (a) if (without regard to this section) such amount, when paid to or on behalf of such individual, is excluded from gross income of the individual or exempt from taxation under any provision of Federal law.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3F416672010449D0B3D6C522EBA11FD8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to amounts paid to a health savings account (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/223">section 223(d)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H6E8CDE5DC7754B488DD95FC9D3CD1931"><enum>7.</enum><header>Publication of health care information</header>
 <subsection id="HCBC7C1CD85C44487B3949F26C927E62C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall make available to the public on an ongoing basis information about the operations of the Veterans Health Administration in a manner similar to publication of information under the Medicare Accountable Care Organization program to better monitor and support continuous improvement in the Veterans Health Administration.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H575722CEE5E6416E8670EA3FCD6CE682"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The information published under subsection (a) shall include information about the operations of the Veterans Health Administration, including metrics regarding quality, safety, patient experience, timeliness, and cost-effectiveness.</text>
			</subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8FC205684CB34D4CAD0AB2BFF70C7DD9" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>8.</enum><header>Veterans' eligibility for long-term care insurance</header>
 <subsection id="H290CC8533F6645268439C0667810121B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 9001 of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HD40EDC3021024E92AF2D9A5F59BCCA98"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (5) through (10) as (6) through (11), respectively;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD2302DFAD36A4BE0903366557AD9AFA6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (4) the following:</text> <quoted-block act-name="" id="HAB514925580D4D588861685568D71A36" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HB037001CAFC64288A67447051ABB6E2F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Veteran</header><text>The term <term>veteran</term> has the same meaning given the term in section 101(2) of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H78B8104385824D96BE40337D9D0F25C3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), as so redesignated—</text> <subparagraph id="H0721E35778FE4739A4B578F6CE0D5DD9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>or (4).</quote> and inserting <quote>(4), or (5).</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD9468799B3E7484793FD61F307BD4788"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>(1) or (3).</quote> and inserting <quote>(1), (3), or (5).</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F788B05C85A45CAADE592187410EF46"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>or (4)</quote> and inserting <quote>(4), or (5)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCBA8192928C84B8DB43FF44525E1E92A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking <quote>or (4)</quote> and inserting <quote>(4), or (5)</quote>;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6131604791743A08FBB76F398FC6163"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (7), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>or (5).</quote> and inserting <quote>(5), or (6).</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H40FCB15C6B1941D39E57FD3B781AAEA6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in paragraph (11), as so redesignated—</text> <subparagraph id="H07AEA176A9B44C1E901914C4785B882E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>Commerce; and</quote> and inserting <quote>Commerce;</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6249552F337429984507AE182BB403E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking <quote>Services.</quote> and inserting <quote>Services; and</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2C4F6323BB0487D89F8CAC2DEE0857A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (D):</text>
						<quoted-block act-name="" id="HAE8B3FB03B13460DA45049393397C9B6" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H193932852B2E4D18B7F6F8E5C8445BDC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>with respect to a veteran, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H05FE5D35CDC74BC69AB50390417C0BD1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title 5, United States Code, is amended as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="HD25A79675B3C49E78B2C6A97FB268DFF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 9002 is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H997C31697E8D46EA83ED89CBC47FFBAA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>or (5)</quote> and inserting <quote>(5), or (6)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E88F205BBAB4C9B89451D1EA7FA1A59"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (e)—</text> <clause id="HD588FC8AC25844B291323F26EAB8F082"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>or (4)</quote> and inserting <quote>(4), or (5)</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEC1DC2AB97FC41C3945279A3AB3DCEE3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>section 9001(9)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 9001(10)</quote>.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H718DCDFD11D84E43A5B51158F4B86741"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 9004(d) is amended by inserting after <quote>withheld under subsection (b)</quote> the following: <quote>, who is an enrollee by virtue of being a veteran described in section 9001(5) of this title,</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9F9BB09F304B470E8F48CCD7D5759A84"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Section 9008(c) is amended by striking <quote>(3) or (4)</quote> and inserting <quote>(3), (4), or (5)</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

