<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H23D24692212C41B0ACDBD7FF4746C7FA" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1680 IH: Women’s Business Centers Improvements Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1680</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170322">March 22, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000387">Mr. Knight</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000586">Mr. Lawson of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Small Business Act to improve the women’s business center program, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HB9DAAE7E291F4E4589238D27A596FA5D" style="OLC">
 <section id="H5A120225D28D4CAA8E3E70627FB19703" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Women’s Business Centers Improvements Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H6ADCAAD7B929428394E1E4DB6E661F2C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Office of women’s business ownership</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 29(g) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/656">15 U.S.C. 656(g)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD9A55CE33B5C409E906864BAC0670D5B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking subparagraphs (B) and (C) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HE369B0B394894FD8970FAA82067C5352" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HFA3FE9301497468EA14AEC07F6AAE76E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>The responsibilities of the Assistant Administrator shall be to administer the programs and services of the Office of Women’s Business Ownership.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19F98E397DC1418A9E496688F372CE46"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Assistant Administrator shall perform the following functions with respect to the Office of Women’s Business Ownership:</text>
 <clause id="H1CCD290BA3604613A8C8D0171CFA8239"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Recommend the annual administrative and program budgets of the Office and eligible entities receiving a grant under the Women’s Business Center Program.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H11E6A6C8079B4A9F934AFB3BE53ED445"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Review the annual budgets submitted by each eligible entity receiving a grant under the Women’s Business Center Program.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H49AB597248E241D48BE898DFC36212B7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Select applicants to receive grants to operate a women’s business center after reviewing information required by this section, including the budget of each applicant.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE0A68DDAF0E4450393E9AABA2F5E498F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Collaborate with other Federal departments and agencies, State and local governments, not-for-profit organizations, and for-profit enterprises to maximize utilization of taxpayer dollars and reduce (or eliminate) any duplication among the programs overseen by the Office of Women’s Business Ownership and those of other entities that provide similar services to women entrepreneurs.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4731CEE832FC4B00BC039DF63EED249B"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Maintain a clearinghouse to provide for the dissemination and exchange of information between women’s business centers.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H104B4A388B6A47F59D80D24E9516E261"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Serve as the vice chairperson of the Interagency Committee on Women’s Business Enterprise and as the liaison for the National Women’s Business Council.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD3E24A1F77964629B7B6F5FD12932F52"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HF5BA0376B6524084A6869CDF883AAAAD" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H0DD977CE71AE4D2781541309B0F68549"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Mission</header><text>The mission of the Office of Women’s Business Ownership shall be to assist women entrepreneurs to start, grow, and compete in global markets by providing quality support with access to capital, access to markets, job creation, growth, and counseling by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H539260C140204322AFB5B54E67382EE2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>fostering participation of women entrepreneurs in the economy by overseeing a network of women’s business centers throughout States and territories;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BDF15EDBC684D0C9D45E3FB6FC7E551"><enum>(B)</enum><text>creating public-private partnerships to support women entrepreneurs and conduct outreach and education to startup and existing small business concerns owned and controlled by women; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H43292B4436B8425E84972057F1D8F8E1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>working with other programs overseen by the Administrator to ensure women are well-represented and being served and to identify gaps where participation by women could be increased.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0FCB19E1890A4013908A5797F3B72945"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Accreditation program</header>
 <subparagraph id="HD508E38210094E75B23473F1D86B1446"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of this paragraph, the Administrator shall establish standards for an accreditation program for accrediting eligible entities receiving a grant under this section, after notice and the opportunity for public comment of no less than 60 days.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF7482EFA0BF481496B9D5444A27A3C0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Transition provision</header><text>Before the date on which standards are established under subparagraph (A), the Administrator may not terminate a grant under this section absent evidence of fraud or other criminal misconduct by the recipient.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92DE1DEFED2545FD8F1544F89B72A32A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Contracting authority</header><text>The Administrator may provide financial assistance, by contract or otherwise, to a relevant national women’s business center representative association to provide assistance in establishing the standards required under subparagraph (A) or for carrying out an accreditation program pursuant to such standards.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H18D5B4708F9A4A61BC7A3AA72FE152E4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Women’s business center program</header>
 <subsection id="H2788FBA187584E6AB07F94F77F446C32"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Section 29(a) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/656">15 U.S.C. 656(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HED7C8751C027414F9E13AEAB34293233"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (4);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2009DFE16278454CB1846533C0DE4E0C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (2) and (3) as paragraphs (3) and (4), respectively;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H473076F91C1B47D1AB2F784C338F28FD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (1) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H8A36F238CD62490FBF11AB1F44C1562C" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H44D66A79F9FF47F48FA863C7D5247C55"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HE3A382B1540A4FF1AFBC94F1C6383A97"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Code;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61293E0E78044357843C855836C4ECA9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a State, regional, or local economic development organization, so long as the organization certifies that grant funds received under this section will not be co-mingled with other funds;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2E5F554394941A1831D298FA1CF4558"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an institution of higher education, unless such institution is currently receiving a grant under section 21;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9B2A50900C7488790AEA488324DDAE0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a development, credit, or finance corporation chartered by a State, so long as the corporation certifies that grant funds received under this section will not be co-mingled with other funds; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25B11A80A7694F7F9D9942E3583EA641"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any combination of entities listed in subparagraphs (A) through (D);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB203ABC8CF2C437D87325541DD108F7B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H7B9F0D041EA947EF9B6E50BF398F4928" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H91262D62954F4E0485EB169DCE8328DD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>women’s business center</term> means the location at which counseling and training on the management, operations (including manufacturing, services, and retail), access to capital, international trade, Government procurement opportunities, and any other matter is needed to start, maintain, or expand a small business concern owned and controlled by women.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1C30CD6AC64540BABA2237D652F293A5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>Section 29(b) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/656">15 U.S.C. 656(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HCE00F778A1B643F1A6918A8D593F8D85"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) as subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C), respectively, and adjusting the margins accordingly;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H85848C6B4C6E4B859B4AFF620FBDA90C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The Administration</quote> and all that follows through <quote>5-year projects</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HBE0BE3E8C31A43928C68953CACCAB614" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HFD848335D4884647AE5B79BF2190380B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established a Women’s Business Center Program under which the Administrator may provide a grant to any eligible entity to operate one or more women’s business centers</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8063914F89C141948072A007BEAEFC89"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The projects shall</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H67799BFBBF2B435FB2C597F224C29B78" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H4E7D0AB6BC8E4947A238AF90ABBDC8F0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>The women’s business centers shall be designed to provide counseling and training that meets the needs of women, especially socially or economically disadvantaged women, and shall</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H16F75EF99B134D77B18E960DC0BEEE68"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H50081A5FF1B442478D6461B23F813D1B" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HE6DB0F0B68154AE68194DD60522E6085"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Amount of grants</header> <subparagraph id="H23B3665DDCE54D20B456BD65D616C015"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amount of a grant provided under this subsection to an eligible entity per project year shall be not more than $185,000 (as such amount is annually adjusted by the Administrator to reflect the change in inflation).</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C82C82059CE4404A10B63DB6E4B2013"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional grants</header>
 <clause id="H6CDC7409DCDA40629FA747D91D3D3DAA"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), with respect to an eligible entity that has received $185,000 in grants under this subsection in a project year, the Administrator may award an additional grant under this subsection of up to $65,000 during such project year if the Administrator determines that the eligible entity—</text>
 <subclause id="H811859F4E61A429D8E0085A79BB9C7AA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>agrees to obtain, after its application has been approved and notice of award has been issued, cash contributions from non-Federal sources of 1 non-Federal dollar for each Federal dollar;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H4D5F1283089146298FBF74032CD1BCA1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is in good standing with the Women’s Business Center Program; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HCA72949296B241DF8DA2F9978548B13E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>has met performance goals for the previous project year, if applicable.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HE8BE94E4E8FB406AB7D070331CB7D9B1"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>The Administrator may only award additional grants under clause (i)—</text> <subclause id="HBA0A8299E7F147F98F79DD3786EAA2EF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>during the 3rd and 4th quarters of the fiscal year; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HDA09F272022D4973AD163FDD266901D1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>from unobligated amounts made available to the Administrator to carry out this section.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1C19712175E4043B1CE68C06CF0A704"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Notice and comment required</header><text>The Administrator may only make a change to the standards by which an eligible entity obtains or maintains grants under this section, the standards for accreditation, or any other requirement for the operation of a women’s business center if the Administrator first provides notice and the opportunity for public comment, as set forth in section 553(b) of title 5, United States Code, without regard to any exceptions provided for under such section.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2F634ACF1D3242BEA228DA23269B1F47"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conditions of participation</header><text>Section 29(c) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/656">15 U.S.C. 656(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H49F64EB0228542A9A91F4CF4729A0DC9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H925DA6D97B8F4739B2B72347FFD88189"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the recipient organization</quote> and inserting <quote>an eligible entity</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92064A3E81A54F5A94E0749439CA3DFD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>financial assistance</quote> and inserting <quote>a grant</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H061FDB6814B64A1E9FD161973FD2FB69"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text> <subparagraph id="H6830C5BC527C431FB08A6AC7211DC429"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>financial assistance authorized pursuant to this section may be made by grant, contract, or cooperative agreement and</quote> and inserting <quote>grants authorized pursuant to this section</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3CE575CB609747DCA4E3E8FC6C7C6446"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the second sentence, by striking <quote>a recipient organization</quote> and inserting <quote>an eligible entity</quote>;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD744AFE755BA40F8A8F5FB9ADBDCB7EF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDFF426A9038A44E5B5A82F332E3E7EE0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>recipient of assistance</quote> and inserting <quote>eligible entity</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96F9BB41D7734248A374FA0D35E5B04B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>during any project, it shall not be eligible thereafter</quote> and inserting <quote>during any project for 2 consecutive years, the eligible entity shall not be eligible at any time after that 2-year period</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H864B125C086C411792CEE04E4343782D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>such organization</quote> and inserting <quote>the eligible entity</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H739A98F293924453841336B9DD293F6F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the recipient</quote> and inserting <quote>the eligible entity</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H22CB36E8BAE847C09AA29F81521FEF95"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H43CD8D2CECED4DBA919D43940323C530" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H594C60F28F824107B9C94DC2F91CC0AF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Separation of project and funds</header><text>An eligible entity shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEFD4801DDEAD4117BF733B0361B9F105"><enum>(A)</enum><text>carry out a project under this section separately from other projects, if any, of the eligible entity; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCC44790A481487B9D35A61AA856DA84"><enum>(B)</enum><text>separately maintain and account for any grants under this section.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H230A8D119BE4425196A82F9442A57839"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Examination of eligible entities</header> <subparagraph id="HA37CB9D47BC442838DCF247BB8848701"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Required site visit</header><text>Each applicant, prior to receiving a grant under this section, shall have a site visit by an employee of the Administration, in order to ensure that the applicant has sufficient resources to provide the services for which the grant is being provided.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB78BDEA8D58A47BEAF6ECA3FF77FFF85"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Annual review</header><text>An employee of the Administration shall—</text> <clause id="HB8CA272BDF23437AB4FB15223DE21843"><enum>(i)</enum><text>conduct an annual review of the compliance of each eligible entity receiving a grant under this section with the grant agreement, including a financial examination; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7EAB1F44DAC643AAA6595EAA5DF37905"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide such review to the eligible entity as required under subsection (l).</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H50696B899E024963AE869FA295EBF152"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Remediation of problems</header> <subparagraph id="H53B7C605AA524EC1BE5BD515E0F59A7F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Plan of action</header><text>If a review of an eligible entity under paragraph (6)(B) identifies any problems, the eligible entity shall, within 45 calendar days of receiving such review, provide the Assistant Administrator with a plan of action, including specific milestones, for correcting such problems.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3317186A2FAA432D87475904A0301F1B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Plan of action review by the assistant administrator</header><text>The Assistant Administrator shall review each plan of action submitted under subparagraph (A) within 30 calendar days of receiving such plan and—</text>
 <clause id="H25AC21E2CC4F4547B262EA60BF66FC6A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>if the Assistant Administrator determines that such plan will bring the eligible entity into compliance with all the terms of the grant agreement, approve such plan;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE6CE99BE63DD41D1AE78C00F0405F87B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the Assistant Administrator determines that such plan is inadequate to remedy the problems identified in the annual review to which the plan of action relates, the Assistant Administrator shall set forth such reasons in writing and provide such determination to the eligible entity within 15 calendar days of such determination.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE97D8472B6348C7920A236FD6F0AC2D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Amendment to plan of action</header><text>An eligible entity receiving a determination under subparagraph (B)(ii) shall have 30 calendar days from the receipt of the determination to amend the plan of action to satisfy the problems identified by the Assistant Administrator and resubmit such plan to the Assistant Administrator.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A8F1901A54D4A72806E3126A9134B65"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Amended plan review by the assistant administrator</header><text>Within 15 calendar days of the receipt of an amended plan of action under subparagraph (C), the Assistant Administrator shall either approve or reject such plan and provide such approval or rejection in writing to the eligible entity.</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4C4131D91D14B32B17AA499AE5EF3D8"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Appeal of assistant administrator determination</header>
 <clause id="HB93F2AB24E3D4EC4ADE6BCC43EC3D0B0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Assistant Administrator rejects an amended plan under subparagraph (D), the eligible entity shall have the opportunity to appeal such decision to the Administrator, who may delegate such appeal to an appropriate officer of the Administration.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H99F2A861722040E7A0EBD7A35F640E2E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Opportunity for explanation</header><text>Any appeal described under clause (i) shall provide an opportunity for the eligible entity to provide, in writing, an explanation of why the eligible entity’s plan remedies the problems identified in the annual review.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4CFEB8C00CC84A18A7B00BA0607B09E9"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Notice of determination</header><text>The determination of the appeal shall be provided to the eligible entity, in writing, within 15 calendar days from the eligible entity’s filing of the appeal.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5E8F2AB623CB43DCA79FA76717C02D4A"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Effect of failure to act</header><text>If the Administrator fails to act on an appeal made under this subparagraph within the 15-calendar-day period specified under clause (iii), the eligible entity’s amended plan of action submitted under subparagraph (C) shall be deemed to be approved.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H83B09230E00048B2B8CDF9B7721BFE0B"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Termination of grant</header>
 <subparagraph id="H9395AE15E7254A4E86B862F6343E3934"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall issue regulations (after providing an opportunity for notice and comment) to provide that, if an eligible entity fails to comply with a plan of action approved by the Assistant Administrator under paragraph (7)(B)(i) or an amended plan of action approved by the Assistant Administrator under paragraph (7)(D) or approved on appeal under paragraph (7)(E), the Assistant Administrator shall terminate the grant provided to the eligible entity under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H32DA24EFECAD40FFBE1FB512D19A44FF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Appeal of termination</header><text>An eligible entity that has a grant terminated under subparagraph (A) shall have the opportunity to challenge the termination on the record and after an opportunity for a hearing.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB790F71C5E3A4AA39F6280F7DB1FF398"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Final agency action</header><text>The determination made pursuant to subparagraph (B) shall be considered final agency action for the purposes of chapter 7, title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H322B5BF373324FC2AC04D85D2141AF9C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Submission of 5-Year plan</header><text>Section 29(e) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/656">15 U.S.C. 656(e)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H23683051DC964B0ABF2F6DFB2BA093B7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>applicant organization</quote> and inserting <quote>eligible entity</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1135F114E9C2457986308F5958CCAC72"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>a recipient organization</quote> and inserting <quote>an eligible entity</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5BB98BEEEAF64250B583C26703EE9B34"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>financial assistance</quote> and inserting <quote>grants</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3EC9B3E3996F4840A108265AB5C4C6CF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by striking <quote>site</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H13AA5B9DA1E6423E86188103BE712F31"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Applications and criteria for initial grant</header><text>Subsection (f) of section 29 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/656">15 U.S.C. 656</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H6C2E221B3BFF4C928AA9E95BFBD5AA57" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="HEA545F23CFB943BDBD42DA71EB8975B1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Applications and criteria for initial grant</header>
 <paragraph id="H0D133AB3125A43FA96CCF6C0AACF8D8C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application</header><text>Each eligible entity desiring a grant under subsection (b) shall submit to the Administrator an application that contains—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H58E20592467448E9ADC847411860A3A7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a certification that the eligible entity—</text> <clause id="H852D2A6A5C5846AAB0F51974E5116EC3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has designated an executive director or program manager, who may be compensated using grant funds under subsection (b) or other sources, to manage the women’s business center for which a grant under subsection (b) is sought;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H64568C13113F4F5F8D332F3DC96A3380"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>meets the accounting and reporting requirements established by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49A18FA49A5E4A00B422987D63C8AAE8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information demonstrating that the eligible entity has the ability and resources to meet the needs of the market to be served by the women’s business center, including the ability to obtain the non-Federal contribution required under subsection (c);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB92FC7B88C1948A9AAC5721702559BB8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>information relating to the assistance to be provided by the women’s business center in the area in which the women’s business center is located;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCBF52FF3853C436CA43EED0EA77AE823"><enum>(D)</enum><text>information demonstrating the experience and effectiveness of the eligible entity in—</text> <clause id="H97BEBF496B0D4DF59C0DC1F079B47317"><enum>(i)</enum><text>conducting the services described under subsection (a)(5);</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7720F02BA9A943C9BA0F09938D5DDA28"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>providing training and services to a representative number of women who are socially or economically disadvantaged; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA10797E09C474EF98F1CCFFF052082F2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>working with resource partners of the Administration and other entities, such as universities; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H028D4356C1E84E62B2C062FB2BEEA078"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a 5-year plan that describes the ability of the eligible entity to provide the services described under subsection (a)(3), including to a representative number of women who are socially or economically disadvantaged.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB196967574364590B1B7DA88A690E988"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review and approval of applications for initial grants</header>
							<subparagraph id="H2A1D29790B6C466F9B8FEF6A3C1F8A5B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Review and selection of eligible entities</header>
 <clause id="H984EE154F8EA4D4997E22C52478EAB02"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall review applications to determine whether the applicant can meet obligations to perform the activities required by a grant under this section, including—</text>
 <subclause id="H03DB8E8CA1414B9CBE948934E14544D9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the experience of the applicant in conducting activities required by this section;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HFA69C8E9779D4CE798C4E0A1ACE89F32"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the amount of time needed for the applicant to commence operations should it be awarded a grant;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE6B2789634A142F2A710A9FB5B44105B"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the capacity of the applicant to meet the accreditation standards established by the Administrator in a timely manner;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HFC18300E2F494419A901CFD8611D6288"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the ability of the applicant to sustain operations for more than 5 years (including its ability to obtain sufficient non-Federal funds for that period);</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HAFEBAFC0B0304BDAB7EDF5BCCCA1BB82"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the location of the women’s business center and its proximity to other grant recipients under this section; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H98F5FA69C46C4822A0F0BA610FD0C802"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>the population density of the area to be served by the women’s business center.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H5E9D7C7CA27047CFB7A21414C3338DA4"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Selection criteria</header> <subclause id="H3C2D87D6439D4EB6BC41332F8498E990"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>The Administrator shall issue regulations (after providing an opportunity for notice and comment) to specify the criteria for review and selection of applicants under this subsection.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD751A3A105BB49BBB75116F1C3814883"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Modifications prohibited after announcement</header><text>With respect to a public announcement of any opportunity to be awarded a grant under this section made by the Administrator pursuant to subsection (l)(1), the Administrator may not modify regulations issued pursuant to subclause (I) with respect to such opportunity unless required to do so by an Act of Congress or an order of a Federal court.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H8A708360A9B243FBBA9880DDB637B36C"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this clause may be construed as prohibiting the Administrator from modifying the regulations issued pursuant to subclause (I) (after providing an opportunity for notice and comment) as such regulations apply to an opportunity to be awarded a grant under this section that the Administrator has not yet publicly announced pursuant to subsection (l)(1).</text>
									</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB77D4EF906614FCA9DEFC265C6D88272"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Record retention</header>
 <clause id="H8CFF83FE6D1D43D891D6775F8DAD1319"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall maintain a copy of each application submitted under this subsection for not less than 5 years.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA5753E6110D04E5A988DC26EC55AACE3"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Paperwork reduction</header><text>The Administrator shall take steps to reduce, to the maximum extent practicable, the paperwork burden associated with carrying out clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H67ACC0B642B7479EAC28DD02A722174E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Notification requirements under the women’s business center program</header><text>Section 29 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/656">15 U.S.C. 656</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after subsection (k) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H8A90E1443BB241F19621CF5B0D56D783" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H405901065368428197266A51E666EC65"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Notification requirements under the women’s business center program</header><text>The Administrator shall provide—</text> <paragraph id="H6739E62277C1403DBD67F2B1BD83FC49"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a public announcement of any opportunity to be awarded grants under this section, and such announcement shall include the standards by which such award will be made, including the regulations issued pursuant to subsection (f)(2)(A)(ii);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4C73E473DA4C476AA8C932FD0E649EC2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the opportunity for any applicant for a grant under this section that failed to obtain such a grant a debriefing with the Assistant Administrator to review the reasons for the applicant’s failure; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF0EFCD453E6D4B8E96244B0EADE2F0D9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>with respect to any site visit or evaluation of an eligible entity receiving a grant under this section that is carried out by an officer or employee of the Administration (other than the Inspector General), a copy of the site visit report or evaluation, as applicable, within 30 calendar days of the completion of such vision or evaluation.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0BDDC747C4C04AF79CEF1A9A9758C8DA"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Continued funding for centers</header><text>Section 29(m) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/656">15 U.S.C. 656(m)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H7511C4B7802A40BD8EAAD12D2F1E6A27"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (3) and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H9A75A46D367E4C83BC1791C1B9B2EC99" style="OLC">
						<paragraph id="HC97CA1CAD036460DB1DCBDEB5C97E7FD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application and approval for continuation grants</header>
 <subparagraph id="HB5209B4E194B47D8A6C7023971D487BD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Solicitation of applications</header><text>The Administrator shall solicit applications and award continuation grants under this subsection for the first fiscal year beginning after the date of enactment of this paragraph, and every third fiscal year thereafter.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C31E7A05BED472B863D4342FA63F004"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents of application</header><text>Each eligible entity desiring a grant under this subsection shall submit to the Administrator an application that contains—</text>
 <clause id="H2BC423B6B35243298BFC9F97383888DD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a certification that the applicant—</text> <subclause id="H140668EA17D6432F83DDBB2821379C64"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is an eligible entity;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H9762D2889A1F4C06A9E103E364EFA8CA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>has designated an executive director or program manager to manage the women’s business center operated by the applicant; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HC98DC19C0F1C41F0843BD1EFD27457B9"><enum>(III)</enum><text>as a condition of receiving a grant under this subsection, agrees—</text> <item id="H48BB25B54690433687E4D8E0DBFABEA3"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>to receive a site visit as part of the final selection process, at the discretion of the Administrator; and</text>
 </item><item id="HBDD182F40E2B4F1284D14628BF975468"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>to remedy any problem identified pursuant to the site visit under item (aa);</text> </item></subclause></clause><clause id="H0EA68E7667994C0F97E76EE62228E8E5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>information demonstrating that the applicant has the ability and resources to meet the needs of the market to be served by the women’s business center for which a grant under this subsection is sought, including the ability to obtain the non-Federal contribution required under paragraph (4)(C);</text>
 </clause><clause id="H994FD212A5A44BE48E5BF5A452C70910"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>information relating to assistance to be provided by the women’s business center in the geographic area served by the women’s business center for which a grant under this subsection is sought;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE7AB5D9AC82247048A16F1256ACBAC89"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>information demonstrating that the applicant has worked with resource partners of the Administration and other entities;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEBB787C95A674243B374EDE3EE68C036"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a 3-year plan that describes the services provided by the women’s business center for which a grant under this subsection is sought—</text>
 <subclause id="HEDC1BB4095D243179876D4423D71F767"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to serve women who are business owners or potential business owners by conducting training and counseling activities; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H77051C3866F34B05855117E47FDFC537"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to provide training and services to a representative number of women who are socially or economically disadvantaged; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HB617616A48E2449CAFA3408CA243F76F"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>any additional information that the Administrator may reasonably require.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83102CC9F73142F3B2F8F64B05F0E887"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Review and approval of applications for grants</header> <clause id="H4B88C27FA5774EE5BB5F31E67A695805"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator—</text>
 <subclause id="HDA1E8025C61E43E8A21433925FB3ED30"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall review each application submitted under subparagraph (B), based on the information described in such subparagraph and the criteria set forth under clause (ii) of this subparagraph; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H0FBDCC1A50314FC5BD5E0560752EE1D7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>as part of the final selection process, may, at the discretion of the Administrator, conduct a site visit to each women’s business center for which a grant under this subsection is sought, in particular to evaluate the women’s business center using the selection criteria described in clause (ii)(II).</text>
									</subclause></clause><clause id="H1A9382AABF25499D8A7895CDCC576A1E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Selection criteria</header>
 <subclause id="H010B6F82A29F46EAA13F5281FDC6B774"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall evaluate applicants for grants under this subsection in accordance with selection criteria that are—</text>
 <item id="H05B88FD852194C3BBD4B4609A6A0FCEB"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>established before the date on which applicants are required to submit the applications;</text> </item><item id="H7D73BFEA132A40E5AA501A037A51A744"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>stated in terms of relative importance; and</text>
 </item><item id="H4E5F1CC2DDDD437F820A6B1FF60DBD33"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>publicly available and stated in each solicitation for applications for grants under this subsection made by the Administrator.</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H8B8724564934432CBF4DDE558D2FCAAB"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Required criteria</header><text>The selection criteria for a grant under this subsection shall include—</text> <item id="H1512105FCD3948E59C3901B9D156FDA0"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the total number of entrepreneurs served by the applicant;</text>
 </item><item id="H00625B6AD1A6413EABCE45E7512DE783"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the total number of new startup companies assisted by the applicant;</text> </item><item id="H89439322D56A4898B6002863F7DF8546"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the percentage of clients of the applicant that are socially or economically disadvantaged;</text>
 </item><item id="HA266DE6CFA62445D807C181D40382651"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>the percentage of individuals in the community served by the applicant who are socially or economically disadvantaged;</text>
 </item><item id="H6A1A4BFF85F6493F8C7B9AA0AE555352"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>the successful accreditation of the applicant under the accreditation program developed under subsection (g)(5); and</text>
 </item><item id="H2C321F0748C247D78C47B9F6B6F491A7"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>any additional criteria that the Administrator may reasonably require.</text> </item></subclause></clause><clause id="HEFE983847F334B58872FF5476AD73DA3"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Conditions for continued funding</header><text>In determining whether to make a grant under this subsection, the Administrator—</text>
 <subclause id="H0600EA06ADF143E4B805C16C21A4A463"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall consider the results of the most recent evaluation of the women’s business center for which a grant under this subsection is sought, and, to a lesser extent, previous evaluations; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H26B77E4339754067A898255FE2DE7B31"><enum>(II)</enum><text>may withhold a grant under this subsection, if the Administrator determines that the applicant has failed to provide the information required to be provided under this paragraph, or the information provided by the applicant is inadequate.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H020A0A9B8ECC4E09972522F385F53231"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>Not later than 60 calendar days after the date of each deadline to submit applications under this paragraph, the Administrator shall approve or deny each submitted application and notify the applicant for each such application of the approval or denial.</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H71143A0402064EDB96CDA9FD57D81053"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Record retention</header>
 <clause id="H790E342568A8486C879F4083203F28E6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall maintain a copy of each application submitted under this paragraph for not less than 5 years.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H69409A8B8E4C40EF9CB9045EBEC82A55"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Paperwork reduction</header><text>The Administrator shall take steps to reduce, to the maximum extent practicable, the paperwork burden associated with carrying out clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEDF0224FEB0B4211A05C683586D6B1A6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (5) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H16744EA891C445258D13EB132773C3D0" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H18F74A104EA946A78428D970893899DB"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Award to previous recipients</header><text>There shall be no limitation on the number of times the Administrator may award a grant to an applicant under this subsection.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H929C587E9074424F8239A7A65374518D"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header><text>Section 29 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/656">15 U.S.C. 656</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HA30963403A1D47A98BDA3F4574937BA8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (h)(2), by striking <quote>to award a contract (as a sustainability grant) under subsection (l) or</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H79010A53918B4DBA9276E16ED1CA99CB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (j)(1), by striking <quote>The Administration</quote> and inserting <quote>Not later than November 1 of each year, the Administrator</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF8D439453D70451CA384AA8115CB8AA1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (k)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC39849BCF7CB4831B792A0562C820681"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking paragraphs (1) and (4);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6866C10121FB4D04ABC815614261D57C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting before paragraph (2) the following:</text>
						<quoted-block id="H9013E8727A5949D98EA713606387713B" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HE0C6DD4E1E704AC28376F35FA658791C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Administration to carry out this section, to remain available until expended, $21,750,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2021.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A288F498067408E9C816F83A4351055"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking subparagraph (B) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H2B05378F77BF4466A2291F0671E9C42A" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H46213AF0854D4F10BB7E1AE081B6989D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>Of the amount made available under this subsection for a fiscal year, the following amounts shall be available for selection panel costs, costs associated with maintaining an accreditation program, and post-award conference costs:</text>
 <clause id="HDFCD43AA66A94205A1D332D3C2108F24"><enum>(i)</enum><text>For the first fiscal year beginning after the date of the enactment of this subparagraph, 2.65 percent.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2A28A8AB4F0F49CEA1A48566F7431198"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>For the second fiscal year beginning after the date of the enactment of this subparagraph and each fiscal year thereafter through fiscal year 2021, 2.5 percent.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBDF6C6121F3A4B38BCB1D8E48A82E1AB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (m)—</text> <subparagraph id="HFE642E3F9AC44A7D88631680749E4966"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>subsection (b) or (l)</quote> and inserting <quote>this subsection or subsection (b)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7516F22757C4E3B89C5A8FF7258D4B5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)(D), by striking <quote>or subsection (l)</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8E0CA3525B1B429FA189975AFFDDD93B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Effect on existing grants</header> <paragraph id="H34E4ACA173454667B7B139F259358D9F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header><text>A nonprofit organization receiving a grant under section 29(m) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/656">15 U.S.C. 656(m)</external-xref>), as in effect on the day before the date of enactment of this Act, shall continue to receive the grant under the terms and conditions in effect for the grant on the day before the date of enactment of this Act, except that the nonprofit organization may not apply for a continuation of the grant under section 29(m)(5) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/656">15 U.S.C. 656(m)(5)</external-xref>), as in effect on the day before the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H35DDEC5119A54CA7A8443FF022B0CE57"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Length of continuation grant</header><text>The Administrator of the Small Business Administration may award a grant under section 29(m) of the Small Business Act to a nonprofit organization receiving a grant under section 29(m) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/656">15 U.S.C. 656(m)</external-xref>), as in effect on the day before the date of enactment of this Act, for the period—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8F638230B8AF4A74BF64E731D0E059BC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>beginning on the day after the last day of the grant agreement under such section 29(m); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C1F255F961D457C895D9D6CCBBE7150"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ending at the end of the third fiscal year beginning after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC4C05DA93A184BD096BA40919EBBB06C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Matching requirements under women’s business center program</header>
 <subsection id="HCB43736A32254C5591C07FB5FD1ADAAD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 29(c) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/656">15 U.S.C. 656(c)</external-xref>), as amended by section 3 of this Act, is further amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDD6B4BADE20C42BEB93F19E46735AE12"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>As a condition</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to paragraph (6), as a condition</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB23A4A567D4846FF9FC729C7CA662013"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="HEC41DDDA875447B5B3AE0F257C8D655B" style="OLC">
						<paragraph id="HE38A009D6595473BA549DD4BED2BC98F"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Waiver of non-federal share</header>
 <subparagraph id="HE7B050E9B6984026A318B5010E167F36"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon request by an eligible entity, and in accordance with this paragraph, the Administrator may waive, in whole or in part, the requirement to obtain non-Federal funds under this subsection for counseling and training activities of the eligible entity carried out using a grant under this section for a fiscal year. The Administrator may not waive the requirement for an eligible entity to obtain non-Federal funds under this paragraph for more than a total of 2 consecutive fiscal years.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E8F64AFCD124A13A8DCF32CD920FE4A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In determining whether to waive the requirement to obtain non-Federal funds under this paragraph, the Administrator shall consider—</text>
 <clause id="HAFCE056AA75344858E6B52506A6F73ED"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the economic conditions affecting the eligible entity;</text> </clause><clause id="H81C1F0DC057748D3B0FFA1C781E75C10"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the impact a waiver under this paragraph would have on the credibility of the Women’s Business Center Program under this section;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H33FDF726246A4F44A3C5B12904B976F6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the demonstrated ability of the eligible entity to raise non-Federal funds; and</text> </clause><clause id="H64FF3A4CA79A439297E44DEFB7A047BF"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the performance of the eligible entity.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8EE86B46142E4151AB7442A3FCED86E5"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Administrator may not waive the requirement to obtain non-Federal funds under this paragraph if granting the waiver would undermine the credibility of the Women’s Business Center Program.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6BE80603B46C4DD38A06188147554176"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Solicitation</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, eligible entity may—</text> <subparagraph id="H9F01D523278847EABF8157EE8EAB9B45"><enum>(A)</enum><text>solicit cash and in-kind contributions from private individuals and entities to be used to carry out the activities of the eligible entity under the project conducted under this section; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB74EBD6F48BB47C5A271995561E9D5BE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>use amounts made available by the Administrator under this section for the cost of such solicitation and management of the contributions received.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF7C0E090B8245F5838C98826F61EF0C"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Excess non-federal dollars</header><text>The amount of non-Federal dollars obtained by an eligible entity that is above the amount that is required to be obtained by the eligible entity under this subsection shall not be subject to the requirements of part 200 of title 2, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor thereto, if such amount of non-Federal dollars—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H608AFB51A0E14132BA250D848E5DE645"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is not used as matching funds for purposes of implementing the Women’s Business Center Program; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF82945C7B51B40EC9FC8113A0FD6EFEA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>was not obtained using funds from the Women’s Business Center Program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2BD477B65EA64DC292D6058A753B2482"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header>
 <paragraph id="H395EC152D8DE4AD0ACB1F35110577224"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator of Small Business Administration shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H839E3FD5B1E5445D9804446E6DE58373"><enum>(A)</enum><text>except as provided in paragraph (2), and not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of this Act, publish in the Federal Register proposed regulations by the Administrator to carry out the amendments made to section 29 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/656">15 U.S.C. 656</external-xref>) by this Act; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02275E1BE778420499FA4D794F823946"><enum>(B)</enum><text>accept public comments on such proposed regulations for not less than 60 days.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H67949EA499D94593BC9D26459001B239"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Existing proposed regulations</header><text>Paragraph (1)(A) shall not apply to the extent proposed regulations by the Administrator have been published on the date of enactment of this Act that are sufficient to carry out the amendments made to section 29 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/656">15 U.S.C. 656</external-xref>) by this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


