<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H401FE34DC7E94189BDAFE8CF2A20859A" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2301 IH: Court Legal Access and Student Support (CLASS) Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2301</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170502">May 2, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Maxine Waters of California</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide that <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/9/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of title 9 of the United States Code, relating to the enforcement of
			 arbitration agreements, shall not apply to enrollment agreements made
			 between students and certain institutions of higher education; and to
			 prohibit limitations on the ability of students to pursue claims against
			 certain institutions of higher education.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HAA01BAE18ED3480E8CC92DA38BBC8623" style="OLC">
 <section id="HEDDA1D113AA646ECA8AAF175F05C77B0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Court Legal Access and Student Support (CLASS) Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H4D0CE25D8F214E95A511D38F49E53857"><enum>2.</enum><header>Inapplicability of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/9/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of title 9, United States Code, to enrollment agreements made between students and certain institutions of higher education</header> <subsection id="H17E0B2AA2D6C4FDCA414C4BF8BB88F06"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/9/1">Chapter 1</external-xref> of title 9 of the United States Code (relating to the enforcement of arbitration agreements) shall not apply to an enrollment agreement made between a student and an institution of higher education.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H310283021113430AABE181564FF6F118"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <quote>institution of higher education </quote> has the meaning given such term in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965.</text> </subsection></section><section id="HC837F0042C08476F9E99D7A50F725471"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on limitations on ability of students to pursue claims against certain institutions of higher education</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 487(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1094">20 U.S.C. 1094(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCC8BAA1568614D26931DB5A1C5B212FE" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H779F4BBB1B814AF8833B08A4E5967F31"><enum>(30)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The institution will not require any student to agree to, and will not enforce, any limitation or restriction (including a limitation or restriction on any available choice of applicable law, a jury trial, or venue) on the ability of a student to pursue a claim, individually or with others, against an institution in court.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="HEC56DC02340E4EDAB1C863720FEEF187"><enum>4.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act and the amendments made by this Act shall take effect 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


