<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1154F8ABC5B443579B5C419652C3B779" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2443 IH: Department of Homeland Security Classified Facility Inventory Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2443</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170516">May 16, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001269">Mr. Barletta</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require an inventory of all facilities certified by the Department of Homeland Security to host
			 infrastructure or systems classified above the Secret level, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HEBC3196EDA1A4D2AA67E4A368B8BCBBC" style="OLC">
 <section id="H048AB2AA85F84A99899B9F184A10A2B3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Department of Homeland Security Classified Facility Inventory Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H57316568753E4ED6B68EA9A92A0CF21C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Inventory</header> <subsection id="H9E42FC648F2642DCA57BB3EFCEA8EAB6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through the Chief Security Officer of the Department of Homeland Security, shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA413BD9BCF974705A16E9D88BED47CC0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>maintain an inventory of all facilities certified by the Department to host infrastructure or systems classified above the Secret level; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H187CB703B455431DBC4F5CF57C097413"><enum>(2)</enum><text>update such inventory on a regular basis.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFA5D569C65A64419A5DFA51BA6A07CB7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The inventory required under subsection (a) shall include the location of such facilities, an identification of the entities operating such facilities, and date of establishment of such facilities.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H02869F4442AC40FBBB4DCB30E6FF65C3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Dissemination</header><text>The Chief Security Officer of the Department of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Under Secretary for Intelligence and Analysis of the Department, may share part or all of the inventory carried out under this section, in accordance with standard information sharing procedures and policies, with the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H6D41E88C2EC84305BB972E86CE6D88D9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Appropriate Department component agencies and field personnel.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H441FF17DC87349C8B73D5EF50BCF3581"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Appropriate State, local, tribal, and territorial personnel eligible to apply for a Top Secret security clearance sponsored by the Department.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


