<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF840FFB6AB574AB89CFBD6E3515FEE82" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1419 IH: Cold War Service Medal Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1419</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170307">March 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="Y000066">Mr. Young of Iowa</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000602">Miss Rice of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001184">Mr. Massie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001107">Mr. Curbelo of Florida</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 10, United States Code, to provide for the award of a military service medal to
			 members of the Armed Forces who served honorably during the Cold War, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H775236F3005E43898472D272FBF3E536" style="OLC">
 <section id="H3C755657E1554FD1AFD7C3DFD34A181A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cold War Service Medal Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HDC341633BA1A4491BFA835D2B4085366"><enum>2.</enum><header>Cold War Service Medal</header> <subsection id="H91E618E3DB104FA692CB82F1F4DED2D2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Medal authorized</header> <paragraph id="HC4B48199582E47D1997CC62D88E64FD3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/57">Chapter 57</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H45173A5452F243419235B2A03DA1687E" style="USC">
						<section id="H5640FD24DC7F4D7CB0D23376BD75F427"><enum>1136.</enum><header>Cold War Service Medal</header>
 <subsection id="H900B9C05B7AD4133B7D0B8AC5FB7E2D1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Medal authorized</header><text>The Secretary concerned may issue a service medal, to be known as the <term>Cold War Service Medal</term>, to persons eligible to receive the medal under subsection (c).</text> </subsection><subsection id="HA1A53F7CA59C4B7AB58722C7A771253C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Design</header><text>The Cold War Service Medal shall be of an appropriate design approved by the Secretary of Defense, with ribbons, lapel pins, and other appurtenances.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H35B272B6221A4D93932FB1958A224072"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible persons</header><text>Subject to subsection (d), a person eligible to be issued the Cold War Service Medal is any person who—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0AA8DD6B45D54BD28C0410C4BCAA65B4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>served on active duty in the armed forces for not less than 24 consecutive months during the Cold War;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4A19D538EE92493E97A2E1D19D6CDB00"><enum>(2)</enum><text>was deployed as a member of the armed forces outside the continental United States for a period of at least 30 days during the Cold War;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC327CBEFED8947DA81F5DCED704DBE76"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">was a member of a reserve component of the armed forces and called or ordered to active duty to participate in exercises or operations directly related to the Cold War, as determined by the Secretary of Defense; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H98315F341108466BACDE2D96B01C05A0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>performed such other service in the armed forces during the Cold War as the Secretary of Defense may prescribe for purposes of this section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE67EBE8F30A8463784216CE5D9E58492"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Required characterization of service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a person described in subsection (c) who is already discharged or released from the armed forces, the person is eligible for the Cold War Service Medal only if the discharge or release was under honorable conditions after service in the armed forces characterized as honorable.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA5520999512F4EE5A4D2916634CD02F0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>One medal authorized</header><text>Not more than one Cold War Service Medal may be issued to any person.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HAF319E7C1F474CF4AFA5771F9A290BAB"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Issuance to next-of-Kin</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a person described in subsection (c) is deceased, the Secretary concerned may provide for issuance of the Cold War Service Medal to the next-of-kin of the person.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H221233B97CB04AFD9273BB18DA1DE466"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Replacement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned, a Cold War Service Medal may be replaced without charge if lost, destroyed, or rendered unfit for use without fault or neglect on the part of the person to whom it was issued.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE81A982384334B87AF45CE0B3215CFF0"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The issuance of a Cold War Service Medal shall be subject to such regulations as the Secretaries concerned shall prescribe for purposes of this section. The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that any regulations prescribed under this subsection are uniform to the extent practicable.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAF0BB6B24C50404A85D565C445D70534"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Cold War defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>Cold War</term> means the period beginning on September 2, 1945, and ending on December 26, 1991.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE3A27BD3E8DC4C4C86E593260A2CBBDB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 57 of such title is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H6E6F01A320BE4BF196F8821FF940BAC1" style="USC">
						<toc>
							<toc-entry idref="H5640FD24DC7F4D7CB0D23376BD75F427" level="section">1136. Cold War Service Medal.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDDFBBAEA278549078D20E4CB6F8599A4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the Secretary of Defense should take appropriate actions to expedite—</text>
 <paragraph id="H168F4138AD7545CBB029251DF1C699E7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the design of the Cold War Service Medal provided for by section 1136 of title 10, United States Code (as added by subsection (a)); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H82AB5AEBD47C4D01B3824D2AEB61F5C9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the establishment and implementation of mechanisms to facilitate the issuance of the Cold War Service Medal to persons eligible for the issuance of the medal under such section.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


