<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HBEF65ED9B5674199AFE65D00ABAE5ECC" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3438 IH: Improving Employment Outcomes of TANF Recipients Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3438</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170726">July 26, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000184">Mrs. Noem</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To increase the employment, job retention, and earnings of former TANF recipients.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HE10B223D391A4AB9A23C41C2CB82334C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H4310FBD75EAD48EBBD9F2E808874F68E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Improving Employment Outcomes of TANF Recipients Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HF8B2F22C8EF047718E5D5D6969340FB8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improving economic mobility of TANF recipients</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 403(a)(4) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/603">42 U.S.C. 603(a)(4)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H316155F302CA4CD687460A11EEAEADE4" style="OLC">
				<paragraph id="H36AABB59E3364E1384A92FCBFEFDD9E5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Improving economic mobility of TANF recipients</header>
					<subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H27C3D7720A8E497D94C14A731EA8772B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Measuring state performance</header>
 <clause id="H80368E9FE200458D9B16391C3EC6230D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State, in consultation with the Secretary, shall collect and report information necessary to measure the level of performance of the State for each indicator described in clause (ii), for fiscal year 2019 and each fiscal year thereafter, and the Secretary shall use the information collected for fiscal year 2019 to establish the baseline level of performance of each State for each such indicator.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H759D8108A78E436AB6A5B6D8356FFC7C"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Indicators</header><text>The indicators described in this clause, for a fiscal year, are the following:</text> <subclause id="H49B41E576E8B433799B6A114E0480888"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The employment percentage for the fiscal year, which is equal to—</text>
 <item id="H203ECEB7FBDB41CE84E4F5D24D2B1754"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of families receiving assistance under the State program funded under this part or any other State program funded with qualified State expenditures (as defined in section 409(a)(7)(B)(ii)) who, during a quarter in the fiscal year, exited from the program, and who, during the 2nd quarter after the exit, include an adult in unsubsidized employment; divided by</text>
 </item><item id="H79BF58F7DF27495692896C7F222781B9"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the number of families who received assistance from the program in the exit quarter referred to in subclause (aa).</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H7130433F79BE49AF80219012E725C58C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The retention percentage for the fiscal year, which is equal to—</text> <item id="HA3E8508FF35E4C919CA312A30CD220FB"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of families receiving assistance from the State program funded under this part or any other State program funded with qualified State expenditures (as defined in section 409(a)(7)(B)(ii)) who, during a quarter in the fiscal year, exited from the program, and who, during the 4th quarter after the exit, include an adult in unsubsidized employment; divided by</text>
 </item><item id="H1EE5F236C8AE46D28DC27251E1705C4D"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the number of families who received assistance under the program in the exit quarter referred to in subclause (aa).</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="HB8E1E2AC7FED433DB397E743F5323F74"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The advancement measure for the fiscal year, which is equal to the median earnings of the adults receiving assistance under the State program funded under this part or any other State program funded with qualified State expenditures (as defined in section 409(a)(7)(B)(ii)) who, during a quarter in the fiscal year, exited from the program, and who during the 2nd quarter after the exit, are in unsubsidized employment.</text>
							</subclause></clause><clause id="H855353CA723F4C33B863F1D9E191780D"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Agreement on requisite performance level for each indicator</header>
 <subclause id="H458507B37BF1439BAE11734D0AD52C91"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Fiscal years <enum-in-header>2020</enum-in-header> and <enum-in-header>2021</enum-in-header></header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The State shall reach agreement with the Secretary on the requisite level of performance for each indicator described in clause (ii), for each of fiscal years 2020 and 2021. In establishing the requisite levels of performance, the State and the Secretary shall—</text>
 <item id="H4823458D685B41B89C7801A9C8B6443C"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>take into account how the levels involved compare with the levels established for other States;</text> </item><item id="HC9D0B073170B432E9E7CCD4B98D6A1A6"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure the levels involved are adjusted, using the objective statistical model referred to in clause (v), based on—</text>
 <subitem id="HAD3610B887A64CBAAE24F4382BEF3525"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>the differences among States in actual economic conditions, including differences in unemployment rates and job losses or gains in particular industries; and</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="HD8DD78C87652415FB746A99C189579A3"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>the characteristics of participants on entry into the program, including indicators of prior work history, lack of educational or occupational skills attainment, or other factors that may affect employment and earnings; and</text>
 </subitem></item><item id="HC381ECEAC72A43B082210B88D61B114E"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>take into account the extent to which the levels involved promote continuous improvement in performance by each State.</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H66020D1045224212A7F07376B5BB4C25"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Fiscal year <enum-in-header>2022</enum-in-header></header><text>The State shall reach agreement with the Secretary, before fiscal year 2022, on the requisite level of performance for each indicator described in clause (ii), for fiscal year 2022, which shall be established in accordance with subclause (I) of this clause.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HD42275C7F3E24CD498E56E0F9924DB9A"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Revisions based on economic conditions and individuals receiving assistance during the fiscal year</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, in accordance with the objective statistical model referred to in clause (v), revise the requisite levels of performance for a fiscal year and a State to reflect the actual economic conditions and characteristics of participants during that fiscal year in the State.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB7E1D788AF72449C9748283FEF23BC08"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Statistical adjustment model</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall use an objective statistical model to make adjustments to the requisite levels of performance for actual economic conditions and characteristics of participants, and shall consult with the Secretary of Labor to develop a model that is the same as or similar to the model described in section 116(b)(3)(viii) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3141">29 U.S.C. 3141</external-xref>).</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8E010DE61704A478D4EC8537E51D5F2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report on state performance</header>
 <clause id="HAF43872AF56E451E807F4E28318F5E84"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than October 1, 2018, the Secretary shall develop a template which each State shall use to report on outcomes achieved under the State program funded under this part or any other State program funded with qualified State expenditures (as defined in section 409(a)(7)(B)(i)).</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB629C706DC184969B7D5AC714905D6A2"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each such report shall include—</text> <subclause id="H3B5B1C66127C4C34B6F3009187094943"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of individuals who exited the program during the year, and their reasons for doing so, including a separate accounting of the number of work-eligible individuals (as so defined) who exited the program during the year and their reasons for doing so;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H8BB21807B11A4C40ADA5EE9733C98893"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the characteristics of the individuals who exited the program during the year, including information on the length of time the individual received assistance under the program, the educational level of the individual, and the earnings of the individual in the 4 quarters preceding the exit; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H9405A1D0866F47898BA956AD5578D379"><enum>(III)</enum><text>information specifying the levels of performance achieved on each indicator described in subparagraph (A)(ii).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H9C899AAE8EA44976868AE856B692AEE1"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>Not later than September 30 of fiscal year 2021 and of each succeeding fiscal year, the Secretary shall make available electronically to the public each report submitted under this subparagraph during the fiscal year.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1EAA3B3A5CB04247A2CC693272C86D7F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to provide for the measurement of State performance on the indicators described in this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H8775D9E259004B7482408B95F91BC7D9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments made by this Act shall take effect on October 1, 2017.</text> </section></legis-body></bill> 

