<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H3076363520FF46CDAD65052E1C58D825" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3768 IH: Reducing Waste in National Parks Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3768</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170913">September 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000523">Mr. Price of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001170">Ms. Shea-Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000465">Ms. Tsongas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To encourage recycling and reduction of disposable plastic bottles in units of the National Park
			 System, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HF8CFC30C3F6A4292B63BE44E97788A6A" style="OLC">
 <section id="HF32CCE988C464543BEC073666BC59C34" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reducing Waste in National Parks Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H9966DD9DCFFD4972B180375CDB46CD49" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Disposable plastic bottle recycling and reduction in units of the National Park System</header> <subsection id="H3596E3D880EF41D8A2164F9CEDD82349"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program for recycling and reduction of disposable plastic bottles in units of the National Park System</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each regional director concerned shall establish in such unit of the National Park System a program for recycling and reduction of disposable plastic bottles, including, if applicable, elimination of the sale of water in disposable plastic bottles under subsection (b).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H7FEFDA5B0F77468EB73D4AE52090F983"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elimination of sale of water in disposable plastic bottles</header>
 <paragraph id="HCC54888FCB3A45CEA5A8B11AE4E9821D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each regional director concerned may eliminate the sale of water in disposable plastic bottles in such unit of the National Park System after consideration of the following factors with respect to such unit:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB799A1FDD4D546C7BDEDE6D223416F55"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The costs and benefits to the overall operations.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF1379DF798B4933A7CEA650641630F1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The amount of waste that would be eliminated.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3AF7B606BCCD4DECBE6E63BCB5113095"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The infrastructure costs and funding sources for bottle refill stations.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74724CA103154F4680522A3531F76504"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Any contractual implications with respect to concessioners, including considerations of new leaseholder surrender interest or possessory interest.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A5DE3C301A2493B8A64D3CCDD8C4D75"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The operational costs of bottle refill stations, including utilities and regular public health testing.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB35368E7DED40EB982687A68F084A6C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The cost and availability of BPA-free reusable containers.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5EBDF80333304829BF30AE76CFF32C0E"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The effect on concessioner and cooperation association sales revenue.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA93252B477D742208D6ABDBF7CFC705A"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The availability of water within concession food service operations.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB33E71E756B947609FAE21C122D306C4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The ability to provide visitor education in the unit and online so that visitors may come prepared with their own water bottles.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90F1D4517ED3402F87A55AACAEFD989A"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Any input from the National Park Service Office of Public Health.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7580FA89A68A4431A2C7F1FFA86091B9"><enum>(K)</enum><text>The feasibility of posting signs so that visitors can easily find bottle refill stations.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5BCFD48AB8A745EE883F6870D238962C"><enum>(L)</enum><text>Safety considerations for visitors who may resort to not carrying enough water or drinking from surface water sources with potential exposure to disease.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE58EB9FB679E48FDB1A66AFA0F58BC77"><enum>(M)</enum><text>Any input from concessioners and cooperating associations within the unit.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A1A3A2EABBB4D71A83815F40E6A82AA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Units of National Park System that have previously eliminated sale water in disposable plastic bottles</header><text>With respect to a unit of the National Park System that does not offer for sale water in disposable plastic bottles on the date prior to the date of the enactment of this Act, the superintendent of such unit may continue to not offer for sale water in disposable plastic bottles if such superintendent, not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, submits to the regional director of such unit an evaluation that analyzes and addresses the factors listed in subparagraphs (A) through (M) of paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2234E1E7C8DD4F0C90AE995C99400574"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Proactive visitor education strategy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each regional director concerned shall develop for such unit of the National Park System a proactive visitor education strategy that addresses visitor expectations of water availability and explains the rationale for the program for recycling and reduction of disposable plastic bottles established under subsection (a) and implemented in such unit.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4A0843504B774382AD0DF3FBBD56B134"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Continuity within unit of the National Park System</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each regional director concerned shall, to the extent possible, implement the program for recycling and reduction of disposable plastic bottles established under subsection (a) in a manner that is consistent throughout such unit of the National Park System, including incorporation of such program into any agreement with an organization operating within the unit, including a concessioner operating plan and cooperating association scope of sales.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H01CDA01869DE4372A9F638D006F75BDE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Bi-Annual evaluation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each regional director concerned shall, not less than once every 2 years—</text> <paragraph id="H8B02FA95AFF5407D8AA7A840370DFEA6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct an evaluation of the program for recycling and reduction of disposable plastic bottles established under subsection (a) for such unit of the National Park System, including—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HC92C639957B3415DA5E7D9773AB9B94B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>public response to the program;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3FF0D6C7337E444ABAB24937DDD917CB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">visitor satisfaction with the availability of water;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7AB75D4A50624C4091012E7C3799D09A"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">buying behavior with respect to products sold in disposable plastic bottles;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE753A7738E9340179ED72BD743180D1A"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">public safety including information on cases of dehydration or exposure to disease from drinking from surface water; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H67825E0FFDFC4CC1A84EC57B195B4343"><enum>(E)</enum><text>disposable plastic bottle collection rates; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE287873F40074845B31CF872F9D0FD5A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit such evaluation to the Director of the National Park Service and the Secretary of the Interior.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0769D934E36149CB8BBCF1DD178E2E89"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definition of regional director concerned</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of this section, the term <quote>regional director concerned</quote> means, with respect to a unit of the National Park System, the regional director of the region of the National Park System in which such unit is located, working in coordination with the superintendent of such unit.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


