<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H55F0C1C20E6D4958BC03A82D160E178C" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1629 IH: Public Safety and Wildlife Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1629</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170320">March 20, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="L000480">Mrs. Lowey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To restrict the use of steel-jaw leghold traps and Conibear traps on animals in the United States.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H22F0BCE9123F485883EE962A8A27F9A3" style="OLC">
 <section id="HB37FC881D8AD46E1970FE3C6D2B4FB94" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Public Safety and Wildlife Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HCDD405984157411DA3FBDE2BFA49030B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Declaration of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States to reduce risks to public safety, as well as unnecessary harm to companion animals and wildlife, from indiscriminate and injurious trapping methods by prohibiting the import or export of, and the shipment in interstate commerce of, steel-jaw leghold traps and Conibear traps.</text>
		</section><section id="H7E065285F633462CB1C6BC2D078EEE75"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibited acts and penalties</header>
 <subsection id="H3036F95D38994013A18882BDF1389E40"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibited acts</header><text>It shall be unlawful for any person—</text> <paragraph id="H40E20019BDDB43919508072AA4C7B2E9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to import, export, deliver, carry, or transport by any means whatever, in interstate commerce, any steel-jaw leghold trap or Conibear trap; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB4A16E2408794859AC7CED5883FEF142"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to sell, receive, acquire, or purchase any steel-jaw leghold trap or Conibear trap that was delivered, carried, or transported in violation of paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H84570B449CE649759470FCB0C91E04B8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whoever knowingly violates subsection (a) shall, in addition to any other penalty that may be imposed, be subject to the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HCD9FBCD454394B7D8ADFCCFA3A903237"><enum>(1)</enum><text>For the first such violation, a civil fine of not more than $500 imposed by the Secretary for each steel-jaw leghold trap or Conibear trap possessed.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H587A5E57DC5749BB9913B6856CFB33B9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For each subsequent violation, a civil fine of not more than $1,000 imposed by the Secretary for each steel-jaw leghold trap or Conibear trap possessed, or imprisonment for not more than 2 years, or both.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCA79901903734213829A71C332165F13"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Payment of court costs and other associated expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person found to be in violation of subsection (a) shall pay all court costs associated therewith.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H841A9F6C3B1845A7BED9C04D673446DB"><enum>4.</enum><header>Rewards</header> <subsection id="HB4F071369C014F82AD8C02CB857372AB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General rule</header><text>The Secretary shall pay, to any person who furnishes information that leads to a conviction of a violation of any provision of this Act or any rule made under this Act, an amount equal to one-half of the fine paid pursuant to the conviction.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H29516A80A53447CA895C6CD764CE13FF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Any officer or employee of the United States or of any State or local government who furnishes information or renders service in the performance of his or her official duties is not eligible for payment under this section.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HB197B3986DC44E91B8A3C9D0A47A3E7B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Enforcement</header>
 <subsection id="H95AFEAECF24142D7BB1C17540BA1999F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except with respect to violations of this Act to which subsection (b) applies, this Act and any rules made under this Act shall be enforced by the Secretary, who may use by agreement, with or without reimbursement, the personnel, services, and facilities of any other Federal agency or any State agency for purposes of enforcing this Act and such rules.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HEF666F1797E6442A81E8E5D89E570122"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Import and export violations</header>
 <paragraph id="H8645B05916744BA08C368A8775504679"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Import violations</header><text>The importation of articles in violation of section 3(a) shall be treated as a violation of the customs laws of the United States, and those provisions of law relating to violations of the customs laws of the United States shall apply thereto.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H102CE606DF734125B529079212D60628"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Export violations</header><text>The authorities under the Export Administration Act of 1979 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc-appendix" parsable-cite="usc-appendix/50/2401">50 U.S.C. App. 2401</external-xref> et seq.) (as continued in effect under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act), including penalties, shall be used to enforce the provisions of this Act relating to the export of articles in violation of section 3(a).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H48BBCD3FA8834F2D8B2F67CD3629FDB6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Forfeiture</header>
 <paragraph id="HB6C3F9DF1D7B453C86AB3F174B412C8F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>General rule</header><text>Except with respect to exports to which the provisions of the Export Administration Act of 1979 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc-appendix" parsable-cite="usc-appendix/50/2401">50 U.S.C. App. 2401</external-xref> et seq.) (as continued in effect under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act) apply, and imports to which the customs laws of the United States apply, pursuant to subsection (b), any steel-jaw leghold trap or Conibear trap taken, possessed, sold, purchased, offered for sale or purchase, imported, exported, transported, delivered, received, carried, or shipped in violation of this Act or any rule made under this Act, shall be subject to forfeiture to the United States. Those provisions of law relating to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE96C7F414A51440F801318927BD480F2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the seizure, summary and judicial forfeiture, and condemnation of property for violations of the customs laws of the United States,</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23171731614F4A309336908583C93E6A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the disposition of such property or the proceeds from the sale thereof,</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BF73670AB084870BACB5FC9C4DE796A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the remission or mitigation of such forfeitures, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D7AE04649794B1EBFF4B2C35E96C571"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the compromise of claims,</text> </subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">shall apply to seizures and forfeitures incurred, or alleged to have been incurred, under the provisions of this subsection, insofar as applicable and not inconsistent with this Act.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD1F77DBAF104FBF9855F6CC95F9E638"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>Such duties as are imposed upon the customs officer or any other person with respect to the seizure and forfeiture of property under the customs laws of the United States may be performed with respect to seizures and forfeitures of property under this subsection by the Secretary or such officers and employees as may be authorized or designated for that purpose by the Secretary, or, upon the request of the Secretary, by any other agency that has authority to manage and dispose of seized property.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7D58613DEB3A40CCB8BAAB9F3FC813BE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Injunctions</header><text>The Attorney General of the United States may seek to enjoin any person who is alleged to be in violation of this Act or any rule made under this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H618B609EE1724EB08DA4A8BE73F0263F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Cooperation</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the head of any other department or agency with enforcement responsibilities under this Act shall cooperate with the Secretary in ensuring that this Act, and rules made under this Act, are enforced in the most effective and efficient manner.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H90CE25550B97477C8871E84B18907AC4"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H9D9F9A20C8FA4920B81C9B127BB504F1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Steel-jaw leghold trap</header><text>The term <term>steel-jaw leghold trap</term>—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD0E3AAE21B4E4DDC84ACD05ACA235BD1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means any spring-powered pan or sear-activated device with one or two opposing steel jaws, whether the jaws are smooth, toothed, padded, enclosed (dog-proof), or offset, that is designed to capture an animal by snapping closed upon the animal’s limb, foot, or part thereof; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H139B463B023347A0B1AA632ED7643FBE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include any cage or box trap; suitcase-type live beaver trap; or mouse or rat snap trap.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF8E85E1E1304B92B246D3BE9FE1188D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conibear trap</header><text>The term <term>Conibear trap</term>—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H138FED37CF9241C3AA5DDE5AB660F5E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any trap consisting of two metal frames hinged at the center point and powered by two torsion springs to create a scissor-like action designed to kill an animal by snapping an animal’s spinal column; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H44AE501B25014F798086E3BC03276E5F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include any cage or box trap; suitcase-type live beaver trap; mouse or rat snap trap.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF0B78D2EB5643F095519846420B65CA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Customs laws of the United States</header><text>The term <term>customs laws of the United States</term> means any other law or regulation enforced or administered by the United States Customs Service.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H73EF331B10F6418A95350D06576A9A14"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Import</header><text>The term <term>import</term> means to land on, bring into, or introduce into, any place subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, whether or not such landing, bringing, or introduction constitutes an entry into the customs territory of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF4A9924C26554ADFB6B55DD25BA35F9C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Interstate commerce</header><text>The term <term>interstate commerce</term> has the meaning given such term in section 10 of title 18, United States Code.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE3F96EFCD9564F4893C21E3F8DCF05B0"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H6111E0F552BA41CABD4C84B974EE1FE4"><enum>7.</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary may make rules to carry out this Act.</text> </section><section id="H6AB41EB3E31F49FEA9E3FD10546D7006"><enum>8.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall take effect 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


