<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H30852FBB52FC40099CC7E1A665B1E610" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3724 IH: Strengthening The Resiliency of Our Nation on the Ground Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3724</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170908">September 8, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001064">Mr. Heck</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001191">Ms. Sinema</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000602">Miss Rice of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To minimize the economic and social costs resulting from losses of life, property, well-being,
			 business activity, and economic growth associated with extreme weather
			 events by ensuring that the United States is more resilient to the impacts
			 of extreme weather events in the short- and long-term, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HBA9DF6FF9F6F44449053180D2815955C" style="OLC">
 <section id="HC63BF246DAF44BD3B1EB0133A90D6D89" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthening The Resiliency of Our Nation on the Ground Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>STRONG Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HF53D175095FA49F7B66C3674CBBC3CF1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purpose</header> <subsection id="H026FFEAB9A854CC3A5EE5AE473FECC81"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress makes the following findings:</text>
 <paragraph id="HFD004BB4BD274794B19639927983F31D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Extreme weather has serious economic costs for Americans, American businesses, and State and local governments. Hurricanes, droughts, floods, tornadoes, extreme heat, and extreme cold cause death, result in loss of property and well-being, especially among the most vulnerable populations, and negatively impact business activity and economic growth.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6126206E997345CCA59A5E12356160A5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Superstorm Sandy, which devastated the Eastern United States in late October 2012, resulted in more than 100 deaths, the evacuation of hundreds of thousands of people from their homes, power outages affecting more than 8,500,000 homes, massive flooding, gasoline shortages, and a crippled regional energy and transportation infrastructure. As a result of this storm, Congress passed the Disaster Relief Appropriations Act, 2013, which appropriated $50,500,000,000 for post-Sandy recovery efforts.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCA0EE6E889C644938D2E06EEC94287BB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In the past 30 years, there have been more than 130 weather-related disasters in the United States that each generated at least $1,000,000,000 in damages or more than $880,000,000,000 in total standardized loss. In addition, there have been many other extreme weather events that generated less than $1,000,000,000 in damages, but still caused immeasurable harm to the Nation’s citizens, infrastructure, and economy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H45CF8A0BBB7B4A61A8FA468D8347A1D3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Hurricane Katrina led to more than 1,800 deaths, property damage exceeding $80,000,000,000, more than $120,000,000,000 in Federal spending, and long-term impacts on the economy and livelihoods of those living in the Gulf Coast region.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCFC25BEDCAA94B1495624E390537E7FC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In 2011, one of the most severe and costly years for weather and climate on record, extreme weather hit every region in the United States, resulting in—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H470270A786AA4E9787807B91ABF3A702"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prolonged droughts in the South and the West;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H303A357DF6344D2B8E0BD5F97A5D4861"><enum>(B)</enum><text>deadly floods in the Southeast and Midwest;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2DEC754FA2EB49FA9BF88F9EC28A0F80"><enum>(C)</enum><text>hundreds of devastating tornadoes across the United States;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0F3B7640F21488AB1759EBF092CDFE5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Hurricane Irene in the Northeast;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H877B219BF9D14D45816BFEA6249F5F36"><enum>(E)</enum><text>more than $50,000,000,000 in weather-related damages;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2E48EFC44C94B508D54038D53E20896"><enum>(F)</enum><text>14 extreme weather events, which resulted in more than $1,000,000,000 in damages each and caused a combined death toll of hundreds of people; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H585D665DAF254F8598E1F03624550082"><enum>(G)</enum><text>many other extreme weather events with lesser, but still significant, impacts.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H27BF8154AF6546778E2199D6A07612A1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In 2012, in addition to Superstorm Sandy, the United States experienced—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8283F0B3BE844936897A99DF2BF60391"><enum>(A)</enum><text>drought conditions in more than 60 percent of the contiguous United States at the peak of the drought, including more than 2,200 counties that have received disaster designations from the Secretary of Agriculture due to the drought;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDCC18ACD3D484CF3B319D15002423034"><enum>(B)</enum><text>deadly floods in Minnesota, Tropical Storm Debby in Florida, and Hurricane Isaac in Louisiana;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72509E9AD5294A689AB221C41B537582"><enum>(C)</enum><text>destructive wildfires on more than 9,000,000 acres across 37 States;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F43B37DCCEF42A9B73F7D9B61B35BF6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>power outages affecting more than 3,400,000 homes due to severe storms during the summer; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20228DC63CAB4B06906C13FD8C4CBB90"><enum>(E)</enum><text>deadly heat waves, highlighted by July as the warmest month on record for the contiguous United States and more than 9,600 daily high temperature records broken during June, July, and August.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5195F36611A34B098D75ED1D18D4E271"><enum>(7)</enum><text>These events and natural disaster trends, when combined with the volatility of weather, ongoing demographic changes, and development in high risk areas, indicate that the negative impacts of extreme weather events and natural disasters have the potential to increase over time. The fact that a significant number of people and assets continue to be located in areas prone to volatile and extreme weather indicates that these events will continue to be expensive and deadly if the United States fails to enhance its resiliency to such events. Recent studies show that the intensity and frequency of some types of, but not all, extreme weather events will likely increase in the future.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8CC44300F9D740AE857B37E5A4A05D2D"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Economic savings can be achieved by considering the impacts of extreme weather over the short- and long-term in the planning process. For example, a 2005 review of the Federal Emergency Management Agency’s hazard mitigation programs, conducted by the National Institute of Building Sciences’ Multi-Hazard Mitigation Council, found that every dollar spent on hazard mitigation yields a savings of $4 in future losses.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0DFE9329B25D426893ECF04C5A42BDEB"><enum>(9)</enum><text>There are several efforts currently underway at the Federal, regional, tribal, State, and local levels that have helped lay the foundation for a federally coordinated effort to increase the Nation’s resiliency to extreme weather events, such as the Hurricane Sandy Rebuilding Task Force, the Presidential Policy Directive on National Preparedness (referred to in this Act as <quote>PPD–8</quote>), the National Preparedness System, the whole community approach led by the Department of Homeland Security, and the Silver Jackets Program by the Army Corps of Engineers. Other recent reports on this subject include the National Academies of Sciences’ reports <quote>Disaster Resilience: A National Imperative</quote> and <quote>Building Community Disaster Resilience through Public-Private Collaboration</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE968E58C4B7E49CCAE790E76ADDF5BDB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this Act is to minimize the economic and social costs and future losses of life, property, well-being, business activity, and economic growth by making the United States more resilient to the impacts of extreme weather events over the short- and long-term, thereby creating business and job growth opportunities by—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE20FFBD652FB4154830F649BB06D12C4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>ensuring that the Federal Government is optimizing its use of existing resources and funding to support State and local officials, businesses, tribal nations, and the public to become more resilient, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H216F4C488594441ABA1BB3409B38125F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>encouraging the consideration of, and ways to incorporate, extreme weather resilience across Federal operations, programs, policies, and initiatives;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE23FA966356F43CCA317D4F4F92F9309"><enum>(B)</enum><text>promoting improved coordination of existing and planned Federal extreme weather resilience and adaptation efforts that impact extreme weather resilience and ensuring their coordination with, and support of, State, local, regional, and tribal efforts;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H15AE07953876422FBE6A77C83CD420E9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>minimizing Federal policies that may unintentionally hinder or reduce resilience, such as damaging wetlands or other critical green infrastructure, or lead Federal agencies to operate at cross-purposes in achieving extreme weather resilience; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4A2160882A54E41B610239B7B68D6EB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>building upon existing related efforts, such as the Hurricane Sandy Rebuilding Task Force, the PPD–8, the National Preparedness System, and the whole community approach;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C4D496802DF46A1B9A8984B649D2620"><enum>(2)</enum><text>communicating the latest understanding and likely short- and long-term human and economic impacts and risks of extreme weather to businesses and the public;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H97BCF9F94BFA49F4A6AD3F7C29A8087C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supporting decisionmaking that improves resilience by providing forecasts and projections, data decision-support tools, and other information and mechanisms; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H881999A8153D4698BB3F057734F4E90A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establishing a consistent vision and strategic plan for extreme weather resilience across the Federal Government.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H221A9B271AA649A497C893298CEE3016"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H8449C6BB366A446E901AF1D353BFEE76"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Director</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Director</quote> means the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1E748621DD5247A8BB72FC8D82D5B3EC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Extreme weather</header><text>The term <quote>extreme weather</quote> includes severe and unseasonable weather, heavy precipitation, hurricanes, storm surges, tornadoes, other windstorms (including derechos), extreme heat, extreme cold, and other qualifying weather events as determined by the interagency group established under section 4(a)(1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE83A7AB514E24C528435E8D9F9D80224"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Resilience</header><text>The term <quote>resilience</quote> means the ability to prepare and plan for, absorb, recover from, and more successfully adapt to adverse events in a timely manner.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H773459B51764430D8364528FBCEFB351"><enum>4.</enum><header>Extreme weather resilience gap and overlap analysis</header>
			<subsection id="H157998D7EEC04EDC915B0CB65010AB64"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Interagency working group</header>
				<paragraph id="H4FDF75A3133C402F9171AC44E058F64C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <subparagraph id="HB24BFADA85D846219888360F36BF620C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Director, with input from the Department of Homeland Security, shall establish and chair an interagency working group with Cabinet-level representation from all relevant Federal agencies.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B43F5302A274CB08C22502DE227E066"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The working group shall—</text> <clause id="H026A73BC026E42A8AF2E031024B70942"><enum>(i)</enum><text>come together to provide a strategic vision of extreme weather resilience;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE1D86947E9D44355BE96E7B9D86EEA66"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>conduct a gap and overlap analysis of Federal agencies’ current and planned activities related to achieving short- and long-term resilience to extreme weather and its impacts on the Nation, such as storm surge, flooding, drought, and wildfires; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H26F383A8D5EE46FDA25A1C244DF21E8C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>develop a National Extreme Weather Resilience Plan in accordance with section 5(a).</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BE849B17D9540EEBD2B1DDD30478D86"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional representation from executive office of the president</header><text>The interagency working group established under paragraph (1) shall include representatives of the relevant offices and councils within the Executive Office of the President, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H30A266319CD048DB8F2A268D42398AE7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Office of Management and Budget;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1CC115D29E7B4ABAB3EE7F9357781A3F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the National Security Staff;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA68470BA799648CB95C327B07EBC00DD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Council of Economic Advisors;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H921647F9244546509184432CC2D57936"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Council on Environmental Quality; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41F9A6ACC27C4F57A4BE4E4B553D0B99"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Domestic Policy Council.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H27843287671446B9AB28095E807E8CC5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consultation with tribal, state, and local representatives</header> <subparagraph id="H7A77966E7E964E61B9FFD1F2C1876772"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Federal interagency working group established under paragraph (1) shall work closely with an advisory group to take into account the needs of State and local entities across all regions of the United States. The advisory group shall consist of—</text>
 <clause id="H73CB3B2E5C254BCB855EED83EFAC96F7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>1 representative from the National Emergency Management Association;</text> </clause><clause id="H32E64A672419425389572E14AC411D64"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>7 representatives from States and State associations; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6ACFB225F20D4143B83CE6F84F5C7C7E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>8 representatives from local entities and associations, including representation from a tribal nation and at least 1 major metropolitan area.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B90976BA25A4AC980F9C5A24072EA54"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Key sectors</header><text>The representatives described in subparagraph (A) shall, in the aggregate, represent all of the key sectors set forth in subsection (b)(1).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8B305D5E8774EF0985E7D6A46C4E8C3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Director shall meet with the representatives described in subparagraph (A) not fewer than 9 times during the development of—</text>
 <clause id="HB56AE2DB26F14FBBB8EFD9E20FF47209"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the gap and overlap analysis under this section; and</text> </clause><clause id="H970BD00B1B1840A0BB69ED600673B180"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the National Extreme Weather Resilience Action Plan under section 5.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB40EA4F34C75491C883D6FA983632765"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Cooperation by federal agencies</header><text>In carrying out the activities described in subsection (b), Federal agency representatives participating in the working group shall be forthright and shall fully cooperate with the Office of Science and Technology Policy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H81FA2CB177894A04A13B1856E5EC1266"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Detailees</header><text>Upon the request of the Director, each agency or entity referred to in paragraph (1) shall provide the working group with a detailee, without reimbursement from the working group, to support the activities described in subsection (b), section 5, and section 7(a). Such detailee shall retain the rights, status, and privileges of his or her regular employment without interruption.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4F9101593CAF479D9166E4754EBF0179"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Volunteer services</header><text>Notwithstanding section 1342 of title 31, United States Code, the working group may investigate and use such voluntary services as the working group determines to be necessary.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H203B074454C4442DBF3AA9F9394734DE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Gap and overlap analysis</header><text>In conducting the gap and overlap analysis required under subsection (a)(1), Federal agency representatives shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB8D454E01B834092BCFAD54490557899"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop a Federal Government-wide working vision for resilience to the impacts of extreme weather events in the short- and long-term, in accordance with the purpose set forth in section 2(b), through an effort led by the Director and the interagency working group, which includes goals and objectives for key sectors. Key sectors shall include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1B775CB8B156489196FCE57BA2F5B57D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>agriculture;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4560509E828E4601ABC4D9EF7FD1A897"><enum>(B)</enum><text>forestry and natural resources management;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H16CFC80134E44C7D92A472BD3318406C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>water management, including supply and treatment;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC307B2920D2A4FFDB29CD470EE41619D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>energy supply and transmission;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8492D1C34DC5433B9F4191D400E6C895"><enum>(E)</enum><text>infrastructure, including natural and built forms of water and wastewater, transportation, coastal infrastructure, and other landscapes and ecosystems services;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F2617EF6D43437AB8DEC5FB6FD73809"><enum>(F)</enum><text>public health and healthcare delivery, including mental health and hazardous materials management;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3104B0EF00CB44B8A102442EA66CC65F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>communications, including wireless communications;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1061F3057D248968E718E54440DF07C"><enum>(H)</enum><text>housing and other buildings;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H651348C5A5FB4AB4A6A7180AF12DD927"><enum>(I)</enum><text>national security;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C832A38D00F4464A0E5BFB8D2A64CD9"><enum>(J)</enum><text>emergency preparedness;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD40EC45982D473FA25ED5A8FB452F63"><enum>(K)</enum><text>insurance; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7FF8E23930604047A40D84559A67FB0E"><enum>(L)</enum><text>other sectors that the Director considers appropriate;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H592195189FCD4D148B5C450D3991B6C6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consider and identify the interdependencies among the key sectors when developing the vision referred to in paragraph (1);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H157EA4D83C7A4CAAA3683901DB0517AE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>create summaries of the existing and planned efforts and programmatic work underway or relevant to supporting State and local stakeholders in achieving greater extreme weather resilience in the short- and long-term for each sector identified under paragraph (1) and across the sectors, specifically including summaries of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC0064A8FB0B14C6BA34A53B2D9543025"><enum>(A)</enum><text>individual Federal agency programs, policies, regulations, and initiatives, and research and data collection and dissemination efforts;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD6412B61DD343C1A32489A1A823558D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>areas of collaboration and coordination across Federal agencies; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E3591C943D44AA893140DDCDF8617A1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>areas of coordination with State and local agencies, private entities, and regional cooperation;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H83D0BBF1B190439FB93995C9AEEAD96C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>identify specific Federal programs, statutes, regulations, policies, and initiatives which may unintentionally hinder resilience efforts, including an analysis of disincentives, barriers, and incompatible programs, policies, or initiatives across agencies and sectors;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2F37274D9F954584A38A14F01AB72F81"><enum>(5)</enum><text>examine how the severity and frequency of extreme weather events at the local and regional level may change in the future and communicate these potential risks to stakeholders;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H691C6F3F67E3428098E72A4A9B8EC0CA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>work together to identify and evaluate existing Federal tools and data to describe, analyze, forecast, and model the potential impacts identified under paragraph (5) and develop recommendations to strengthen their ability to provide reliable and accurate forecasts at the national, regional, State, and local levels;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6CB7318661834A2CA4EEEF86FA1DB9C6"><enum>(7)</enum><text>identify gaps and overlaps in Federal agency work, resources, and authorities that impair the ability of the United States to meet the vision for short- and long-term extreme weather resilience, by comparing the goals and objectives identified for each sector and across sectors with the summaries identified in paragraph (3), specifically identifying gaps relating to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB3F2530B455444AC8FF445642EFD21FD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>individual Federal agency programs, policies, and initiatives, and research data collection and dissemination efforts;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21D1B4D411DC467BBF5C3070D9EFEAFD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>areas of collaboration and coordination across Federal agencies; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3AD9317B52B48BFBD9FBB5E1C7E6823"><enum>(C)</enum><text>areas of coordination with State and local agencies and private entities, and regional cooperation;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H20EB5E77F5E948CF9A5CCD9881DCA3A3"><enum>(8)</enum><text>determine potential measures to address the issues referred to in paragraph (4) and to address the gaps and overlaps referred to in paragraph (7) by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8863FD8E0B0D45DBAA685A37064E9073"><enum>(A)</enum><text>designating individual or multiple Federal agencies to address these gaps;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6BF7A4104AF348B8B838B43213CACE9B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>building upon existing delivery mechanisms;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3B135C2BBFC4A05BDEF5137CA1AF659"><enum>(C)</enum><text>evaluating options for programs, policies, and initiatives that may particularly benefit extreme weather resilience efforts, including the role of ecosystem-based approaches;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A9EE0D65BDB4E768F18AA759A5A1FDE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>recommending modifications to existing Federal agency programs, statutes, regulations, policies, and initiatives to better support extreme weather resiliency;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAAB1207B8E5B484FA46F35190A1275D7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>requesting new authorities and resource requirements, if needed; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD3A670F86EA040388B97AB9D90A85FC4"><enum>(F)</enum><text>identifying existing Federal Government processes that can be built upon to address the purpose of this Act; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F894AE529504284ADB2AA1E32EC48A3"><enum>(9)</enum><text>establish, with the assistance of the General Services Administration or such other Federal agency as the Director may designate, a Federal advisory working group to provide ongoing collective input to the process.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9C5E9574E73D43F9B93B45FCC2F35AF2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Working group</header><text>The Federal advisory working group established pursuant to subsection (b)(9) shall consist of relevant private sector, academic, State and local government, tribal nation, regional organization, vulnerable population, and nongovernmental representatives, with representation from each sector described in paragraph (1). The Director may designate an existing Federal advisory committee under which the working group would operate independently, with the same rights and privileges held by members of the advisory committee. The members of the working group established pursuant to subsection (b)(9) may not simultaneously serve as members of the advisory committee designated pursuant to this subsection. The activities of the working group should complement and not duplicate the stakeholder process conducted under PPD–8.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HA0EFAA893A2F41B2924C52AC6370349C"><enum>5.</enum><header>National Extreme Weather Resilience Action Plan</header>
 <subsection id="H26ECFC0EFA684ABCBA8FCEA1C673172F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Based on the results of the gap and overlap analysis conducted under section 4, the Director, working with the interagency working group established under such section, and considering the efforts described in section 2(a)(9), shall develop a National Extreme Weather Resilience Action Plan (referred to in this section as the <quote>Plan</quote>)—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7F72AD5B18F24A5CAA2DC1B47A258B74"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to build upon existing Federal Government processes referred to in section 4(b)(8)(F)—</text> <subparagraph id="H7A0B8943C9B346A9A16362D732BDD016"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to address the results of the gap and overlap analysis under section 4; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H39E6ABF173134FE5A7BABB88359AF7C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to incorporate the activities required under subsection (c);</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9A7C1364EE6489D85767152BC11145B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to best utilize existing resources and programs through improved interagency coordination and collaboration;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H974F6F4550B2474387B3798A288FAAF7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to improve Federal coordination with existing regional entities, State and local governments, networks, and private stakeholders;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2491667E6A654FC88EB61E892F6D3845"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to make data and tools accessible and understandable and to help facilitate information exchange for tribal, State, and local officials, businesses, and other stakeholders in a manner that addresses the needs expressed by these stakeholders;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4D6BCEF3D33541F98F9169C3F0336F00"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to facilitate public-private partnerships;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDAB06BB7A01A46109582BF8A86A87395"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to improve Federal agencies’ economic analytical capacity to assess—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H51266676E8714F6095C00F76BB6A7FDC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the likelihood and potential costs of extreme weather impacts by region and nationally; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF8E3383FEF26450481B221523BDF14DD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the relative benefits of potential resilience measures to multiple stakeholders;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HED7163148E814C1F90DD2B7561618236"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to provide tools to stakeholders—</text> <subparagraph id="HC1C807B80EE64AAB8E010BE06F9B2E97"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to conduct analyses similar to those described in paragraph (6); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H153DF03276ED48ED8E5FDA78B9CA69D2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to support decisionmaking;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2822878DB084426AA6BA4E2F1396AF7C"><enum>(8)</enum><text>to support resiliency plans developed by State and local governments, regional entities, and tribal nations, to the extent possible; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H30B74B10969A41C980B4274D5AE2D42E"><enum>(9)</enum><text>to request further resources, if necessary, to fill in gaps to enable national resilience to extreme weather, including resilience of tribal nations, and particularly vulnerable populations, and the use of green infrastructure and ecosystem-based solutions.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0D0CF2E9E9B344CB9B075C9BCF6B3B3C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Cooperation</header><text>Any Federal agency representative contacted by the Director, in the course of developing the Plan, shall be forthright and shall fully cooperate with the Office of Science and Technology Policy, as requested.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HDAF90371D4B3477292DD8DBE1FA4A076"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Required activities</header>
 <paragraph id="HF4A28FD6E62D44C9AC9C0B064B7493B7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>The Plan shall include specific Federal agency and interagency responsibilities, identify potential new authorities, if necessary, and employ risk analysis—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H370FBC73BB154AC59C868CEC235DB613"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to address the gaps identified through the gap and overlap analysis; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E5676E5C8454C24BC2F6C41876CE643"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to improve Federal interagency coordination and Federal coordination with State, regional, local, and tribal partners.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HED50385AA1C7418F99975BC1867CA0AB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Available funding opportunities</header>
 <subparagraph id="H35001632756242C480C3609E59D4FEA9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Identification</header><text>The Director shall identify—</text> <clause id="H48A4BFFDBF7C4FC0B90DD9D76EA929BE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>existing Federal grant programs and other funding opportunities available to support State and local government extreme weather resiliency planning efforts; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6BA0D17846DB40BD8AACDF883B6F6C96"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>projects to advance extreme weather resiliency.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H735120BD5C134DD3BE78EB06F06CF098"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>The Director shall publish the information described in subparagraph (A) in the information portal identified in paragraph (3).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0FFA3E36D1346ED9E17CF935A8A6CF4"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>Each participating agency shall—</text> <clause id="H66F83AB7EA8B4A59B8FCB764C3811382"><enum>(i)</enum><text>consider incorporating criteria or guidance into existing relevant Federal grant and other funding opportunities to better support State and local efforts to improve extreme weather resiliency; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H784BEA31366842F784FA393715808E9E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>evaluate and modify existing Federal funding opportunities, as appropriate, to maximize the return on investment for pre-disaster mitigation activities.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H689D1925402F4FE883F9751AEC7F52DF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Information portal</header>
 <subparagraph id="H3A21A1C3F53E4F69A67409227A0190DC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Plan shall—</text> <clause id="H4BE5FE5BF5C34BE6B0A77628125829D6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>include the establishment of an online, publicly available information portal for use by Federal agencies, their partners, and stakeholders, that directs users to key data and tools to inform resilience-enhancing efforts; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA40E1C16A5434FEF98161E305F5ABDA3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>build off and be complementary to existing Federal efforts, including data.gov.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8057363C656246EEA40F1D37CED11435"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Maintenance</header><text>The coordinating entity identified under paragraph (4) shall be responsible for establishing and maintaining the information portal.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4AE4E1344C07437B9EDAEC023515566B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Information supplied</header><text>Information shall be supplied as requested by Federal agencies, their partners, academia, and private stakeholders, in coordination with regional, State, local, and tribal agencies.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06C4AE1D9B1D4D83B245E012A684FA57"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The information portal established under this paragraph shall direct users to coordinated and systematic information on—</text>
 <clause id="HF0145CE7B49D45FC87409881E2270686"><enum>(i)</enum><text>best or model practices;</text> </clause><clause id="H6A854D3877EA4B9194FB99429DEC57F8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>data;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1715310DD01A4F428139C14EBFF5FA4B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>case studies;</text> </clause><clause id="H8A97274B88184140B72ED4B086169F68"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>indicators;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEC6D79EFDB8F4625AF8C8924303A3D22"><enum>(v)</enum><text>scientific reports;</text> </clause><clause id="H90655007073C4C93AB73F2186F06713E"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>resilience and vulnerability assessments;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1CD90B79F2FB469EA3056683E5D3A765"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>guidance documents and design standards;</text> </clause><clause id="HB53A11A98FFD4A67B14DF61650A02877"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>incentives;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA4649F9C334B4477A5F6A24D220A9D51"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>education and communication initiatives;</text> </clause><clause id="H734E730F88E04D588CD930CE549D7FE5"><enum>(x)</enum><text>decision support tools, including risk management, short- and long-term economic analysis, and predictive models;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H979A4096F97B4ECCBEE72433C4976BEC"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>planning tools;</text> </clause><clause id="HBF40D4AE79B94D3987955B04EC76123E"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>public and private sources of assistance; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3F17437B80BF42B0869B9F5B32445450"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>such other information as the coordinating entity considers appropriate.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H25643355348142B4B37D459D4E0A9B35"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Coordinating entity</header><text>The Plan shall include the identification of a Federal agency, interagency council, office, or program, which participated in the gap and overlap analysis and Plan development. Such entity shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H823C5B55B21B43D885B339862C7393D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>coordinate the implementation of the Plan;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5DEC7F64E5B8436B96A95F459A322588"><enum>(B)</enum><text>track the progress of such implementation; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H460DFF8E247847D4B6B0D7D8FFDBE173"><enum>(C)</enum><text>transfer responsibilities to another Federal agency, interagency council, office, or program to serve as the coordinating entity if the entities participating in the working group agree that circumstances necessitate such a change.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F0E0E1532FA4BC686BAAD2FF5959C78"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Resiliency officer</header><text>Each Federal agency that assists with the gap and overlap analysis required under section 4 shall designate, from among the agency’s senior management, a Senior Resiliency Officer, who shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCC6352B3679140F29AB2AFA62C3A3410"><enum>(A)</enum><text>facilitate the implementation of the agency’s responsibilities under paragraph (1);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3011B11C1A974E05B8ADE06C7C5D9882"><enum>(B)</enum><text>monitor the agency’s progress and performance in implementing its responsibilities under paragraph (1);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42F139B526964A6C89DC53DE20D97535"><enum>(C)</enum><text>report the agency’s progress and performance to the head of the agency and the coordinating entity identified under paragraph (4); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5A2AC9EF400462997F6331282774D13"><enum>(D)</enum><text>serve as the agency lead in ongoing coordination efforts within the Federal agency and between the coordinating entity, other Federal agencies, public and private partners, and stakeholders.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1F21376C638048BEBD940F2563C5E19E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Publication</header>
 <paragraph id="H07EFED7E731D4C64B676B1EA4172ECBB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Draft plan</header><text>Not later than 420 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director shall publish a draft of the Plan developed under this section in the Federal Register.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H77C3A55C5E654131BABE3BD68B0CC936"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public comment period</header><text>During the 60-day period beginning on the date on which the draft Plan is published under paragraph (1), the Director shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF30085B441044F999E284E6181F17E4E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>solicit comment from the public; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD804BFD8C1B44D409B72DA0B6C426CB7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conduct a briefing for Congress to explain the provisions contained in the draft Plan.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0C98965619E4585A60980683B68E2AF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Final plan</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the end of the public comment period described in paragraph (2), the Director shall publish the final Plan in the Federal Register.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA633DFE65B1C4927A909C50644F30A62"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Not later than 630 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director shall begin implementing the final Plan published under subsection (d)(3).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAFC70F4D68B64C2CA595C6CA32B8019A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Financing</header><text>To the extent possible—</text> <paragraph id="H4C722045DF5C407FB7DBB0B61A7C8718"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Federal funding should be used to leverage private sector financing for resilience building activities, consistent with the implementation of the Plan, through public-private partnerships; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4E2F655E51984442ABBD7B35895F4D80"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Federal grant and loan programs of the Federal agencies participating in the interagency working group for this effort shall consider extreme weather resilience as a key factor when awarding funding, including the projected extreme weather risk to a project over the course of its expected life.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H616B24CD0E9C465FBF2A8E7014B9C421"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Tribal, state, and local responsibilities</header><text>The Plan may not place new unfunded requirements on State or local governments.</text> </subsection></section><section id="HAB3C2AAED0C5475B8FC8BAA11C5FE2EF"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authorization of other activities</header> <subsection id="HDF69EDF5FAE04C7F82B85B9C1C443CFA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Federal agencies are authorized to develop tools and disseminate information to improve extreme weather resilience in the key sectors set forth in section 4(b)(1).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H714786772ED14F9FAE6462FACE1B3066"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Office of science and technology policy</header><text>In conducting the gap and overlap analysis under section 4 and developing the National Extreme Weather Resilience Action Plan under section 5, the Director may carry out additional activities in support of the purpose of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HC8806C2284E1478BAE9627855BD3C407"><enum>7.</enum><header>Reports</header>
 <subsection id="HB92905E5D4274B73A4ED9BDAC70CEE9A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Government accountability office report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit a report to Congress that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDFFA1F3D47D945FC85ACDD27893CBE32"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifies existing Federal Government programs and policies related to disaster relief, response, and recovery that impede improving short- and long-term extreme weather resilience; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H405D0EB444D946A5BB2FFB636EEAA5AA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make recommendations for how the programs or policies could be structured differently to better support short- and long-term resilience after an extreme weather event.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H06A0BDD38B9E4E9B969CAA1F0C094E4C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director shall submit a report to Congress that contains—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA51D4D31E97A44A2987C3DA92C9CF786"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the results of the gap and overlap analysis;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC0F95F4980974322998AE36387AB8ADD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the final National Extreme Weather Resilience Action Plan;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H22241EA7000F45D1AF02F9AB1721C363"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an update on the implementation of the plan; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4914829D16B64210911471BBF301F802"><enum>(4)</enum><text>available resources for the sustained implementation of the plan.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAC659D9D90E549A2A5B92394195E21C9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Triennial reports</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the submission of the report under subsection (a), and every 3 years thereafter, the coordinating entity identified under section 5(c)(4), in cooperation with the interagency working group established under section 4(a), shall submit a report to Congress that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2C7EB8FF9AEE4B478A4B20A51D53995C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>contains an update of the National Extreme Weather Resilience Action Plan;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA1CD8B1FD0D04E38B0AE1AE049F233D7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>describes the progress of the plan’s implementation;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H62BF4C46ED5D43BF9B534E14840AF8F7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>improves upon the original analysis as more information and understanding about extreme weather events becomes available;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2D93C858B0AE477E966A72F0DEE3EF0E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establishes criteria for prioritization of activities described in the plan;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBD0192091F494D4097C9376194BB2AC7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>reconsiders and makes changes to the plan based on the availability of new information described in paragraph (3); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H80D904E5124340819FAFF660619C0101"><enum>(6)</enum><text>identifies cost-effective changes to laws, policies, or regulations that could advance the purpose of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1D7DA6130AC1457B84DAD9A67D562F94"><enum>(d)</enum><header>FEMA reports on funding</header>
 <paragraph id="HBA68D4FF623A42E9AD03CDB2E779C4BD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H51D9EB1DE75A4C72B48F37A62EF875AD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Federal Emergency Management Agency grant programs are a key vehicle that exists to fund activities related to resiliency planning and projects.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70BAE82D988C4EB5905585F0CE57781D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In order to ensure that the United States becomes more resilient to extreme weather, it is important to ensure that sufficient resources are available to support resiliency activities.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D6486D301EF4FBE9DB73049BF72B940"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>At the end of each fiscal year, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (in this paragraph referred to as <quote>FEMA</quote>) shall submit a report to Congress that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEC602F43E1054D04B563CD9864FD1613"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifies the amounts that were made available to FEMA during such fiscal year for State and local entities to use for activities that support the purposes of this Act;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4190C06862A94719A14FF54613AE6D92"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identifies the amounts disbursed by FEMA to State and local entities during such fiscal year for such activities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3EB117AE029E4BF6888659F789F27CE2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>describes the resources requested by State and local entities for activities that support the purposes of this Act; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDAB11557DC514792A7E8BC32CA7D0B70"><enum>(D)</enum><text>identifies the difference between the amounts disbursed by FEMA and the amounts requested from FEMA by State and local entities.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H16EED2CFD9A74B5CAB34A5205B17361B"><enum>8.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="HAFA1BFD4FE904E24BE0B24ED3EE4B0DD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amounts for analysis, plan development and implementation, and reports</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for fiscal years 2018 through 2020—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H69B6E4319B914C4E84E65BF98C639F8C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to conduct the gap and overlap analysis required under section 4;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3B34E9FE20FF46D3A5BCF64B1C07E4C4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to conduct the activities required under section 5, including the creation and maintenance of the information portal; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H9E5733FF842B4585A50E0D30D529F072"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to prepare the reports to Congress required under subsections (b) and (c) of section 7.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HEA6D9844583F41059F13D2CDE818CB0E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability of funds</header><text>Amounts appropriated pursuant to subsection (a) shall remain available for the purposes set forth in such subsection through December 31, 2020.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


