<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB23AC130B0D8473589DBDF24FD4EFCF6" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3994 IH: Advancing Critical Connectivity Expands Service, Small Business Resources, Opportunities, Access, and Data Based on Assessed Need and Demand Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3994</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171006">October 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000567">Mr. Lance</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Office of Internet Connectivity and Growth, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HA0E04FFC5FAF48E08253665A6E24CA9F" style="OLC">
 <section id="H79519E97EC0A4DB7A21A79EC60FA1592" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Advancing Critical Connectivity Expands Service, Small Business Resources, Opportunities, Access, and Data Based on Assessed Need and Demand Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>ACCESS BROADBAND Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="H3850565729584207813B07FA6051DC79"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of the Office of Internet Connectivity and Growth</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary shall establish the Office of Internet Connectivity and Growth within the National Telecommunications and Information Administration.</text>
		</section><section id="H4FE7BFC79525493CA5153BB8341F84EA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Duties</header>
 <subsection id="H5211F252A4EF47C1B3A2061EE6BBD318"><enum>(a) </enum><header>Outreach</header><text>The Office shall—</text> <paragraph id="HE4ECCC64CA26490D95AD0088941464D4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>connect with communities that need access to high-speed internet and improved digital inclusion efforts through various forms of outreach and communication techniques;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4237C753F4A04383B67C24198AFAD99F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>hold regional workshops across the country to share best practices and effective strategies for promoting broadband access and adoption;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE967849C1B3D460CA198A81E781E36E3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>develop targeted broadband training and presentations for various demographic communities through various media; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2C04057EA3294B0CB158A1CF55B4676F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>develop and distribute publications (including toolkits, primers, manuals, and white papers) providing guidance, strategies, and insights to communities as the communities develop strategies to expand broadband access and adoption.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H550C7A40BDD940E5A400478F935A1EF1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Tracking of Federal dollars</header>
 <paragraph id="HC1866B6540714F4B9FD4CB1AB9268542"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Broadband infrastructure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Office shall track the construction and use of any broadband infrastructure built using any Federal support in a central database.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFD92DF18C7FF4D228D6365AC1AB3CC03"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Accounting mechanism</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Office shall develop a streamlined accounting mechanism by which any agency offering a Federal broadband support program and the Commission through the Universal Service Fund shall provide the information described in paragraph (1) in a standardized and efficient fashion.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA34C7BC06904489D832788F5553A96C3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every year thereafter, the Office shall make public on the website of the Office and submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report on the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB6EC27EB96AE4DA18A5CD75DF0AE59D9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the work of the Office for the previous year and the number of residents of the United States that received broadband as result of Federal broadband support programs and the Universal Service Fund program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H65387F29EBF64FC9882E07DEB56A76E2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of how many residents of the United States were provided broadband by which universal service mechanism or which Federal broadband support program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H30A9B249D02A4AAD88FE88CE1DE9D9D6"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An estimate of the economic impact of such broadband deployment efforts on the local economy, including any effect on small businesses or jobs.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HAADBF3ED381B4DA3B53EA8C971532F32"><enum>4.</enum><header>Streamlined Applications for Support</header>
 <subsection id="H58717C1E014E44529442D1086C258F88"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Agency consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Office shall consult with any agency offering a Federal broadband support program to streamline and standardize the applications process for such program.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H725AA3C0C5EE43408D2DE73B8054E5BC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Agency streamlining</header><text>Any agency offering a Federal broadband support program shall amend their applications for broadband support, to the extent practicable and as necessary, to streamline and standardize applications for Federal broadband support programs across the Government.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB83A1F45E1E34943B372CFA89B27443A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Single application</header><text>To the greatest extent practicable, the Office shall seek to create one application that may be submitted to apply for all, or substantially all, Federal broadband support programs.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8E7451ECD1CE4DB1A1F9CAC6E401396D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Website required</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Office shall create a central website through which potential applicants can learn about and apply for support through any Federal broadband support program.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HA739BC8D40E84FD4993AA614BFD76EC2"><enum>5.</enum><header>Coordination of Support</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Office, any agency that offers a Federal broadband support program, and the Commission through the Universal Service Fund shall coordinate with the Office to ensure that support is being distributed in an efficient manner, in a financial sustainable manner, with the goal of serving the largest number of persons in the United States while promoting the most job and economic growth for all residents of the United States.</text>
 </section><section id="H2572F718710F45C889E59E0DF422DA2F"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HCEF05881403C47F7BC54122AD48CDA2C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given that term in section 551 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HEA8E075F4DDE48FEAF213B3E8D1B4129"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assistant secretary</header><text>The term <term>Assistant Secretary</term> means the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6DB3E627229A41808A3D48730CC758F2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Communications Commission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H17385388212F45338977D762444A0498"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Federal broadband support program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Federal broadband support program</term> does not include any Universal Service Fund program and means any of the following programs (or any other similar Federal program) to the extent the program offers broadband internet service for residential, commercial, or academic establishments:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H41B06F405873439D9B6345C6AE33C9C1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Telecommunications and Technology Program of the Appalachian Regional Commission.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2766418C5F84418B316940E4FC19693"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Telecommunications Infrastructure Loans and Loan Guarantees, the Rural Broadband Access Loans and Loan Guarantees, the Substantially Underserved Trust Areas Provisions, the Community Connect Grant Program, and the Distance Learning and Telemedicine Grant Program of the Rural Utilities Service of the Department of Agriculture.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF65725F4CF2431F93B8CCE4A1AB438D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Public Works and Economic Adjustment Assistance Programs and the Planning and Local Technical Assistance Programs of the Economic Development Administration of the Department of Commerce.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H882003BEB2D24A25BB8817E6656C6669"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Community Development Block Grants and Section 108 Loan Guarantees, the Funds for Public Housing Authorities: Capital Fund and Operating Fund, the Multifamily Housing, the Indian Community Development Block Grant Program, the Indian Housing Block Grant Program, the Title VI Loan Guarantee Program, Choice Neighborhoods, the HOME Investment Partnerships Program, the Housing Trust Fund, and the Housing Opportunities for Persons with AIDS of the Department of Housing and Urban Development.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10773DD54F6346F6B01549669E14E7EB"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The American Job Centers of the Employment and Training Administration of the Department of Labor.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF176ED47E27F43ADA2F243E7C51094A6"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Native American Library Services Basic Grants, the Native American Library Services Enhancement Grants, the Native Hawaiian Library Services Grants, the Laura Bush 21st Century Librarian Program, the National Leadership Grants for Libraries, and the Sparks! Ignition Grants for Libraries of the Office of Library Services of the Institute of Museum and Library Services.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB64F7EC0912347268907E18B5FB8C44A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Office</header><text>The term <term>Office</term> means the Office of Internet Connectivity and Growth established pursuant to section 2.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDFCB4ED5BF1D4F46B34100ADDF72EEEA"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Universal service fund program</header><text>The term <term>Universal Service Fund program</term> means any program authorized under section 254 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/254">47 U.S.C. 254</external-xref>) to help deploy broadband.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE6EE0B784529446FB47EEFD96BEA5D33"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Universal service mechanism</header><text>The term <term>universal service mechanism</term> means any funding stream provided by a Universal Service Fund program to support broadband access.</text> </paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

