<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H3F8EC36AEF494A1A8F198CDFAFE1B1AC" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3998 IH: Protect America Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3998</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171010">October 10, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="Z000017">Mr. Zeldin</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To increase public safety by permitting the Attorney General to deny the transfer of firearms or
			 the issuance of explosives licenses to known or suspected terrorists, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H8A6554CE6FA9407692B04AF902F71D2C" style="OLC">
 <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6A3E18A4DFD140559724BE082780AA0E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protect America Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HC148C53E96DC40919CA1C74584970CBD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Granting the Attorney General the Authority To Deny the Sale, Delivery, or Transfer of Firearms to Known or Suspected Terrorists; Requiring Information-Sharing Regarding Attempted Firearms Purchases by Known or Suspected Terrorists; Authorizing the Investigation of Known or Suspected Terrorists Who Attempt To Purchase Firearms</header> <subsection id="H93E87E30F2654B3EBBD468025BB7C91E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short Title</header><text>This section may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preventing Terrorists From Obtaining Firearms Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB56D3A6C8818475293CA92540D2376C8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amendment</header><text>Section 922(t) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB5B016E2661E4A61AF78BEC4902D1F10" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HF098111C2210485DB81AA4D59A6B850E" indent="up1"><enum>(7)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H71A3CF27DB78458F9C14CFF136D8F06A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>If the Attorney General is notified of a request to transfer a firearm to a person who is being investigated, or has been investigated during the preceding 5 years, as a known or suspected terrorist, the Attorney General shall—</text>
 <clause id="H6C6FF9FBA19B44FCB142BF50ABB68208" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>as appropriate, take further steps to confirm the identity of the prospective transferee and confirm or rule out the suspected nexus to terrorism of the prospective transferee;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H420BD64321D840B888D8E92FF26BCBA1" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>as appropriate, notify relevant Federal, State, or local law enforcement agencies or intelligence agencies concerning the identity of the prospective transferee; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDB5472427B814993AD22F938F9EF8F68" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>determine whether the prospective transferee is already the subject of an ongoing terrorism investigation and, as appropriate, initiate such an investigation.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD98D418427E847D29B2A2CBC53F474D5" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Upon being notified of a prospective transfer under subparagraph (A), the Attorney General or the United States attorney for the district in which the licensee is located may—</text>
 <clause id="H784DFB4893B5495DB50169D7925EA444"><enum>(i)</enum><text>delay the transfer of the firearm for a period not to exceed 72 hours; and</text> </clause><clause id="H0982CAFD676A4596BC1643B2C2D5D65B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>file an emergency petition in the United States district court for the district involved to prohibit the transfer of the firearm.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF773469490954710BD66ACAE93EC67E2" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0DDDE12D5ACD49AEAE40ED7939B03843"><enum>(i)</enum><text>An emergency petition filed under subparagraph (B) shall be granted upon a showing of probable cause to believe that the prospective transferee has committed or is furthering a plan to commit an act of terrorism.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD4F8AB86A9C34C3D95C870A3FC09C3FB" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>An emergency petition filed under subparagraph (B) to prohibit the transfer of a firearm may be granted only after a hearing—</text>
 <subclause id="H70F9A8C3B18D4269A5D8AA0C81F4D760"><enum>(I)</enum><text>of which the prospective transferee receives actual notice; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HF7F35907AFF84C3EB1758F02842DF7E1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>at which the prospective transferee has an opportunity to participate with counsel.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB1100620B134CB2B8CAD2724A96440C" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>For purposes of this paragraph—</text> <clause id="H8AF7B6C3CD6C47FB93E37004C7DFA822"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the term <term>known or suspected terrorist</term> means a person determined by the Attorney General to be known (or appropriately suspected) to be or have been engaged in conduct constituting, in preparation for, in aid of, or related to terrorism, or providing material support or resources for terrorism;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3AD0D422A9D24262B4447ADE95416A38"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the term <term>material support or resources</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2339A; and</text> </clause><clause id="H6C7BA20BB5684528AB3B31D08F0646E1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the term <term>terrorism</term> includes international terrorism and domestic terrorism, as defined in section 2331.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF9E51429E35A43669E33C6489D2A5953" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, a person shall not be considered to have been investigated as a known or suspected terrorist solely by reason of being identified in the terrorist screening database (as such term is defined in section 2101(10) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/621">6 U.S.C. 621(10)</external-xref>), if the name of the person was thereafter removed from the database because the person was erroneously included.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H14451F81CE4041DB9F9C5BEFB068DA4E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Granting the Attorney General the Authority To Deny the Sale, Delivery, or Transfer of Explosives
			 to Known or Suspected Terrorists; Requiring Information-Sharing Regarding
			 Attempted Explosives Purchases by Known or Suspected Terrorists;
			 Authorizing the Investigation of Known or Suspected Terrorists Who Attempt
			 To Purchase Explosives</header>
 <subsection id="H67BB6D33ED0C48EB91942825F26B54F4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short Title</header><text>This section may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preventing Terrorists From Obtaining Explosives Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H4F665321EAF444C4B29FEC61086D62E0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amendment</header><text>Section 843 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H58F72DEB8B7D48ED99E2143F352D828D" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H2240590F80E741869629E48E53C2DBCB"><enum>(j)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H5C8F3E66EEDD417087F580E2252C9F6F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Attorney General receives an application for a user permit, limited permit, or license to import, manufacture, or deal in explosive materials from a person who is being investigated, or has been investigated during the preceding 5 years, as a known or suspected terrorist, or receives information under subsection (h) about a responsible person or employee who is being investigated, or has been investigated during the preceding 5 years, as a known or suspected terrorist, the Attorney General shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF0DD6D2008414EF8B4589EFEB74A58CA" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as appropriate, take further steps to confirm the identity of the applicant, responsible person, or employee and confirm or rule out the suspected nexus to terrorism of the applicant, responsible person, or employee;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC34F3FEEE1B04B1DA12B3F4AE4BD0216" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as appropriate, notify relevant Federal, State, or local law enforcement agencies or intelligence agencies concerning the identity of the applicant, responsible person, or employee; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0D1BD233AD547B4BA911507B56C84F4" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>determine whether the applicant, responsible person, or employee is the subject of an ongoing terrorism investigation and, as appropriate, initiate such an investigation.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF12C6A11B8134135BEFBB333F40056A2" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Upon receipt of an application or information described in paragraph (1), the Attorney General or the United States attorney for the district in which the applicant, responsible person, or employee is located may—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF8C79BB613F745138327CC5EC6D0A4DE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for a period not to exceed 90 days, delay the approval of the application or the determination to issue a letter of clearance under subsection (h), as the case may be; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A2BFC34268F43A7A7C0F214C2F6E811"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">file an emergency petition in the United States district court for the district involved to prohibit the approval of the application or the issuance of a letter of clearance under subsection (h), as the case may be.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H515F765F2FE84C20ABA1D535B185DE87" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H6DEC7075E6FB436A890703D7DAB9D588"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An emergency petition filed under paragraph (2) shall be granted upon a showing of probable cause to believe that the applicant, responsible person, or employee has committed or is furthering a plan to commit an act of terrorism.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA778E99E7E194CEBB1FC4207CBE4C2BE" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An emergency petition filed under paragraph (2) may be granted only after a hearing—</text> <clause id="HE100B4D11FDF4551B39A537A4413A580"><enum>(i)</enum><text>of which the applicant, responsible person, or employee receives actual notice; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H904D9E07E13E47F29C48256BB3497FAD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>at which the applicant, responsible person, or employee has an opportunity to participate with counsel.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA7B56F1457B4C089304299F3FDFFE70" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>For purposes of this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="H8BB88959630A4F379BC6B9CC84CD01F4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>known or suspected terrorist</term> means a person determined by the Attorney General to be known (or appropriately suspected) to be or have been engaged in conduct constituting, in preparation for, in aid of, or related to terrorism, or providing material support or resources for terrorism;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1BF65667CA1432180686A86F6EF285B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <term>material support or resources</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2339A; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD39DA0B7E98541FF813DBA2004211E68"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the term <term>terrorism</term> includes international terrorism and domestic terrorism, as defined in section 2331.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H86658CFCFD6247C8AA1ADD562E124EC6" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, a person shall not be considered to have been investigated as a known or suspected terrorist solely by reason of being identified in the terrorist screening database (as such term is defined in section 2101(10) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/621">6 U.S.C. 621(10)</external-xref>), if the name of the person was thereafter removed from the database because the person was erroneously included.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section id="H7779425C62E24A3286F54965F269E153"><enum>4.</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments made by sections 2 and 3 shall cease to have effect after the 3-year period that begins with the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </section><section id="HB853EA6A86C64CD0ADA05E1D27CA5E28"><enum>5.</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not earlier than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act and not later than 3 years after such date of enactment, the Attorney General shall submit to the Congress a written report on the petitions filed and court orders granted under sections 2 and 3, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="HBC83596866DE4FCEBF6A61789EE5F30D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of petitions so filed;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFC7558DF65EE4C95B5347293C62DE9F6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of orders so granted;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF73CF28339B94FD99DA37C0362F811EB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the number of petitions that were denied;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2E143140A6F140CC9FCCD011789B835C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the disposition of any arrest made after such an order was granted, including any charges brought and the outcome of those charges;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB4897B8113B142A19C6258E5AB741F9E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>with respect to each of the matters described in paragraphs (1) through (4), whether the subject of the petition or order was a United States citizen or foreign national and whether the allegations involved domestic terrorism or international terrorism;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8171762D02EE45C3B48C38E67A205CAB"><enum>(6)</enum><text>for any such order issued against a foreign national, whether a deportation proceeding was initiated against the individual and, if so, the outcome of the deportation proceeding; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H987841F19AD9414AB312665856F9F02E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>whether multiple petitions were filed against any individual.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H466BFB54A46B4C49B05967EFDB7A493A"><enum>6.</enum><header>Correction of the Terrorist Watch List and <quote>No-Fly List</quote></header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Within 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H45C7748DF4AD491B8844D61E8FA82766"><enum>(1)</enum><text>review the terrorist watch list and the no-fly list referred to in section 44903(j) of title 49, United States Code, and any other list used by the Transportation Security Administration for purposes of identifying individuals who are prohibited from boarding aircraft because they pose a threat of terrorism, and remove from any such list the name of any person erroneously placed on the list or otherwise is not a known or suspected terrorist; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8200E3DA0F1D4C5B9EB9FB0324096B66"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to the Congress a written report that describes the steps taken to comply with paragraph (1).</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


