<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1BCF9C44E64D4810BF2663710484A5B1" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3879 IH: Taxpayers Don’t Incur Meaningless Expenses Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3879</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170928">September 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000171">Mr. O'Halleran</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001180">Mr. Schrader</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To limit the use of Federal funds for the use of the travel expenses of senior Federal officials in
			 contravention of certain regulations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HE48B2775860745D993ECA9111486BCB5" style="OLC">
 <section id="HBAB2A4A53C6B4908878AB40266D40ABA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Taxpayers Don’t Incur Meaningless Expenses Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Taxpayers DIME Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H7EDA842E724C47B1BB4A7361FA208A21"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on use of funds for certain Federal employee travel in contravention of certain regulations</header> <subsection id="H839E7E37CE6F4C6FB641615B94F138DD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, no Federal funds appropriated or otherwise made available in any fiscal year may be used for the travel expenses of any senior Federal official in contravention of sections 301–10.260 through 301–10.266 of title 41, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HA682997DE3744DBA85AE356E43853AD8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Quarterly report on travel</header>
 <paragraph id="H7DC7220197DD4899A3A892FBA0E70D48"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act and every 90 days thereafter, the head of each Federal agency shall submit a report to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate detailing travel on Government aircraft by any senior Federal official employed at the applicable agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3EC50651F34D43F6B80F9A6935C29935"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text>Any report required under paragraph (1) shall not include any classified travel, and nothing in this Act shall be construed to supersede, alter, or otherwise affect the application of section 101–37.408 of title 41, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDE073059E4B74075B706DF7B2762AAA7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Travel regulation report</header><text>Not later than one year after enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Government Ethics shall submit a report to Congress detailing suggestions on strengthening Federal travel regulations. On the date such report is so submitted, the Director shall publish such report on the Office’s public website.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2EBEFD39AD4E4BD4B7003F5ABD8ACE30"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition of senior Federal official</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act, the term <quote>senior Federal official</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 101–37.100 of title 41, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act, and includes any senior executive branch official (as that term is defined in such section).</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


