<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8FCD43003ADB4BEDB630070B48CBB868" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1688 IH: To avoid duplicative annual reporting under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1688</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20170322">March 22, 2017</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="R000582">Mr. Roe of Tennessee</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To avoid duplicative annual reporting under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H934F1EE09C1B4F33A1DAC88398611EA5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HAC62DCD788BE41E990EE3FC61A2B435F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Combined annual report for group of plans</header> 
<subsection id="H49D9AA6311FA4814BDFF36F4A974AB56"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of Labor shall, in cooperation, modify the returns required under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6058">section 6058</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and the reports required by section 104 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1024">29 U.S.C. 1024</external-xref>) so that all members of a group of plans described in subsection (c) may file a single aggregated annual return or report satisfying the requirements of both such sections.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H196B153A6D634A61A5DAA747303593CB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administrative requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the consolidated return or report under subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of Labor may require such return or report to include any information regarding each plan in the group as such Secretaries determine is necessary or appropriate for the enforcement and administration of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3804311AAB6845F88367ED5B85BCB1B3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Plans described</header><text>A group of plans is described in this subsection if all plans in the group—</text> <paragraph id="H8350F091E08449CBAD90379DE0CF61B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are individual account plans or defined contribution plans (as defined in section 3(34) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1002">29 U.S.C. 1002(34)</external-xref>) or in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/414">section 414(i)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB6254925553B4D47BA39C00E8CF33841"><enum>(2)</enum><text>have—</text> <subparagraph id="HC8F311260F86410FAB70F758B6BC30F4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the same trustee (as described in section 403(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1103">29 U.S.C. 1103(a)</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5EA7F977DFA745C0A3EAFE902CE97EB7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the same one or more named fiduciaries (as described in section 402(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1102">29 U.S.C. 1102(a)</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3FA1C5F1E8214572AACCCADCD2D0752B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the same administrator (as defined in section 3(16)(A) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1002">29 U.S.C. 1002(16)(A)</external-xref>)) and plan administrator (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/414">section 414(g)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBE1847F7973A43D9AF250003A8C1F8B0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>plan years beginning on the same date; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA3D710B8197D4171B8B72332D93CB67E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide the same investments or investment options to participants and beneficiaries.</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">A plan not subject to title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 shall be treated as meeting the requirements of paragraph (2) as part of a group of plans if the same person that performs each of the functions described in such paragraph, as applicable, for all other plans in such group performs each of such functions for such plan.</continuation-text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H620C66F6F5D44072A2BD465001ADEE22"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clarification relating to electronic filing of returns for deferred compensation plans</header> 
<paragraph id="H0AA3254AEBB54D8A938522399BDAC3E3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6011">Section 6011(e)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCB0C498724C44461B8D10349EB6E733D" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HAC4F8F0A19D44594AEE96A92100E16CD"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Application of numerical limitation to returns relating to deferred compensation plans</header><text>For purposes of applying the numerical limitation under paragraph (2)(A) to any return required under section 6058, information regarding each plan for which information is provided on such return shall be treated as a separate return.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC994EECF17AD4C7CA34EB156D0F485FA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by paragraph (1) shall apply to returns required to be filed with respect to plan years beginning after December 31, 2017.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC76B747E43B744CF9092BC961FA64B4C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The modification required by subsection (a) shall be implemented not later than January 1, 2021, and shall apply to returns and reports for plan years beginning after December 31, 2020.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body>
</bill> 


