<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H668B739D23164AE2A236955ED48CE987" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3707 IH: Apprenticeship and Jobs Training Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3707</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170907">September 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000554">Mr. LoBiondo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a tax credit for on-site apprenticeship programs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H61203030B1624B56A6F09712D44962B4" style="OLC">
 <section id="H2C60D677E94747B8A180075F9CB4D8C3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Apprenticeship and Jobs Training Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H10A0F323C7874236A6654DC79BE6BFB4" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Tax Credit for Apprenticeship Programs</header> <subsection id="H6D5F9961F24C44DAAAAE2C66E82B4452"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDEA8C6CAA09C4D1FB0E9E210C002514C" style="OLC">
					<section id="HF82B64864B62498FBD6450BC500D7AC9"><enum>45S.</enum><header>Credit for apprenticeship program expenses</header>
						<subsection id="HF22C7326DABF4ADDB86F6090B8BA119F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Tax Credit</header>
 <paragraph id="HB6A00A40AF084371B16B394C54B543C5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of section 38, in the case of an employer, the apprenticeship program credit determined under this section for any taxable year is an amount equal to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H960EC9FB844D436CB8178F54CA16B8A1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to each qualified individual in a qualified apprenticeship program, the lesser of—</text> <clause id="H48ED05A1D814477E90B6B5BF3054AC62"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount of any wages (as defined in section 51(c)(1)) paid or incurred by the employer with respect to such qualified individual during the taxable year, or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H034AAF7E7A184CEBBB716E09E86E4D51"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>$5,000, and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H26D4B43BDA37443B9B862544BC8C36EF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to each qualified individual in a qualified multi-employer apprenticeship program, the lesser of—</text>
 <clause id="H0E9ECB753D9A42189A4BADA5E2A19509"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an amount equal to the product of—</text> <subclause id="H540F1E900F8E4B4A867CB00EABBA9FE7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the total number of hours of work performed by such qualified individual for such employer during such taxable year, multiplied by</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H9702818053E24393BE87746C8C71718C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>$3, or</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H543D5D3D66AE4B2E81A721214AAB0D54"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>$5,000.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFFB156BA668B4B889CDEAB2FEDE8E74B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Established apprenticeship programs</header>
 <subparagraph id="HEDF0B3E397AF45E28BFBC6AFD7F19091"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The apprenticeship program credit determined under this section for the taxable year shall only be applicable to the number of qualified individuals employed by the employer through a qualified apprenticeship program or a qualified multi-employer apprenticeship program which are in excess of the apprenticeship participation average for such employer (as determined under subparagraph (B)).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9EA1CCA91D014438A1B48CF824ABFFF5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Apprenticeship participation average</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the apprenticeship participation average shall be equal to the average of the total number of qualified individuals employed by the employer through a qualified apprenticeship program or qualified multi-employer apprenticeship program for—</text>
 <clause id="HC8CD44483B434909B33052F0B8E927B7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the 3 preceding taxable years, or</text> </clause><clause id="HDF03CA2D5B834517844C99BFAF8D1092"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number of taxable years in which the qualified apprenticeship program or the qualified multi-employer apprenticeship program was in existence, whichever is less.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H10F8A522746A452CB4604564B851A20F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Denial of double benefit</header><text>No deduction or any other credit shall be allowed under this chapter for any amount taken into account in determining the credit under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1BF0041D07324E1983C32FAC6C6F6761"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Election not to claim credit</header><text>This section shall not apply to a taxpayer for any taxable year if such taxpayer elects to have this section not apply for such taxable year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA3A2E4F9D2CD485F836528A67EDAC0E7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The apprenticeship program credit under this section shall not be allowed for more than 3 taxable years with respect to any qualified individual.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF4E51EBA82634CA889CC8D438F7AC63B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Qualified individual</header>
 <paragraph id="H34E46405A0E149BA8FF78A5A1BACAE4C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>qualified individual</term> means, with respect to any taxable year, an individual who is an apprentice and—</text> <subparagraph id="H6A6488903E7941FBA286ACBFA014B999"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is participating in a qualified apprenticeship program or a qualified multi-employer apprenticeship program with an employer that is subject to the terms of a valid apprenticeship agreement (as defined in the Act of August 16, 1937 (commonly known as the <quote>National Apprenticeship Act</quote>; 50 Stat. 664, chapter 663; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/50">29 U.S.C. 50</external-xref> et seq.)),</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7A0BC5517E6A40DB949EB4FD81362022"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has been employed under a qualified apprenticeship program or a qualified multi-employer apprenticeship program for a period of not less than 7 months that ends within the taxable year,</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F7FBD28DA514376AB21ED4EA9B497A8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is not a highly compensated employee (as defined in section 414(q)), and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB40FB402AB3B452099CBB044CAD39CB5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is not a seasonal worker (as defined in section 45R(d)(5)(B)).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H300D6E9DAACE4AD1BB113C274926619A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Training received by members of the Armed Forces</header><text>An employer shall consider and may accept, in the case of a qualified individual participating in a qualified apprenticeship program or a qualified multi-employer apprenticeship program, any relevant training or instruction received by such individual while serving in the Armed Forces of the United States, for the purpose of satisfying the applicable training and instruction requirements under such qualified apprenticeship program.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H062C9CA4D9A94C508ABE7440D5569C4A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Qualified apprenticeship program and qualified multi-Employer apprenticeship program</header>
							<paragraph id="HE731AD1EFDBD431EB0F9DD52AAE5290B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Qualified apprenticeship program</header>
 <subparagraph id="H009B5E0ECB694692A4B680BBE877EC33"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>qualified apprenticeship program</term> means a program registered under the National Apprenticeship Act, whether or not such program is sponsored by an employer, which—</text>
 <clause id="H2D4633B89D544BCE9AECE9243F5D5E79"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provides qualified individuals with on-the-job training and instruction for a qualified occupation with the employer,</text>
 </clause><clause id="H22FD1516A8A4441194A7005C48724F7F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is registered with the Office of Apprenticeship of the Employment and Training Administration of the Department of Labor or a State apprenticeship agency recognized by such Office of Apprenticeship,</text>
 </clause><clause id="H16622C9A976D45219A278C523256DD06"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>maintains records relating to the qualified individual, in such manner as the Secretary, after consultation with the Secretary of Labor, may prescribe, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8B476C3E1CAB449F8DB43BC831653B1B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>satisfies such other requirements as the Secretary, after consultation with the Secretary of Labor, may prescribe.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3649D4AB21C4A33BF95E06E53DA5F6D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Qualified occupation</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A)(i), the term <term>qualified occupation</term> means a skilled trade occupation in a high-demand mechanical, technical, healthcare, or technology field (or such other occupational field as the Secretary, after consultation with the Secretary of Labor, may prescribe) that satisfies the criteria for an apprenticeable occupation under the National Apprenticeship Act.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A2AC7C24B244276BAB64F6D9084EF2B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified multi-employer apprenticeship program</header><text>The term <term>qualified multi-employer apprenticeship program</term> means an apprenticeship program described in paragraph (1) in which multiple employers are required to contribute and that is maintained pursuant to one or more collective bargaining agreements between one or more employee organizations and such employers.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8BFE0FB2DA0E47CC864CB8BFA1A08AE8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Apprenticeship agreement</header>
 <paragraph id="HBDB036E7538A4ED68622F3A4B198F3F8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>apprenticeship agreement</term> means an agreement between a qualified individual and an employer that satisfies the criteria under the National Apprenticeship Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H09A5E0F6D8394E21ACE1A61D0227699F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Credit for training received under apprenticeship agreement</header><text>If a qualified individual has received training or instruction through a qualified apprenticeship program or a qualified multi-employer apprenticeship program with an employer which is subsequently unable to satisfy its obligations under the apprenticeship agreement, such individual may transfer any completed training or instruction for purposes of satisfying any applicable training and instruction requirements under a separate apprenticeship agreement with a different employer.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFFF276462C6046DA8F8DF3719E6D51C0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Application of certain rules</header><text>For purposes of this section, all persons treated as a single employer under subsection (a) or (b) of section 52, or subsection (m) or (o) of section 414, shall be treated as a single person.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0D84AF0C513E4945AC2DC8C53DED77B1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H52C03520484349C68FF81270EC957E90"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Credit To be part of general business credit</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/38">Section 38(b)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>plus</quote> at the end of paragraph (35), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (36) and inserting <quote>, plus</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block act-name="" id="H66A3BF0C440A48308616A3BE2D089AB5" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H566AE91739394A9A8B9F0BE44B80A182"><enum>(37)</enum><text>the apprenticeship program expenses credit determined under section 45S(a).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF8EE941F19B44AEF9A2B7AEDD368B78B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HFCB6C07B3E824556B0B1AD08FD3C11C9" style="OLC">
					<toc>
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 45S. Credit for apprenticeship program expenses.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6091CAE0A9F8459DACEB7F7962255908"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE34C26CCFED64091AF7250A80BE41B2E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rule for employment credits</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/280C">Section 280C(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting <quote>45S(a),</quote> after <quote>45P(a),</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCE90756B0C324CA983C3BE421E8E3BD8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exclusion for determination of credit for increasing research activities</header><text>Clause (iii) of section 41(b)(2)(D) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>the apprenticeship program credit under section 45S(a) or</quote> after <quote>in determining</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4806276536AA4D5BA56BE5972B37FDA4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit a report to the Committees on Finance and Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committees on Ways and Means and Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives that contains an evaluation of the activities authorized under this Act, including—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCD946039AF8E438793D4ED2C8F270B07"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the extent to which qualified individuals completed qualified apprenticeship programs and qualified multi-employer apprenticeship programs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF000FC23BB68401CB277B349335BB506"><enum>(2)</enum><text>whether qualified individuals remained employed by an employer that received an apprenticeship program credit under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/45S">section 45S</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and the length of such employment following expiration of the apprenticeship period;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCBA4B0CC04534F5EA8AACBB7CF1EC0E7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>whether qualified individuals who completed a qualified apprenticeship program or a qualified multi-employer apprenticeship program remained employed in the same occupation or field; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF13FDD6E24C44464B069ACB2F6D03AD4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recommendations for legislative and administrative actions to improve the effectiveness of the apprenticeship program credit under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/45S">section 45S</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H11723BAC77DE4807AA7716727C87410B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2017.</text> </subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE8C3EF21E53C40518307CA6129253898"><enum>3.</enum><header>Encouraging mentors to train the future</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF944BB0788334CEDBE355645905779DC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Early distributions from qualified retirement plans</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/72">Section 72(t)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H957E7BD94B124491944021A91332E480"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD46F9A8C400144BFAEBB65D141440D59"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of clause (vii);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3BD6D9CDE52045A4934BFBCFB98FB73D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of clause (viii) and inserting <quote>, or</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA20BA432A7D449A7B1FABA5699CAEF70"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6AD9A4F6A9054E6EBFB2A89A4921F047" style="OLC">
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBEABE610355A468898342971FC88B895"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>made to an employee who is serving as a mentor.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1392E96BF629494C9559E2C1B41FBDA1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC0489C7CDD4847338EB3A5FEF12E778B" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDDE2BFF07EB1433A8906C03ECA5AFF3A"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Distributions to Mentors</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>mentor</term> means an individual who—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0E572B7061B7476F8B7AF2BBD549A5E3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has attained 55 years of age,</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H973FADD240C941D6A51A3629CB5B179D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is not separated from their employment with a company, corporation, or institution of higher education,</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9C18E00955D442DEAC1DEEF7A938DF22"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in accordance with such requirements and standards as the Secretary determines to be necessary, has substantially reduced their hours of employment with their employer, with the individual to be engaged in mentoring activities described in clause (iv) for not less than 20 percent of the hours of employment after such reduction, and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAD6C6D37952F48A7A0AF7B971EC94D75"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>is responsible for the training and education of employees or students in an area of expertise for which the individual has a professional credential, certificate, or degree.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H055DACB838BC409380222DE5ADBF1270"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Distributions during working retirement</header><text>Paragraph (36) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/401">section 401(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE1F8533C3B14414E9A15CE7FD1E17F1F" style="OLC">
					<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H699B94C06CCB4194ABCA9C21EA45B66E"><enum>(36)</enum><header>Distributions during working retirement</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB72D0CFB75C94B5785871BE4337F81B8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A trust forming part of a pension plan shall not be treated as failing to constitute a qualified trust under this section solely because the plan provides that a distribution may be made from such trust to an employee who—</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCFE8BFAB25D84DA9991304E417DDE6EA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has attained age 62 and who is not separated from employment at the time of such distribution, or</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H105C67EA23C04643AF768C66775D8D71"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>subject to subparagraph (B), is serving as a mentor (as such term is defined in section 72(t)(2)(H)).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFE70C022487A48AE9BE27818694C8979"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation on distributions to mentors</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A)(ii), the amount of the distribution made to an employee who is serving as a mentor shall not be greater than the amount equal to the product obtained by multiplying—</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC5F0DB9CAEB347F4B429F30AD05362D1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount of the distribution that would have been payable to the employee if such employee had separated from employment instead of reducing their hours of employment with their employer and engaging in mentoring activities, in accordance with clauses (iii) and (iv) of section 72(t)(2)(H), by</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5DD1BAD9C1EE480998631F0060647C37"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the percentage equal to the quotient obtained by dividing—</text> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEC13995D79EA4FF5AF932C134CDC6D19"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the sum of—</text>
 <item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7C74A1F447094E44AB793E09DE55EC49"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the number of hours per pay period by which the employee's hours of employment are reduced, and</text> </item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H924B21A1C5F04B218BE47865CCE43BB1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the number of hours of employment that such employee is engaging in mentoring activities, by</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0483E89EA0334267A9AF44EB16F5AE11"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the total number of hours per pay period worked by the employee before such reduction in hours of employment.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6EEF949C4F584E2EBA92A91DAF313227"><enum>(c)</enum><header>ERISA</header><text>Subparagraph (A) of section 3(2) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1002">29 U.S.C. 1002(2)</external-xref>) is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting the following: <quote>, or solely because such distribution is made to an employee who is serving as a mentor (as such term is defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/72">section 72(t)(2)(H)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986).</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7D100F2098B8453CBD887DCBC7AD64A2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to distributions made in taxable years beginning after December 31, 2017.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


