<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H070CA334AB844BDF8933D55C68CD8C93" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 748 IH: Safeguarding Sanctuary Cities Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 748</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170130">January 30, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000248">Mr. Serrano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To protect any State or local authority that limits or restricts compliance with an immigration
			 detainer request remains eligible for grants and appropriated funds.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H4882B260A343489CB284940CA83A3E6C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H69F2FCC840794724928CDCBCE5D8A1B1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safeguarding Sanctuary Cities Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H9755EFCD4E824FA79570919D7F37D664"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HFEEF46B01A28489A9C3E5AE7CD0ADF57"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Existing Federal law authorizes any authorized immigration officer to issue an immigration detainer that serves to advise another law enforcement agency that the Federal department seeks custody of an undocumented immigrant presently in the custody of that agency, for the purpose of arresting and removing the undocumented immigrant.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC774878AB72E41D39029B32F3D1D9201"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Unlike criminal detainers, which are supported by a warrant and require probable cause, there is no requirement for a warrant and no established standard of proof, such as reasonable suspicion or probable cause, for issuing an ICE detainer request. Immigration detainers have erroneously been placed on United States citizens, as well as immigrants who are not deportable.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC098BCFAE7D2401F911A25BDFE52DC0F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Galarza v. Szalczyk, U.S. Court of Appeals for the Third Circuit ruled in March 2014 that States and counties are not required to keep undocumented immigrants in jail on immigration detainers; and in April 2014, Miranda-Olivares v. Clackamas County, the U.S. District Court in Portland, Oregon, found that county governments would be exposed to civil rights lawsuits for honoring detainers not issued in compliance with Fourth Amendment protections, including a showing of probable cause.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H0E1CB70A205E430CBE7A9D588755ED65"><enum>3.</enum><header>Discretion to comply with immigration detainers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law (including section 642 of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996), if a State or unit of local government has in place any policy that limits or restricts compliance with a detainer or otherwise does not comply with a detainer, Federal financial assistance (as such term is defined in section 7501(a)(5) of title 31, United States Code) that the State or unit of local government would otherwise receive may not be reduced or not made available to that State or unit of local government by reason of such noncompliance.</text>
 </section><section id="H75AF0891A84A49398931E4690879D862"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <quote>detainer</quote> means any order or request by the Secretary of Homeland Security to a State or local official—</text> <paragraph id="H7829A6BB842C4D99AE735F6F595F953B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to temporarily hold a person in the custody of that State or unit of local government until such person may be taken into Federal custody;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC100D86641D74C188EA0629832A9527B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to transport such a person for transfer to Federal custody; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H87BF0E2F3AF04969980B25DAD5B28096"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to notify the Secretary prior to the release of such a person.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


