<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HA76114B424514C8CBC8E6687A28A0187" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4384 IH: Act to Sustain the Protection of Immigrant Residents Earned through TPS Act of 2017 </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4384</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171114">November 14, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="R000435">Ms. Ros-Lehtinen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide protected status for certain aliens present
			 in the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HA0328B605C86417EA01ECC03DA68F85F" style="OLC">
 <section id="H1EEEE87A0B9246CA97DF519C099FE33F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Act to Sustain the Protection of Immigrant Residents Earned through TPS Act of 2017 </short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>ASPIRE–TPS Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HB7A3DC5FAE234A6081663C749478DDEB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Protected status for certain aliens present in the United States</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by inserting after section 244 the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2BDE5BA979444A429035B1A782F1AD07" style="OLC">
				<section id="HC08F1842F18B49A9A2ACDB7293562D6E"><enum>244A.</enum><header>Protected status for certain aliens present in the United States</header>
 <subsection id="HD4CC030726DD4F40BCB8DD04464C0FDB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, including section 244(h), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall grant protected status under this section to an alien who meets the eligibility requirements under subsection (b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB25E2F2D74234CDB8453669980A0C82A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility requirements</header><text>The eligibility requirements are the following:</text> <paragraph id="H64D9F871C2594A46A46C1E16A2DD3859"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On January 1, 2017, the alien had been granted or was eligible for Deferred Enforced Departure or for temporary protected status under section 244.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3B8492DF27B742E784F2A8721FF33905"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The alien has continuously resided in the United States for the 5-year period prior to the date of the enactment of this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEA7A3EC0A140405F9DF5D44F49AE0159"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The alien is admissible as an immigrant, except as otherwise provided under paragraph (2)(A) of section 244, and is not ineligible under paragraph (2)(B) of such section, except that in making such a determination, no conviction for a misdemeanor which conviction occurred earlier than 6 years prior to the date on which the alien applies for status, or a renewal of such status, under this section may be considered.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1A4C4276D95B4FA983FB368CC18E320E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To the extent and in a manner which the Secretary establishes, the alien registers for the protected status under this section during a registration period of not less than one year.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H675F80FB641C4176B512B4E2CD46773C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duration of status</header><text>Protected status under this section shall be for a period of 6 years, and may be renewed for additional 6-year periods. An alien seeking to renew protected status under this section shall re-register with the Secretary.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="HC599530EF8754FBFB2761979E38FB178"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notice</header>
 <paragraph id="HA42109B29F8846A0AECFDD9A9C7F08F4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the first day of the registration period under subsection (b)(4), the Secretary shall provide each alien who was granted temporary protected status under section 244 or Deferred Enforced Departure with information concerning protected status under this section.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="HB1EAB58957A04E73A4A901C40783DBE2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Removal proceedings</header>
 <subparagraph id="HF7DF40B78AE24048B5F1EED63A9993D2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall promptly notify any alien against whom removal proceedings are initiated who is a national of a country (or in the case of an alien having no nationality, the country in which the alien last habitually resided) that on January 1, 2017, was designated under section 244 or under the Deferred Enforced Departure program, that status under this section may be available.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08CBB98BD62D40498F0C7CA086AB1B94"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Removal proceedings initiated prior to the date of enactment</header><text>The Secretary shall promptly notify any alien who is in removal proceedings on the date of the enactment of this section and who is a national of a country (or in the case of an alien having no nationality, the country in which the alien last habitually resided) that on January 1, 2017, was designated under section 244 or under the Deferred Enforced Departure program, that status under this section may be available.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7CFD2BE60464BA5B2903CD20C728A69"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form</header><text>Notices under this paragraph shall be provided in a form and language that the alien can understand.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFAF4873CCDF54BD9ADBF00A84568932B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Temporary treatment for eligible aliens</header>
 <paragraph id="HC08F4C4DF52040B49D0A95DD54C64E70"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Registration not available</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an alien who can establish a prima facie case of eligibility for protected status under this section, but for the fact that the period of registration under subsection (b)(4) has not begun, until the alien has had a reasonable opportunity to register during the first 30 days of such period, the Secretary shall provide the alien with work authorization under subsection (f), and shall not initiate or proceed with removal proceedings against the alien.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H24A93C35DC784414B8F7B81CDE45CECB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination pending</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an alien who establishes a prima facie case of eligibility for protected status under this section, until a final determination with respect to the alien's eligibility for such status has been made, the Secretary shall provide the alien with work authorization under subsection (f), and shall not initiate or proceed with removal proceedings against the alien.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H27472633091946989CE1CEFBC03DC39E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Work authorization</header>
 <paragraph id="H6AD3083CFB204AC483242F55BBA89D8F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall authorize each alien granted protected status under this section to engage in employment in the United States and provide the alien with an <quote>employment authorized</quote> endorsement or other appropriate work permit.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA405E2CDD29B4E21B93B0051CC05F380"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>Work authorization provided under this section shall be effective throughout the period the alien is in protected status.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H676134374ACF4C31B15E023C1BC91CBC"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may require payment of a reasonable fee, in an amount not to exceed $50, as a condition of registering an alien under this section. The Secretary may impose a separate, additional fee for providing an alien with documentation of work authorization. Notwithstanding section 3302 of title 31, United States Code, all fees collected under this subparagraph shall be credited to the appropriation to be used in carrying out this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE427485B9FEB4D71942A36B600D79CDA"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Withdrawal of protected status</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall withdraw protected status granted to an alien under this section if—</text> <paragraph id="H971FF3466EFB4D2FB433B21E4323E6BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary finds that the alien was not in fact eligible for such status under this section; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6360C736AF924E18A7B4711C439B029B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the alien fails, without good cause, to register with the Secretary at the end of each 36-month period after the granting of such status, in a form and manner specified by the Secretary.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H78B1F0B389964515A1D58D65896B89DF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Treatment of brief, casual, and innocent departures and certain other absences</header>
 <paragraph id="HC505E475B24B4E1D8FD0B545CA09ECF0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of subsection (b)(2), an alien shall not be considered to have failed to maintain continuous residence in the United States by virtue of brief, casual, and innocent absences from the United States without regard to whether such absences were authorized by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDD6EBED84D7D4A26B52488BD7A467547"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Renewal of protected status</header><text>For purposes of subsection (b)(2), in the case of an alien seeking to renew protected status under this section, absence from the United States for a continuous period, beginning on the date on which the Secretary most recently granted or renewed the alien’s protected status under this section—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF3E8109064D74B43B55F15A09FCB30B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>of one year or less, shall not break the continuity of such residency requirement; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A941A4742B24A96B8681B42231C934A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>of longer than one year, shall break the continuity of such residence, unless the applicant establishes to the satisfaction of the Secretary that he did not abandon his residence in the United States during such period.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H69514DED994145D6A7F95AFC68E3E80E"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Confidentiality</header>
 <paragraph id="H129743D856A445EFBBC3638A0AB6AB19"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not disclose or use information provided under this section for the purpose of enforcing the immigration laws.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB536C9804464472689C2244D2CFC9CDE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Referrals prohibited</header><text>The Secretary may not refer any alien granted protected status under this section to U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement or to U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H025D41C695CF4431A970DACE8E7A8A91"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraphs (1) and (2), the Secretary may disclose information provided under this section to Federal security and law enforcement agencies—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H748C66EB94CF435AAE7DFC38F22722BA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for assistance in the consideration of an application for protected status under this section;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37699F0328E447CBB667D572818C8E4E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to identify or prevent fraudulent claims for protected status under this section;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2768755ECCE94D42948CA7BD50C444B4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for national security purposes; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57E9E70BB7FC4721A4C8979E049DAC06"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in relation to the investigation or prosecution of any felony not related to the alien’s immigration status.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA90B4B5194EE4A5E82909C5A17EE3B91"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>Whoever knowingly discloses or uses information in violation of this subsection shall be fined not more than $10,000.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H919B5B38A0FE402A861031EA591559E0"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Treatment during period of protected status</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During a period in which an alien is granted protected status under this section—</text> <paragraph id="HF15A745627924147B6CCA5945EB85EDD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the alien shall be considered a qualified alien for purposes of title IV of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC8D489AE89CC4A21B5F71E4809BEF9B1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the alien may travel abroad without the prior consent of the Secretary; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC29DA3FD1DE84CD89F5255640EC7EB27"><enum>(3)</enum><text>for purposes of adjustment of status under section 245 and change of classification under section 248, the alien shall be considered as having been inspected and admitted into the United States, and as being in, and maintaining lawful status as a nonimmigrant.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0D12E4B3C84C49D3969BE752741BBD1E"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed as authorizing the Secretary to deny protected status to an alien based on the alien's immigration status or to require any alien, as a condition of being granted such status, either to relinquish nonimmigrant or other status the alien may have or to execute any waiver of other rights under this chapter. The granting of protected status under this section shall not be considered to be inconsistent with the granting of nonimmigrant status under this chapter.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="HE5D23E0D2C1144FE94EA8E2AE54CCB0A"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Adjustment of status in cases of extreme hardship</header>
 <paragraph id="H31BD990761A04ECFA198C4C52662E527"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, including section 244(h), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall adjust the status of an alien to that of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence if the alien—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H534A9517AB454807AE0515C348F50E4E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">meets the eligibility requirements of paragraphs (1) and (3) of subsection (b);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H431D1AA5CCCE4C179DB12C22547280BC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establishes that removal would result in extreme hardship to the alien or to the alien’s United States citizen or lawful permanent resident spouse, parent, or child; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7FED5266E856415FBE80D026494BABC0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>submits an application to the Secretary.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB3F22BC13214DC786FE66484C628595"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Numerical limitations do not apply</header><text>The numerical limitations of sections 201 and 202 shall not apply to the adjustment of aliens to lawful permanent resident status under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H540B3252C6154C72841618815748CDD4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>This subsection does not prevent an alien granted protected status under this section who does not meet the requirement of paragraph (1)(B) from adjusting status under section 245.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAEEBB2F6E9E54555A750A1E390584474"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Review</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a process for an alien denied protected status under this section to seek review of such a determination. Such process shall not prevent an alien from asserting eligibility for status under this section in removal proceedings.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section commented="no" id="H16EEF1FC1CEF4654A775ECBD9F5A5072"><enum>3.</enum><header>Temporary protected status clarifications</header>
 <subsection id="HCE5AF0222E724A9AA916813693ACB77C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Expunged convictions not a bar</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 244(c)(2) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1254a">8 U.S.C. 1254a(c)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H669E272C220C4389ADC0409462843670" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H2EF0EDD3F2D949F5B5D1BDD8884042E9"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Conviction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>conviction</term> does not include an adjudication or judgment of guilt that has been dismissed, expunged, deferred, annulled, invalidated, withheld, or vacated, an order of probation without entry of judgment, or any similar disposition.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBBAFAB0B748F4E45954F18BF6DB0BA6D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Aliens considered inspected and admitted into the United States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 244(f)(4) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1254a">8 U.S.C. 1254a(f)(4)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after <quote>considered</quote> the following: <quote>as having been inspected and admitted into the United States, and</quote>.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HAF65BA4CB9004C9CA700DFA656576815"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report on protected status</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">On the date that is 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 90 days thereafter, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and of the Senate a report that includes, for the previous 90-day period—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD0C23487352749A2B7C64F084E2B8CDA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of aliens who submitted applications to the Secretary for protected status under section 244A of the Immigration and Nationality Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5CFCD745526F4F1896AD4B5885126CD8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of such applications that were approved;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAF357561F0B14BBB882F4DB0A289633F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the number of aliens present in the United States with protected status, including information related to the States in which such aliens reside, the ages of such aliens, and the duration of their residence in the United States; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5583A6D1D05B44F082FB8D1C5B0F4B19"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any additional information determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text> </paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

