<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB783D8C6937B42D2BAF987FFC74DC8AF" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2845 IH: Jumpstart on College Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2845</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170608">June 8, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000380">Mr. Kildee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000248">Mr. Serrano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000598">Mrs. Davis of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001177">Mr. Sablan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001170">Ms. Shea-Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000581">Mr. Gonzalez of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001038">Mr. Crowley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000127">Mr. Nolan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001303">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Education to make grants to support early college high schools and dual
			 or concurrent enrollment programs.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H26A9D882F257403FB00375C4CC59A97F" style="OLC">
 <section id="H4F62353D88A5478ABA231C6B43043E08" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Jumpstart on College Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H57540E0C063E475E864511424B3E2FE0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to increase the percentage of students who complete a recognized postsecondary credential within 100 percent of the normal time for the completion of such credential, including low-income students and students from other populations that are underrepresented in higher education.</text>
 </section><section id="H425A2A02ED694193BEC7EE4609BD01C8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H33C33A0F0DE64D6898D82B630F9B3540"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means an institution of higher education in partnership with one or more local educational agencies (which may be an educational service agency). Such partnership may also include other entities such as nonprofit organizations or businesses.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2B6C91C4CC0B4232AF678B6E765205DF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5C86FA3113744D489690E001BFF05C08"><enum>(3)</enum><header>ESEA Terms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>dual or concurrent enrollment program</term>, <term>early college high school</term>, <term>educational service agency</term>, <term>four-year adjusted cohort graduation rate</term>, <term>local educational agency</term>, <term>secondary school</term>, and <term>State</term> have meanings given the terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H78852946781442628E065DEE99787B0B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Low-income student</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>low-income student</term> means a student counted under section 1124(c) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6333">20 U.S.C. 6333(c)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFECFA6771DF749A99F10E4E1A10A166B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Recognized postsecondary credential</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>recognized postsecondary credential</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD9A84E74A34F4561AE677E0808BAD8F3"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="HF875408B03924A5C906B091AE6B707EE"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations; reservations</header> <subsection id="H65784DA3A00840ECAF15DF93EC9B40BF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To carry out this Act, there are authorized to be appropriated $250,000,000 for fiscal year 2018 and such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2028.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9DE06C07AEC145E8BC60659313E708B7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reservations</header><text>From the funds appropriated under subsection (a) for each fiscal year, the Secretary shall reserve—</text> <paragraph id="HC0CB1D4276A342EB83A0623F05A7FBC7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not less than 40 percent for grants to eligible entities under section 5;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H07432B0130384DF7A570C5F1BD9442A4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less than 55 percent for grants to States under section 6; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8283DC32824A49D5B52BFBA25A0DA4B7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less than 5 percent for national activities under section 8.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8A23521553554291824DD09AB6DCA4A7"><enum>5.</enum><header>Grants to eligible entities</header>
 <subsection id="H7E0841BB028F4A70BE3EDDD9D8A11C42"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall award grants to eligible entities, on a competitive basis, to assist such entities in establishing or supporting an early college high school or dual or concurrent enrollment program in accordance with this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEA0508C611CD440397E3F1326127368C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>Each grant under this section shall be awarded for a period of 6 years.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HF4D0D14645944C4C9D7FCE0A5F0B50F2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant amount</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the amount of each grant under this section is sufficient to enable each grantee to carry out the activities described in subsection (h), except that a grant under this section may not exceed $2,000,000.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H175F6C664303442D85B95098F519EE92"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Matching requirement</header>
 <paragraph id="HA336099D09C94CE88303A8C87EB0D787"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each year that an eligible entity receives a grant under this section, the entity shall contribute matching funds, in the amounts described in paragraph (2), for the activities supported by the grant.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3346C00267CC43628FB2C48FBE69917E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amounts described</header><text>The amounts described in this paragraph are:</text> <subparagraph id="H90F1343DC0BB45B891126D0A439C166F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each of the first and second years of the grant period, 20 percent of the grant amount.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H056852957FB2427997C89294B1F050DA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each of the third and fourth years of the grant period, 30 percent of the grant amount.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C45FDB7D404480FB410F606658298D3"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the fifth year of the grant period, 40 percent of the grant amount.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H07E82FE10BAD467681050E0F43C32EF4"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the sixth year of the grant period, 50 percent of the grant amount.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5D3F684DA6F4296AEB6439272766398"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Determination of amount contributed</header> <subparagraph id="H5C2BBF2DC95F462AB12097B942774E31"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In-kind contributions</header><text>The Secretary shall allow an eligible entity to meet the requirements of this subsection through in-kind contributions.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6BD74405EA164377853D1924428D4118"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Non-Federal sources</header><text>Not less than half of each amount described in paragraph (2) shall be provided by the eligible entity from non-Federal sources.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFCD64CDB40AF400EB5F020C6FA4CDCC4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text>An eligible entity shall use a grant received under this section only to supplement funds that would, in the absence of such grant, be made available from other Federal, State, or local sources for activities supported by the grant, not to supplant such funds.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2EC6A8CC589D489AB36EE35AEDBE2186"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities that—</text> <paragraph id="HCFC43A7682364ED3B0B064D262C1967B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>propose to establish or support an early college high school or other dual or concurrent enrollment program that will serve a student population of which not less than 51 percent are low-income students;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA79C2C76A6604884B2DDC23FE99BA0E2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are from States that provide assistance to early college high schools or other dual enrollment programs, such as assistance to defray the costs of higher education (including costs of tuition, fees, and textbooks); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAE564C6A0CF04D169DFDC733645B5E87"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">propose to establish or support an early college high school or dual or concurrent enrollment program that meets quality standards established by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAE44FE7C34D8451EA15AD6547ACF562E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a nationally recognized accrediting agency or association that offers accreditation specifically for such programs; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A4AAEF001D845E5AC3BE16F4C97596B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a State process specifically for the review and approval of such programs.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0D558DCC6A6D49F29133A7DC32F4763A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Equitable distribution</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure, to the extent practicable, that eligible entities receiving grants under this section—</text>
 <paragraph id="H58009E5A738249FFAB9D8E71D6E83151"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are from a representative cross section of—</text> <subparagraph id="H71104DA1AED54325A62205AA90F8F581"><enum>(A)</enum><text>urban, suburban, and rural areas; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H91E3D42F429943B5850F0D9A6BC6A9B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>regions of the United States; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7B4969DB468432BAB354083B290B948"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include both two-year and four-year institutions of higher education.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1E7B3F73827646499A0AF6160448C426"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Uses of funds</header>
				<paragraph id="H56F58450DA274460ADAA23C4A8EC4F77"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Mandatory activities</header>
 <subparagraph id="H8AF373D649DB4719B8D5EF805932BA94"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity shall use grant funds received under this section—</text> <clause id="H904B939CB00E494887AD569639FEA6EF"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to support the activities described in its application under subsection (i);</text>
 </clause><clause id="H053DB39353944B62AF3F568F8BC92E18"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to create and maintain a coherent system of supports for students, teachers, principals, and faculty under the program, including—</text>
 <subclause id="H67E435841B8C4E4E89F5C4D8332CF3EA"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">college and career readiness, academic, and social support services for students; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H5D1C94A73463421683E443B924322B82"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">professional development for secondary school teachers, faculty, and principals and faculty from the institution of higher education, including—</text>
 <item id="HCDA1A180B31A4FAD8168CC58FC4AEE40"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>joint professional development activities; and</text> </item><item id="HA4B985EF900A4BD1919C9701E8E4106C"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>activities to assist such teachers, faculty, and principals in using effective parent and community engagement strategies and to help ensure the success of students academically at risk of not enrolling in or completing postsecondary education, first-generation college students, and students described in section 1111(b)(2)(B)(xi) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311(b)(2)(B)(xi)</external-xref>);</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause id="HE8A4711DCC904FBBA7991E11DA2915FD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to carry out liaison activities among the partners that comprise the eligible entity pursuant to an agreement or memorandum of understanding documenting commitments, resources, roles, and responsibilities of the partners consistent with the design of the program;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB0B2BD0C8FD540EA945032E7C1E5FAEC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for outreach programs to ensure that secondary school students and their families, including students academically at risk of not enrolling in or completing postsecondary education, first-generation college students, and students described in section 1111(b)(2)(B)(xi) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311(b)(2)(B)(xi)</external-xref>), are—</text>
 <subclause id="H192F4AB4975F47B0A31BA6E19C834B59"><enum>(I)</enum><text>aware of, and recruited into, the early college high school or dual or concurrent enrollment program; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H8D4F44BDDDA44450B9DACE6D048EA3FB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>assisted with the process of enrolling in the early college high school or program;</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H3E65F40780D349C58FA480D2AA41BCE3"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to collect, share, and use data (in compliance with section 444 of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1232g">20 U.S.C. 1232g</external-xref>)) for program improvement and program evaluation; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H967D3431DD054A6C9DF082DD9354F5E9"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>to review and strengthen its program to maximize the potential that students participating in the program will eventually complete a recognized postsecondary credential, including by optimizing—</text>
 <subclause id="H86534409F23F4441AA5090F829F6DAF8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the curriculum of the program;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H37EBF77F5A7B450B932DE7EF7584540A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the sequence of courses offered by the program; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA002B270756B4C5BB7AEAF5819CCEEFB"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the alignment of academic calendars between the secondary schools and the institution of higher education participating in the program.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98DAEB58A0704BD4A557C00958E8E008"><enum>(B)</enum><header>New programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an eligible entity that uses a grant under this section to establish an early college high school or dual or concurrent enrollment program, the entity shall use such funds during the first year of the grant period—</text>
 <clause id="HEB4C28B1CFD94A94B2037D8A9DEAB74D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to design the curriculum and sequence of courses in collaboration with, at a minimum—</text> <subclause id="H1D8344278988451E9FEEC1142B5160B9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>faculty from the institution of higher education;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB20A866BBA7A4E629F541725CE4E5B79"><enum>(II)</enum><text>teachers and faculty from the local educational agency; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H517E898B8B6644E8A214EAC9E2994410"><enum>(III)</enum><text>in the case of a career and technical education program, employers or workforce development entities to ensure that the program is aligned with labor market demand;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HBA14FD9EA5D54EBA91647CCBE4B5F142"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop and implement an articulation agreement between the institution of higher education and the local educational agency that governs how secondary and postsecondary credits will be awarded under the program; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H23AE5526524B4A4E932E4EEEE0F37152"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to carry out the activities described in subparagraph (A).</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H18482A93239C493FA946CAF706E50FAA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Allowable activities</header><text>An eligible entity may use grant funds received under this section to support the activities described in its application under subsection (i), including by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H521A439A14D045899C5A2B1F5BECDF09"><enum>(A)</enum><text>purchasing textbooks and equipment that support the program’s curriculum;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H105DCAB2DF124D9B888F343BA8DF02D6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">pursuant to the assurance provided by the eligible entity under subsection (i)(3)(A), paying tuition and fees for postsecondary courses taken by students under the program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D531858D364457C911FE64BAA38FC69"><enum>(C)</enum><text>incorporating work-based learning opportunities into the program (which may include partnering with entities that provide such opportunities), including—</text>
 <clause id="HB6F15F4C856C402E9F80991D9E644BBE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>internships;</text> </clause><clause id="HE9A003EBD6E24F6F88F63A0A142944EC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>career-based capstone projects;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1DEA75DDE58444A4B26598B3161936BB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">pre-apprenticeships and apprenticeships provided by eligible providers of apprenticeship programs described in section 122(a)(2)(B) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3152">29 U.S.C. 3152(a)(2)(B)</external-xref>); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H374032423CA34197B6630257E9696108"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">work-based learning opportunities provided under chapters 1 and 2 of subpart 2 of part A of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a-11">20 U.S.C. 1070a–11</external-xref> et seq.);</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H817194DC1C434FF18D9F64E5449EC5A3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>providing students with transportation to and from the program;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H444851E032B843CF9DA99DD399880B99"><enum>(E)</enum><text>paying costs for—</text>
 <clause id="H97F5D207597C46C9B08885023DC7BD4F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>high school teachers to obtain the skills, credentials, or industry certifications necessary to teach for the institution of higher education participating in the program; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H32223A9116EF4E1897C16770A4BE6FE5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>postsecondary faculty to become certified to teach high school; or</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC21A4F47B01845008430115D7D00B78A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>providing time during which secondary school teachers and faculty and faculty from an institution of higher education can collaborate, which may include the planning of team activities for such teachers and faculty.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9A98D4277D8943378A5C1956425539F9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Application</header>
 <paragraph id="H982FF745DA444A84BCFDE1ECAC9F8454"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4C0FD6198C85434BA65D267828B363EE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents of application</header><text>The application under paragraph (1) shall include, at minimum, a description of—</text> <subparagraph id="H64C23C349FD74A37A6217FA3826848B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the partnership that comprises the eligible entity, including documentation of partner commitments, resources and budget, roles, and responsibilities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F415A2C946D4004AB8F5DF009F7B1CF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how the partners that comprise the eligible entity will coordinate to carry out the mandatory activities described in subsection (h)(1);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA732923F3AA3413A8689F927D95674EC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number of students intended to be served by the program and demographic information relating to such students;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7CD46EBB5283451AAFB8CCFB9E0D2A1D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>how the eligible entity’s curriculum and sequence of courses form a program of study leading to a recognized postsecondary credential;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9C79397F2984980BED8AEDD25379F11"><enum>(E)</enum><text>how postsecondary credits earned will be transferable to institutions of higher education within the State, including any applicable statewide transfer agreements and any provisions of such agreements that are specific to dual or concurrent enrollment programs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF045CAC0A2B04DF7A35F953472642562"><enum>(F)</enum><text>how the eligible entity will ensure that students understand how credits earned by such students will transfer;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA235F71CF6144CD8BA1F4C370BEFE7F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>outreach programs to provide secondary school students, especially those in middle grades, and their parents, teachers, school counselors, and principals information about, and academic preparation for, the early college high school or other dual enrollment program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF702338B359439B916C35928B79AC9D"><enum>(H)</enum><text>how the eligible entity will determine the eligibility of students for postsecondary courses, including an explanation of the multiple factors the entity will take into account to assess the readiness of students for such courses; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9697DF97225F4CDABAAD6B90BCF82C43"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the sustainability plan for the early college high school or other dual or concurrent enrollment program.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H80D851EDBFE6448E808707EC773352A8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Assurances</header><text>The application under paragraph (1) shall include assurances from the eligible entity that—</text> <subparagraph id="HEE9284D771D74078BA94068923BA1E75"><enum>(A)</enum><text>students participating in a program funded with a grant under this section will not be required to pay tuition or fees for postsecondary courses taken under the program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CDE84385E10434896F8141B089D6802"><enum>(B)</enum><text>postsecondary credits earned by students under the program will be transcribed upon completion of the required course work; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9BD745EF0BFE4FE7A8838950890CBE9A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>instructors of postsecondary courses under the program will meet the same standards applicable to other faculty at the institution of higher education that is participating in the program.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HCA4B15D3D75D45149DD82A816DAD754B"><enum>6.</enum><header>Grants to States</header>
 <subsection id="H4B6667F88EF546B0B995F3B7F2C0CE3F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall award grants to States, on a competitive basis, to assist States in supporting or establishing early college high schools or dual or concurrent enrollment programs.</text>
 </subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB6AA72536C944D8DB0F08E8412EB9EC1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>Each grant under this section shall be awarded for a period of 6 years.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HF055C468A2BB4587AB0C1CB0CDF6B7EE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that the amount of each grant under this section is sufficient to enable each grantee to carry out the activities described in subsection (f).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H32308570923046EC989DA5713380DF5B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Matching requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each year that a State receives a grant under this section, the State shall provide, from non-Federal sources, an amount equal to 50 percent of the amount of the grant received by the State for such year to carry out the activities supported by the grant.</text>
 </subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD73DA335E90D41A0A30F582C3E624E59"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text>A State shall use a grant received under this section only to supplement funds that would, in the absence of such grant, be made available from other Federal, State, or local sources for activities supported by the grant, not to supplant such funds.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H5307421E45B94D5CBDA6C31075AE8103"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Uses of funds</header>
 <paragraph id="H1BEE21027D90474C9875C86EEAE30AC9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Mandatory activities</header><text>A State shall use grant funds received under this section to—</text> <subparagraph id="HF819A3452CA54B3080EC6D0CEA683BCF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>support the activities described in its application under subsection (g);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H345EFE387CD44B04A35A8204BA4E632E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>plan and implement a statewide strategy for expanding access to early college high schools and dual or concurrent enrollment programs for students who are underrepresented in higher education to raise statewide rates of secondary school graduation, readiness for postsecondary education, and completion of recognized postsecondary credentials, with a focus on students academically at risk of not enrolling in or completing postsecondary education;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E5A00F24ED54781BA3D15B9893CF74C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identify any obstacles to such a strategy under State law or policy;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56CED21394304FE9960A6CF00F78CBB4"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide technical assistance (either directly or through a knowledgeable intermediary) to early college high schools and other dual or concurrent enrollment programs, which may include—</text>
 <clause id="HDAE5A4BF27A6460D8BAC343D8C05538F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>brokering relationships and agreements that forge a strong partnership between elementary and secondary and postsecondary partners; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8451E83FEE9C4F30A9962576F13696DB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>offering statewide training and peer learning opportunities for school leaders, instructors, and counselors or advisors;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H871ADFB2F5AD4227A00C32560E4B1D3B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>identify and implement policies that will improve the effectiveness and ensure the quality of early college high schools and dual or concurrent enrollment programs, such as eligibility and access, funding, data and quality assurance, governance, accountability, and alignment policies;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H46A5ECB6D69E4C4A83A2F59E350CD37D"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disseminate best practices for early college high schools and dual or concurrent enrollment programs, which may include best practices from programs in the State or other States;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F0283AAD8AD42EF8EB547D384F5F7C9"><enum>(G)</enum><text>facilitate statewide secondary and postsecondary data collection, research and evaluation, and reporting to policymakers and other stakeholders; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H446691A4A057468996E2D6C56F28654B"><enum>(H)</enum><text>conduct outreach programs to ensure that secondary school students, their families, and community members are aware of early college high schools and dual enrollment programs in the State.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3447AA9EC52644139CB4F26371BB78FB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Allowable activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State may use grant funds received under this section to—</text> <subparagraph id="HFB9E2FA52048423B8AC4877B446F19D2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish a mechanism to offset the costs of tuition, fees, and support services for low-income students enrolled in dual or concurrent enrollment programs or early college high schools;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC2984342115414BABD0F7149E0F27C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establish formal transfer systems within and across State higher education systems, including two-year and four-year public and private institutions, to maximize the transferability of college courses;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9FFB1AB05164B18969B8E94568A239B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide incentives to school districts that—</text> <clause id="H11D9D01D340D4DE8B2DE6C04E3F2E530"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assist high school teachers in getting the credentials needed to participate in dual or concurrent enrollment and early college high school programs; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE6B8C891304D429FBCFBB34C2CDC05BE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>encourage the use of college instructors to teach college courses in high schools; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB6442B13AD547A2B044E44C7310E0C8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>support initiatives to improve the quality of dual or concurrent enrollment programs at participating institutions, including by assisting such institutions in aligning programs with the quality standards described in section 5(f)(3).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H55E796BCE2D94C508393E79D34D2CC0F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>State applications</header>
 <paragraph id="H2EB09B1A2CFA40F688861A3DCAEA40BE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, a State shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9B1DC90412CD4DBA979FE4254AF8CA04"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents of application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The application under paragraph (1) shall include, at minimum, a description of—</text> <subparagraph id="H2A68172B658B4113B9963C5C23E4C2BB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>how the State will carry out the mandatory State activities described subsection (f)(1);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H549EC40BDF1942EFBB04453D945FC9B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how the State will ensure that any programs funded with a grant under this section are coordinated with programs under—</text>
 <clause id="HD9EA264578E549708C1DF02ACD731FC7"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2301">20 U.S.C. 2301</external-xref> et seq.);</text> </clause><clause id="H4016CF2E616149AAA7258614EE563B41"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3101">29 U.S.C. 3101</external-xref> et seq.); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB991B2F9B33E4D7580ACEAEEB303DDDE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6301">20 U.S.C. 6301</external-xref> et seq.);</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19348A2404F24EE797307762F736802E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the State intends to use grant funds to address achievement gaps for each category of students described in section 1111(b)(2)(B)(xi) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311(b)(2)(B)(xi)</external-xref>) as identified by the State in its accountability system under section 1111(c) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311(c)</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3101614922B84B96B863274CFA15A9A9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>how the State will access and leverage additional resources necessary to sustain early college high schools or other dual or concurrent enrollment programs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2AF9128F75B04F89994E08FA8DC65E21"><enum>(E)</enum><text>how the State will identify and eliminate barriers to implementing effective early college high schools and dual or concurrent enrollment programs after the grant expires, including by engaging businesses and nonprofit organizations; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01071BA91B7948B2B21A536F382BFC94"><enum>(F)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6E8860F008804283A8D742A66F9C4878"><enum>7.</enum><header>Reporting and oversight</header> <subsection id="HFA9C5B7879164366BC8CF215E83B4F22"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less frequently than once annually, each State and eligible entity that receives a grant under this Act shall submit to the Secretary a report on the progress of the State or eligible entity in carrying out the programs supported by such grant.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0E2C5E6F84D546C3BFE53A3C6D42F759"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form of report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report under subsection (a) shall be submitted to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require. The Secretary shall issue uniform guidelines describing the information that shall be reported by grantees under such subsection.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HA31FBB03793B491998D2B6A3F981123E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Contents of report</header>
 <paragraph id="H545499539E7441E5ADB0C5AF85DAE040"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The report under subsection (a) shall include, at minimum, the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H4B494A0A7B1145A2BA7267FFF2CE79C3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The number of students enrolled in the early college high school or dual or concurrent enrollment program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A13A88E51AE4E6B9C7418788ABDBBEE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The number and percentage of students enrolled in the early college high school or dual or concurrent enrollment program who earn a recognized postsecondary credential concurrently with a high school diploma.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A661DD75E504F709E08B36DB7149EB6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The number of postsecondary credits earned by eligible students while enrolled in the early college high school or dual or concurrent enrollment program that may be applied toward a recognized postsecondary credential.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC84BE1AA66084858869AB9F0E4775D4D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The number and percentage of students who earn a high school diploma.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0FF1218EBEE3451BAF499380B4721AF1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Total number and percentage of eligible students who enroll in and subsequently complete the early college high school or dual or concurrent enrollment program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F3FE9D0D6ED44D48888E97C9EAC66D7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The number and percentage of graduates who enroll in postsecondary education, in military service, and in employment.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D5884AEAA3B44B2AE859BE3E07692BE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Categories of students</header><text>The information described in each of subparagraphs (A) through (F) of paragraph (1) shall be set forth separately for each category of students described in section 1111(b)(2)(B)(xi) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311(b)(2)(B)(xi)</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8A8B3440A40448FCAB87DDCCA1E73CA1"><enum>8.</enum><header>National activities</header>
 <subsection id="HE177030C1C52410B8F8FDC80A1BE1EAA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reporting by Secretary</header><text>Not less frequently than once annually, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that includes—</text>
 <paragraph id="H5ACED15AFD1E40F696956FC4F8E12855"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an analysis of the information received from States and eligible entities under section 7;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H11C6FEC62C3B4A9FAAE461A6B8EDF9C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an identification of best practices for carrying out programs supported by grants under this Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H554B687B0F864A2FB1F94B25A4205132"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the results of the evaluation under subsection (b).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2127D2D4A5B14DB6B61C69EFA58C398E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>National evaluation</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall seek to enter into a contract with an independent entity to perform an evaluation of the grants awarded under this Act. Such evaluation shall apply rigorous procedures to obtain valid and reliable data concerning student outcomes by social and academic characteristics and monitor the progress of students from secondary school to and through postsecondary education.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3E5FFC547CDB47B3B308D16C38BB620D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary shall provide technical assistance to States and eligible entities concerning best practices and quality improvement programs in early college high schools and dual or concurrent enrollment programs and shall disseminate such best practices among eligible entities, States, and local educational agencies.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H17154A302AF345D6935AC2B171C76F81"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From amounts reserved to carry out this section under section 4(b)(3), the Secretary may reserve such sums as may be necessary for the direct administrative costs of carrying out the Secretary’s responsibilities under this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HA10B103484F849ACBA4BAFFA5D5027AF"><enum>9.</enum><header>Rules of construction</header>
 <subsection id="H0873863056E5433F8E371BCFA0D81E1A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Employees</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to alter or otherwise affect the rights, remedies, and procedures afforded to the employees of local educational agencies (including schools) or institutions of higher education under Federal, State, or local laws (including applicable regulations or court orders) or under the terms of collective bargaining agreements, memoranda of understanding, or other agreements between such employees and their employers.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5912B709AF8E4B1385EFC43F931A3459"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Graduation rate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A student who graduates from an early college high school supported by a grant under section 5 within 100 percent of the normal time for completion described in the eligible entity’s application under such section shall be counted in the four-year adjusted cohort graduation rate for such high school.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


