<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9CC06AB1CFEF47FAAD0E0863D753A56C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><form><distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 520</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170113">January 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000369">Mr. Amodei</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture to more efficiently develop domestic sources of the minerals and mineral materials of strategic and critical importance to the economic and national security and manufacturing competitiveness of the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB3CBC3EE9E2F4DC984FEA3DAFE1BC263" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF2F7259700424B849F4A3F3CF6A9833F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Strategic and Critical Minerals Production Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H61515121C3E94382A9525F09A0510631"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text>
<paragraph id="H2B9DB4D84699449CB2C46566C3F00816"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the industrialization of developing nations has driven demand for nonfuel minerals necessary for telecommunications, military technologies, healthcare technologies, and conventional and renewable energy technologies;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H74E161D2CD1B4BCBAF4A3013623406EA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the availability of minerals and mineral materials are essential for economic growth, national security, technological innovation, and the manufacturing and agricultural supply chain;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA3D27C25BC6C49B5BF194224305AA831"><enum>(3)</enum><text>minerals and mineral materials are critical components of every transportation, water, telecommunications, and energy infrastructure project necessary to modernize the crumbling infrastructure of the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H88366A7E890346A891C0969DDCA7D965"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the exploration, production, processing, use, and recycling of minerals contribute significantly to the economic well-being, security, and general welfare of the United States;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCE4FC158926048C5863101323C19B92A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the United States has vast mineral resources but is becoming increasingly dependent on foreign sources of mineral resources, as demonstrated by the fact that—</text> <subparagraph id="H37861CD4528B45158931BEB185BF0FA3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>25 years ago, the United States was dependent on foreign sources for 45 nonfuel mineral materials, of which—</text>
<clause id="H52DFF643CBDA469CAEEAFB81FEBDF277"><enum>(i)</enum><text>8 were imported by the United States to fulfill 100 percent of the requirements of the United States for those nonfuel mineral materials; and</text></clause> <clause id="HCCDBF1141B1F44C9A433DEF3D99A635F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>19 were imported by the United States to fulfill greater than 50 percent of the requirements of the United States for those nonfuel mineral materials;</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H201BE926B61A4DD3B2E5F7E6440C3856"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by 2015 the import dependence of the United States for nonfuel mineral materials increased from dependence on the import of 45 nonfuel mineral materials to dependence on the import of 47 nonfuel mineral materials, of which—</text> <clause id="H2A6A33861417460AA9EC165404B88D12"><enum>(i)</enum><text>19 were imported by the United States to fulfill 100 percent of the requirements of the United States for those nonfuel mineral materials; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H068A81ABF28A477A8EEF86E192E5B785"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>22 were imported by the United States to fulfill greater than 50 percent of the requirements of the United States for those nonfuel mineral materials;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE61DEBDAD44B456E8D164973066450B3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>according to the Department of Energy, the United States imports greater than 50 percent of the 41 metals and minerals key to clean energy applications;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8468A4B1B56B4950B431CE5999823F06"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the United States share of worldwide mineral exploration dollars was 7 percent in 2015, down from 19 percent in the early 1990s;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H31B31117C34F476492AD0D48028A773E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the 2014 Ranking of Countries for Mining Investment, which ranks 25 major mining countries, found that 7- to 10-year permitting delays are the most significant risk to mining projects in the United States; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6E9023F5C59F43FEBB0BA5839BB8C124"><enum>(F)</enum><text>in late 2016, the Government Accountability Office found that—</text> <clause id="H117EC65BC8AF45CF879551B119EBA6AF"><enum>(i)</enum><text><quote>the Federal government’s approach to addressing critical materials supply issues has not been consistent with selected key practices for interagency collaboration, such as ensuring that agencies’ roles and responsibilities are clearly defined</quote>; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H1443E3C9DB504C5CA41A1802BC4C8024"><enum>(ii)</enum><text><quote>the Federal critical materials approach faces other limitations, including data limitations and a focus on only a subset of critical materials, a limited focus on domestic production of critical materials, and limited engagement with industry</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="HDFC889D6208F4743B0AE12AC0B2068DF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="H3B0CB9816A854C88A5D44744CC29951A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <term>agency</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H53620AFB67E34162B84DCB8ED5C6423D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any agency, department, or other unit of Federal, State, local, or tribal government; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HCA9FA3DD4E4142119C22088061D88C87"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an Alaska Native Corporation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDE8BB579434E40AE82BD5CF1F8C59C2D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Alaska Native Corporation</header><text>The term <term>Alaska Native Corporation</term> has the meaning given the term <term>Native Corporation</term> in section 3 of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1602">43 U.S.C. 1602</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE3133EAE6D5848F8B94F9A5C01EE5439"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Lead agency</header><text>The term <term>lead agency</term> means the agency with primary responsibility for issuing a mineral exploration or mine permit for a project.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H58F20151836C41D7BBA9042A06A072C0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Mineral exploration or mine permit</header><text>The term <term>mineral exploration or mine permit</term> includes—</text>
<subparagraph id="H6C16DBA5FDC643A99A511338E1B3F863"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an authorization of the Bureau of Land Management or the Forest Service, as applicable, for premining activities that requires an environmental impact statement or similar analysis under the <act-name parsable-cite="NEPA69">National Environmental Policy Act of 1969</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD3EDE51F1B4D4DDEA1EA7FEFD650E725"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a plan of operations issued by—</text>
<clause id="H6ED9D09B214E443B9E387045914548C0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Bureau of Land Management under subpart 3809 of part 3800 of title 43, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations); or</text></clause> <clause id="H3FBBA8F010E64D7FAC11C71B99394F9B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Forest Service under subpart A of part 228 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations); and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H077B4FA67861469C8B346B87457718C2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a permit issued under an authority described in section 3503.13 of title 43, Code of Federal regulations (or successor regulations).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB8AE8F6D6A784661B98DEB8606385FF4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Project</header><text>The term <term>project</term> means a project for which the issuance of a permit is required to conduct activities for, relating to, or incidental to mineral exploration, mining, beneficiation, processing, or reclamation activities—</text>
<subparagraph id="H15DA84D3128148C88AB4CCDB9A4B763C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on a mining claim, millsite claim, or tunnel site claim for any locatable mineral; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCFE266066A8642B9AC0C325CAA5FCAD5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in conjunction with any Federal mineral (other than coal and oil shale) that is leased under—</text>
<clause id="HAA1380774A554D179E79108A66D3D437"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Mineral Leasing Act for Acquired Lands (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/351">30 U.S.C. 351</external-xref> et seq.); or</text></clause> <clause id="HC86E0753D95840E49F887166D74C893A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>section 402 of Reorganization Plan Numbered 3 of 1946 (5 U.S.C. App.).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section>
<section id="H1092C2B8EC35423A893914E9BE236CB3"><enum>4.</enum><header>Improving development of strategic and critical minerals</header>
<subsection id="HFB0B348034F6456D88ECC8FAB98D78CB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of strategic and critical minerals</header><text>In this section, the term <term>strategic and critical minerals</term> means minerals that are necessary—</text> <paragraph id="HB4F8A84BB57C465AAC3CF455C8FBB4B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for the national defense and national security requirements;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H24010479A14047528727C4C9A18599B8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for the energy infrastructure of the United States, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H3189A34971D946C593C95DEC83CB2E52"><enum>(A)</enum><text>pipelines;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H02516EB83A914B8C8055A5D972891CF1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>refining capacity;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H43D90046BA704638B4FF98B5184A1616"><enum>(C)</enum><text>electrical power generation and transmission; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB14FA283729F4715B04BBB2E686A27EC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>renewable energy production;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0BDACF57D8AE4D9898A1844075969823"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to support domestic manufacturing, agriculture, housing, telecommunications, healthcare, and transportation infrastructure; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H195FA68AE4AE4FB3BD9680D82CFA8D33"><enum>(4)</enum><text>for the economic security of, and balance of trade in, the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB758411F5CC549E19D1E89DB02E6CF82"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consideration of certain domestic mines as infrastructure projects</header><text>A domestic mine that, as determined by the lead agency, will provide strategic and critical minerals shall be considered to be an infrastructure project, as described in Executive Order 13604 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/601">5 U.S.C. 601</external-xref> note; relating to improving performance of Federal permitting and review of infrastructure projects).</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H21CD6D952BCB4E1A85961AEF11FDF966"><enum>5.</enum><header>Responsibilities of the lead agency</header>
<subsection id="HFB7ECD573BE7471EA850B5E00F62537A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The lead agency shall appoint a project lead within the lead agency, who shall coordinate and consult with cooperating agencies and any other agencies involved in the permitting process, project proponents, and contractors to ensure that cooperating agencies and other agencies involved in the permitting process, project proponents, and contractors—</text> <paragraph id="HCA5142C777B643B78437872C12690F87"><enum>(1)</enum><text>minimize delays;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H053450262D0643E19745B734F3B010B5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>set and adhere to timelines and schedules for completion of the permitting process;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H209075F917A34AD3A57AC6A70CBD10B6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>set clear permitting goals; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H29E8B1DAAF934222A1B4677505DFD43A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>track progress against those goals.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB6E0A16DFEE940A4B749B21E33250C3B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Determination under NEPA</header> <paragraph id="H88397EC89BF14C329C16C3B087A4881E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To the extent that the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.) applies to the issuance of any mineral exploration or mine permit, the requirements of that Act shall be considered to have been procedurally and substantively satisfied if the lead agency determines that any State or Federal agency acting under State or Federal law has addressed or will address the following factors:</text>
<subparagraph id="H655CDE4D813E4BED9CD8755E52820542"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The environmental impact of the action to be conducted under the permit.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H33748170523A43DD9E8E1617F3CBED0A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Possible adverse environmental effects of actions under the permit.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA22323D3677C45D39748A1AF31304BE4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Possible alternatives to issuance of the permit.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1B61DE5D00024EEF904D11DB2304D61F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The relationship between long- and short-term uses of the local environment and the maintenance and enhancement of long-term productivity.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9C9F492D24AA4E7EA06F461E485A0320"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Any irreversible and irretrievable commitment of resources that would be involved in the proposed action.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0A11C30997FB4C43BE33CBB42EF43C49"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Whether public participation will occur during the decisionmaking process for authorizing actions under the permit.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H00C5E9F375B14B52AA9B38667294DC4E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Written requirement</header><text>In making a determination under paragraph (1), not later than 90 days after receipt of an application for the permit, the lead agency, in a written record of decision, shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H8CFACE38E8A64927A142092D3E7101FD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>explain the rationale used in reaching the determination;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDB716DF5BD7D46B297C7445D8C7FF57B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>state the facts in the record that are the basis for the determination; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA78AAA1ECEBD4660898B04C62F58D582"><enum>(C)</enum><text>show that the facts in the record could allow a reasonable person to reach the same determination as the lead agency did.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HEEE963F313D4473A9197B3C59C05B2FE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination on Permitting Process</header>
<paragraph id="HB9D82B4680764DCB92602441A74B158B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The lead agency shall enhance government coordination for the permitting process by—</text> <subparagraph id="H50B1EDB571CD4EE693053099F4A5A79A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>avoiding duplicative reviews;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB4850081BCDC4F77B16D0BAF787DD33F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>minimizing paperwork; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3550842913374BA7BC125192D3635817"><enum>(C)</enum><text>engaging other agencies and stakeholders early in the process.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCFCD706898D64BDF965D2C96122F1679"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the lead agency shall consider—</text> <subparagraph id="H0A0CDF8C72184AA2AD85DDF4289FC8E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>deferring to, and relying on, baseline data, analyses, and reviews performed by State agencies with jurisdiction over the proposed project; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H600FB9C92B114BB9A5977057513C682E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to the maximum extent practicable, conducting any consultations or reviews concurrently rather than sequentially if the concurrent consultation or review would expedite the process.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEF7B2C1E88C0458D95ADCA8A48E8627B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Memorandum of Agency Agreement</header><text>If requested at any time by a State or local planning agency, the lead agency, in consultation with other Federal agencies with relevant jurisdiction in the environmental review process, may establish memoranda of agreement with the project sponsor, State and local governments, and other appropriate entities to accomplish the coordination activities described in this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H592404048A214C3692FA87BEE8178D3F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Schedule for Permitting Process</header>
<paragraph id="H2F46EFBD9A9141FE97C85533D92B3C96"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For any project for which the lead agency cannot make the determination described subsection (b), at the request of a project proponent, the lead agency, cooperating agencies, and any other agencies involved with the mineral exploration or mine permitting process shall enter into an agreement with the project proponent that sets time limits for each part of the permitting process, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H97166AFD697A4FBBB5E79EECFA82DF79"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the decision on whether to prepare an environmental impact statement or similar analysis required under the <act-name parsable-cite="NEPA69">National Environmental Policy Act of 1969</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.);</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H55BC97B8545B48D495F4F09EA7E2CF19"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a determination of the scope of any environmental impact statement or similar analysis required under the <act-name parsable-cite="NEPA69">National Environmental Policy Act of 1969</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5CBE562E36F443CE8489AC964332F247"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the scope of, and schedule for, the baseline studies required to prepare an environmental impact statement or similar analysis required under the <act-name parsable-cite="NEPA69">National Environmental Policy Act of 1969</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.);</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD8F24FD441DE498F9AE27833FDD348BA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>preparation of any draft environmental impact statement or similar analysis required under the <act-name parsable-cite="NEPA69">National Environmental Policy Act of 1969</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE3D3F3BE6F65425FB71A1D1AACD3CAB0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>preparation of a final environmental impact statement or similar analysis required under the <act-name parsable-cite="NEPA69">National Environmental Policy Act of 1969</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.);</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7DB48E3B21F145B6A4EC792E5C47F612"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any consultations required under applicable law;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB5F6017334E74E19BCCDE858FAE00763"><enum>(G)</enum><text>submission and review of any comments required under applicable law;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H11B91652A95E41ED98E154EC72A43802"><enum>(H)</enum><text>publication of any public notices required under applicable law; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5EE2CB04077C46DABB775BA2C4B9D72F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any final or interim decisions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7484063D6F9E45D0B6E6160E0695E37B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Time Limit for Permitting Process</header><text>Except if extended by mutual agreement of the project proponent and the lead agency, the time period for the total review process described in paragraph (1) shall not exceed 30 months.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB3383770D6914582AF630CE0025B4198"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Limitation on Addressing Public Comments</header><text>The lead agency shall not be required to address any agency or public comments that were not submitted—</text>
<paragraph id="H1D4C38009774484782F73830531E4503"><enum>(1)</enum><text>during a public comment period or consultation period provided during the permitting process; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H65381B4DA9C9418388E4D4681A45BC4F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>as otherwise required by law.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H9C4FC9411426430A824F0245DDB502A7"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Financial Assurance</header><text>The lead agency shall determine the amount of financial assurance required for reclamation of a mineral exploration or mining site, on the condition that the financial assurance shall cover the estimated cost if the lead agency were to contract with a third party to reclaim the operations according to the reclamation plan, including construction and maintenance costs for any treatment facilities necessary to meet Federal, State, or tribal environmental standards.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2E126EDBDAF94F3FA2F956E6E4D46795"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Projects within National Forests</header><text>With respect to projects on National Forest System land, the lead agency shall—</text>
<paragraph id="H748D1675254047FEB08138EB66B53FF2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>exempt from the requirements of part 294 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations)—</text> <subparagraph id="HC58B07BD70DA4B6BB98471E98F5A9BEC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>all areas of identified mineral resources in land use designations, other than nondevelopment land use designations, in existence on the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H38495D793FEF47FFB8C6837715B231E5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>all additional routes and areas that the lead agency determines necessary to facilitate the construction, operation, maintenance, and restoration of an area described in paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD52FB3014EF34776A685DB60ACFABA5F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>continue to apply the exemptions described in paragraph (1) after the date on which approval of the minerals plan of operations described in section 3(4)(B)(ii) for the National Forest System land.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HE4D8F5D5CDC14D71B0670B0B76B707F8"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Application to Existing Permit Applications</header>
<paragraph id="H2EB38D587AC84E1FB92EC33C3B274AE6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>This section applies to a mineral exploration or mine permit for which an application was submitted before the date of enactment of this Act if the applicant for the permit submits a written request to the lead agency for the permit.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF6BD8A0EC6D54FF0AD6D02112906C47E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The lead agency shall begin implementing this section with respect to an application described in paragraph (1) not later than 30 days after the date on which the lead agency receives the written request for the permit.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H126079BFA2FD4CA8ABA4EDE721572561"><enum>6.</enum><header>Federal Register process for mineral exploration and mining projects</header>
<subsection id="H6130C5D0B47A4C048384E9ED2CB0178B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Departmental Review</header><text>Absent any extraordinary circumstances, as determined by the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture, as applicable, and except as otherwise required by law, the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture, as applicable, shall ensure that each Federal Register notice associated with the issuance of a mineral exploration or mine permit and required by law shall be—</text> <paragraph id="H59F67C05E5034C128E9DE070042D992F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>subject to any required reviews within the Department of the Interior or the Department of Agriculture, as applicable; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDD85856727924D8794F7A6A7C7D5BE49"><enum>(2)</enum><text>published in final form in the Federal Register not later than 45 days after the date of initial preparation of the notice.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6739100BCD9341F49C5F9BFAFD1642AB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Preparation</header><text>The preparation of any Federal Register notice described in subsection (a) shall be delegated to the organizational level within the lead agency.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H1FBC46389CB74852B830DC561F7BC346"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transmission</header><text>All Federal Register notices described in subsection (a) regarding official document availability, announcements of meetings, or notices of intent to undertake an action shall originate in, and be transmitted to the Federal Register from, the office in which, as applicable—</text> <paragraph id="H56FBC1372A954C17982B3BC5A78E69AB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the documents or meetings are held; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H43A83B652BCF4807AE90975ACD7EBC90"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the activity is initiated.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H84BEF2A8D1E84CB8ABA2C4D21A978F30"><enum>7.</enum><header>Secretarial order not affected</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall not apply to any mineral described in Secretarial Order 3324, issued by the Secretary of the Interior on December 3, 2012, in any area to which the order applies.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

