<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H055890AF9A954D51AA3E0FA71D309D09" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2747 IH: Economic Growth and Development Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2747</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170525">May 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="Y000065">Mr. Yoho</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000378">Mr. Kinzinger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000583">Mr. Thomas J. Rooney of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To catalyze market-based economic growth in developing countries, create opportunities for the
			 private sector of the United States to effectively engage in foreign
			 assistance programs, improve planning and coordination among relevant
			 United States departments and agencies, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HA75CCA9057904201BE9A713B2B9E550A" style="OLC">
 <section id="H00C0AD67E3DF47E9BF7FD916CBAD3F28" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Economic Growth and Development Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H3531EAD33A0A468F89478194ADDA82A0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress on United States development assistance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE884420997474AD48C50A65ED2E1E40E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>United States development assistance—</text> <subparagraph id="H0DA9B3408BBB4CA98F401EDB244D36D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is most effective in countries with governments that demonstrate a commitment to the rule of law, human rights, investing in their own people, combating corruption, and creating a policy environment and legal framework that enables trade, investment, and enduring economic growth;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7450C5A65834D6991C9CCD2C4135B91"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is most likely to produce sustainable results when it aligns with the development priorities of the recipient country, creates opportunities for growth lead by the private sector, and complements rather than replacing government investments in priority sectors through a transparent and accountable system of domestic resource mobilization;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C0F2A2BC50447698BC48B82C4C8A4C5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>should be guided by a unified strategy, ambitious targets, and robust monitoring and evaluation to ensure that it is efficient, effective, and results-oriented;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBDC817CBD3494271959993BEF785A0A9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>should be targeted in recipient countries in a manner that—</text> <clause id="H36157B7010704FA9A38920354D8053C6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>advances the rule of law;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD604E6C7F3D04B8B898E3CE49F1181CF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>builds and strengthens civic institutions and trade capacity;</text> </clause><clause id="H7257C2698E3E4F5BA1095034EB4738C9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>addresses binding constraints to market-based economic growth;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1615FE6216554280BC5C3114AD37EACE"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>catalyzes private sector investment in key development areas, such as utilities, infrastructure, agriculture, health, and education;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8E1F3AA673E64BBE8A1B378DDC2ACCF4"><enum>(v)</enum><text>promotes transparency and accountability among donors, governments, and citizens; and</text> </clause><clause id="H961E93E09CB84D0C93AAFC4706B05EDB"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>places recipient countries on a trajectory toward graduation from foreign assistance; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82B8826289AC4C3A83A25DC78E0B7631"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">should prioritize and better coordinate resources that support enhanced trade capacity and facilitate fairer and more sustainable trade with partner countries; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1CDA4EDF81AD49BEA31168032F366346"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">United States development finance programs, which mobilize private capital to achieve development objectives and may soon outpace traditional grant-based assistance programs in terms of total capital investments, should—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H12E9E7DE160745C4B3555885E0FA9CCD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be appropriately leveraged to complement, rather than replace, other forms of private capital;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0C820D820C84B09ABC02430E62F13E5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>drive inclusive, enduring economic growth; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82F42B0ADFFB472BA6A48EDBFC7787B8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>have stability and predictability by being provided a multi-year authorization.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H0B07717207DA4F1AB70F9AC396E89DF2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Interagency mechanism to coordinate United States development programs and private sector investment</header> <subsection id="H003917085FBD40218C5DE346722FCBD0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall establish a primary interagency mechanism to coordinate United States development assistance programs carried out by Federal departments and agencies engaged in planning or providing such assistance overseas with the investment activities of the private sector.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5F354BE301B44DF6A1E59C1DEC44B40A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The interagency mechanism established under <internal-xref idref="H003917085FBD40218C5DE346722FCBD0" legis-path="3.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref> shall—</text> <paragraph id="HA20E50412D514CE5A5A5CEC3AEEC7FEC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>streamline the private-sector liaison, coordination, and investment promotion functions of such Federal departments and agencies;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5A3CCD068382414E9A024D8AF59B1F80"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilitate the use of development and finance tools across such Federal departments and agencies to attract greater participation in development activities by the private sector; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5651AFDEF29945D0B34F58EC36262E40"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish a single point of contact for entities in the private sector of the United States to pursue partnership opportunities with such Federal departments and agencies.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9F8D94DA9E574E118D49D1A788414CC5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter through 2022, the President shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report evaluating the progress of the interagency mechanism in carrying out the duties described in <internal-xref idref="H5F354BE301B44DF6A1E59C1DEC44B40A" legis-path="3.(b)">subsection (b)</internal-xref>.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H898D874BD4684A24912B2C15CAA5195B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Development strategies</header>
 <subsection id="HB8D76C62B92D4ACCA00FCA069C824D28"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The heads of Federal departments and agencies engaged in planning or providing United States development assistance overseas shall ensure that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDD340CFE5B3349A8B5E960D6C9804146"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a rigorous analysis of the constraints to economic growth and investment within a country receiving such assistance guides any development strategy of the United States with respect to such country; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H64CC0B2EB2204DD8A941270FA6A6BB87"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the development strategies of the United States are coordinated with activities carried out by the private sector within countries receiving such assistance, to the greatest extent practicable and appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H05446F4FC1FC48B5AE17E817A6D50C64"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters To be included</header><text>Each analysis required under <internal-xref idref="HDD340CFE5B3349A8B5E960D6C9804146" legis-path="4.(a)(1)">subsection (a)(1)</internal-xref> shall include an identification and analysis of—</text> <paragraph id="H4F75FBBE5CAF402DA96CE8F7A092DC12"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the constraints posed by inadequacies in critical infrastructure, the education system, the rule of law, the tax and investment codes, or the customs or regulatory regimes in the recipient country; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB320A5F41D704D9EB9A07910AE4A8647"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the particular economic sectors, such as the agriculture, transportation, energy, education, or financial services sectors, that are central to achieving economic growth in the recipient country.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4728A48DE151432AA16BE02F29811225"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Results</header><text>The results of each analysis required under <internal-xref idref="HDD340CFE5B3349A8B5E960D6C9804146" legis-path="4.(a)(1)">subsection (a)(1)</internal-xref> shall be—</text> <paragraph id="HB955618AE56343E79040A4D91AA39F4D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>incorporated into any relevant development strategy, as defined in <internal-xref idref="H8BB155F5F9C24051840394E32889E878" legis-path="4.(d)">subsection (d)</internal-xref>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H71947644E980407D9EF0CB195C4A3998"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">used to inform and guide the allocation of resources by Federal departments and agencies engaged in planning or providing United States development assistance overseas.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8BB155F5F9C24051840394E32889E878"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Development strategy defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>development strategy</quote> means any global, sectoral, or country development strategy of the United States and includes any integrated country strategy, regional or functional strategy, country development cooperation strategy, or mission strategic resource plan.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


