<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2823911EE2704EE78757E19968848F55" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1692 IH: Countering Illegal Firearms Trafficking to Mexico Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1692</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170322">March 22, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To address the problem of illegal firearm trafficking to Mexico.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H1424E99B19F242DF97B30713AB164D81" style="OLC">
 <section id="H234BA9A7B4D742BBADFBC12BBBE7748D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Countering Illegal Firearms Trafficking to Mexico Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H2130DE06FA4B4B37A9C04BF9ECA20071"><enum>2.</enum><header>Collaboration between U.S. Immigrations and Customs Enforcement and the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The President shall design and implement a strategy to improve collaboration between U.S. Immigrations and Customs Enforcement and the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives in the investigation of illegal firearm trafficking to Mexico, including formal monitoring of the implementation of the 2009 Memorandum of Understanding between the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives and U.S. Immigrations and Customs Enforcement.</text>
 </section><section id="H621E6B96F5244E8A8B9E2FB8C934B65A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Comprehensive indicators to stem arms trafficking to Mexico</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Office of National Drug Control Policy shall establish comprehensive indicators that more accurately reflect progress made in efforts to stem arms trafficking to Mexico.</text>
		</section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCB5D89A9800947E3ACC7A6BA6D668BB4"><enum>4.</enum><header>Firearms trafficking</header>
 <subsection id="H4DE96FF4EE934E878B05BF68466A8E2F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/44">Chapter 44</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7D5DC69D8DDE45B78D28C0727D094378" style="USC"> <section id="H271FA86FBBAA40E0BC2C9FA7837C51F0"><enum>932.</enum><header>Trafficking in firearms</header> <subsection id="HB1B2CF98CC55489EAC21E4AAF764887A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Offenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be unlawful for any person, regardless of whether anything of value is exchanged—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7A9A63CF7A8341978721F8618F571741"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to ship, transport, transfer, or otherwise dispose to a person, 2 or more firearms in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce, if the transferor knows or has reasonable cause to believe that such use, carry, possession, or disposition of the firearm would be in violation of, or would result in a violation of any Federal, State, or local law punishable by a term of imprisonment exceeding 1 year;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB54C43D05E134808BCD75B62EC06E91E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to receive from a person, 2 or more firearms in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce, if the recipient knows or has reasonable cause to believe that such receipt would be in violation of, or would result in a violation of any Federal, State, or local law punishable by a term of imprisonment exceeding 1 year;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2BD6A8238051439D9560406FEC8261CA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to make a statement to a licensed importer, licensed manufacturer, or licensed dealer relating to the purchase, receipt, or acquisition from a licensed importer, licensed manufacturer, or licensed dealer of 2 or more firearms that have moved in or affected interstate or foreign commerce that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H790799EC332A44578F571E92D9397F9F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is material to—</text> <clause id="H2519AF4631994E1D81D0F657D3DE1E2F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the identity of the actual buyer of the firearms; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8BD5F8BF3EEE4C51B2F2B2D772FCFBC8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the intended trafficking of the firearms; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66F0E1745B474F338194BC5706160172"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the person knows or has reasonable cause to believe is false; or</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H75F29E482889449EB1573B17879A10A6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to direct, promote, or facilitate conduct specified in paragraph (1), (2), or (3).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H652DB280AD284F65B35C893830404AAF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Penalties</header> <paragraph id="HC5E59FBD0A2741869F160F4EEA8014CA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any person who violates, or conspires to violate, subsection (a) shall be fined under this title, imprisoned for not more than 20 years, or both.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9179DF68733A4669BF7471B4F189A2B0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Organizer enhancement</header><text>If a violation of subsection (a) is committed by a person in concert with 5 or more other persons with respect to whom such person occupies a position of organizer, a supervisory position, or any other position of management, such person may be sentenced to an additional term of imprisonment of not more than 5 consecutive years.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6D89D00844CF4E3AA53020BAB2374E79"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="H3B636E986AF0457DBEB42BE8AA015527"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>actual buyer</term> means the person for whom a firearm is being purchased, received, or acquired; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFB435F40667E48D189D9DB6FE969D35F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>term of imprisonment exceeding 1 year</term> does not include any offense classified by the applicable jurisdiction as a misdemeanor and punishable by a term of imprisonment of 2 years or less.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE7DB800D8C4441F4AF7B53AF7D052040"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for chapter 44 of such title is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE4EED5C9ECE94C6989A32829411DDB45" style="OLC"> <toc> <toc-entry bold="off" level="section">932. Trafficking in firearms.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection></section><section id="HFE0248AD2C1248E7A06158A3D0A619D3"><enum>5.</enum><header>Requirement that Federal firearms licensees report multiple sales of firearms</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 923(g)(3)(A) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>pistols, or revolvers, or any combination of pistols and revolvers totalling two or more,</quote> and inserting <quote>firearms</quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="H552B3715ADF0404FB73660E323F6F205"><enum>6.</enum><header>Public availability of information about firearms seized by Mexico and submitted to the Bureau of
 Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives for tracing</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Within 30 days after the beginning of each fiscal year that begins more than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives shall make public detailed information about the type, make, model, and caliber of each firearm seized by authorities of the Government of Mexico and submitted to the Bureau for tracing.</text>
 </section><section id="H879BCC6FD0684EC38E02DC9708296945"><enum>7.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act and the amendments made by this Act shall take effect on the date that is 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


