<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H7F839728BC1B4283929CA3BF3B39D77B" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3565 IH: Federal Land Freedom Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3565</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170728">July 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001273">Mrs. Black</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000459">Mr. Fleischmann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000392">Mr. Kustoff of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001192">Mr. Stewart</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000582">Mr. Roe of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001243">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000533">Mr. Duncan of Tennessee</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To achieve domestic energy independence by empowering States to control the exploration,
			 development, and production of oil and gas on all available Federal land,
			 and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HAE003CD60D5E476A9FADF2FCA50226C1" style="OLC">
 <section id="H6A5AD2F639DE4E8EA18E4AB6CDB263BB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Land Freedom Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H59CB8CD49D85403B862CB6A0C49D971E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H46DB7F543B0A47AF82197E4CB9A72785"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as of the date of the enactment of this Act—</text> <subparagraph id="HF434B57A86D948AEBDCFC73D15BDCCE9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">113,000,000 acres of onshore Federal land are open and accessible for oil and gas development; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBDD9B099E00F4425909FC3ACB7734F4D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>approximately 166,000,000 acres of onshore Federal land are off-limits or inaccessible for oil and gas development;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F9FF002530547008B172B4DE50373D3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>despite the recent oil and gas boom in the United States, the number of acres of Federal land leased for oil and gas exploration has decreased by 31 percent since 2008;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6A29AF04F2BA4731AD49B0294DA8405E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in 2015, the Federal Government leased only 36,000,000 acres of Federal land, in contrast to the 131,000,000 acres that were leased in 1984;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H96BE01DFB5EB4C508660FD423A0008F3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the reduction in leasing of Federal land harms economic growth and Federal revenues;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H37BDC5AAD669413D9CE390AF2B98C6B5"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in 2015, it took, on average, 220 days to process applications for permits to drill on Federal land; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H22FE773B96CF43D2819360B0ECEEC9BC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>States have extensive and sufficient regulatory frameworks for permitting oil and gas development.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H5521F776E6DA4DC890CD3EED5C139F27"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H7E4C4EB18F224C11A4506E05F301D260"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Available federal land</header><text>The term <term>available Federal land</term> means any Federal land that, as of May 31, 2017—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H6EF84FAB961A49A69EA00511C1E874EA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is located within the boundaries of a State;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HEB7CDF8E49484A56AB5E2671D424FDF4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not held by the United States in trust for the benefit of a federally recognized Indian tribe;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6E7E582E6BFF4CCCB72C628BBCC06080"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is not a unit of the National Park System;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H51138F3A2E11456A9E14D60285F0E9A9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is not a unit of the National Wildlife Refuge System;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H00DCE5DABB7647AD9217B663B230B768"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not Congressionally approved wilderness area under the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</external-xref> et seq.); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H150BC33B6C034B8F8D7EEADDAFEEB275"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has been identified as land available for lease for the exploration, development, and production of oil or gas—</text>
 <clause id="H8F48CE9FC5A44235BDC39AF5974E0EF2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by the Bureau of Land Management under a Resource Management Plan pursuant to the process provided for in the Federal Land Management and Policy Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.); or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA04521EE5D014080967CCBBAFA6B8737"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by the Forest Service under a Forest Management Plan pursuant to the process provided for in the National Forest Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1600">16 U.S.C. 1600</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H54D8925AA9AA4D7B98483ADB3580CBE6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HB05AF0DE1060446F9C5C0A7BA0C5F4D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>one of the several States; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H130D9D3C55494C3BA36365BA9C3EDEE2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the District of Columbia.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC0A83A2AC00B41B186EF8BD95A2CC8ED"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State regulatory program</header><text>The term <term>State regulatory program</term> means a program established pursuant to State law that regulates oil and gas exploration, development, and production on land located in the State.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4DD5FA949C9A4E1AB7BC0BBA7084092D"><enum>4.</enum><header>State control of oil and gas exploration, development, and production on all available Federal land</header>
 <subsection id="H479ADE82498C4D4BBE863DF3415DB3EA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Submission of State regulatory program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State in which there may be the leasing, permitting, or regulating of oil and gas exploration, development, and production activities on available Federal lands, and which wishes to assume exclusive jurisdiction over the leasing, permitting, and regulation of such oil and gas activities, shall submit to the Secretaries of the Interior and Agriculture a State regulatory program which demonstrates that such State has the capability of carrying out the provisions of this Act and meeting its purposes through—</text>
 <paragraph id="H07958B96480B4311A7CB6B24F5F0F278"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a State law which provides for the leasing, regulation and permitting of oil and gas exploration, development, and production activities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H732345DA41424905BCBC41983C9670DB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a State law which provides sanctions for violations of State laws, regulations, or conditions of permits concerning oil and gas exploration, development, and production activities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDF2A0A61C48546E8A0A61D082A449255"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a State regulatory authority with sufficient administrative and technical personnel, and sufficient funding to enable the State to lease, regulate and permit oil and gas exploration, development, and production activities; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9723276459314EA8A7D7539998BD58B1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a State law which provides for the effective implementation, maintenance, and enforcement of a permit system for oil and gas exploration, development, and production activities on available Federal lands within the State.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE2C54FC8BAF84CCD8358FF18F95A08F0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Approval of state regulatory program</header>
 <paragraph id="H900FB01ABCD946B2BEB4C4D687F7C6FC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The State regulatory program submitted under subsection (a) shall be deemed approved, unless, not later than 60 days after submission, the Secretaries of the Interior and Agriculture—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFC26B90E3DED48E9B64C320971A04626"><enum>(A)</enum><text>find approval of a State regulatory program would result in decreased royalty payments to the Federal Government; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H040EB041A64B4BDB84C61A1DB6BC2EB5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>determine that the State Regulatory Program submitted under subsection (a) does not have the capability to carry out the provisions of this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E6C80783FBC4346AD4448746F735BCE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Adverse determination</header><text>For any adverse determination by the Secretaries, the Secretaries shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H40AE6F1E6B7B43CB9B866D361369A026"><enum>(A)</enum><text>notify, in writing, the State applicant of the reason for the withholding of approval; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7999AEDAD1B845148A01764ADA98F12D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide any additional information, data, or analysis upon which such determination is based.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HE3FAAB31412443458C69EC192CAD04F4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effect of Approval of State regulatory program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, on approval of a State regulatory program under subsection (b), the State shall assume the Federal leasing, permitting and regulatory responsibilities for oil and gas exploration, development, and production on available Federal land located in the State in accordance with the approved plan.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD469D5618EB440FFA0A5349FAFF801EB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effect of State action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any action by a State to lease, permit, or regulate oil and gas exploration, development, and production in accordance with an approved State regulatory program shall not be subject to, or considered a Federal action, Federal permit, or Federal license under—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB8CA6583EFF94642BA5F7C9B9E8E3CC6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>subchapter II of chapter 5, and chapter 7, of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the ‘‘Administrative Procedure Act’’);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4BC37E1619654265ACC387278A8E72E7"><enum>(2)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/54/3001">chapter 3001</external-xref> of title 54, United States Code;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE4E116B629A04F6FA2423839FA8C2FC1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531</external-xref> et seq.); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5351142A55134687B62ADC7B3A750A25"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HA807F47833154D7895BC96762725BAD0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reassumption of regulatory authority by the Secretary</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="H718E230B9A134173BC9A0AFE012638A7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Voluntary surrender of authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a State regulatory program has been approved under subsection (b), such state may voluntarily revoke such approval, and relinquish the duties under subsection (c) upon providing a 60-day notice to the Secretaries of the Interior and Agriculture. Upon the expiration of the 60-day period, the state shall no longer be permitted to lease, regulate, or permit oil and gas exploration, development, and production activities on available Federal lands.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC3122D2FFDB445DD9EB39E4235FE1DFD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Involuntary surrender of authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretaries of the Interior or Agriculture determine a State regulatory program has resulted in a 20-percent decrease in royalties to the Federal government from the preceding year, the Secretaries shall notify the state of such decrease. Such notified state shall have 180 days to address the royalty deficiency. If a state fails to improve the amount of royalties paid to the federal government, then the Secretaries of the Interior and Agriculture may jointly determine to revoke the approval of the state regulatory program under subsection (b).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H773AB92C2AFB4B7D8F141007B136931C"><enum>5.</enum><header>No effect on Federal revenues</header>
 <subsection id="H2CC5F0754C4C4416BB496FBD7D2EDF5C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any lease or permit issued by a State under section 4 shall include provisions for the collection of royalties or other revenues in an amount equal to the amount of royalties or revenues that would have been collected if the lease or permit had been issued by the Federal Government.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEFD2C97772E143B3942F251B48B000B4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Disposition of revenues</header><text>Any revenues collected under a lease or permit issued by a State under section 4 shall be deposited in the same Federal account in which the revenues would have been deposited if the lease or permit had been issued by the Federal Government.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4A7D777717A74FF38408FA166BA6462B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effect on State processing fees</header><text>Nothing in this Act prohibits a State from collecting and retaining a fee from an applicant to cover the administrative costs of processing an application for a lease or permit.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


