<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H6F6146E274544034B05BB2EB026A0958" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4438 IH: To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to waive a prohibition, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4438</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171116">November 16, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000577">Mr. Graves of Louisiana</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000588">Mr. Richmond</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001048">Mr. Culberson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001111">Mr. Crist</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001051">Mr. Carter of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000460">Mr. Farenthold</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000806">Mr. Webster of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000582">Miss González-Colón of Puerto Rico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to waive a
			 prohibition, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H205F1568F71B48199156E764B3443ACF" style="OLC">
		<section id="HE17FD58C992949BFBEEA4CB90A67F92A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Duplication of benefits</header>
 <subsection id="HF3C8D5D213D94C46B1BC8617A17AC928"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 312(b) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5155">42 U.S.C. 5155(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE2CBEA875BB14544B33F819B82EF5508" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="H57A10362AA79481E94631734E647C086"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Waiver of general prohibition</header>
 <subparagraph id="H0E0DE06236BF4E88887E3FB4AA37E091"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may waive the general prohibition provided in subsection (a) upon request of a Governor, if the President finds such waiver is in the public interest. In making this decision the President may consider the following:</text>
 <clause id="H336C91FCE51E4A69B0256ADF4439E9FB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The recommendations of the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency made in consultation with the Federal agency administering the duplicative program.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H28F298C11CEC47C0A7D45572BBD08D1F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The cost benefits to be achieved by funding the assistance if the waiver is granted.</text> </clause><clause id="H83E3F07F08BC49E693931CFF2FC7B6B0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Equity and good conscience.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H726AFA8FE7234012A6033908F9F7AC0E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Other matters of public policy considered appropriate by the President.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA0DBFF700664A51B9E90DBD37657036" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Grant or denial of waiver</header><text>A request under subparagraph (A) shall be granted or denied not later than 45 days after submission of such request.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6CB68C15040437AAEB71B1E2468533F" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Prohibition on determination that loan is a duplication</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (c), in carrying out subparagraph (A), the President may not determine that a loan is a duplication of assistance.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="HDCFF4C62720E41319CB9BCD4491E6228"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Funding of a federally authorized water resources development project</header>
 <paragraph id="H8EC8E8D9524C4ECC97FB2AA9B5929A58"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Notwithstanding section 312 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act and its implementing regulations, assistance provided pursuant to section 404 of such Act may be used to fund eligible activities under section 404 associated with the construction of a federally authorized water resources development project of the Army Corps of Engineers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H808AE9DEDEFD48DEA8D7002F58B26D44"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to change the cost share of the hazard mitigation measures as determined under section 404.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC2311159A20B466BAEB305848C37251A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>All Federal funding provided under section 404 pursuant to this subsection shall be considered Federal funding for the purposes of a federally authorized water resources development project of the Army Corps of Engineers to which the State or local funding is applied.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0F57F3DBFC9347D5BE38B4A5B4316084"><enum>(4)</enum><text>All non-Federal match funding provided under section 404 pursuant to this subsection shall be considered non-Federal funding for the purposes of a federally authorized water resources development project of the Army Corps of Engineers to which State or local funding is applied.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE5279B9A43364853864E790D880D0EFC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Funding provided under section 404 pursuant to this subsection may not exceed the total Federal share for a federally authorized water resources development project of the Army Corps of Engineers.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


