<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H0A47D03475434B6CB30991028A59BC18" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3980 IH: Hate Crimes Commission Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3980</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171005">October 5, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001251">Mr. Butterfield</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000535">Mr. Gutiérrez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001200">Mr. McEachin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000127">Mr. Nolan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000390">Mr. Kihuen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000576">Mr. Ruppersberger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000581">Mrs. Lawrence</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000627">Mrs. Demings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000062">Mr. Yarmuth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000593">Mr. Perlmutter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Maxine Waters of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001165">Mr. Sires</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001170">Ms. Shea-Porter</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a United States Commission on Hate Crimes to study and make recommendations on the
			 prevention of the commission of hate crimes, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HED3471C4A4B54082AE3FED1E565CDEE0" style="OLC">
 <section id="H6897CD382D3B49BD87811FF02ADF355A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Hate Crimes Commission Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HF327132E7B474EFA98D69EC0F3E7CBFE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="H12D7BD38FA224A25848866616A34A0B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Bureau of Investigation defines a <quote>hate crime</quote> to be a criminal offense—such as murder, arson, or vandalism—against a person or property motivated in whole or in part by an offender’s bias against a race, religion, disability, sexual orientation, ethnicity, gender, or gender identity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3A6FF8EE785146848680C43462B7ED04"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Forty-five States and the District of Columbia have statutes criminalizing various types of bias-motivated violence or intimidation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H593C92A26CB54AB7AF0A32B24445AA12"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Federal Government has had hate crimes statutes since 1968, with the most recent law enacted in 2009.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEA156EFB8399462ABA7070EEF9B2BBA6"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The impact of underreporting on hate crimes statistics hinders hate crimes prevention.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7CFE0966F79248948C98067B7514A9EF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>According to multiple, nonpartisan studies, hate crimes have increased sharply over the past year, with over 900 new hate incidents reported since November 2016.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4509A66EC92147E08AA439A08DC09F4F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The U.S. Commission on Civil Rights found that in 2016, there was a 6.7-percent increase in reported hate crimes since the prior year, one of the largest one-year increases in over a decade.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H86CBEDF43ECE440FB06CF29DB0EFBF6E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>In May 2017, the FBI found that White supremacists and rightwing extremist groups were responsible for 49 deaths in 26 incidents between 2000 and 2016, the most of any domestic extremist group. The same report found that White supremacists and rightwing extremist groups were the largest threat of domestic terror, and were likely to continue to pose a lethal threat over the next year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD9BB8866A5CA48B9BED019A4408F119D"><enum>(8)</enum><text>In February 2017, a White supremacist entered a bar in Kansas and shot at two Indian men, Srinivas Kuchibhotla and Alok Madasani while shouting racial epithets. Srinivas later died of his injuries.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H28D2A516A5174FB3BF21D4DA7E44EF85"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The nonpartisan Center for the Study of Hate and Extremism documented 55 instances of anti-Semitism between January and March 2017 in New York City alone, a 189-percent increase from the same time period in 2016, and close to 100 bomb threats have been received by Jewish Community Centers and Schools.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8CEB02179D014E6D8F596FA9AE3F7409"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Since January, there have been at least five attacks on LGBT centers across the country.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD6E13CE13A9046EBA6744C3559271023"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The White nationalist and neo-Nazi protests in Charlottesville, Virginia, on August 11–13, 2017, which resulted in 1 death and 20 injuries from a White nationalist driving his car into a group of counterprotesters, show the need for increased action to combat hate-based attacks.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HDD7278BAE8534E9BA90DE1F64DEC24ED"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of Commission</header>
 <subsection id="H236180FE5F774F2486B98405798A2792"><enum>(a)</enum><header> Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established the United States Commission on Hate Crimes (hereinafter in this act referred to as the <quote>Commission</quote>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H33B1ABB136D142C58CC5C5D1D4A377E7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall be composed of 12 members. Membership of the Commission shall be appointed in accordance with the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HCCB7B663182A4FB191F016F634D9FC15"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Two members shall be appointed by the majority leader of the Senate.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6EF382E6A51F484797551C09A64D672F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Two members shall be appointed by the minority leader of the Senate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6833B7B5B2AD4AF4AD3D21ED3737474A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Two members shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9F1249309FCF4F23B8D0D692BD2D6C72"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Two members shall be appointed by the minority leader of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9B7AF8382ADD4077BD638F520E2EB073"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Two members shall be jointly appointed by the two appointing officials under paragraphs (1) through (4) who are members of, or caucus with, the Democratic Party.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H11D0529A944E4E71A5C6839885B07437"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Two members shall be jointly appointed by the two appointing officials under paragraphs (1) through (4) who are members of, or caucus with, the Republican Party.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H274D4992BAEF4C86B94ECBC71037F710"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Not more than 6 members of the Commission shall be from the law enforcement community and not more than 6 members of the Commission shall be of the civil rights community.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H61A97038F4D043AC80C7C198BDDCD729"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not more than six of the members shall be of the same political party.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD02A47DB8E29482096154BEFC93550D7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duties of the Commission</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Commission shall investigate the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HCEA3FDAF4159444FBE27E78FA3239BDE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>If there has been an increase in hate crimes during the period beginning January 1, 2007, and ending 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H66176DCCC064449098EBFA8076D46D4F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To the extent that any increase in the commission in hate crimes is determined to exist, what factors have contributed to such increase.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H99440F0F5CC8455EA5907AACFAE182E1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>What policies or actions law enforcement agencies might adopt or engage in to reduce the commission of hate crimes.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF7A8ECE2DF154DE6BC5C1DFB20AE86EF"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The impact of underreporting on hate crimes statistics and hate crimes prevention.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="HABF471D4FC1440ECB3F18106C95AD1BC"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall submit a report to Congress and the President setting forth the results of the investigation under section 4.</text>
 </section><section id="H7CEF2EE433154EF2848CA254A0B8D800"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>hate crime</term> means an offense under section 249 of title 18, United States Code.</text> </section></legis-body></bill> 

