<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H7CD34826C1D34DAEA38C02D3C2F77587" key="H" public-private="public">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2905 IH: Justice for Victims of IRS Scams and Identity Theft Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2905</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20170615">June 15, 2017</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="Y000066">Mr. Young of Iowa</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001191">Ms. Sinema</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To require the Attorney General to establish procedures for expedited review of the case of any person who unlawfully solicits personal information for purposes of committing identity theft, while purporting to be acting on behalf of the IRS, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form> 
<legis-body id="H199FB1BFE309491FA4DEBE5D1BE096F9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCF1FD9787D694EE3B4EBC27216DA85A5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Justice for Victims of IRS Scams and Identity Theft Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="HB7B310FCAA11485399B10DC6281FAA3C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Procedures for expedited review of IRS impersonation fraud</header> <subsection id="H53FA16F501C048EA8EEA14F09C65A966"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of procedures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">By not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall establish procedures for expediting review of, and, where appropriate, seeking an indictment in, any case involving an offense described in subsection (b).</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H28E9CA96275F43CBA3BACFEA29C17A0F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Offense described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An offense described in this subsection is any violation of section 1028(a) or 1028A(a) of title 18, United States Code, wherein the defendant misrepresented himself or herself to be engaged in lawful activities on behalf of, or carrying out lawful duties as an officer or employee of the Internal Revenue Service.</text> </subsection></section> <section id="HB39985E9470F494B9B39DCC9610DB3EC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header> <subsection id="HB922F9F4BF634D108BC7481C7A8E561F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Secretary of the Treasury report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury shall submit a report to Congress detailing—</text> 
<paragraph id="H219F3689E4A5467D9D799F5B8C1D793F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">current efforts by the Secretary to assist with the prosecution of offenses described in section 2(b);</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H2C9CA2078DC34E31A8512FFB69ADAD55"><enum>(2)</enum><text>overall trends in the commission of such offenses;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBFF0886216264CB48158141F8A726271"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Secretary’s recommendations regarding what resources are needed to facilitate improved review and prosecution of such cases; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H3925E4D5161A4E268FF8DD53D31540A3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>information on what assistance the Internal Revenue Service may offer victims of such offenses.</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HD7788FB4F1354C41AF6029A6E84A1FDF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Attorney General report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall submit to Congress a report on the status of prosecutions for violations of section 1028(a) or 1028A(a) of title 18, United States Code, including—</text> <paragraph id="H20216D153A8A4733AC55A7002111E8EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of cases referred to the Attorney General during the 5-year period immediately preceding the date of the report by any agency of the Federal Government, disaggregated by the type and number of complaints referred by each agency;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1A24FCA17E0F4CFD84EDDAB308B66413"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a map of the United States indicating how many cases were referred for prosecution by agencies of the Federal Government in each judicial district;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H52530139974E4D3BA0729A92598A1AC7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the rate, by year and judicial district, of conviction for cases so referred; and</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H041086ED222244BF91051CC68E918FF3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Attorney General’s recommendations regarding—</text> <subparagraph id="H493C4CBD42AD455494E69D483FF47463"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identification of trends in the commission of such offenses;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE81CA94B33F24DE896043C2480F8478C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how to improve collaboration with other Federal agencies;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFF0BD603667A40FF978287A8A247D055"><enum>(C)</enum><text>how to improve law enforcement deterrence and prevention of such offenses; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5E2B23DF21FC424DAA2E455BB673E1C7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>whether such offenses are being committed by individuals or criminal organizations.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H9671B45099084DE3A2028943CEBC6E9E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Publication of report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall make the report submitted under section 3(b) publically available on an Internet webpage of the Attorney General.</text> </section>
</legis-body>
</bill> 


