<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC907146C1E044469816021CCDD7CE5CF" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1146 IH: Equal Opportunity for Residential Representation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1146</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170216">February 16, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to establish a pilot program to make
			 grants to eligible organizations to provide legal assistance to low-income
			 families regarding housing disputes, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H2AEB528768604C22A7B7DD0EDC1B442A" style="OLC">
 <section id="H3CE0C75219524768B6DAD7F7752B75B2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Equal Opportunity for Residential Representation Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H2D8EFCBB1CA74621A9416738726D6C09"><enum>2.</enum><header>Congressional findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDCC09BA01847499A96B16D4B3AF9F343"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">eviction prevention programs provide important and effective social and economic benefits;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H31CCB58BB7B94096998A5D462C0A72ED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such programs help protect low-income and at-risk households from the trauma and disruption of homelessness and save property owners from the high costs of forced eviction and re-occupancy; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8C6B21D2D8034C45BFA49F53F302766E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>investing more resources in eviction prevention helps communities save on the high cost of homelessness by stopping homelessness before it starts—for example, according to 2015 data, the Massachusetts Housing and Shelter Alliance estimates that a homeless individual residing in Massachusetts creates an additional cost burden for State-supported services (such as shelters, emergency room visits, and incarceration) that is $9,372 greater per year than for a housed individual.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HF7CA9231273E4A47A800E9335DB18330"><enum>3.</enum><header>Pilot program for legal assistance for housing issues for low-income families</header>
 <subsection id="HA80B154649E9414FA3E5994D34B3141F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall carry out a program under this section, through the Office of Community Planning and Development, to make grants to the extent amounts for such grants are made available pursuant to subsection (f) to eligible organizations under subsection (d) to provide legal services and other related supportive services under subsection (e) on behalf of eligible low-income families under subsection (c).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H038C9DA5E22D4F7ABF50AD42F48A55A1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Selection of grantees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall select eligible organizations under subsection (d) to receive grants under this section taking into consideration factors, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB67F180CE4A14EC9B3F340B363C241EB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">factors necessary to ensure an equitable distribution of grants to grantees serving urban areas (as such term is defined by the Secretary) and to grantees serving rural areas (as such term is defined by the Secretary), except that the Secretary shall ensure that, of any amounts made available for any fiscal year for grants under this section, not less than 20 percent shall be used for grantees serving rural areas;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9C8B678654FF43A19CEDA9AF55B02EAB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of rental units in the area served by the grantee that are affordable to low-income households having incomes at or below 80 percent of the area median income and paying more than 30 percent of their incomes for rent;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF75B7895232040DE9CD89EF166DA9901"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the extent to which the population of the area served by the grantee uses eviction or other housing-related legal services or has a need for such services;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4CC7BE2B2B5B42C6ABC8B1C507EA1054"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the extent to which tenants in the area served by the grantee are evicted;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEBBE6882DDAA4B05ADF878E5206C3946"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of rental units in the area served by the grantee that are affordable to households having incomes at or below 80 percent of the area median income;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H40EE6B0EC06D4EB7BD10AD6228CD3C81"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the extent of poverty in the area served by the grantee;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H05FEE28BB7C94408965E5CC1CE788BD9"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of renter households in the area served by the grantee that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6BD14FBE2F0F4474A6C4931500110E2F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have incomes at or below 80 percent of the area median income;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D3B0E75CB174313B38DB88203AFA15C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are not provided rental assistance, such as rental assistance under section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937 or occupancy in a dwelling unit in public housing; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFFC429A840C34E498F4A12F608748D97"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">live in severely inadequate housing, as measured using the American Housing Survey definition of housing having severe physical problems; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H59CD8D7F4DC144D5938F01DB33B56344"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other factors that the Secretary considers appropriate for purposes of this section, except that the Secretary may not consider data from a point-in-time count of the homeless (as defined in section 103(a) of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11302">42 U.S.C. 11302(a)</external-xref>)).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAB5DCFCB31A0455B9BA0A5952ABE9362"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible low-Income families</header><text>Amounts from a grant under this section may be used only to provide eligible services under subsection (e) with respect to families (including individuals and including victims of domestic violence) who—</text>
 <paragraph id="H490E2359B73048498F26B895D09C6831"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reside in a rental dwelling unit; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8FD6FB6ECBAD45EF8DC919F4B27CB708"><enum>(2)</enum><text>have an income (as such term is defined in section 3(b) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437a">42 U.S.C. 1437a(b)</external-xref>)) that does not exceed 80 percent of the median income for the area in which the family resides.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H07CA547B44134D24AC5E6645E162E519"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligible organizations</header><text>Grants under this section may be made only to—</text> <paragraph id="H17536FE0A03C4711A91F59D30CBE1565"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a nonprofit organization that provides legal services on behalf of persons or families whose eligibility for such services includes a limitation on income, including any organizations that receive funding from the Legal Services Corporation (established under the Legal Services Corporation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2996">42 U.S.C. 2996</external-xref> et seq.)) to provide such services on behalf of such persons or families;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9FFEE0967B2B493C8A511A69598F6C1A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>legal clinics sponsored by law schools or other organizations; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEF7B0CEA49E84F0C88257F42C99920F5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>such other institutions, organizations, and entities as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2E92C8EDAF47497692B474F2807CE006"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Eligible services</header><text>Amounts from a grant under this section may be used only to provide, on behalf of eligible low-income families under subsection (c), legal services and other related supportive services in connection with—</text>
 <paragraph id="H47389AA709814CD9B86EFD307EFD1E92"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an eviction of such a family;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDE0BF0947B4B433CB2D3EB016D47DA3E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the prevention of an eviction of such a family;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC1F590DA30A042AB9CF915FAB38DE6E4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a dispute between the landlord and a tenant who is a member of such a family; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H32E1B16A2F314046A41B436AD93EA0C9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>enforcing the legal rights of such a family under Federal, State, or local laws regarding tenancy or fair housing.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2F4DC60C8767401083B0E95BFFE20AF9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Use of mortgage interest deduction savings for grants</header>
 <paragraph id="H0328BE0B95174C6AA288F421C8542297"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Determination of savings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022, the Secretary of the Treasury shall determine the amount of revenues accruing to the general fund of the Treasury by reason of the enactment of the amendment made by section 4 of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6500AB2A341548DDBDEDF6C6C7DA5DA9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated for grants under this section for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022 the amount determined under paragraph (1) for such fiscal year.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H4ED66FE198E248BC955C5944809ED797" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header>Reduction in limitation on mortgage interest deduction relating to acquisition indebtedness for
			 certain taxpayers</header>
 <subsection id="H356E7C66B16040A88E45513AE6DBE7C4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Acquisition indebtedness</header><text>Clause (ii) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/163">section 163(h)(3)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H12F2862F17E7418D8360D11B7E93C8EC" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H22F3C9C8A4C246579E4FE530360C9D24"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The aggregate amount treated as acquisition indebtedness for any period shall not exceed—</text> <subclause id="H4711DA80EEEF498EA2C0A399AEE82DBE"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$1,000,000 in the case of a joint return ($500,000 in the case of a married individual filing a separate return), and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H5771D15B91484C86BF84D45EE23A100A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the applicable amount in any other case.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HFFDBF753DBA5464D9CE185D9B5DC9F28"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Applicable amount</header><text>For purposes of clause (ii)(II), the applicable amount is as follows:</text>
						<pagebreak></pagebreak><table align-to-level="section" blank-lines-before="1" colsep="1" frame="topbot" line-rules="hor-ver" rowsep="0" rule-weights="4.4.4.0.0.0" table-template-name="Generic: 1 text, 1 num" table-type="">
							<tgroup cols="2" grid-typeface="1.1" rowsep="0" thead-tbody-ldg-size="10.10.12"><colspec coldef="txt" colname="column1" colwidth="258pts" min-data-value="200" rowsep="0"></colspec><colspec coldef="fig" colname="column2" colwidth="137.25pt" min-data-value="12" rowsep="0"></colspec><thead>
									<row><entry align="center" colname="column1" morerows="0" namest="column1" rowsep="1">For taxable years—</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" morerows="0" namest="column2" rowsep="1">The applicable<linebreak></linebreak> amount is—</entry></row></thead>
								<tbody>
									<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">Beginning in calendar year 2018</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" rowsep="0">$900,000</entry></row>
									<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">Beginning in calendar year 2019</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" rowsep="0">$800,000</entry></row>
									<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">Beginning in calendar year 2020</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" rowsep="0">$700,000</entry></row>
									<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">Beginning in calendar year 2021</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" rowsep="0">$600,000</entry></row>
									<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">Beginning in or after calendar year 2022</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" rowsep="0">$500,000.</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1CEDE068D6E942989EE32C3F951BCFB5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply to amounts paid or incurred after December 31, 2017.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


