<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="H63E8F38F262F488A949871AD7115AF3E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 469 EH: Congressional Article I Powers Strengthening Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>115th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 469</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To impose certain limitations on consent decrees and settlement agreements by agencies that require the agencies to take regulatory action in accordance with the terms thereof, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H2F7C4BCA223E40E0914B26292CCE4E10" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H231B9C4239414996BC5F77AC23A11441" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header> 
<subsection id="H3C8E64B16D59441DAE1059E5DBF8EFED"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Congressional Article I Powers Strengthening Act</short-title></quote>. </text></subsection> <subsection id="H5B447ECC42A84FF295A7A89676DD6C59"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents of this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> 
<toc-entry idref="H231B9C4239414996BC5F77AC23A11441" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HC67210C0B06D435BB954E9D9D91A5A35" level="title">Title I—Sunshine for Regulations and Regulatory Decrees and Settlements</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H807A436A95254513970C874B143B50DB" level="section">Sec. 101. Short title.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H768A52B175434DCD8A41D793442D1747" level="section">Sec. 102. Definitions.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H74C2E685E6664B4BADB556201CDB3FCD" level="section">Sec. 103. Consent decree and settlement reform.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H5C8873EAC156479AAE75069788A8B2E6" level="section">Sec. 104. Motions to modify consent decrees.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HF23CDD87A1EB4CA39465458E3F42C3E5" level="section">Sec. 105. Effective date.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H37CF02ADDF734C30B6CFC709BA32D13C" level="title">Title II—Judgment Fund Transparency</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H0E279CA41EE745BFB667F088F9631D27" level="section">Sec. 201. Short title.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H1866F819F8924EF8A6826E31CB3DA89A" level="section">Sec. 202. Judgment fund transparency.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H3CC84525E71E4EAFB6CAAA147FB6FEC3" level="title">Title III—Article I Amicus and Intervention</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HD63A75F086FF4F0E8DA4837F9D6455DB" level="section">Sec. 301. Short title.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HD5FBE17CA8814443AFA5E5CC053222CE" level="section">Sec. 302. Congressional intervention as of right.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HC2207BF2000E438FB3CE45D48D7BF2EC" level="section">Sec. 303. Intervention and amicus authority for house of representatives.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section> 
<title id="HC67210C0B06D435BB954E9D9D91A5A35"><enum>I</enum><header>Sunshine for Regulations and Regulatory Decrees and Settlements</header> 
<section id="H807A436A95254513970C874B143B50DB" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>101.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This title may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sunshine for Regulations and Regulatory Decrees and Settlements Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H768A52B175434DCD8A41D793442D1747"><enum>102.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title—</text> 
<paragraph id="H43EB4AD99D3E45C9A7FF4C34FAE46C7A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the terms <quote>agency</quote> and <quote>agency action</quote> have the meanings given those terms under section 551 of title 5, United States Code;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H427FBB3CED674CE5A8B712BF46E8928A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <quote>covered civil action</quote> means a civil action—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H90898543D7714024811285A5F2F063DF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>seeking to compel agency action;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5CC63B5E30E04F7CB32C5ADE06ECC380"><enum>(B)</enum><text>alleging that the agency is unlawfully withholding or unreasonably delaying an agency action relating to a regulatory action that would affect the rights of—</text> 
<clause id="H516E0F862BD542C9A38BBB62E08C91BB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>private persons other than the person bringing the action; or</text></clause> <clause id="H5DFD6876AF1D405FA4063860F2486867"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a State, local, or tribal government; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5D505965BA924CD9A9C9837EA54AA237"><enum>(C)</enum><text>brought under—</text> <clause id="HEA11DA1F4F74499C92845E66BECCD79E"><enum>(i)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/7">chapter 7</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HFDA268D28CA3446AAACA59A7F4CE3B83"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any other statute authorizing such an action;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3C5F09B6A21E46CF8DD0D3E49B0F019A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <quote>covered consent decree</quote> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H76C1F75B621B4C3AB9D276B327734DCE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a consent decree entered into in a covered civil action; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8AE3BD24E85045758F382AEA2CFFEABE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other consent decree that requires agency action relating to a regulatory action that affects the rights of—</text> 
<clause id="H88B7C4797BF6405C9E5DAFEECAF167F9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>private persons other than the person bringing the action; or</text></clause> <clause id="HA86DA2648E07479C98B6F8D533F7695E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a State, local, or tribal government;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3E7D8DBCABF54AB7B35E7C10DE5C27DB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <quote>covered consent decree or settlement agreement</quote> means a covered consent decree and a covered settlement agreement; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8C6A6683E3A6486DB474BB70FEFB7F7C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <quote>covered settlement agreement</quote> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H759F710B9A6F4F1893667D75FF68EC27"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a settlement agreement entered into in a covered civil action; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H09265D7F032C407788707EC1478D1DCA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other settlement agreement that requires agency action relating to a regulatory action that affects the rights of—</text> 
<clause id="H744C8F2703484E1280931EFA162B5EAA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>private persons other than the person bringing the action; or</text></clause> <clause id="H58938A1409AC4D7B9767693146FF0531"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a State, local, or tribal government.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H74C2E685E6664B4BADB556201CDB3FCD"><enum>103.</enum><header>Consent decree and settlement reform</header> 
<subsection id="HAB026D4890774D8FAF64E6262BC3B6A7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Pleadings and preliminary matters</header> 
<paragraph id="HDC15D91B784A419A86E8BDB54467BAF8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In any covered civil action, the agency against which the covered civil action is brought shall publish the notice of intent to sue and the complaint in a readily accessible manner, including by making the notice of intent to sue and the complaint available online not later than 15 days after receiving service of the notice of intent to sue or complaint, respectively.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H917F6FD95920422A997E806E558470DC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Entry of a covered consent decree or settlement agreement</header><text>A party may not make a motion for entry of a covered consent decree or to dismiss a civil action pursuant to a covered settlement agreement until after the end of proceedings in accordance with paragraph (1) and subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (2) of subsection (d) or subsection (d)(3)(A), whichever is later.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2A19420C930F44C6A6726609B3EA2544"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Intervention</header> 
<paragraph id="HCB4DF988627745459B4D8F57F7BAFF8E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rebuttable presumption</header><text>In considering a motion to intervene in a covered civil action or a civil action in which a covered consent decree or settlement agreement has been proposed that is filed by a person who alleges that the agency action in dispute would affect the person, the court shall presume, subject to rebuttal, that the interests of the person would not be represented adequately by the existing parties to the action.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE216EBF440F941988AD16AB816B2567C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State, local, and tribal governments</header><text>In considering a motion to intervene in a covered civil action or a civil action in which a covered consent decree or settlement agreement has been proposed that is filed by a State, local, or tribal government, the court shall take due account of whether the movant—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H025C021E70B64BAAA8B77402414212AA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>administers jointly with an agency that is a defendant in the action the statutory provisions that give rise to the regulatory action to which the action relates; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC9D5204BFA714A599CE2732EA83AF3A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>administers an authority under State, local, or tribal law that would be preempted by the regulatory action to which the action relates.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HADDA4AFD0DEF46F5862D82323A2950B9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Settlement negotiations</header><text>Efforts to settle a covered civil action or otherwise reach an agreement on a covered consent decree or settlement agreement shall—</text> <paragraph id="HDB1E48741725492E95BA30F6C1DBFAE5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be conducted pursuant to the mediation or alternative dispute resolution program of the court or by a district judge other than the presiding judge, magistrate judge, or special master, as determined appropriate by the presiding judge; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAE2D1DEFB13C4237A70D9E7BDEB39CCD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include any party that intervenes in the action.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCCBEE7AE46784B0EB51105B61DAED13C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Publication of and comment on covered consent decrees or settlement agreements</header> <paragraph id="H150C8383806445C79F471EACF8B1F9E7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days before the date on which a covered consent decree or settlement agreement is filed with a court, the agency seeking to enter the covered consent decree or settlement agreement shall publish in the Federal Register and online—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD1EF2D7432B54146A109E2CFB340121F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the proposed covered consent decree or settlement agreement; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H785FAFB4079F47C985F0FC7F26EBF5E1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a statement providing—</text> 
<clause id="H1452B84030AB438AAC9D8888E85BD80E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the statutory basis for the covered consent decree or settlement agreement; and</text></clause> <clause id="H489E3D770DD64DB3BA11A5CA3F2D3186"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a description of the terms of the covered consent decree or settlement agreement, including whether it provides for the award of attorneys’ fees or costs and, if so, the basis for including the award.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H961F11AE654C4E3DB548DDC08EE30070"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public comment</header> 
<subparagraph id="H3B7F689F23A4408A88980EE05ADF113B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An agency seeking to enter a covered consent decree or settlement agreement shall accept public comment during the period described in paragraph (1) on any issue relating to the matters alleged in the complaint in the applicable civil action or addressed or affected by the proposed covered consent decree or settlement agreement.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD584F0E01CC04050824C4360F7AC826A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Response to comments</header><text>An agency shall respond to any comment received under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6202D98B2CB14A5CB3A27F853136A257"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Submissions to court</header><text>When moving that the court enter a proposed covered consent decree or settlement agreement or for dismissal pursuant to a proposed covered consent decree or settlement agreement, an agency shall—</text> <clause id="H0B1995AD24F2426DA2235089ED1C6A45"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inform the court of the statutory basis for the proposed covered consent decree or settlement agreement and its terms;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8FC07307E72D4EC0B38C72A7942324D7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>submit to the court a summary of the comments received under subparagraph (A) and the response of the agency to the comments;</text></clause> <clause id="HD92FAF04BF5348BC9FEBA34EDDE0DFFF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>submit to the court a certified index of the administrative record of the notice and comment proceeding; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDA1AB4C2F36C4D769A512B6F19CC29AC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>make the administrative record described in clause (iii) fully accessible to the court.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H44A353F8D8594DCFA819FDF722015F60"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Inclusion in record</header><text>The court shall include in the court record for a civil action the certified index of the administrative record submitted by an agency under subparagraph (C)(iii) and any documents listed in the index which any party or amicus curiae appearing before the court in the action submits to the court.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9D6FBED91582463A874CD63A4A37EFB4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public hearings permitted</header> 
<subparagraph id="HF61840E4702A47DD8BB889C1ECE4C429"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>After providing notice in the Federal Register and online, an agency may hold a public hearing regarding whether to enter into a proposed covered consent decree or settlement agreement.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB3AA96961C464867ABBD5D6D05DF6503"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Record</header><text>If an agency holds a public hearing under subparagraph (A)—</text> 
<clause id="HB2681ECFB02C4203A930816DF583993A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the agency shall—</text> <subclause id="HC9C9E70A78FD410987AD4685B21E0AEE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>submit to the court a summary of the proceedings;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H69675FE0D61B47DEAD35422EC8C927FA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>submit to the court a certified index of the hearing record; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H0062568A33754DD28C36CC6C486C2A4E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>provide access to the hearing record to the court; and</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H460BAC4C542940679D88F8562E8D45FF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the full hearing record shall be included in the court record.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC34C2BB0028C43829D91C3D89944FFE3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Mandatory deadlines</header><text>If a proposed covered consent decree or settlement agreement requires an agency action by a date certain, the agency shall, when moving for entry of the covered consent decree or settlement agreement or dismissal based on the covered consent decree or settlement agreement, inform the court of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF72BAC72151543DB85E0CDC609A74F76"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any required regulatory action the agency has not taken that the covered consent decree or settlement agreement does not address;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9FDF97E0FD7E4AA08CC3247133BA68F6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how the covered consent decree or settlement agreement, if approved, would affect the discharge of the duties described in subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0EBA3936734747968B3C20C556A95318"><enum>(C)</enum><text>why the effects of the covered consent decree or settlement agreement on the manner in which the agency discharges its duties is in the public interest.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD22D51D93FD04BD4A70A4140CE2EBE41"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Submission by the government</header> <paragraph id="H8933FED9FDE04B79868F7D6A58649CF0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For any proposed covered consent decree or settlement agreement that contains a term described in paragraph (2), the Attorney General or, if the matter is being litigated independently by an agency, the head of the agency shall submit to the court a certification that the Attorney General or head of the agency approves the proposed covered consent decree or settlement agreement. The Attorney General or head of the agency shall personally sign any certification submitted under this paragraph.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6FC3DEA841E641338ED0F7A5802CC67D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Terms</header><text>A term described in this paragraph is—</text> <subparagraph id="HD9EAF73A64EF4F53A7896ADA1B808A77"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a covered consent decree, a term that—</text> 
<clause id="H25BACFBFC76B47EDA5747B00BEA411D0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>converts into a nondiscretionary duty a discretionary authority of an agency to propose, promulgate, revise, or amend regulations;</text></clause> <clause id="H27DC5F22321B4FBDB467917E79DCF62B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>commits an agency to expend funds that have not been appropriated and that have not been budgeted for the regulatory action in question;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H35453C661F2540FB9496C232210C959B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>commits an agency to seek a particular appropriation or budget authorization;</text></clause> <clause id="HD11A9244833141B3B08A0BDD8E50C196"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>divests an agency of discretion committed to the agency by statute or the Constitution of the United States, without regard to whether the discretion was granted to respond to changing circumstances, to make policy or managerial choices, or to protect the rights of third parties; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H94F3D336012848ADB9D0E5042800E56A"><enum>(v)</enum><text>otherwise affords relief that the court could not enter under its own authority upon a final judgment in the civil action; or</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF22765CF24F3436A95F3DDE71C7D36B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a covered settlement agreement, a term—</text> 
<clause id="H5DB4F4109FA34EE5BCCA08D227C4739F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that provides a remedy for a failure by the agency to comply with the terms of the covered settlement agreement other than the revival of the civil action resolved by the covered settlement agreement; and</text></clause> <clause id="H8652D0CEEA224FA2BB954D791307830A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that—</text> 
<subclause id="HC2A62C5818124B99A52066337E2AF0DC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>interferes with the authority of an agency to revise, amend, or issue rules under the procedures set forth in <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, or any other statute or Executive order prescribing rulemaking procedures for a rulemaking that is the subject of the covered settlement agreement;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HB68C4D096BAB4B7DAE157156D4F662DE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>commits the agency to expend funds that have not been appropriated and that have not been budgeted for the regulatory action in question; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H8F76AF825D3040B3A897C51ED2113D5D"><enum>(III)</enum><text>for such a covered settlement agreement that commits the agency to exercise in a particular way discretion which was committed to the agency by statute or the Constitution of the United States to respond to changing circumstances, to make policy or managerial choices, or to protect the rights of third parties.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2E1AAF7D1F8F44298815C02B3BD6BC31"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Review by court</header> <paragraph id="HF1E515888A0B42D6B416792CB559E9AA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Amicus</header><text>A court considering a proposed covered consent decree or settlement agreement shall presume, subject to rebuttal, that it is proper to allow amicus participation relating to the covered consent decree or settlement agreement by any person who filed public comments or participated in a public hearing on the covered consent decree or settlement agreement under paragraph (2) or (3) of subsection (d).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC2C5F547412C4267A10BC4508392EE73"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review of deadlines</header> 
<subparagraph id="H53F21286EC5C4CB5B300002AFD005DC0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Proposed covered consent decrees</header><text>For a proposed covered consent decree, a court shall not approve the covered consent decree unless the proposed covered consent decree allows sufficient time and incorporates adequate procedures for the agency to comply with <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, and other applicable statutes that govern rulemaking and, unless contrary to the public interest, the provisions of any Executive order that governs rulemaking.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HECEA9A7532B34BA3B08628DBC66F9180"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Proposed covered settlement agreements</header><text>For a proposed covered settlement agreement, a court shall ensure that the covered settlement agreement allows sufficient time and incorporates adequate procedures for the agency to comply with <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, and other applicable statutes that govern rulemaking and, unless contrary to the public interest, the provisions of any Executive order that governs rulemaking.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC3227C9DEB1D432CB0CEED58974CC70F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text>Each agency shall submit to Congress an annual report that, for the year covered by the report, includes—</text> <paragraph id="H77B496B017DC41628A1386FA0F9342F6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number, identity, and content of covered civil actions brought against and covered consent decrees or settlement agreements entered against or into by the agency; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB108203E61B44C1F8CD2803B5CD5BFB3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of the statutory basis for—</text> <subparagraph id="H4729C23B34B64CFC8AC2C7DB62780C2D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each covered consent decree or settlement agreement entered against or into by the agency; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8FBB4E0EDFB14456B49193304C50B099"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any award of attorneys fees or costs in a civil action resolved by a covered consent decree or settlement agreement entered against or into by the agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H5C8873EAC156479AAE75069788A8B2E6"><enum>104.</enum><header>Motions to modify consent decrees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If an agency moves a court to modify a covered consent decree or settlement agreement and the basis of the motion is that the terms of the covered consent decree or settlement agreement are no longer fully in the public interest due to the obligations of the agency to fulfill other duties or due to changed facts and circumstances, the court shall review the motion and the covered consent decree or settlement agreement de novo.</text></section> 
<section id="HF23CDD87A1EB4CA39465458E3F42C3E5"><enum>105.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This title shall apply to—</text> <paragraph id="H3ABCFA0989A14E6C8E15328A5AF69852"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any covered civil action filed on or after the date of enactment of this title; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF8CA744E29444EBCAE67F221637D63DE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any covered consent decree or settlement agreement proposed to a court on or after the date of enactment of this title.</text></paragraph></section></title> <title id="H37CF02ADDF734C30B6CFC709BA32D13C"><enum>II</enum><header>Judgment Fund Transparency</header> <section id="H0E279CA41EE745BFB667F088F9631D27" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>201.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This title may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Judgment Fund Transparency Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H1866F819F8924EF8A6826E31CB3DA89A"><enum>202.</enum><header>Judgment fund transparency</header> 
<subsection id="HE545939B718043D1805BF31763DD5836"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Transparency requirement</header><text>Section 1304 of title 31, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H57842F59207C45E9A1DD783B01CC065C" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H54624E19B6AC4E84967E882B7FF6E65A"><enum>(d)</enum> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H4F15AC5F6A214198A092B0A78AD7BD72"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Unless the disclosure of such information is otherwise prohibited by law (other than section 552a of title 5, United States Code) or court order, the Secretary of the Treasury shall make available to the public on a website, as soon as practicable, but not later than 30 days after the date on which a payment under this section is tendered on or after January 1, 2016, the following information with regard to that payment:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HEEAB0713F3EA4212B845F92A9CAB6020" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The name of the specific agency or entity whose actions gave rise to the claim or judgment.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H22FAD84B2F4B482C95E3561734542F8B" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The name of the plaintiff or claimant.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H52D880E118714B068C4D29A738CA3EBA" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The name of counsel for the plaintiff or claimant.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7C73E9D487604EF788585A8009D6D445" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The amount paid representing principal liability, and any amounts paid representing any ancillary liability, including attorney fees, costs, and interest.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3AA769BB0F7D45B0ABA536691553F378" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A brief description of the facts that gave rise to the claim.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0CA29C67CF984F7FAF8082B402381A85" indent="up1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The name of the agency that submitted the claim.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9DD5C63D78884859BD26EFC4116EE26E" indent="up1"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any information available on reports generated by the Judgment Fund Payment Search administered by the Treasury Department.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBB830A664F114823AE72816C76E0F329" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In addition to the information described in paragraph (1), if a payment under this section is made to a foreign state on or after January 1, 2016, the Secretary of the Treasury shall make available to the public in accordance with paragraph (1), the following information with regard to that payment:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H898D7D1B5545413C8F74C814CB137FEC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of the method of payment.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H71FFA37D997947C49DEB2E5D6A80B549"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of the currency denominations used for the payment.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H14BBE73B2C0A439D871CC15627C1498A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The name and location of each financial institution owned or controlled, directly or indirectly, by a foreign state or an agent of a foreign state through which the payment passed or from which the payment was withdrawn, including any financial institution owned or controlled, directly or indirectly, by a foreign state or an agent of a foreign state that is holding the payment as of the date on which the information is made available.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE9EBD85B1E374704A144999D5BAEBCEF" indent="up1" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than January 1, 2018, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of the Treasury shall make available to the public on the website described in paragraph (1)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H273C79114C5249E3BF8B96CFE9FD6CE7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the total amount paid under this section during the year preceding the date of the report; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA72076E4F43240FBB647D133A2F98534"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount paid under this section during the year preceding the date of the report—</text> 
<clause id="H8B00DC580EAB40BA9E178F1FAA9B3EE8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for attorney fees;</text></clause> <clause id="H9AED6C11FEE9490EB5CCCAFB31C09E28"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for interest; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H449443AE69284F1C8713F681DB982F0F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>for all other payments.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBDA96261EBAB4F1888EA484DFD053860" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>foreign state</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 1603 of title 28.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H68CED0420EB64B909E5EDC01AA653672"><enum>(e)</enum><text>Except with regard to children under eighteen, the disclosure of information required in this section shall not be considered a <quote>clearly unwarranted invasion of personal privacy</quote> for purposes of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H144C15E6688540DAA5B0AA4AAB0CA473"><enum>(f)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No payment may be made under this section to a state sponsor of terrorism, as defined in section 1605A(h) of title 28, or to an organization that has been designated as a foreign terrorist organization under section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189</external-xref>).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H313FBBBE687E4F26891E9D8EBBEE91A1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall carry out the amendment made by this section by not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this title.</text></subsection></section></title> <title id="H3CC84525E71E4EAFB6CAAA147FB6FEC3"><enum>III</enum><header>Article I Amicus and Intervention</header> <section id="HD63A75F086FF4F0E8DA4837F9D6455DB" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>301.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This title may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Article I Amicus and Intervention Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HD5FBE17CA8814443AFA5E5CC053222CE"><enum>302.</enum><header>Congressional intervention as of right</header> 
<subsection id="H2179C85239D6417B9A76CE1F800A93AC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Deadline for report on limitation on enforcement of laws</header><text>Paragraph (2) of section 530D(b) of title 28, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="H14DCE64B77974B6897A93E51D5C9949C" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HEC11FF9BE3E5477CB96AAD0A6E8F2773"><enum>(2)</enum><text>under subsection (a)(1)(B), within such time as will reasonably enable the House of Representatives and the Senate to take action, separately or jointly, to intervene in a timely fashion in the proceeding, but in no event—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H091BBB7646254818B990DE04A5BCF69B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>later than 30 days after the making of each determination; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H03526435A2E64712B2CDD57EA10265FA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>later than 21 days before any applicable deadline for filing any pleading necessary—</text> 
<clause id="H14BF96EDD8054C9E8B5DAB29B4FAD67A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to defend or assert the constitutionality of the provision at issue; or</text></clause> <clause id="H06558445697F4B769A8C93882FBCF1F4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to request review of any judicial, administrative, or other determination adversely affecting the constitutionality of such provision;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3C333DDD8C5F469FB495B7F3E3ABAD91"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Intervention as of right</header><text>Section 530D of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H10D28AAE8D51408284B2D333BE690D88" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H3216E9AC1A3045AFB5BF9D3CD626D886"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Intervention as of right</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Senate or House of Representatives may intervene as of right in any proceeding referenced in subsection (a)(1)(B) in order to defend or assert the constitutionality of any provision of any Federal statute, rule, regulation, program, policy, or other law, or to appeal or request review of any judicial, administrative, or other determination adversely affecting the constitutionality of any such provision. Notwithstanding any otherwise applicable time limits or other provisions of law to the contrary, if such intervention is filed not later than 21 days after receipt of the notice required by this section the intervention shall be deemed timely and shall preserve the right of the Senate or House of Representatives to advance any applicable legal arguments in favor of the constitutionality of any such provision.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
<section id="HC2207BF2000E438FB3CE45D48D7BF2EC"><enum>303.</enum><header>Intervention and amicus authority for house of representatives</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> Section 101 of the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/5571">2 U.S.C. 5571</external-xref>), is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H4BDE8B57D3804C698D452DD34D57F35E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking subsection (d); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5A2BAFDBD7664C379F6E4C3450A23805"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following (and redesignating succeeding subsections accordingly):</text> <quoted-block id="HA85DEB1697BF49E5BE3EF6640D554915" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HD2CCDE62ECF2440E8A1131737CCA8C81"><enum>(c)</enum><header>House of representatives intervention and amicus authority</header> <paragraph id="HC1A5B27D7C534815974D224608650257"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Actions or proceedings</header><text>When directed to do so in accordance with the Rules of the House of Representatives, the General Counsel of the House of Representatives shall intervene or appear as amicus curiae in the name of the House, or in the name of an officer, committee, subcommittee, or chair of a committee or subcommittee of the House, or other entity of the House, in any legal action or proceeding pending in any court of the United States or of a State or political subdivision thereof.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEF600E7E05B64004A059400E14D31700"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Intervention or appearance as of right</header><text>Intervention as a party or appearance as amicus curiae shall be of right and may be denied by a court only upon an express finding that such intervention or appearance is untimely and would significantly delay the pending action or, in the case of intervention, that standing to intervene is required and has not been established under section 2 of article III of the Constitution of the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H85A8A56F29144B65805D7D7310406FF2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to confer standing on any party seeking to bring, or jurisdiction on any court with respect to, any civil or criminal action against Congress, either House of Congress, a Member of Congress, a committee or subcommittee of a House of Congress, any office or agency of Congress, or any officer or employee of a House of Congress or any office or agency of Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></title> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20171025" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives October 25, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement>
</bill> 


