<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2D13B4D2A1D44392B40CB6CA722496FE" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2457 IH: J. Bennett Johnston Waterway Hydropower Extension Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2457</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170516">May 16, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000299">Mr. Johnson of Louisiana</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To extend the deadline for commencement of construction of certain hydroelectric projects.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HEBA3610418894EDB99D33AE8C9CD8E43" style="OLC">
 <section id="H5D8A6CD2DE034F189AEED90A038E30AC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>J. Bennett Johnston Waterway Hydropower Extension Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H23516393A1A348AF817708BF3DC4B499"><enum>2.</enum><header>Extension</header> <subsection id="HD529736A82934389BE7167CA03956F9E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding the time period specified in section 13 of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/806">16 U.S.C. 806</external-xref>) that would otherwise apply to Federal Energy Regulatory Commission project numbers 12756, 12757, and 12758, the Commission may, at the request of the licensee for the applicable project, and after reasonable notice, in accordance with the good faith, due diligence, and public interest requirements of that section and the Commission’s procedures under that section, extend the time period during which such licensee is required to commence the construction of its applicable project for up to 3 consecutive 2-year periods from the date of the expiration of the extension originally issued by the Commission under that section for such project.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H95A9CFDA1AB94385A6BEC97E310322BF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Obligation for payment of annual charges</header><text>Any obligation of a licensee for a project described in subsection (a) for the payment of annual charges under section 10(e) of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/803">16 U.S.C. 803(e)</external-xref>) shall commence when the construction of the project commences.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H3DBDC9944F7D447280392E20974B6CF7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reinstatement of license; effective date for extension</header>
 <paragraph id="HD5E07F79533B483FB9D4E7F229692DB2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reinstatement</header><text>If the time period required for commencement of construction of a project described in subsection (a) has expired prior to the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commission may reinstate the license for such project, effective as of the date of the expiration of the license.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7788E7A4180449D6A7109476150973B9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date for extension</header><text>If the Commission reinstates a license under paragraph (1) for a project, the first extension authorized under subsection (a) with respect to such project shall take effect on the effective date of such reinstatement under paragraph (1).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


