<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF372764959354F5F845F57CA71123BEF" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2675 IH: Truth in Settlements Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2675</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170525">May 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000599">Mr. Posey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000754">Mr. Cooper</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require adequate information regarding the tax treatment of payments under settlement agreements
			 entered into by Federal agencies, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H6994B750496143BC93C70BD7019926C7" style="OLC">
 <section id="H5A56444AD5EC4D79A28DAD423DBBF6E5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Truth in Settlements Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HA854F4EFFB7545A18533320A872F1FD6" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Information regarding settlement agreements entered into by Federal agencies</header> <subsection id="HEBDDAE508A654042B37CE7B2A5643F46"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirements for settlement agreements</header> <paragraph id="HCB0814ACF6074C01AF88A68706074364"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/3">Chapter 3</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H326FE6583FBD4B0AACD635DA739C99E2" style="USC">
						<section id="H6F4317BEF8BA411AAA6C0A9E867C8823"><enum>307.</enum><header>Information regarding settlement agreements</header>
 <subsection id="HD5052BEB962D40E48D65B706CDAA0B9B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="H4778CD8349664E93A8900FBC6FCF97A4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>covered settlement agreement</term> means a settlement agreement (including a consent decree) that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H87FF84EED9B74E5DA9B108C72648B7DF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is entered into by an Executive agency;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67194D70DF334F1C96F91B2B7027C59C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>relates to an alleged violation of Federal civil or criminal law; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3375358403644D01AEB04F2E5635CBDA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>requires the payment of a total of not less than $1,000,000 by one or more non-Federal persons;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD8EBF343774A4510AEDEF70915F2BC79"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>entity within the Federal Government</term> includes an officer or employee of the Federal Government acting in an official capacity; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3520BF5007F94253893773E540BB24E4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>non-Federal person</term> means a person that is not an entity within the Federal Government.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCFEE82045DAD4DF4A09874AB1D0D4826"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information To be posted online</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB80ED0828F094EDAB4C3A0B94A928362"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9C19F0A5EE894ABDA99D0492BCFFFD1F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subparagraph (B), the head of each Executive agency shall make publicly available in a searchable format in a prominent location on the Web site of the Executive agency—</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H74079BCB647140F4928B9CDF4C03CA44"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of each covered settlement agreement entered into by the Executive agency, which shall include, for each covered settlement agreement—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4061957AF70C49BE9047EB2F76B1662C"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date on which the parties entered into the covered settlement agreement;</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7476D06D4359437296476FC50D23B7E1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the names of the parties that settled claims under the covered settlement agreement;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD8CE27F68317454CB56597A878B44704"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the claims each party settled under the covered settlement agreement;</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7E1D959880E3493B91BD1CDA9C469E97"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount each party settling a claim under the covered settlement agreement is obligated to pay under the settlement agreement;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD8B2B2C51A004C98A5EEC2F1C05D4021"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the total amount the settling parties are obligated to pay under the settlement agreement; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HE9E3B593BF6A4D0A87CD65812897B774"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>for each settling party—</text>
 <item id="H00CC62E9850648E2ABD981AE4013F9D6"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the amount, if any, the settling party is obligated to pay that is expressly specified under the covered settlement agreement as a civil or criminal penalty or fine; and</text>
 </item><item id="H9BB5A2ECA2CD4398A56005725BF5AE80"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the amount, if any, that is expressly specified under the covered settlement agreement as not deductible for purposes of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; and</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1E8B584B73384C8497E9B0F21CF36FEF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a copy of each covered settlement agreement entered into by the Executive agency.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H39AD8612C9094845A374C03FBFBED54E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Confidentiality provisions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirement to disclose information or a copy of a covered settlement agreement under subparagraph (A) shall apply to the extent that the information or copy (or portion thereof) is not subject to a confidentiality provision that prohibits disclosure of the information or copy (or portion thereof).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HACD037FEB4F44E50B3500BB2F8C16B70"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of each Executive agency shall ensure that—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3C3BD09AA0FB4127BEBD73A966E81978"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information regarding a covered settlement agreement is publicly available on the list described in paragraph (1)(A)(i) for a period of not less than 5 years, beginning on the date of the covered settlement agreement; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H08E91C1E14B141359DB0497DD83AA092"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a copy of a covered settlement agreement made available under paragraph (1)(A)(ii) is publicly available—</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H90BE115D219246328A260292404089B8"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for a period of not less than 1 year, beginning on the date of the covered settlement agreement; or</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HACCDF4A27EB04BD7BFEB60F2068D6FFC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for a covered settlement agreement under which a non-Federal person is required to pay not less than $50,000,000, for a period of not less than 5 years, beginning on the date of the covered settlement agreement.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2B590377EE744E5D89AB09264D064B40"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public statement</header><text>If the head of an Executive agency determines that a confidentiality provision in a covered settlement agreement, or the sealing of a covered settlement agreement, is required to protect the public interest of the United States, the head of the Executive agency shall issue a public statement stating why such action is required to protect the public interest of the United States, which shall explain—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H127837CAFB0549458585353C37F41299"><enum>(1)</enum><text>what interests confidentiality protects; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7B2C3345FD4D443B8E6C87ADC25C03F1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>why the interests protected by confidentiality outweigh the public’s interest in knowing about the conduct of the Federal Government and the expenditure of Federal resources.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFDF8D3999E0744F4A0EE06ACAD5F718D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Requirements for written public statements</header><text>Any written public statement issued by an Executive agency that refers to an amount to be paid by a non-Federal person under a covered settlement agreement shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H97BE65F3BA6146C08747286E128AB84E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>specify which portion, if any, of the amount to be paid under the covered settlement agreement by a non-Federal person—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA483832C41A8428B8A849C322A286282"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is expressly specified under the covered settlement agreement as a civil or criminal penalty or fine to be paid for a violation of Federal law; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H242E0B28272C44A29A0B449A2F42F39F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is expressly specified under the covered settlement agreement as not deductible for purposes of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H15D53EF994A34E36B0CED08A40B8C4D5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if no portion of the amount to be paid under the covered settlement agreement by a non-Federal person is expressly specified under the covered settlement agreement as a civil or criminal penalty or fine, include a statement specifying that is the case; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H66F2D408FFA64AC1B8D6CFC12F28A25B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>describe in detail—</text> <subparagraph id="H93CCA1C2980D45859629361EFA896445"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any actions the non-Federal person shall take under the covered settlement agreement in lieu of payment to the Federal Government or a State or local government; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H087DDF75E7C74804A40A371A6CAEA6DA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any payments or compensation the non-Federal person shall make to other non-Federal persons under the covered settlement agreement.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5A029D990B574FA88117D95958976151"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Confidentiality</header><text>The requirement to disclose information under subsection (d) shall apply to the extent that the information to be disclosed (or portion thereof) is not subject to a confidentiality provision that prohibits disclosure of the information (or portion thereof).</text>
							</subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H41BB30FF886349EF905B7ACBF4B0283A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reporting</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCF5C633B7DCE40A5836EAC932D20A6C7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than January 15 of each year, the head of an Executive agency that entered into a covered settlement agreement during the previous fiscal year shall submit to each committee of Congress with jurisdiction over the activities of the Executive agency a report indicating—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9BE6B1FDFA6343C6913D2CBD6A065168"><enum>(A)</enum><text>how many covered settlement agreements the Executive agency entered into during that fiscal year;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50A16C82FF2E42609B8956638CDFAEC6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how many covered settlement agreements the Executive agency entered into during that fiscal year that had any terms or conditions that are required to be kept confidential; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9FC13E5C79734521985B23BB6FE10D1B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>how many covered settlement agreements the Executive agency entered into during that fiscal year for which all terms and conditions are required to be kept confidential.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H15E4389870904310859A75141CE1F5B6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability of reports</header><text>The head of an Executive agency that is required to submit a report under paragraph (1) shall make the report publically available in a searchable format in a prominent location on the Web site of the Executive agency.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4A1222237F4A419CB584940E715B645C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/3">chapter 3</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H93D781278F6947D1800CFEC119C9294C" style="USC">
						<toc>
							<toc-entry level="section">307. Information regarding settlement agreements.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB507DE7BC3E94A4CBCA6D81DF773013A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Securities reporting</header>
 <paragraph id="H2A5CCA1634F54AB8B6D4A9014A412514"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each issuer of securities that is required to file annual or other periodic reports with the Commission under section 13 or 15(d) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78m">15 U.S.C. 78m</external-xref> and 78o(d)) shall describe in such a report any claim filed for a deduction under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 during the reporting period that relates to a payment required under a covered settlement agreement.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDC46A4D30C59461799C5DF5A1E612BF2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>As used in this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="HB3BD721CADC24932AA492BAD36F04672"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>Commission</term> means the Securities and Exchange Commission;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28C484097BFB487AB18467C73B4E577E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <term>covered settlement agreement</term> has the meaning given that term in section 307 of title 5, United States Code, as added by subsection (a); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H76B984A960324681A49756BD1F24D17B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the term <term>issuer</term> has the same meaning as in section 3 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c</external-xref>).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H781FE67DA7154321BF765E922AF5692B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Review of confidentiality of settlement agreements</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report regarding how Executive agencies (as defined under section 105 of title 5, United States Code) determine whether the terms of a settlement agreement or the existence of a settlement agreement will be treated as confidential, which shall include recommendations, if any, for legislative or administrative action to increase the transparency of Government settlements while continuing to protect the legitimate interests that confidentiality provisions serve.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


