<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HFF09958825C547B7956C434F2E0882DC" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1316 IH: Prescription Drug Price Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1316</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170302">March 2, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001093">Mr. Collins of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000565">Mr. Loebsack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000533">Mr. Duncan of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001159">Mrs. McMorris Rodgers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001294">Mr. Blum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001168">Mr. Sarbanes</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for pharmacy benefits manager standards
			 under the Medicare prescription drug program and Medicare Advantage
			 program to further transparency of payment methodologies to pharmacies,
			 and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HEB2F65ABFD4C42F299E9115DFFFAE959" style="OLC">
 <section id="H21B52F38A4D1486FBC0D898C1268A6DD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prescription Drug Price Transparency Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HC40F368070A44039830C3FD4AAA0C759"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pharmacy benefits manager standards under the Medicare program for prescription drug plans and MA–PD plans</header> <subsection id="HE2EDA2EB25044E9789B8CE0AB605234E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1860D–12(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-112">42 U.S.C. 1395w–112(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H79CE774103B8474ABFF68B8F32C76A82" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H7F971F0761144E7E899EC393DCBC2D1A"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Pharmacy benefits manager transparency requirements</header><text>Each contract entered into with a PDP sponsor under this part with respect to a prescription drug plan offered by such sponsor or with an MA organization offering an MA–PD plan under part C shall provide that the sponsor or organization, respectively, may not enter into a contract with any pharmacy benefits manager (referred to in this paragraph as a <quote>PBM</quote>) to manage the prescription drug coverage provided under such plan, or to control the costs of the prescription drug coverage under such plan, unless the PBM adheres to the following criteria when handling personally identifiable utilization and claims data or other sensitive patient data:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEA3F70C6757048B4BB1EDA5EDB360FC4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The PBM may not transmit any personally identifiable utilization, protected health information, or claims data, with respect to a plan enrollee, to a pharmacy owned by a PBM if the plan enrollee has not voluntarily elected in writing or via secure electronic means to fill that particular prescription at the PBM-owned pharmacy.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5EEAC3F42B8546FAAEED74AD08B89020"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The PBM may not require that a plan enrollee use a retail pharmacy, mail order pharmacy, specialty pharmacy, or other pharmacy entity providing pharmacy services in which the PBM has an ownership interest or that has an ownership interest in the PBM, or provide an incentive to a plan enrollee to encourage the enrollee to use a retail pharmacy, mail order pharmacy, specialty pharmacy, or other pharmacy entity providing pharmacy services in which the PBM has an ownership interest or that has an ownership interest in the PBM, if the incentive is applicable only to such pharmacies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2091717C4F9A454CB965A823DB3B54BB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regular update of prescription drug pricing standard</header><text>Paragraph (6) of section 1860D–12(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-112">42 U.S.C. 1395w–112(b)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBD57A65AA8B349959EE1C3962E3E509A" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="H9E7A884C6FFC41EFA9FED554D1FA1B6F"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Regular update of prescription drug pricing standard</header>
 <subparagraph id="HED6F85DDB1234F5ABEF52D650160A624"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the PDP sponsor of a prescription drug plan (or MA organization offering an MA–PD plan) uses a standard for reimbursement (as described in subparagraph (B)) of pharmacies based on the cost of a drug, each contract entered into with such sponsor under this part (or organization under part C) with respect to the plan shall provide that the sponsor (or organization) shall—</text>
 <clause id="H870503FB56C14D388ED754ABE07DDA19"><enum>(i)</enum><text>update such standard not less frequently than once every 7 days, beginning with an initial update on January 1 of each year, to accurately reflect the market price of acquiring the drug;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF5CD4D2A9826430B9AE0DCE36DC3594E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>disclose to applicable pharmacies and the contracting entities of such pharmacies the sources used for making any such update immediately without requirement of request;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H58842D8930FA488C8473021985DE71B7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the source for such a standard for reimbursement is not publicly available, disclose to the applicable pharmacies and the respective contracting entities of such pharmacies all individual drug prices to be so updated in advance of the use of such prices for the reimbursement of claims;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC344E4DC1DA84A92831606C6B34A40F4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish a process to appeal, investigate, and resolve disputes regarding individual drug prices that are less than the pharmacy acquisition price for such drug, which must be adjudicated within 7 days of the pharmacy filing its appeal; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6067D29325064E98B0FB5C87FED1D6E4"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide all such pricing data in an .xml spreadsheet format or a comparable easily accessible and complete spreadsheet format.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD21DAA19BA384EE5A8384E88F60B95D4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prescription drug pricing standard defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subparagraph (A), a standard for reimbursement of a pharmacy is any methodology or formula for varying the pricing of a drug or drugs during the term of the pharmacy reimbursement contract that is based on the cost of the drug involved, including drug pricing references and amounts that are based upon average wholesale price, wholesale average cost, average manufacturer price, average sales price, maximum allowable cost (MAC), or other costs, whether publicly available or not.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H70A16795875644A48CDBD837C3E2E9A5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2018.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H5D67F8B2902B4F2ABBD063E980756DA7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Regular update of prescription drug pricing standard under TRICARE retail pharmacy program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1074g(d) of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF0D9B7B97F6A4AC49C8F95A1F232755F" style="USC">
 <paragraph id="H0DD214C35B424F8FB22B02E3DEC851AB" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent practicable, with respect to the TRICARE retail pharmacy program described in subsection (a)(2)(E)(ii), the Secretary shall ensure that a contract entered into with a TRICARE managed care support contractor includes requirements described in section 1860D–12(b)(6) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-112">42 U.S.C. 1395w–112(b)(6)</external-xref>) to ensure the provision of information regarding the pricing standard for prescription drugs.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="H40530A1168134852B45A98D3F77BA443"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prescription drug transparency in the Federal Employees Health Benefits program</header>
 <subsection id="H49485211E7C0425E935ED91B43A9CC94"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 8902 of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsections:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAEA95B62B62F4DD0B973FF99E324593C" style="USC">
 <subsection id="HC97C0DB4B02B485681FB766F04817B2B"><enum>(p)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A contract may not be made or a plan approved under this chapter under which a carrier has an agreement with a pharmacy benefits manager (in this subsection referred to as a <quote>PBM</quote>) to manage prescription drug coverage or to control the costs of the prescription drug coverage unless the carrier and PBM adhere to the following criteria:</text>
 <paragraph id="H825C9AB124514CCF9D61257A283EFD20"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The PBM may not transmit any personally identifiable utilization, protected health information, or claims data with respect to an individual enrolled under such contract or plan to a pharmacy owned by the PBM if the individual has not voluntarily elected in writing or via secure electronic means to fill that particular prescription at such a pharmacy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBED2B531CFBC431089E70EDC7E34F311"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The PBM may not require that an individual enrolled under such contract or plan use a retail pharmacy, mail order pharmacy, specialty pharmacy, or other pharmacy entity providing pharmacy services in which the PBM has an ownership interest or that has an ownership interest in the PBM or provide an incentive to a plan enrollee to encourage the enrollee to use a retail pharmacy, mail order pharmacy, specialty pharmacy, or other pharmacy entity providing pharmacy services in which the PBM has an ownership interest or that has an ownership interest in the PBM, if the incentive is applicable only to such pharmacies.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4A9B43CB6E734BA7BF228523A9D4002F"><enum>(q)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H31833ACDF7B8447BA9A903A08314331E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>If a contract made or plan approved under this chapter provides for a standard for reimbursement (as described in paragraph (2)) with respect to a prescription drug plan, such contract or plan shall provide that the applicable carrier—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H96680025AFFD4A369F17F5A4337231A0" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">update such standard not less frequently than once every 7 days, beginning with an initial update on January 1 of each year, to accurately reflect the market price of acquiring the drug;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BA9881BE4A84065B825E27618D73A08" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disclose to applicable pharmacies and the contracting entities of such pharmacies the sources used for making any such update immediately without requirement of request;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E9888F0C7E946F59501968B97A90035" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>if the source for such a standard for reimbursement is not publicly available, disclose to the applicable pharmacies and contracting entities of such pharmacies all individual drug prices to be so updated in advance of the use of such prices for the reimbursement of claims;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35113BBBC7E644E3AB6A4BA3AB12D5E4" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>establish a process to appeal, investigate, and resolve disputes regarding individual drug prices that are less than the pharmacy acquisition price for such drug, which must be adjudicated within 7 days of the pharmacy filing its appeal; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H79329E14AEE14894B5431B6895AA3D0B" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide all such pricing data in an .xml spreadsheet format or a comparable easily accessible and complete spreadsheet format.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC23DEC91E3C94134B2E2F59D542B0C45" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), a standard for reimbursement of a pharmacy is any methodology or formula for varying the pricing of a drug or drugs during the term of the pharmacy reimbursement contract that is based on the cost of the drug involved, including drug pricing references and amounts that are based upon average wholesale price, wholesale average cost, average manufacturer price, average sales price, maximum allowable cost, or other costs, whether publicly available or not.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEE599EF436E341478959D47252282563"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply to any contract entered into under section 8902 of title 5, United States Code, on or after the date of enactment of this section.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


