<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HAC9D3A875FD143E599FD53E3F97CF380" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 37 IH: Born-Alive Abortion Survivors Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 37</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170103">January 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 18, United States Code, to prohibit a health care practitioner from failing to
			 exercise the proper degree of care in the case of a child who survives an
			 abortion or attempted abortion.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H3EB64BB051BF45D6B2A1C11A95803271" style="OLC">
 <section id="H45F36B8633D24E1994F9DB7955FA9C51" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Born-Alive Abortion Survivors Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section commented="no" id="HB1715CE2108A41299381237E9D3F80E2" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds as follows:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H44AD035649F84BA28B4B311AF8122EA1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an abortion results in the live birth of an infant, the infant is a legal person for all purposes under the laws of the United States, and entitled to all the protections of such laws.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HBBA272520DAF45F58EF730ED6E1F5806"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any infant born alive after an abortion or within a hospital, clinic, or other facility has the same claim to the protection of the law that would arise for any newborn, or for any person who comes to a hospital, clinic, or other facility for screening and treatment or otherwise becomes a patient within its care.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H91B06B8A9E1943039EC70B6A83724E40"><enum>3.</enum><header>Born-alive infants protection</header>
 <subsection id="H0A3A5CD2B162465798639677C9765114"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirements pertaining to born-Alive abortion survivors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/74">Chapter 74</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/1531">section 1531</external-xref> the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC192379AEFB748D38EEFD3F28F7145EB" style="USC">
					<section id="H294BE29C8194412A901573BA20EF0ECC"><enum>1532.</enum><header>Requirements pertaining to born-alive abortion survivors</header>
 <subsection id="HE644EFF948FC4FB6ABC966006D770548"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirements for health care practitioners</header><text>In the case of an abortion or attempted abortion that results in a child born alive (as defined in section 8 of title 1, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Born-Alive Infants Protection Act</quote>)):</text>
 <paragraph id="H5B7A2462E273430795274F3FF45E28AE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Degree of care required; immediate admission to a hospital</header><text>Any health care practitioner present at the time the child is born alive shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H25E995A828084DAE9AC3F716121B64E5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>exercise the same degree of professional skill, care, and diligence to preserve the life and health of the child as a reasonably diligent and conscientious health care practitioner would render to any other child born alive at the same gestational age; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF822762F551F4D698950DA0266F046C0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">following the exercise of skill, care, and diligence required under subparagraph (A), ensure that the child born alive is immediately transported and admitted to a hospital.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE2DD529FB9224C44ADB20770D148BFEA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Mandatory reporting of violations</header><text>A health care practitioner or any employee of a hospital, a physician’s office, or an abortion clinic who has knowledge of a failure to comply with the requirements of paragraph (1) shall immediately report the failure to an appropriate State or Federal law enforcement agency, or to both.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC3E7E3DA31BD41C7B80A69AED94BC649"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Penalties</header>
 <paragraph id="H9C406341038346C38BDE590BB089F34F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Whoever violates subsection (a) shall be fined under this title or imprisoned for not more than 5 years, or both.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC9063244F35449D2A3A7564B6768A3FF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Intentional killing of child born alive</header><text>Whoever intentionally performs or attempts to perform an overt act that kills a child born alive described under subsection (a), shall be punished as under section 1111 of this title for intentionally killing or attempting to kill a human being.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2D8E257DCD4047E1A85DDEEC4A793C5E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Bar to prosecution</header><text>The mother of a child born alive described under subsection (a) may not be prosecuted under this section, for conspiracy to violate this section, or for an offense under section 3 or 4 of this title based on such a violation.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H979329F8C11B4CFA82BB587F6B4E3F35"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Civil remedies</header>
 <paragraph id="HDDF30132FCFC4B5F9AD4EC7F7B2E9F4A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Civil action by a woman on whom an abortion is performed</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a child is born alive and there is a violation of subsection (a), the woman upon whom the abortion was performed or attempted may, in a civil action against any person who committed the violation, obtain appropriate relief.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD7D592E79CFC4128BC9A5036A55708D0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate relief</header><text>Appropriate relief in a civil action under this subsection includes—</text> <subparagraph id="H0D3BCC57C4124146A198782BDF3C86C3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>objectively verifiable money damage for all injuries, psychological and physical, occasioned by the violation of subsection (a);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCEBDC508C80248D3A83131D37FC5F8E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>statutory damages equal to 3 times the cost of the abortion or attempted abortion; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H32D435632FF444229DBD952CFCB8FC06"><enum>(C)</enum><text>punitive damages.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0CA3E6966B02405DB277D743BA433E76"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Attorney’s fee for plaintiff</header><text>The court shall award a reasonable attorney’s fee to a prevailing plaintiff in a civil action under this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFB38B4A6B7424FA89563C76E56048ABB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Attorney’s fee for defendant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a defendant in a civil action under this subsection prevails and the court finds that the plaintiff’s suit was frivolous, the court shall award a reasonable attorney’s fee in favor of the defendant against the plaintiff.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H17FAB20ED51D4D9298E53C1530B45946"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section the following definitions apply:</text> <paragraph id="HCA797DF482364B59838A122A1F65285B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Abortion</header><text>The term <term>abortion</term> means the use or prescription of any instrument, medicine, drug, or any other substance or device—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2B3B4CF9C3494F5BA57BAF6F97A25CF9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to intentionally kill the unborn child of a woman known to be pregnant; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6121DEDFFB34FAF94FA6C152E61010C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to intentionally terminate the pregnancy of a woman known to be pregnant, with an intention other than—</text>
 <clause id="HB40A66D3D15945E09F7329679A01FFE8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>after viability, to produce a live birth and preserve the life and health of the child born alive; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4012815BDEF2433CAE60C7D3C144DC9D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to remove a dead unborn child.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC61A78D4E9A64B45B335CEAB1B0B9383"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Attempt</header><text>The term <term>attempt</term>, with respect to an abortion, means conduct that, under the circumstances as the actor believes them to be, constitutes a substantial step in a course of conduct planned to culminate in performing an abortion.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF2985EA93DAA4F3DAB1378D8D5CA458B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/74">chapter 74</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item pertaining to section 1531 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H08968F98473B46B4B1F96834242864AC" style="USC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">1532. Requirements pertaining to born-alive abortion survivors.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="HB624DADFF2FB483B9E67B4361DD76A37"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Chapter heading amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="H8E53A8DFCA1D4F6AA99E7370D36D700D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Chapter heading in chapter</header><text>The chapter heading for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/74">chapter 74</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">Partial-Birth Abortions</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">Abortions</header-in-text></quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H534BA1BFA1844F2D9A21A28632C18A12"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Table of chapters for part I</header><text>The item relating to chapter 74 in the table of chapters at the beginning of part I of title 18, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>Partial-Birth Abortions</quote> and inserting <quote>Abortions</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


