<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H5D34958F2DC742D1A63A3770D15CA57B" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2497 IH: End Subsidizing Palestinian Terrorism Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2497</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170517">May 17, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit assistance for the Palestinian Authority and the West Bank and Gaza, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H224D575840874EBF933B7B42ACB2C6AB" style="OLC">
 <section id="H39FB7B037D67432FB8FA4260068D721E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>End Subsidizing Palestinian Terrorism Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H3592DAA3DD6243668EB9771CD81BF0F3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header> <subsection id="HDAE607671B894F9C867AC4EDAB4B8411"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H8B5E8477ECDB4C198F2EC5B096C43FC1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Since September 2015 a series of more than 250 terrorist attacks have been carried out against citizens of Israel.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB115EFB56FAE441F9030681BC86B0AD3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>These terror attacks are the direct result of incitement by radical Palestinian elements provoking violence and calling on Palestinian youth to murder Jews.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H52DFC59DF35B4F87B62B6A89B89A0BB3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Palestinian terrorist attacks are part of the Palestinian Authority’s strategy of <quote>popular resistance</quote> that was formally adopted by the Palestinian Authority and Fatah at the Sixth Fatah conference in August 2009.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5613652987EC419BBA856EF8C3EFED8F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>According to the Israeli Ministry of Foreign Affairs, since September 2015 Palestinian terrorists have targeted Israeli citizens in 169 stabbings, 124 shootings, 51 vehicular attacks, and 1 vehicle bombing.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H83BB83B2E574470FA5F5A959B346F8CB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>It is appropriate to list these attacks and attempted attacks, which include, but are not limited to, the attacks and attempted attacks described in subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2CF49C82EA924554B83EFE89D2DE16BD"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The international community has remained nearly silent in response to the attacks and attempted attacks described in subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H34863209BAB74A42854C2C0D169F7884"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Palestinian violence is driven by anti-Jewish incitement and delegitimization of Israel’s right to exist.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7F560DCC0B8748B9A275AA3645E11C8A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Palestinian Authority President Mahmoud Abbas, in addressing the Arab League in Cairo, Egypt, stated on May 28, 2016, that <quote>we [the Palestinian Authority] incite [against Israel] in the media and in educational institutions</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF21BB19E435E4E7885D5ADCBA4527D37"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Palestinian Authority President Mahmoud Abbas said on July 30, 2013, that <quote>in a final resolution, [the Palestinian Authority] would not see the presence of a single Israeli</quote> in the state of Palestine.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HED1956557B6941119E28ABDB833FF6B5"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Palestinian Authority President Mahmoud Abbas stated on a September 16, 2015, television broadcast that <quote>We welcome every drop of blood spilled in Jerusalem. This is pure blood, clean blood, blood on its way to Allah. With the help of Allah, every martyr will be in heaven, and every wounded will get his reward.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H650ABED4F5974F9CBA183852AA6A6B11"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The Palestinian Government praises Palestinian terrorists as heroes to be commended and emulated.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2EC7518E86154425AB6B76CB9634B4E8"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Palestinians in Hamas-controlled Gaza routinely distribute sweets to celebrate successful terrorist attacks.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCF2C376D57954F57B911AD4E65B4764B"><enum>(13)</enum><text>On September 30, 2015, Palestinian Authority President Mahmoud Abbas said during a speech to the United Nations that the Palestinian Authority is no longer bound to the 1995 Oslo Accords which established the two-state solution for peace.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H48865737D325454A8462AF4DF8F92BCC"><enum>(14)</enum><text>In a November 2014 address commemorating the 10th anniversary of Yasser Arafat’s death, President Abbas said that as Israel has no claim to Jerusalem, he will not allow the Temple Mount to be <quote>contaminated by Jews</quote>, and threatened that Jewish prayer at the site would cause <quote>devastating religious war</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H674595D3D7F84EFB887C45CDDB8C673B"><enum>(15)</enum><text>In June 2013, Palestinian Authority President Mahmoud Abbas referenced Israeli acts which <quote>indicate an evil and dangerous plot to destroy Al- Aqsa and build the alleged temple</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA97D338DCC0A48C1B3EE28F61161DBA8"><enum>(16)</enum><text>Israelis and Palestinians alike have the right to live in safety and dignity.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H34E695D21FE04B468E0804C3AA03F1CD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Attacks and attempted attacks described</header><text>The attacks and attempted attacks described in this subsection are the following:</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H35CC0ABC33D840CAA007DB633AF0EF64"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An attack on January 8, 2017, when a Palestinian used his vehicle to ram a group of Israel Defense Forces cadets at the Armon Hanatziv promenade in Jerusalem, killing 4 and injuring 17.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2119010B1B9245A9A09F7A5B2D12C285"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An attack on December 25, 2016, when terrorists fired shots at Israelis from a vehicle in Beit El.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD8675526E99147C5B6749640680DD010"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An attempted attack on December 24, 2016, when Israeli security forces thwarted a stabbing attack by an Arab woman in Jerusalem’s Old City.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H458BD784446742B0B91588A00FE480A7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An attack on December 24, 2016, when terrorists threw six Molotov cocktails at cars in Ofarim.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE6D4ABC599247A480DDD5814BA56B8C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An attack on December 23, 2016, when a Palestinian stabbed a 50-year-old man in Efrat.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9A0BB2698712427D98B9D6FAF981CC7D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>An attack on December 14, 2016, when a Palestinian stabbed two Israeli border police officers and a 13-year-old boy in Jerusalem’s Old City.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC60DD612652F459AAC37D9526EA0BCCB"><enum>(7)</enum><text>An attempted attack on December 8, 2016, when a Palestinian attempted to stab an Israeli border police officer at the Tapuah Junction.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA9B0BAB283F3404F908F4B4F8F37BA54"><enum>(8)</enum><text>An attack on November 26, 2016, when terrorists threw a Molotov cocktail at Israeli police officers in Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA7CF5BAC9BB94FFF848DD74EB572A33C"><enum>(9)</enum><text>An attempted attack on November 25, 2016, when a 16-year-old Palestinian attempted to stab an Israeli officer in Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA8AB15A61B824C95AD1BDB15B4A70A2F"><enum>(10)</enum><text>An attack on November 23, 2016, when terrorists threw five Molotov cocktails at a bus near Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6A659BC7276345618ED98362FA85AD29"><enum>(11)</enum><text>An attack on November 14, 2016, when terrorists threw stones and pipe bombs at Israel Defense Forces soldiers near Rachel’s Tomb in Bethlehem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H876920DE2BDA4602A23DE48FE5042FB8"><enum>(12)</enum><text>An attack on November 3, 2016, when a terrorist attempted to stab Israel Defense Forces soldiers stationed at a roadside bus stop near Ofra.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0FA2C1619CED489F9DF3C4D7A897DE8A"><enum>(13)</enum><text>An attack on October 31, 2016, when a member of the Palestinian Authority’s security forces shot and wounded three Israel Defense Forces soldiers in Beit El.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3FB6D2B791E64A1387F0CB63FB202A63"><enum>(14)</enum><text>An attack on October 30, 2016, when a Palestinian used his vehicle to ram and injure three Israeli border police officers near Hebron.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD1A4CDC08EBA495E8EB2C04B11E49DA8"><enum>(15)</enum><text>An attempted attack on October 29, 2016, when a Palestinian attempted to use his vehicle to ram Israel Defense Forces soldiers, after which he exited the vehicle and attempted to stab them, near Ofra.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE5106BA300224832BD12ADD69E864963"><enum>(16)</enum><text>An attempted attack on October 19, 2016, when a Palestinian attempted to stab Israeli border police officers at Tapuah Junction.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H377615BC72F442368B9788717A034325"><enum>(17)</enum><text>An attack on October 9, 2016, when a Palestinian killed two Israelis in a triple shooting in Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC751D70CFA2428C850F40D453C57CC2"><enum>(18)</enum><text>An attack on September 30, 2016, when a Palestinian stabbed a member of the Israeli security forces at the Qalandia crossing.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC0C0CB4F4F6D409DA2FCD6E1E3308424"><enum>(19)</enum><text>An attempted attack on September 20, 2016, when a Palestinian attempted to stab an Israel Defense Forces soldier near Kiryat Arba.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H44EC9F1D792444D691346C247442C136"><enum>(20)</enum><text>An attack on September 20, 2016, when two Israel Defense Forces soldiers were wounded by petrol bombs near Bethlehem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H67A6C6D2DCFE4C5AADBC5875678E8987"><enum>(21)</enum><text>An attempted attack on September 19, 2016, when a Palestinian attempted to stab an Israel Defense Forces soldier in Hebron.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H363888DCC52A4A72B60E3042E8AF6515"><enum>(22)</enum><text>An attempted attack on September 19, 2016, when two Palestinians attempted to stab Israel Defense Forces soldiers in Hebron.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H155FA5BFB8844FDB842CEE1F94791D18"><enum>(23)</enum><text>An attack on September 19, 2016, when a Palestinian stabbed two Israeli police officers at Jerusalem’s Flower Gate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5CB1FF7CEC814EA08EB574B4BC47CA9B"><enum>(24)</enum><text>An attack on September 18, 2016, when a Palestinian stabbed an Israel Defense Forces soldier in Efrat.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF8CF63055F15445FB0C6F543CC8465AD"><enum>(25)</enum><text>An attack on September 17, 2016, when a Palestinian stabbed an Israel Defense Forces soldier in Hebron.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEDBFF95B0CB64FB986F834E9AC5892D6"><enum>(26)</enum><text>An attack on September 16, 2016, when a Palestinian stabbed an Israel Defense Forces soldier in Hebron.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H111DB15BD83E4417A036E27F8BA50011"><enum>(27)</enum><text>An attempted attack on September 16, 2016, when two Palestinians attempted to use their vehicle to ram Israeli civilians in Kiryat Arba.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC68ED50436A24DB39C302234791798F0"><enum>(28)</enum><text>An attack on September 16, 2016, when a Jordanian attempted to stab Israeli police officers near Jerusalem’s Old City.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4E82454D350E4C30960C79C4F23D5756"><enum>(29)</enum><text>An attempted attack on September 5, 2016, when a Palestinian attempted to stab Israel Defense Forces soldiers in Jerusalem’s Old City.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3A8FE66D1FC3432DA3D490652129309D"><enum>(30)</enum><text>An attack on August 31, 2016, when an Israel Defense Forces soldier guarding Jewish worshipers at Joseph’s Tomb was shot by fire coming from the Balata refugee camp in Nablus.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H33CF9507FDCC4869A2B066699600F0FF"><enum>(31)</enum><text>An attack on August 24, 2016, when a Palestinian stabbed an Israel Defense Forces soldier near Gilad.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H49118B1B179C4D089988A5A2B41D3177"><enum>(32)</enum><text>An attack on August 18, 2016, when Israelis riding in a bus were injured after the vehicle was struck by stones.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H91554F8778D44713A8E4FD6710064717"><enum>(33)</enum><text>An attack on August 14, 2016, when a Palestinian stabbed an Israel Defense Forces soldier in Shaked.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA99C71E2C52F40E6B6744A4C708259EC"><enum>(34)</enum><text>An attack on August 11, 2016, when a Palestinian stabbed an Israeli citizen visiting the Mount of Olives cemetery in Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H611D3E0E77D0465EA81BCDF54961FFF6"><enum>(35)</enum><text>An attempted attack on July 31, 2016, when a Palestinian attempted to stab Israel Defense Forces soldiers in Hawara.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2E9E69DAD5C44C5B8223C4244F62FF2C"><enum>(36)</enum><text>An attack on July 18, 2016, when a Palestinian stabbed two Israel Defense Forces soldiers on the Gush Etzion-Hebron Highway.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFB9A4E5415604637A8F21877E20303E3"><enum>(37)</enum><text>An attempted attack on July 17, 2016, when a Palestinian was arrested carrying several pipe bombs and knives in Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H348185C83CCB46D795235E4B7B97E23A"><enum>(38)</enum><text>An attack on July 9, 2016, when a Palestinian shot and wounded an Israeli motorist at the Tekoa Junction.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5273DA847C794160A3F58BE089C867AF"><enum>(39)</enum><text>An attempted attack on July 5, 2016, when a Palestinian attempted to stab two Israel Defense Forces soldiers in Ariel.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA4BA5B5738CF4201B2E0C9C3BF84DEA5"><enum>(40)</enum><text>An attack on July 1, 2016, when a Palestinian killed one and injured three in a drive-by shooting in Gush Etzion.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8286B04495C54EA085D91B6C4ED7FD8B"><enum>(41)</enum><text>An attempted attack on July 1, 2016, when a Palestinian attempted to stab an Israeli border police officer in Hebron.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H273AA676A3CF4BC98A8A2A2238DE8CE5"><enum>(42)</enum><text>An attack on June 30, 2016, when a 13-year-old girl was stabbed to death in her bed by a Palestinian terrorist from a village near Kiryat Arba.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB350F147FC0245B69580A09067CC7265"><enum>(43)</enum><text>An attack on June 30, 2016, when two Israelis were stabbed near the Netanya market.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H699D48E3B81E4C3591FCC39CF11D26D4"><enum>(44)</enum><text>An attack on June 26, 2016, when a Molotov cocktail was thrown at an Israeli car on the Aboud bypass road.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H93A215731BA6468FA2A368C579D256ED"><enum>(45)</enum><text>An attack on June 26, 2016, when a Palestinian driver rammed her vehicle into a car at a hitch-hiking stop, injuring two Israelis near Kiryat Arba.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5F0DC321A90941EEB2AB35FF9D7CBC1C"><enum>(46)</enum><text>An attack on June 21, 2016, when Palestinians threw stones at cars traveling on Route 443.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H28FED9BA5AE14D2C93C2453A35CF6786"><enum>(47)</enum><text>An attack on June 18, 2016, when Palestinians threw more than 20 Molotov cocktails at the Psagot Settlement.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFAAC977E02934E68B8414FDC213F92A5"><enum>(48)</enum><text>An attack on June 17, 2016, when Palestinians threw four Molotov cocktails at an Israeli home in Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE1E7E1ADB7024C5799442F79356E4F19"><enum>(49)</enum><text>An attack on June 8, 2016, when two Palestinian men killed four and injured 17 in the Sarona Market in Tel Aviv.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H468F990BCAFD4E2E85434655D33E85D6"><enum>(50)</enum><text>An attack on June 6, 2016, when a Palestinian shot at vehicles on Route 465.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB2F17CFE081C482984DDFB738090DD61"><enum>(51)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An attack on June 5, 2016, when Palestinians barraged with stones a bus traveling on Road 437.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H36DC401A7878462A841EA4990C127F74"><enum>(52)</enum><text>An attack on June 2, 2016, when Palestinians threw Molotov cocktails at Jewish worshipers in Nablus.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2849FAE32987424EBF1217BB458C33FA"><enum>(53)</enum><text>An attempted attack on June 2, 2016, when a Palestinian attempted to stab an Israel Defense Forces soldier near Einay.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD9BA0BDCE91546029EB5B93CECB84B95"><enum>(54)</enum><text>An attack on June 1, 2016, when Palestinians threw stones at cars traveling on Route 443.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6E777F830EC749F8882974565F44455F"><enum>(55)</enum><text>An attack on May 30, 2016, when a Palestinian stabbed an Israel Defense Forces soldier with a screwdriver in Tel Aviv.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H99237F57CD3F4E46B875776F10F295E7"><enum>(56)</enum><text>An attack on May 24, 2016, when Palestinians threw stones at a bus in Jerusalem.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H96118757ACDA4C84B59198314967ED11"><enum>(57)</enum><text>An attempted attack on May 23, 2016, when a Palestinian attempted to stab two Israeli border police officers in Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEA079545AAFB4B7C95ABAD73FF1ACF8C"><enum>(58)</enum><text>An attack on May 22, 2016, when a Molotov cocktail was thrown at a bus in the village of Hawara.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2CB143C19AFF4A0FBED6037AEBD830BD"><enum>(59)</enum><text>An attack on May 22, 2016, when Palestinians threw stones at a bus on Highway 443.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6FC8C6B9289F43FAB8DEB72DC43CE96F"><enum>(60)</enum><text>An attack on May 21, 2016, when Palestinians shot at a passenger bus near Gush Etzion.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8411035741164D32AE14EF20BC0DEE86"><enum>(61)</enum><text>An attack on May 10, 2016, when multiple pipe bombs injured two Israel Defense Forces soldiers near Hizma.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8C6ADE8F9F434C0B91ED54F445BFD571"><enum>(62)</enum><text>An attack on May 10, 2016, when two Palestinians stabbed two Israeli women, aged 86 and 82, in Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H146A45D91F2A4639B3EBDE6734EA7009"><enum>(63)</enum><text>An attack on May 3, 2016, when a Palestinian driver rammed his vehicle into three Israel Defense Forces soldiers near Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6AEF1B42E10C457498976A5990C33755"><enum>(64)</enum><text>An attack on May 2, 2016, when a Palestinian stabbed an Israeli man in Jerusalem’s Old City.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC8888FBAD363451191D0A5F13D69F497"><enum>(65)</enum><text>An attack on May 1, 2016, when Palestinians threw stones at a car traveling near Efrat, injuring two children.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB6B2EFB0CE294B42A41B0114AD655792"><enum>(66)</enum><text>An attack on April 19, 2016, when a bomb planted aboard a bus exploded, injuring 21 in Jerusalem.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF85021526D28427FA35E9BED03F6CEA5"><enum>(67)</enum><text>An attack on April 14, 2016, when a Palestinian attacked a group of Israel Defense Forces soldiers with an axe near Gush Etzion.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA8EE5F1C24D542DF9EA5614440163159"><enum>(68)</enum><text>An attack on April 14, 2016, when stones were thrown at a car traveling on Highway 431.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7DD8934BDDEB49C7AD7AB601667FCE95"><enum>(69)</enum><text>An attempted attack on April 14, 2016, when two Palestinian children were arrested with knives in Jerusalem’s Old City.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD57D4C9A10EF48A6BCB91274E977634C"><enum>(70)</enum><text>An attack on March 25, 2016, when a Palestinian attempted to stab Israel Defense Forces soldiers in Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8780410F2A5E4766983322A5CED59422"><enum>(71)</enum><text>An attack on March 24, 2016, when two Palestinians stabbed an Israel Defense Forces soldier near Hebron.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0A24804D19674229A64DB51D585EC5AD"><enum>(72)</enum><text>An attack on March 18, 2016, when three Palestinians attacked Israel Defense Forces soldiers with knives.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4B6B6AC05222455DAF55E2495D142649"><enum>(73)</enum><text>An attack on March 17, 2016, when two Palestinians stabbed an Israel Defense Forces soldier in Ariel.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF84DD1C776C640BA8E35EA8209E369A7"><enum>(74)</enum><text>An attack on March 14, 2016, when two Palestinians attempted to use their vehicle to ram Israelis, later opening fire on civilians and soldiers standing at a bus stop near the entrance to Kiryat Arba.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1567558B2DE8435DB2B02226C8B069D6"><enum>(75)</enum><text>An attack on March 11, 2016, when a Palestinian stabbed an Israeli man in Jerusalem.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCC27BE4A018A4FE4B18264B5D1A29247"><enum>(76)</enum><text>An attack on March 11, 2016, when a Palestinian shot two Israel Defense Forces soldiers near Beit Horon.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCEE532557AF54F049320B137AF5A6B98"><enum>(77)</enum><text>An attack on March 9, 2016, when two Palestinians opened fire on police officers and civilians near Jerusalem’s Old City.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H74AA2913B55A40B09B40837631005D19"><enum>(78)</enum><text>An attempted attack on March 8, 2016, when a Palestinian attempted to stab Israeli border police officers in Jerusalem’s Old City.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H108612CB239A4F1E8D2617DAD498B7DA"><enum>(79)</enum><text>An attack on March 8, 2016, when a Palestinian opened fire on Israeli border police officers with an automatic weapon near Jerusalem’s Old City.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE5B6F640D1EE479399FB6803DFEBA520"><enum>(80)</enum><text>An attack on March 8, 2016, when a Palestinian stabbed an Israeli in Petah Tikva.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7A9955980607405FBF32BB643E9ADB89"><enum>(81)</enum><text>An attack on March 8, 2016, when a Palestinian went on a stabbing spree in Tel Aviv’s Jaffa Port, injuring 10 and killing American student Taylor Force.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEBD9E631EC5C494B85025014FAC6E27E"><enum>(82)</enum><text>An attack on March 3, 2016, when a Palestinian used her vehicle to ram an Israel Defense Forces soldier at the Gush Etzion junction.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H602E4DF4FE24445FBD173E4878C37F33"><enum>(83)</enum><text>An attack on March 3, 2016, when a Palestinian stabbed a police officer in the Jordan Valley.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2F56F748A4E7428FB13F082635EFDC1A"><enum>(84)</enum><text>An attack on March 3, 2016, when a Palestinian shot and injured a police officer in Rahelim.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H10DA05F99CED44ECAB0BD68C2CBD84EA"><enum>(85)</enum><text>An attack on March 2, 2016, when two Palestinians attacked an Israeli man in his home in Eli.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H962F285B30E04677AC18C9B11852C7F4"><enum>(86)</enum><text>An attack on March 2, 2016, when two Palestinians stabbed two police officers in Har Brakha.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3ECE5B892FE14B9B96837934E90EDF97"><enum>(87)</enum><text>An attack on February 26, 2016, when a Palestinian critically wounded an Israeli with an axe near Ma’ale Adumin.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFA4CB136493E4F54856013AD96780860"><enum>(88)</enum><text>An attempted attack on February 26, 2016, when a Palestinian attempted to stab Israel Defense Forces soldiers near Ramallah.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H304FB073E17947749A498FEF5B9B2CE6"><enum>(89)</enum><text>An attack on February 24, 2016, when a Palestinian stabbed an Israel Defense Forces reservist near Gush Etzion.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3C4BD7351DCE45F9905655F1CEA520F4"><enum>(90)</enum><text>An attempted attack on February 24, 2016, when two Palestinians were arrested with pipe bombs near Jerusalem’s Old City.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3F3F1B46229842C4AF3F391E032E9029"><enum>(91)</enum><text>An attempted attack on February 21, 2016, when a Palestinian was arrested with a large knife while attempting to attack Israeli civilians.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H24CB9A96301A4700B1E3AF4A9BDD2D6B"><enum>(92)</enum><text>An attempted attack on February 21, 2016, when a Palestinian attempted to stab an Israel Defense Forces soldier in Hebron.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6709C903D03C4585B963DE0902D08534"><enum>(93)</enum><text>An attack on February 21, 2016, when a Palestinian attempted to stab an Israel Defense Forces soldier near Nablus.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF454B58BB463450A8E57A95C5B03305E"><enum>(94)</enum><text>An attempted attack on February 20, 2016, when a Palestinian attempted to stab an Israel Defense Forces soldier outside of Jerusalem’s Old City.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H747CA3A4EAB44F10810CF3A59D89D7E8"><enum>(95)</enum><text>An attack on February 19, 2016, when a Palestinian stabbed two Israeli border policemen outside of Jerusalem’s Old City.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H825FD5102F604E1F8244BDADCD4F1CF6"><enum>(96)</enum><text>An attempted attack on February 19, 2016, when a Palestinian attempted to use her vehicle to ram Israel Defense Forces soldiers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H32F0DFAE47C84EAAB72871BFA6B9175F"><enum>(97)</enum><text>An attack on February 18, 2016, when two Palestinians stabbed shoppers at a supermarket in Sh’ae Binyamin.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8A70014DE09A468FBF8A27CB3B73614B"><enum>(98)</enum><text>An attempted attack on February 15, 2016, when a Palestinian attempted to stab an Israel Defense Forces soldier outside of Jerusalem’s Old City.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H718273E568DC43EC996D0D5EF905FEB0"><enum>(99)</enum><text>An attack on February 14, 2016, when two Palestinians shot at Israel Defense Forces soldiers outside of Jerusalem’s Old City.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H92C5E8C65FC64A67A2ED26B5EE3C5CBC"><enum>(100)</enum><text>An attempted attack on February 14, 2016, when a Palestinian attempted to stab an Israel Defense Forces soldier in Hebron.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0B0972A89EF04FEB95D9123573DE49C0"><enum>(101)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An attempted attack on February 19, 2016, when a Palestinian attempted to stab an Israel Defense Forces soldier outside of Tekoa-Har Homa.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7D2D20037D634F058008A8509CE54652"><enum>(102)</enum><text>An attack on February 19, 2016, when two Palestinians shot at Israel Defense Forces soldiers near Hinanit.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEB62A94C7B434CAFB4D057DE14110FD9"><enum>(103)</enum><text>An attack on February 13, 2016, when a Palestinian stabbed an Israel Defense Forces soldier and a Palestinian man in Hebron.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H609E4C15A75D4B7E8032DE12FB0493A2"><enum>(104)</enum><text>An attack on February 9, 2016, when a Palestinian stabbed an Israeli soldier in Hebron.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1CF3A81037FE41AC8BB347A2988AB126"><enum>(105)</enum><text>An attack on February 6, 2016, when a Palestinian stabbed an Israeli woman in Rahat.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H059A4CFBBADC4E5A9A5D69AA030D5204"><enum>(106)</enum><text>An attack on February 4, 2016, when two Palestinians stabbed a mall security guard in Ramle.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H86A8E664F4A34E16BFEB4C282A2D6CA0"><enum>(107)</enum><text>An attack on February 3, 2016, when three Palestinians killed one Israeli border police officer and wounded two others outside of Jerusalem’s Old City.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H774C183572EF41B4B9F6D003741518FA"><enum>(108)</enum><text>An attempted attack on February 1, 2016, when a Palestinian attempted to stab an Israeli in Sal’it.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9A22A1E591E94F27A94F22513201A038"><enum>(109)</enum><text>An attack on January 31, 2016, when a Palestinian opened fire on three Israel Defense Forces soldiers, wounding three near Beit El.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA7AC098908C749A0A5BCE84E2C419AD4"><enum>(110)</enum><text>An attack on January 30, 2016, when a Palestinian stabbed an Israeli outside of Jerusalem’s Old City.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBE26B7B24CD44E27977EDA67F809D8C5"><enum>(111)</enum><text>An attack on January 27, 2016, when a Palestinian stabbed an Israeli in Givat Ze’ev.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDC060DD6F93742138ABC8F93AC25C13B"><enum>(112)</enum><text>An attack on January 25, 2016, when two Palestinians stabbed two Israeli women at a supermarket in Beit Horon.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H41AC1934316D4991AC78B78634C9CB78"><enum>(113)</enum><text>An attack on January 24, 2016, when a Palestinian gunman opened fire at a vehicle driving near the community of Dolev.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC4E45399497D427988DF40AEA5E957B0"><enum>(114)</enum><text>An attempted attack on January 20, 2016, when a Palestinian attempted to stab an Israeli in Hebron.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H831F45570F5D4119B3A6B817A4E890AE"><enum>(115)</enum><text>An attack on January 18, 2016, when a Palestinian stabbed a pregnant Israeli woman in Tekoa.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9DCA2E5821B54237B87D06E87214FA91"><enum>(116)</enum><text>An attempted attack on January 17, 2016, when a Palestinian attempted to stab an Israeli in the West Bank.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H93E3406CF86A432BBF4669414EEB570F"><enum>(117)</enum><text>An attack on January 17, 2016, when a Palestinian stabbed an Israeli woman to death outside of her home in Otniel.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC70FECCBABA14C33B8D792D1DBE60C21"><enum>(118)</enum><text>An attack on January 14, 2016, when a Palestinian stabbed an Israel Defense Forces soldier near Nablus.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB53C7B01C0854E01AC3876ED2CE590CF"><enum>(119)</enum><text>An attempted attack on January 14, 2016, when a Palestinian attempted to stab an Israeli near Beit Anoun.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H69E8D3EB6237419DABECBC216994E0CA"><enum>(120)</enum><text>An attack on January 13, 2016, when an Israeli bus driver was injured after his bus was damaged by a rock thrown by a Palestinian near Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5DAE0F3E1F1945AEA162E7CFD9B7DC80"><enum>(121)</enum><text>An attempted attack on January 12, 2016, when two Palestinians attempted to stab Israelis near Kiryat Arba.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC64455B8E1E24E51990FAED7B45684CE"><enum>(122)</enum><text>An attempted attack on January 9, 2016, when two Palestinians attempted to stab Israelis in the Jordan Valley.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H73771FF1FC7743C48F8664C418C4FC11"><enum>(123)</enum><text>An attempted attack on January 7, 2016, when a Palestinian attempted to stab an Israeli near Kiryat Arba.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H46298F0EF9B34AE6BCDBCFA7A73289B8"><enum>(124)</enum><text>An attempted attack on January 7, 2016, when three Palestinians attempted to stab an Israeli near Gush Etzion.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3B1E0183AC63497FB20305F0F7E61E16"><enum>(125)</enum><text>An attack on January 5, 2016, when an Israeli bus driver was injured after his bus was damaged by a rock thrown by a Palestinian on Highway 79.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1FFDBECE77E547D8A0D59B71053CF899"><enum>(126)</enum><text>An attempted attack on January 4, 2016, when a Palestinian attempted to stab Israelis outside of the National Police Headquarters in Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HABA2455EA10045B7A8F780903DF2C61C"><enum>(127)</enum><text>An attempted attack on January 3, 2016, when a Palestinian attempted to stab an Israeli in Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9462E386840E4E6CA3966E59AEDA600D"><enum>(128)</enum><text>An attack on January 3, 2016, when a Palestinian opened fire on an Israel Defense Forces soldier in the South Hebron Hills.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0EC5B8B8F1F848F5B67B00F893494AA9"><enum>(129)</enum><text>An attack on January 3, 2016, when Palestinian snipers shot an Israel Defense Forces soldier in Hebron.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC749781C8EE64FB2BB4F45EE972D5CBC"><enum>(130)</enum><text>An attack on January 2, 2016, when a Palestinian opened fire on Israeli vehicles near Jerusalem.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF36F86AE654149EB8CAA8C53476AFCE9"><enum>(131)</enum><text>An attack on January 1, 2016, when a Palestinian killed two and injured eight in a shooting attack in Tel Aviv.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H452C5D165A754244B7400DA6BCBC9212"><enum>(132)</enum><text>An attack on January 1, 2016, when a Palestinian shot and killed an Israeli taxi driver in Tel Aviv.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H165206D97E6D43CBB9D6F151423F8BF0"><enum>(133)</enum><text>An attack on December 31, 2015, when a Palestinian used his vehicle to ram an Israel Defense Forces soldier in the West Bank.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB9013B8AC7484CD99E3736ACA3A5E378"><enum>(134)</enum><text>An attack on December 27, 2015, when two Palestinians stabbed an Israel Defense Forces soldier in Hawara.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8BA3CF441AA8420C84917E8A1AD99FD0"><enum>(135)</enum><text>An attempted attack on December 27, 2015, when a Palestinian attempted to stab an Israeli in Hebron.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA9F9A90D90C2429398BD9EB4C5B75005"><enum>(136)</enum><text>An attempted attack on December 27, 2015, when a Palestinian attempted to stab an Israeli in the West Bank.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDC0C673D8DB34042AD12F0E3BA06CD04"><enum>(137)</enum><text>An attempted attack on December 27, 2015, when a Palestinian attempted to stab an Israeli in Jerusalem’s Old City.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0B3F3B3AA67A4C12B511ED60EE319D5E"><enum>(138)</enum><text>An attack on December 27, 2015, when a Palestinian stabbed an Israel Defense Forces soldier in Jerusalem’s Old City.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HABFAF4E1F3BB48C0AB14D89FB37B90E7"><enum>(139)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An attack on December 26, 2015, when a Palestinian used his vehicle to ram an Israel Defense Forces soldier in the West Bank.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H50C715E9364247C79E42335A60D592B9"><enum>(140)</enum><text>An attempted attack on December 26, 2015, when a Palestinian attempted to stab an Israeli in Jerusalem’s Old City.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB1FA95D11C7F4C32962140BFDF166B8C"><enum>(141)</enum><text>An attack on December 25, 2015, when Palestinians attacked the vehicle of the Latin Patriarch in Bethlehem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB03D05DBE11C43AC960F8FE25783D0DE"><enum>(142)</enum><text>An attempted attack on December 25, 2015, when a Palestinian attempted to use his vehicle to ram an Israeli in Silwad.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0E10EBDE52AF4C63A116CF43CB6D2E67"><enum>(143)</enum><text>An attempted attack on December 24, 2015, when a Palestinian attempted to stab an Israel Defense Forces soldier in Hebron.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAA0633F06C06485C8E3B30CAF6E2CA1C"><enum>(144)</enum><text>An attack on December 24, 2015, when a Palestinian stabbed two Israel Defense Forces soldiers in Ariel.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBF3EF7C71FC1452EA0645DCE67FFB081"><enum>(145)</enum><text>An attack on December 23, 2015, when a Palestinian stabbed and killed a rabbi outside of Jerusalem’s Old City.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB8C2A83A072842779E130F3B67A49B89"><enum>(146)</enum><text>An attack on December 19, 2015, when a Palestinian stabbed three Israelis in Raanana.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H56337CC8CD9D49FEA39D6728AF00E168"><enum>(147)</enum><text>An attempted attack on December 18, 2015, when a Palestinian attempted to use his vehicle to ram Israel Defense Forces soldiers in the West Bank.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEB5CEC47916A483D908840DEDE17DD3B"><enum>(148)</enum><text>An attack on December 14, 2015, when three Israelis were injured after a rock was thrown through the windshield of their car in Beit Aryeh.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1D2FB6C1F187439B8EA5CB0F485664B0"><enum>(149)</enum><text>An attack on December 14, 2015, when 14 Israelis were injured in a vehicular ramming attack at a bus stop in Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H38AF40CA652744B1B395DF11FA81A059"><enum>(150)</enum><text>An attempted attack on December 13, 2015, when a Palestinian attempted to stab an Israeli civilian in Kiryat Arba.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBFE9A766255E46C6BAD93A55EE0CB9D6"><enum>(151)</enum><text>An attempted attack on December 11, 2015, when a Palestinian attempted to use his vehicle to ram Israel Defense soldiers near Kiryat Arba.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H62AD851EA4B840DBAB9B7C1F1CE9F03D"><enum>(152)</enum><text>An attack on December 11, 2015, when a Palestinian opened fire on Israel Defense Forces soldiers in Gilboa.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE2E837332601492A8C78C7648ED8CF71"><enum>(153)</enum><text>An attack on December 10, 2015, when a Palestinian used his vehicle to ram Israel Defense soldiers in the West Bank.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H602A9498497E4D96B3CE5D8DD5981F4C"><enum>(154)</enum><text>An attempted attack on December 9, 2015, when three Palestinians were apprehended with butcher knives in Afula.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H527988280C5E413DB6B4E92255014D9F"><enum>(155)</enum><text>An attack on December 9, 2015, when Palestinians opened fire on an Israeli family in a drive by shooting, injuring two in the West Bank.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1B88B323AF9745819189AE9E16DCCD23"><enum>(156)</enum><text>An attack on December 9, 2015, when a Palestinian stabbed a civilian and an Israel Defense Forces soldier in Hebron.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA977AE74ABF747FCB3F6375D9B737F2C"><enum>(157)</enum><text>An attack on December 7, 2015, when a Palestinian stabbed an Israeli civilian in Hebron.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7DE8BE3E60DC4839B6722A3E8CB78F7E"><enum>(158)</enum><text>An attack on December 6, 2015, when a Palestinian used his vehicle to ram and subsequently stab Israelis in Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6E586497C8214032AEF9F9045A15603C"><enum>(159)</enum><text>An attack on December 4, 2015, when a Palestinian used his vehicle to ram two Israel Defense Forces soldiers in Ofra.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H00225F912D8E4902B5DB3D62E28CEA18"><enum>(160)</enum><text>An attack on December 4, 2015, when a Palestinian stabbed an Israel Defense Forces soldier in Abud.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB11511FFB129443FB64E8E8800FDC25E"><enum>(161)</enum><text>An attack on December 4, 2015, when two Palestinians stabbed an Israel Defense Forces soldier in Hebron.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEC46528693D04836A81F07B7143B37FD"><enum>(162)</enum><text>An attack on December 3, 2015, when a Palestinian shot an Israel Defense Forces soldier and an Israeli civilian north of Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8325F12B6EDD4E649972939EEBEA84CF"><enum>(163)</enum><text>An attack on December 3, 2015, when a Palestinian stabbed an Israel Defense Forces soldier near Jerusalem’s Old City.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2C5718DA9A0C4E84B35CD7625F4B7E21"><enum>(164)</enum><text>An attempted attack on December 3, 2015, when a Palestinian attempted to stab an Israeli at the Gush Etzion junction.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD681801C68BC466AAA0A2817240B04B6"><enum>(165)</enum><text>An attempted attack on December 3, 2015, when a Palestinian attempted to stab an Israel Defense Forces soldier in the West Bank.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H89DBFEF22343415EB5DD71E8C49D9FFA"><enum>(166)</enum><text>An attack on November 29, 2015, when a Palestinian stabbed an Israeli border police officer near Jerusalem’s Old City.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAD104D60D5BD4A5188B955A024B92539"><enum>(167)</enum><text>An attack on November 29, 2015, when a Palestinian stabbed a foreign worker from Nepal in Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H149F842C5FAB42C5AB28440F2D0D8BD9"><enum>(168)</enum><text>An attack on November 27, 2015, when a Palestinian used his vehicle to ram two Israel Defense Forces soldiers in Kfar Adumim.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB864FDAF085E44F2A5C65404923A191C"><enum>(169)</enum><text>An attack on November 27, 2015, when a Palestinian used his vehicle to ram six Israel Defense Forces soldiers in the West Bank.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H300A2F9AF39441A4B70F6F7E099FCF43"><enum>(170)</enum><text>An attack on November 25, 2015, when a Palestinian stabbed an Israel Defense Forces soldier in the West Bank.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H898B084A4690410CB2485674EA21626C"><enum>(171)</enum><text>An attack on November 24, 2015, when a Palestinian used his vehicle to ram three Israel Defense Forces soldiers and one border police officer in the West Bank.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H52FF92D4F6C044269FAEC17D60819A11"><enum>(172)</enum><text>An attack on November 23, 2015, when two Palestinians stabbed an elderly Palestinian man from Bethlehem near Jerusalem’s Mahane Yehuda market.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE9317D38B08C427790A0F80E595FCFCB"><enum>(173)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An attack on November 23, 2015, when a Palestinian used his vehicle to ram an Israeli near Shavei Shomron.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H046E949016574AB4B358306B2454BFBA"><enum>(174)</enum><text>An attempted attack on November 23, 2015, when a Palestinian attempted to stab Israel Defense soldiers in the West Bank.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H204B410695EB4A589F5948E2F05A413D"><enum>(175)</enum><text>An attack on November 23, 2015, when a Palestinian stabbed and killed an Israel Defense Forces soldier and wounded two others near Modi’in.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5C0BD7122EEC4FC8AAA4A547FB2484E0"><enum>(176)</enum><text>An attempted attack on November 22, 2015, when a Palestinian attempted to stab an Israeli civilian in the West Bank.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H591F265C33AC44FD81CDF45156C2FDDF"><enum>(177)</enum><text>An attempted attack on November 22, 2015, when a Palestinian taxi driver attempted to use his vehicle to ram a group of Israeli pedestrians in Kfar Adumim.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF42FC3E46944443D9D2F129590C3DED5"><enum>(178)</enum><text>An attack on November 22, 2015, when a Palestinian stabbed and killed an Israeli civilian in Gush Etzion.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H49330E8C86494FCCB4CF8A007A421F4C"><enum>(179)</enum><text>An attack on November 21, 2015, when a Palestinian stabbed four people in Kiryat Gat.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE210315220DA4C1DBC0A0708D208562A"><enum>(180)</enum><text>An attack on November 19, 2015, when a Palestinian killed two Israelis and wounded one in a stabbing attack in Tel Aviv.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD5D92331F7FB4CB9B3FE1D257143E40C"><enum>(181)</enum><text>An attack on November 19, 2015, when a Palestinian gunman opened fire and killed three, including one American, sitting in a traffic jam south of Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE46C58877B7B4D57BE27D32F8ED29036"><enum>(182)</enum><text>An attack on November 13, 2015, when a Palestinian gunman opened fire and killed two and wounded four in Otniel.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9258AD9124B34A64B26F2C15E4B7C3B5"><enum>(183)</enum><text>An attack on November 10, 2015, when two Palestinian youth stabbed an Israeli security guard on the Jerusalem light rail.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6F07308735494272A84D6500D58C0888"><enum>(184)</enum><text>An attempted attack on November 10, 2015, when a Palestinian attempted to stab an Israeli police officer outside of Jerusalem’s Old City.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2E0E37CC779348B598AA8552232CC906"><enum>(185)</enum><text>An attempted attack on November 10, 2015, when a Palestinian attempted to stab an Israeli border police officer near Abu Dis.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAB9568F74B8946FB971D79C483049316"><enum>(186)</enum><text>An attempted attack on November 9, 2015, when a Palestinian attempted to stab Israeli police officers in the West Bank.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H36D057BF20EB49128B9D04DEA60D472D"><enum>(187)</enum><text>An attack on November 8, 2015, when a Palestinian used his vehicle to ram four Israelis at a hitchhiking stop at the Tapuah Junction in the West Bank.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8F56296E087A4D17A07C2E5910C82510"><enum>(188)</enum><text>An attack on November 8, 2015, when a Palestinian stabbed an Israeli security guard near Jerusalem.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3AC48807EE9F46A18FE7471403F884BC"><enum>(189)</enum><text>An attack on November 8, 2015, when a Palestinian stabbed an Israeli man in the West Bank.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF50DE16C0F3641FBB9AA2EA0A30BA52D"><enum>(190)</enum><text>An attack on November 6, 2015, when a Palestinian stabbed an Israeli man near Jerusalem.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE9169CF69B6942B5B65A3045F4EB800F"><enum>(191)</enum><text>An attack on November 6, 2015, when two Palestinians opened fire and wounded two Israelis in Hebron.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE91C211FC4E145B6B8F9E526BFE1B8B7"><enum>(192)</enum><text>An attack on November 6, 2015, when a Palestinian opened fire and wounded an Israel Defense Forces soldier near Hebron.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H653D6D260EBB4D809E16E603FB75FDE2"><enum>(193)</enum><text>An attempted attack on November 5, 2015, when a Palestinian attempted to stab an Israeli in Gush Etzion.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H963837CFA6B940E8A6FDA883B9DC1E5E"><enum>(194)</enum><text>An attack on November 4, 2015, when a Palestinian used his vehicle to ram three Israeli border police officers, killing one and wounding two near Hebron.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2DEC953BE15242FCB539B646B918720F"><enum>(195)</enum><text>An attack on November 2, 2015, when a Palestinian stabbed a 71-year-old Israeli man in Netanya.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H25A4303DA2D143898938CCFB637A214D"><enum>(196)</enum><text>An attack on November 2, 2015, when a Palestinian stabbed three Israelis, including an 80-year-old woman, in Tel Aviv.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4171D64C11B34077B030F4DDB18725FF"><enum>(197)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An attempted attack on November 2, 2015, when two Palestinians attempted to stab an Israel Defense Forces soldier in the West Bank.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HADE0DB76B0904FC8B9D48ABD13D1E063"><enum>(198)</enum><text>An attack on November 1, 2015, when a Palestinian used his vehicle to ram three Israel border police officers in Hebron.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2EB3995AABA8482180B829B6DF94ED63"><enum>(199)</enum><text>An attack on October 31, 2015, when a 17-year-old Palestinian attempted to stab Israel Defense Forces soldiers near the Gilboa crossing.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2839C02CBABD42B9B7BD28FE1E764800"><enum>(200)</enum><text>An attack on October 30, 2015, when two Palestinians attempted to stab Israeli border police officers near the Tapuach Junction.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7FC9764FE5744290AF3EC35A9546CDA1"><enum>(201)</enum><text>An attack on October 30, 2015, when an Israeli was stabbed by a Palestinian near the French Hill light rail station in Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA91B9FF6D8934042A6311ED5079FB3D5"><enum>(202)</enum><text>An attack on October 29, 2015, when a Palestinian stabbed an Israel Defense Forces soldier near the Tomb of the Patriarchs in Hebron.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H87DFB6B03DBE4E5697DF200DB23F34E8"><enum>(203)</enum><text>An attempted attack on October 29, 2015, when a Palestinian attempted to stab an Israel Defense Forces soldier in the neighborhood of Beit Hadassah.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H69166BADFB4543B8B62C313D44A0288D"><enum>(204)</enum><text>An attack on October 29, 2015, when shots were fired from a vehicle toward a bus stop near Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9A1208E8C295474AA9FA86B04CCDD081"><enum>(205)</enum><text>An attack on October 28, 2015, when an Israeli woman was stabbed by a Palestinian outside of the Rami Levy supermarket near Gush Etzion.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H428E1991321F4C9C930D3FDD64972C87"><enum>(206)</enum><text>An attempted attack on October 28, 2015, when a Palestinian attempted to stab an Israel Defense Forces soldier near the Tomb of the Patriarchs in Hebron.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB30C96A7F19B49E590135B8882AAC1DD"><enum>(207)</enum><text>An attack on October 27, 2015, when two Palestinians stabbed an Israel Defense Forces soldier near Gush Etzion.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H052205CE724142D591EECC708DD8D801"><enum>(208)</enum><text>An attempted attack on October 27, 2015, when two Palestinian teenagers were apprehended with a knife and an axe in Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H24D46A5FD45649489BE898F7EFA2F480"><enum>(209)</enum><text>An attack on October 26, 2015, when an Israel Defense Forces soldier was stabbed by two Palestinians near Gush Etzion.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9564F94A387F4817BE1E9E5683F2D35D"><enum>(210)</enum><text>An attack on October 26, 2015, when an Israel Defense Forces soldier was stabbed and seriously wounded near Hebron.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD638437309654814BA03B33DE8B92E5F"><enum>(211)</enum><text>An attempted attack on October 26, 2015, when a Palestinian attempted to stab an Israel Defense Forces soldier outside of the Tomb of the Patriarchs in Hebron.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H483EFDD8DCB44553B4DD1822EA98AA91"><enum>(212)</enum><text>An attack on October 25, 2015, when an Israeli man was wounded in a stabbing attack after his car was stoned by Palestinians near Metzad.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDE569B98F189450B97DB2087AF637F3E"><enum>(213)</enum><text>An attempted attack on October 25, 2015, when a 17-year-old female Palestinian attempted to stab an Israel Defense Forces soldier near Hebron.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFAD746B96EF348168C6B585CF52B7738"><enum>(214)</enum><text>An attack on October 25, 2015, when an Israeli man was stabbed near Ariel.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H48E67CB0752847A184B2F109FB2FF2B4"><enum>(215)</enum><text>An attempted attack on October 24, 2015, when a 16-year-old Palestinian posing as a candy vendor attempted to stab a security guard near the Gilboa crossing.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6F15A78FEAFC49A7B64D98E68926AA94"><enum>(216)</enum><text>An attack on October 23, 2015, when an Israel Defense Forces soldier was stabbed in Gush Etzion.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4CB94E03C5324C9D829F3E5167F91638"><enum>(217)</enum><text>An attack on October 23, 2015, when an Israeli couple and their three young children were wounded when a firebomb was thrown at their car near Beit El.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8BBF074CB19F49D3BD542F1E9538E357"><enum>(218)</enum><text>An attempted attack on October 22, 2015, when a student was stabbed and moderately injured while waiting for the bus in Bet Shemesh.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H75CDC91FF1EE45C4BEAA07BA666AE6AC"><enum>(219)</enum><text>An attempted attack on October 22, 2015, when two Palestinian terrorists attempted to board an Israeli school bus to carry out a knife attack in Bet Shemesh.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H736D26630CAD481685B336B683AD7B47"><enum>(220)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An attempted attack on October 21, 2015, when a 15-year-old Palestinian with a knife attempted to attack Israeli security forces in Yitzhar.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2994BC9B5BCC48A2ADFE3B3608D44C9D"><enum>(221)</enum><text>An attack on October 21, 2015, when an Israeli policeman was injured in a car-ramming attack in Ofra.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD66381A372094341866AF3F1F25FCA0C"><enum>(222)</enum><text>An attack on October 21, 2015, when an Israel Defense Forces soldier was critically wounded in a stabbing attack at the Adam Junction near Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H68097949761D494496CC5B8CFB68952B"><enum>(223)</enum><text>An attempted attack on October 21, 2015, when two Palestinians were apprehended by Israeli security forces who found homemade explosive devices in their vehicle.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H638BC8AB667F418F9AEA69A5145C4BFB"><enum>(224)</enum><text>An attack on October 21, 2015, when five Israel Defense Forces soldiers were injured after their vehicle was attacked with stones, and, after exiting the vehicle in order to apprehend the stone-throwers, were rammed by a vehicle near Beit Ummar.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H84FDEB583C484127B9002AB5A11D4A5D"><enum>(225)</enum><text>An attack on October 20, 2015, when an Israeli man was killed after his vehicle was stoned, and, after escaping the vehicle, was struck and run over in a vehicular attack.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCB953675F6514049AD99D6F596BDE2A2"><enum>(226)</enum><text>An attack on October 20, 2015, when an Israel Defense Forces soldier was injured in a stabbing attack in Hebron.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8533F7F33A844DADB3EE7D52A44A06DB"><enum>(227)</enum><text>An attack on October 20, 2015, when two Israelis were wounded in a vehicular attack and attempted stabbing at a bus stop at the Gush Etzion Junction.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF98415E50026455DB71FBE99476F261C"><enum>(228)</enum><text>An attack on October 18, 2015, when an Israel Defense Forces soldier was killed and 10 civilians and police officers wounded after a Palestinian terrorist entered the Central Bus Station of Be’er Sheva and opened fire.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H18E298C872F648A0B2982E9273E290EE"><enum>(229)</enum><text>An attempted attack on October 17, 2015, when a 16-year-old Palestinian attempted to stab Israeli border police officers in Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3A4F9567B909439590F7F73F386DF536"><enum>(230)</enum><text>An attempted attack on October 17, 2015, when a Palestinian attempted to stab an Israeli civilian in Hebron.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H03283596DCEE4D31A334B53BFA28FAD5"><enum>(231)</enum><text>An attack on October 17, 2015, when a 16-year-old Palestinian woman stabbed an Israeli border police officer in Hebron.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFD29493D52B8495CA050F5B0648DFA51"><enum>(232)</enum><text>An attack on October 17, 2015, when a Palestinian stabbed an Israel Defense Forces soldier at a police checkpoint in Hebron.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H31DC41679E2F4C13BC2AE87B8C0E539D"><enum>(233)</enum><text>An attempted attack on October 17, 2015, when a Palestinian attempted to stab an Israeli police officer and bomb squad officer at the Kalandiya Checkpoint near Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H77F252F38F844864A3B98BF203AE49AA"><enum>(234)</enum><text>An attack on October 16, 2015, when Palestinian rioters set fire to Joseph’s Tomb, a Jewish Holy site in Nablus.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA94CD5D71797472581FB260A918910F5"><enum>(235)</enum><text>An attempted attack on October 16, 2015, when Israeli border police detected an explosive device at a checkpoint near Hebrew University’s Campus at Mount Scopus in Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3B1B6700EA154938A2FEF6A374C5DC5A"><enum>(236)</enum><text>An attack on October 16, 2015, when a Palestinian disguised as a photojournalist stabbed an Israel Defense Forces soldier near Hebron.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBBB5FA12CB2F4E75881BE9023DC6D926"><enum>(237)</enum><text>An attempted attack on October 14, 2015, when Israeli border police discovered a knife hidden under the assailant’s seat in Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8665A60B79CF4F33A1DCE0C178D10333"><enum>(238)</enum><text>An attack on October 14, 2015, when a Palestinian stabbed two people by the Damascus Gate in Jerusalem’s Old City.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3E6E66806D404539AEC97C1DFC209645"><enum>(239)</enum><text>An attack on October 14, 2015, when an Israeli woman was stabbed by a Palestinian while waiting for a bus near the Central Bus Station in Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD6814D8F91144A1083BDF9306E28346A"><enum>(240)</enum><text>An attack on October 13, 2015, when an Israeli man was stabbed in the center of Raanana.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3B8DBF572DA14E8291D4F534CB3E7D80"><enum>(241)</enum><text>An attack on October 13, 2015, when four Israelis were wounded in a stabbing attack in Raanana.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8CC325119EFF48728F0C381772538947"><enum>(242)</enum><text>An attack on October 13, 2015, when two Israelis were killed and 15 wounded when two Palestinians boarded a bus and began to attack passengers in Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC37FED9C73B5429CB309D5AB211D94A6"><enum>(243)</enum><text>An attack on October 13, 2015, when an Israeli man was killed and five wounded by a Palestinian in a vehicle attack in Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEE610EA3BF204C6780D4BDBBFC314F29"><enum>(244)</enum><text>An attempted attack on October 12, 2015, when a stabbing attack was foiled outside of the Lion’s Gate in Jerusalem’s Old City.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF449664AADE54CD5AD78CF936ECCDC0E"><enum>(245)</enum><text>An attack on October 12, 2015, when an Israeli border police officer was stabbed by a 16-year-old Palestinian in Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H834A6FCDCFDE4C028D75463761540303"><enum>(246)</enum><text>An attack on October 12, 2015, when two Palestinians stabbed two Israeli civilians, including a 13-year-old Israeli boy riding his bicycle, in Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5C0A3B3854E241459E039EDB413148A0"><enum>(247)</enum><text>An attack on October 12, 2015, when a Palestinian stabbed an Israel Defense Forces soldier on a bus in Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9A489D37C96B4C6890DA859B2E8AB9EC"><enum>(248)</enum><text>An attack on October 11, 2015, when an Israeli police officer was injured after the driver of the car he pulled over set off an explosive device in Ma’ale Adumim.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC8F87EA483C8433F9A1574766F9152B8"><enum>(249)</enum><text>An attack on October 10, 2015, when a 16-year-old Palestinian stabbed two Israelis near the Damascus Gate in Jerusalem’s Old City.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB78BF87260424AC7BAB53787D4ADD2CD"><enum>(250)</enum><text>An attack on October 10, 2015, when a Palestinian stabbed two Israeli police officers near the Damascus Gate in Jerusalem’s Old City.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1B07838B5E6C41E59B7B2991EC6AB103"><enum>(251)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An attack on October 9, 2015, when a 16-year-old Israeli boy was stabbed by a Palestinian in Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAD08B6F3015D43C393F3BA759C3A4F60"><enum>(252)</enum><text>An attack on October 9, 2015, when a Palestinian stabbed a police officer in Kiryat Arba.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H582E55CAC368427289ED8AEBAE6C1AD4"><enum>(253)</enum><text>An attempted attack on October 9, 2015, when a Palestinian attempted to stab an Israeli security guard at the Central Bus Station of Afula.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB67F9ACCEC1F4386AABDB112853CB935"><enum>(254)</enum><text>An attack on October 8, 2015, when an Israel Defense Forces soldier and three others were stabbed by a Palestinian in Tel Aviv.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBEF0B80FDA4743BCB7CBA5B2CBDB7613"><enum>(255)</enum><text>An attack on October 8, 2015, when a Palestinian stabbed an Israeli civilian near the light rail in Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2C5B4ABEB7D149D88EEDC9ACC20CC860"><enum>(256)</enum><text>An attack on October 8, 2015, when a man was stabbed and seriously wounded by a Palestinian in Kiryat Arba.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6B3F543E147346E6950CC9D0F42DD3FE"><enum>(257)</enum><text>An attack on October 8, 2015, when an Israel Defense Forces soldier was wounded in a stabbing attack in Afula.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H62E3ED8FE64B43D0AF7615661B37B81E"><enum>(258)</enum><text>An attack on October 7, 2015, when a Palestinian wounded an Israeli man in a stabbing attack in Petach Tikva.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7445150E17E8408BA11A627497BE884E"><enum>(259)</enum><text>An attack on October 7, 2015, when an 18-year-old Palestinian stabbed an Israeli man near the Lion’s Gate of Jerusalem’s Old City.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB946F402B8154362A1E6F109ED0511E8"><enum>(260)</enum><text>An attack on October 7, 2015, when a Palestinian stabbed an Israel Defense Forces soldier in Kiryat Gat.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5864EA07373844068B0EB011F49F7B9D"><enum>(261)</enum><text>An attack on October 4, 2015, when a 15-year-old Israeli boy was stabbed by a Palestinian in Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H05107E1F554E46F68607DC0FD9A6802A"><enum>(262)</enum><text>An attack on October 3, 2015, when two Israelis were stabbed to death and two others injured by a Palestinian in Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCDD049A00C3C4F6ABF443D3F8CC55C40"><enum>(263)</enum><text>An attack on October 1, 2015, when two Israelis traveling with their four children were killed in a drive-by shooting near Nabulus.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD76FF07C195E43A89371A45EDE62962E"><enum>(264)</enum><text>An attempted attack on September 22, 2015, when a Palestinian attempted to stab an Israel Defense Forces soldier in Hebron.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9739F361F4D648A8A24878DA1D67EEE3"><enum>(265)</enum><text>An attempted attack on September 21, 2015, when an Israel Defense Forces soldier was injured by a firebomb near Joseph’s Tomb.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H144A97DE64AC46299038F35E250C9788"><enum>(266)</enum><text>An attack on September 13, 2015, when an Israeli was killed after his vehicle was struck by rocks near Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD240D64E031B448CA9AA79E1F7E56CB8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Declaration of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress—</text> <paragraph id="HEF9A73820DF44BFD95926630562D197A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">condemns incitement and acts of violence against Israeli citizens;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF2E16BE352A14F088B7959F6DCB556D3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>calls on Palestinian Authority President Mahmoud Abbas to publicly condemn incitement and acts of violence against Israeli citizens and to discontinue incitement in Palestinian Authority-controlled media outlets;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAE91B4C43CCD4D91A3902B0C8CA78F38"><enum>(3)</enum><text>calls on the international community to condemn incitement and acts of violence against Israeli citizens;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2F04DF1C6A0B441AA7881FBA9E6BCE87"><enum>(4)</enum><text>believes that any chance at lasting peace can only happen through peaceful, bilateral, discussions and sound consultation with peaceful allies, not calls for bloodshed;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H45DFCE99C88B427AB2BB340ADDA8047E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>expresses support for individuals and organizations working to encourage cooperation between Israelis and Palestinians, and the many activists within Israel and the Palestinian territories working to bring an end to the conflict; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAA1FAE9AE25D4DE9A7FF102F30356ADE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>reaffirms the friendship between Israel and the United States.</text> </paragraph></section><section commented="no" id="HDEFD152BEF654A039F42FADC58CFE712"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibition on assistance for the Palestinian Authority and the West Bank and Gaza</header> <subsection id="H543350A664FA42E4940F60043A59E0E2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No funds described in subsection (b) may be obligated or expended unless the Secretary of State certifies to Congress that the Palestinian Authority—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H1955894FAF5541259CDF653F78B3262B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is taking credible steps to end terrorist acts against United States and Israeli citizens perpetrated by individuals under its jurisdictional control;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HFCD28A72C08849018C035255386F0A93"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has publicly condemned acts of violence and is taking steps to investigate or is cooperating with investigations of such acts to bring the perpetrators to justice; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H85F1B346DBF445E6BDB4F6928D89536C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>has terminated payments for acts of terrorism against United States and Israeli citizens to any individual who has been imprisoned after being fairly tried and convicted for such acts of terrorism and to any individual who died committing such acts of terrorism, including to a family member of such individuals.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4EF68FA663304F24B2FAB94257A5DDC3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amounts described</header><text>Funds described in this subsection are funds made available under any provision of law for any of the following purposes:</text>
 <paragraph id="HC7C9836919A948449A9633FB1C5C902D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assistance for the Palestinian Authority.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H061952B35089431AB655B5F591EF829A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Assistance for the West Bank and Gaza.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


