<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H7900BE78BBC64F5E9A9953308EF27802" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4141 IH: Selective Service Modernization Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4141</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171026">October 26, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Military Selective Service Act to ensure that the records of persons registered
			 pursuant to that Act are updated to remove persons who are deceased,
			 receiving supplemental security income benefits due to a disability, or
			 otherwise no longer eligible for induction, and to permit the induction of
			 persons who have been convicted of nonviolent offenses, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H08DEEE688D1B4BE6A9055B2D92383AC6" style="OLC">
 <section id="H2C8640735A7A4406BA85BF7CFB9803C8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Selective Service Modernization Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H3E8332B41ECC406287847AA619471712"><enum>2.</enum><header>Military Selective Service Act modernization initiatives</header> <subsection id="H3FD94208BEDD489AB8B90AEF0FEB51F5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Maintenance of registration records</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 10(b)(3) of the Military Selective Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3809">50 U.S.C. 3809(b)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after the first sentence the following new sentence: <quote>The President shall ensure that the records of persons registered under this title are periodically updated to exclude persons who are no longer subject to induction into the Armed Forces of the United States, such as deceased persons and persons receiving supplemental security income benefits under title XVI of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1381">42 U.S.C. 1381</external-xref> et seq.) due to a disability or Federally or State administered supplemental benefits of the type described in section 212(a) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/93/66">Public Law 93–66</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1382">42 U.S.C. 1382</external-xref> note) due to a disability.</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC7E1E6FAC5FB47938E5DF3D938D58883"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Expungement of convictions and sentences commuted of nonviolent offenders</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 6(m) of the Military Selective Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3806">50 U.S.C. 3806(m)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>In the case of the induction of a person convicted of other than a crime of violence (as defined in section 16 of title 18, United States Code), upon the induction of the person, the conviction shall be expunged and the sentence commuted to time served.</quote>.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


