<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H3266D756C470421590A5E80F6614F8BB" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4614 IH: Nuclear Powers America Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4614</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171211">December 11, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001181">Mr. Meehan</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001106">Mr. Costello of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000576">Mr. Ruppersberger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000482">Mr. Michael F. Doyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001286">Mrs. Bustos</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for an investment tax credit related to the
			 production of electricity from nuclear energy.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HAC7906DE6912426BB37898942A3B2817" style="OLC">
 <section id="HFF4F4F7EC7364A52932FF3EDBC05F95D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Nuclear Powers America Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H5E6E1028C8C14BDC8BA1824D94433492"><enum>2.</enum><header>Energy credit for nuclear energy property</header> <subsection id="H7425CBA4D1FA4FA8A703A18993A7FF02"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/48">Section 48(a)(3)(A)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended in clause (vi) by striking <quote>or</quote>, by inserting <quote>or</quote> at the end of clause (vii), and by adding at the end the following new clause:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H086367DAB03843E090869A6E9E3B60F0" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H05D92E7E0AC246AEBCB349076CB1B26E"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>qualified nuclear energy property,</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H968C0936A98745CB964B139200BCE7B3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible for 30-Percent credit</header><text>Section 48(a)(2)(A)(i) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> in subclause (III) and by adding at the end the following new subclause:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H5162C9656CAF4D449AA2722D0ACFA7DD" style="OLC">
 <subclause id="HE27893C0A78A4CF88D653273E851A8C1"><enum>(V)</enum><text>energy property described in paragraph (3)(A)(viii) but only with respect to property placed in service before January 1, 2024, and</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD7099DECE4744D5FB027DB7D845B1D24"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Qualified nuclear energy property</header><text>Section 48(c) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block id="H790DD110DE5E4AC19DB35BB0E8296748" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H40438B53229546E5B51F2F89E4B0D8D7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Qualified nuclear energy property</header> <subparagraph id="HDFB4ADA6AB4A4C03937DDCE1C028D703"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>qualified nuclear energy property</quote> means any amounts paid or incurred for the refueling of, and any other expenditures described in section 263(a) with respect to, a qualifying nuclear power plant.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD06FCA54028F4FE6B110CAA5A713B3B0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Qualifying nuclear power plant</header><text>The term <quote>qualifying nuclear power plant</quote> means a nuclear power plant which—</text> <clause id="HD8375F9EC6CD418D8CCFEC8E51264C0A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>submitted an application for license renewal to the Nuclear Regulatory Commission in accordance with part 54 of title 10, Code of Federal Regulations, before January 1, 2024, or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAA48C1A457A44D89BEE6995FA604D28E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>certified to the Secretary (at such time and in such form and in such manner as the Secretary prescribes) that such plant will submit an application for license renewal to the Nuclear Regulatory Commission in accordance with part 54 of title 10, Code of Federal Regulations, before January 1, 2024.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0DE217A8CA2D410CAAB9068DF8AD0A61"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Special rules</header>
 <clause id="HD0F4948B653F4222AA90A16AA8751818"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Basis</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a), the cumulative amounts paid or incurred by the taxpayer during the taxable year with respect to a qualifying nuclear power plant, which are properly chargeable to capital account, shall be treated as the basis of the qualified nuclear energy property placed in service for that taxable year.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H021BC098B5254ED49CB9AB8B33A42673"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Placed in service</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a), qualified nuclear energy property shall be treated as having been placed in service on the last day of the taxable year in which the taxpayer pays or incurs such amounts described in clause (i).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0C80239A3F784AA4998F6D6F673BB286"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Recapture</header><text>The Secretary shall, by regulations, provide for recapturing the benefit of any credit allowable under subsection (a) to any qualifying nuclear power plant which made a certification pursuant to subparagraph (B) but does not file an application of license renewal to the Nuclear Regulatory Commission in accordance with part 54 of title 10, Code of Federal Regulations, before January 1, 2024.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H11465E53FF7346BBAAB1B1F9B9F40417"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Phaseout of 30-Percent credit rate for nuclear energy property</header><text>Section 48(a) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block id="H066161078DFB40BFBF5D71FE94D53B55" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H62B875C85B68408CA10944CB09E66861"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Phaseout for qualified nuclear energy property</header><text>In the case of qualified nuclear energy property, the energy percentage determined under paragraph (2) shall be equal to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB7BCB80BB6454622B703E49C8603EEED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of any property placed in service after December 31, 2021, and before January 1, 2023, 26 percent, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12C5E47A412043B68EF29D717244AD9E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of any property placed in service after December 31, 2022, and before January 1, 2024, 22 percent.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H67B485C7CBBD4A659E41649F6595CCA9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Coordination with credit for production from advanced nuclear power facilities</header><text>The last sentence of section 48(a)(3) is amended by inserting <quote>or 45J</quote> after <quote>section 45</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H76C23636D8444CAC800BB314833D4F3F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Transfer of credit by certain public entities</header> <paragraph id="H0C5E5B1CA577494D81D3223148D833C0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 48 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
					<quoted-block id="HD62D0DB1178E4075A5DACBC8288C16D0" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="HA4D8A2C68A94402FB009C01F47FEA373"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Special rule for qualified nuclear energy property</header>
 <paragraph id="HB48FDE2FDE3D44008BF2EA07F663DFA7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any qualified nuclear energy property, if, with respect to a credit under subsection (a) for any taxable year—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H76B35D5B9E684069B7F07887A9EC4CA2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the taxpayer would be a qualified public entity, and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E7D0523D176447D91F156A6FB1095B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such entity elects the application of this subsection for such taxable year with respect to all (or any portion specified in such election) of such credit, the eligible project partner specified in such election (and not the qualified public entity) shall be treated as the taxpayer for purposes of this title with respect to such credit (or such portion thereof).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H068481A9DFC64823A634E5B4B6FE9730"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="H9EC60BEBBD0746298463FEAD54447F21"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Qualified public entity</header><text>The term <quote>qualified public entity</quote> means—</text>
 <clause id="HFEC0E67F84544CEF803E7CCBC769EDCC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a Federal, State, or local government entity, or any political subdivision, agency, or instrumentality thereof,</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1F120884B9424F84BBB0FCD2AB524ABD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a mutual or cooperative electric company described in section 501(c)(12) or section 1381(a)(2), or</text> </clause><clause id="HB9BE9AD0A9004B63AE5CB93FFBF01975"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a not-for-profit electric utility which has or had received a loan or loan guarantee under the Rural Electrification Act of 1936.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF976AD9796524D20BDA38DF8F756E930"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligible project partner</header><text>The term <quote>eligible project partner</quote> means—</text> <clause id="HA66F8A7F0BBC499CAAF655B1BCC40490"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any person responsible for operating, maintaining, or repairing the qualifying nuclear power plant to which the credit under subsection (a) relates,</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7FB4F8A884164D65B8D9DEC251AF9EBA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any person who participates in the provision of the nuclear steam supply system to the qualifying nuclear power plant to which the credit under subsection (a) relates,</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7A8E7FEC97EA40719C81E831EF1CAC19"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any person who participates in the provision of nuclear fuel to the qualifying nuclear power plant to which the credit under subsection (a) relates, or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC41D92A5A7344E9CB8204F7C8F85A031"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any person who has an ownership interest in such facility.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H32753786435346098FBED615E5571F91"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Special rules</header> <subparagraph id="H1B5EECCBD1C443568D8F50E36DE6A1D3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Application to partnerships</header><text>In the case of a credit under subsection (a) which is determined with respect to qualified nuclear energy property at the partnership level—</text>
 <clause id="HA8C2D4F6BB1D44169153E94281A079C1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for purposes of paragraph (1)(A), a qualified public entity shall be treated as the taxpayer with respect to such entity’s distributive share of such credit, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0083D354E05A4227843848C8E75A44E8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the term <quote>eligible project partner</quote> shall include any partner of the partnership.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02B8A97DD2D14139B28E2336C34E73DB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Taxable year in which credit taken into account</header><text>In the case of any credit (or portion thereof) with respect to which an election is made under subsection (e), such credit shall be taken into account in the first taxable year of the eligible project partner ending with, or after, the qualified public entity’s taxable year with respect to which the credit was determined.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H700D12EE3AE6440D822B1C405272DF5E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Treatment of transfer under private use rules</header><text>For purposes of section 141(b)(1), any benefit derived by an eligible project partner in connection with an election under this subsection shall not be taken into account as a private business use.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC8546233359A4472AE4F6DF7CD45168A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rule for proceeds of transfers for mutual or cooperative electric companies</header><text>Section 501(c)(12) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block id="HB058F9F2CCD54559825D29E4D3339479" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H6D6CD7E7D88342C9993FCC3B90FA7AC0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>In the case of a mutual or cooperative electric company described in this paragraph or an organization described in section 1381(a)(2), income received or accrued in connection with an election under section 48(e) shall be treated as an amount collected from members for the sole purpose of meeting losses and expenses.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H424F98886F6F4D53B8DDE4816D06847C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 48(a)(2)(A) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>paragraph (6)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (6) and (7)</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HE72367B5AECA49938AEA92AE005BD877"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to periods after December 31, 2016, in taxable years ending after such date, under rules similar to the rules of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/48">section 48(m)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (as in effect on the day before the enactment of the Revenue Reconciliation Act of 1990).</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


