<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE6AA2430E8ED4B17B3AED9376F2E6F66" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3824 IH: Texas Flood Accountability Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3824</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170925">September 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000592">Mr. Poe of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000410">Mr. Gene Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001048">Mr. Culberson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Al Green of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="O000168">Mr. Olson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of the Army to submit to Congress a report with respect to dams,
			 reservoirs, lakes, and other water retention facilities in Texas, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HA674640EF0FB4645886808AFC24D5E41" style="OLC">
 <section id="H20608227AF874632A11D76E9C9829730" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short Title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Texas Flood Accountability Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H0B4E2BD00C1845CDBF052877A5184423"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on Dams, Reservoirs, Lakes, and Other Water Retention Facilities in Texas</header> <subsection id="HA73DAFA5CC224E8F8DD456451A97B740"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, shall submit to Congress and make publicly available a report with respect to covered facilities.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBEBC914B157B422291CE011BE694B594"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="HA36D3CC795364191A3D0554B2499056B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>For each covered facility—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF8624814C7FB487C9E1B2D9C0C9708FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the maximum water capacity that would necessitate an unplanned release of water;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8291CEAD6B78433E8AF7D25F8E82DEEA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the water level at which the facility and each spillway of the facility will overflow; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5AF2CF76BA3946C09D4ED4004B06682F"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">existing plans to notify first responders, local officials, and communities of flood emergencies and the projected water levels during such emergencies.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA64B01C8DFD47C1A747D39CF891AE82"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of steps taken by the Secretary to limit or prevent unplanned releases of water or overflows from covered facilities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8416A0B91BA544A0A37F423B9BA150FB"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommendations of the Secretary for infrastructure improvements and dredging of existing covered facilities needed to limit or prevent unplanned releases of water or overflows from covered facilities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H59893FFA4B554F7B991310A0FB5BF8C5"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Existing plans to coordinate among covered facilities during a flood emergency.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9246F44E9E7645D2AA1C170066B70504"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A list identifying the covered facilities under the jurisdiction of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission that includes, with respect to each such facility, a description of the process for lowering water levels at the facility.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAB995DBA397D406FB296B00D201EA37B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Security Exclusion</header><text>The Secretary may exclude from the report information that the Secretary determines necessary to exclude for national security purposes.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H7070421F658F4028828B77D3EE32FC0D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Information from Non-Federal Entities</header>
 <paragraph id="H33D773A1948D403291844C4D118021EE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement for Non-Federal Entities</header><text>Upon the request of the Secretary, a non-Federal entity that owns, operates, or has jurisdiction over a covered facility shall provide to the Secretary the information described in subsection (b)(1) with respect to that facility.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H31A56A7418EE483E86978F15CFBCA49F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligibility for Federal Financial Assistance</header><text>An entity that fails to comply with paragraph (1) is not eligible for Federal financial assistance otherwise available to the facility owned or operated by or under the jurisdiction of the entity until such time as the entity complies with such paragraph.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H63076ED154834E74A127C9BEF054484D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Paragraph (2) shall apply with respect to Federal financial assistance made available on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD74C2A3E6039470E97F9A18E88C33F43"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Covered Facility Defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>covered facility</quote> means a dam, reservoir, lake, or other water retention facility in Texas.</text> </subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

