<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H8F0DA8C35E9C48DA9DD599492E7B82D7" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2344 IH: Crab Emergency Disaster Assistance Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2344</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170503">May 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To make funds available for fisheries resource disaster assistance for the 2015–16 Dungeness crab
			 and rock crab fisheries disaster, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H271074B84B114FB99680CB58EECC9FBA" style="OLC">
 <section id="HAAEEA4CB37954E7BB1C2641D647BA105" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Crab Emergency Disaster Assistance Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H05B9302D6109454DA331E186068DD1B2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Fishery resource disaster assistance for the 2015–16 dungeness crab and rock crab fisheries disaster</header> <subsection id="HF4465E979FB84CAFB8C13BD3A5D07543"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Disaster assistance</header> <paragraph id="H3845B0126CED4749B415ED5B3C1D2DA2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriation of funds</header><text>In addition to any other funds available for such purpose, there is appropriated to the Secretary of Commerce $117,393,750 to make a lump sum payment to the Pacific States Marine Fisheries Commission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC634F0A0B0ED41FCABC1AEFD156C6987"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Distribution</header><text>The Commission shall distribute such amount among fishing communities, Indian Tribes, small businesses, including fishermen, fish processors, and related businesses, individuals, and other entities, for assistance for the economic and social effects of the fishery resource disaster for the 2015–16 Dungeness crab and rock crab fisheries as determined by the Secretary of the Commerce on January 18, 2017, and to mitigate the economic losses to such communities, Tribes, businesses, individuals, or other entities caused by fishing closures or other restrictions on the harvesting of Dungeness crab or rock crab.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H109C4C1CDA6C4DDAB5D3A1651D196E04"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Amounts appropriated by this subsection shall remain available for the period with respect to which the determination referred to in paragraph (2) is made.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H43D477DB090C4B6CAB1C59CDE150F5A4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Unused funds</header><text>Any amount appropriated by this subsection that is not expended or otherwise obligated for the purpose described in paragraph (1) shall be returned to the Treasury of the United States.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HACB38899F94F4A89BA3C971EADEF88D4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Research</header>
 <paragraph id="H3A0A215FA8504898B394373031C6D06E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriation of funds</header><text>There is appropriated to the Secretary of Commerce—</text> <subparagraph id="HFF9A29E750B04098863670187760A751"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$1,000,000 for West Coast domoic acid sampling and monitoring; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEBF9F189752C437BB64950632F0875FF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$5,000,000 for competitive grants for projects, activities, and research that advance the capacity—</text> <clause id="H571F020FAE8943599563F6D1140FD2A3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to predict the occurrence of harmful algal blooms in the offshore waters of California, Washington, and Oregon; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H27F631A1E1E049D4B0F5D68A43A5E6A9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to evaluate the toxicity of domoic acid bioaccumulation and transmission to humans through the food supply.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E5441DCCB50476B9318E19DD70E20B4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Establishment of grant program</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a grant program with amounts appropriated by paragraph (1)(B) not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3EDF2D7626FB48CC8BEE4DDFC9C14901"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation on administrative expenses</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce may not use more than 4 percent of the amount appropriated under each of subsections (a) and (b) for administrative expenses.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


