<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H5F3CCB35B66E46E99CC6FC123B5CC9EB" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 583 IH: To direct the Federal Communications Commission to revoke certain changes to the ownership reporting requirements for noncommercial educational broadcast stations.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 583</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170117">January 17, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001243">Mrs. Blackburn</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Federal Communications Commission to revoke certain changes to the ownership
			 reporting requirements for noncommercial educational broadcast stations.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H106611E321CE40B0AF157ACFB9A2C0C4" style="OLC">
		<section id="HE67C67CB4D5C4587AA016521A0B293EC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Relief from certain ownership reporting requirements for noncommercial educational broadcast
			 stations</header>
 <subsection id="H2FEB0A6296D44AF59DCAF229571E1519"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, except as provided in subsection (b), the Federal Communications Commission shall take all actions necessary to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H50DD0054C6354A94BE229C4D55956092"><enum>(1)</enum><text>revoke the changes to paragraphs (d), (e), and (f) of section 73.3615 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, and to Schedule 323–E of FCC Form 2100 that were adopted by the Commission on January 8, 2016, in the Report and Order, Second Report and Order, and Order on Reconsideration in the matter of Promoting Diversification of Ownership in the Broadcasting Services (FCC 16–1); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H31B2BBCF03614E6AA88B80DFF7E975FA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>maintain in effect or restore to effect such paragraphs and such Form as in effect immediately before the adoption of such Report and Order.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF74F0A4E360341318CE2696CCD9F283C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Retention of change to filing deadline for biennial reports</header><text>In taking the actions required by subsection (a), the Commission shall retain the filing deadline of December 1 in all odd-numbered years for biennial ownership reports of noncommercial educational broadcast stations, but with information current as of a date not more than 60 days prior to the filing of the report. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to prohibit the Commission from changing such deadline in a rulemaking proceeding that is conducted separately from any proceeding in which the Commission takes the actions required by subsection (a).</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


