<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Placed-on-Calendar-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H0274DA3DE12B4785A6E3D61F881E68D9" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 447 PCS: To extend the deadline for commencement of construction of a hydroelectric project.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<calendar>Calendar No. 137</calendar><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 447</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date>June 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and placed on the calendar</action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To extend the deadline for commencement of construction of a hydroelectric project.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H3823BC580BB8430CBE71DE6FB024CC4C" style="OLC">
		<section id="H04213F082D30481FB51B316C87E2EC35" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Extension</header>
 <subsection id="HF214F2859F3C44D4BD16DDBBC6B053E0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the time period specified in section 13 of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/806">16 U.S.C. 806</external-xref>) that would otherwise apply to the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission project numbered 12740, the Commission may, at the request of the licensee for the project, and after reasonable notice, in accordance with the good faith, due diligence, and public interest requirements of that section and the Commission’s procedures under that section, extend the time period during which the licensee is required to commence the construction of the project for up to 3 consecutive 2-year periods from the date of the expiration of the extension originally issued by the Commission.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC155BB8DAF0C4628929D37EB21B9F79A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reinstatement of expired license</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the period required for commencement of construction of the project described in subsection (a) has expired prior to the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commission may reinstate the license for the project effective as of the date of its expiration and the first extension authorized under subsection (a) shall take effect on the date of such expiration.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20170612">Passed the House of Representatives June 12, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk</role></attestation-group></attestation>
	<endorsement display="yes"><action-date>June 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and placed on the calendar</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill>


