<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE3A6447B45E649E894CF37ABF22D518F" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3471 IH: American Job Creation and Investment Into Public Works Reform Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3471</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170727">July 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend section 203(b)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act to implement new reforms, and to
			 reauthorize the EB–5 Regional Center Program, in order to promote and
			 reform foreign capital investment and job creation in communities in the
			 United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H66A39AFC526740F68D7431AA72DC09C4" style="OLC">
		<section id="H081CFFCF8C1E408BBDEBAB8C4EEE8DF5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="H8FF8218BDEDD42E289BAD7AA14D96803"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Job Creation and Investment Into Public Works Reform Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HFD4D50E2C87E4ED69959113CB0D66EF6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
					<toc-entry idref="H081CFFCF8C1E408BBDEBAB8C4EEE8DF5" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H538605073D264F0098F5D622E1651989" level="section">Sec. 2. New EB–5 general provisions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HB013B0216B414D52A77EBC5F4A48A782" level="section">Sec. 3. Reauthorization and reform of the regional center program.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H610B2F7FFAB642FB887545B2D70467BD" level="section">Sec. 4. Other EB–5 visa reforms.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HDD8CF92BB8F54F6CB42AFCDDE7827940" level="section">Sec. 5. Conditional permanent resident status for alien investors, spouses, and children.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H51268F28B66249999557A1DB4568BBC4" level="section">Sec. 6. Procedure for granting immigrant status.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HBBA37092F88743BEBF58317E82292B27" level="section">Sec. 7. Timely processing.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H964D64686A234679A1B9AE5A7CFFEDDD" level="section">Sec. 8. Transparency.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H405973A1796C4A42B06E4C01A3832E92" level="section">Sec. 9. Reports.</toc-entry>
				</toc>
			</subsection></section><section id="H538605073D264F0098F5D622E1651989"><enum>2.</enum><header>New EB–5 general provisions</header>
 <subsection id="H397F81EFF59A4043A1BE8EB19A93500B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 203(b)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after subparagraph (C) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2E37077DC73C4CDEBFBAA9297E63BF2D" style="OLC">
					<subparagraph commented="no" id="H29FA26BD688343079F26D89DCC29ED10"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Source of funds</header>
 <clause commented="no" id="H789BC16C2F2E423BABB45F0906EF5278"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An alien investor shall demonstrate that the capital required under subparagraph (A) and any funds used to pay administrative costs and fees associated with the alien’s investment were obtained from a lawful source and through lawful means.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H16234906F8EE489B8442DD6BE90DCFBB"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Required information</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall require, as applicable, that an alien investor’s petition under this paragraph contain—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" id="H627C303329224E3CBC035F33A9DE32E8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>business and tax records, or similar records, including, but not limited to—</text> <item commented="no" id="H55BD6140CE774E049BAF572BB0A51747"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>foreign business registration records;</text>
 </item><item commented="no" id="HA605F62965C84B718C52B57CF9E33691"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>to the extent such tax returns have been prepared, corporate or partnership tax returns (or tax returns of any other entity in any form filed in any country or subdivision of such country), and personal tax returns including income, franchise, property (whether real, personal, or intangible), or any other tax returns of any kind, filed within 7 years, with any taxing jurisdiction in or outside the United States by or on behalf of the alien investor; and</text>
 </item><item commented="no" id="H53AF45630E5D43A6ABB027CE056E85CB"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>evidence identifying any other source of capital or administrative fees;</text> </item></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H0ADC8B92964A4FA6822A7A22F2418727"><enum>(II)</enum><text>evidence related to monetary judgments against the alien investor, including certified copies of any judgments, and evidence of all pending governmental civil or criminal actions, governmental administrative proceedings, and any private civil actions (pending or otherwise) involving possible monetary judgments against the alien investor from any court in or outside the United States; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HCEDA905BF10848808D683B8913D29619"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the identity of all persons who transfer into the United States, on behalf of the alien investor—</text> <item commented="no" id="HEDBA35CD80C64A208C05028A8B0DFC75"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>any funds that are used to meet the capital requirement under subparagraph (A); and</text>
 </item><item commented="no" id="H8436CC6A81FB4E599E8943446F6543C3"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>any funds that are used to pay administrative costs and fees associated with the alien’s investment.</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="HD3E9BCFB993344C49CC6ED77DB0AAD2A"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Gift restrictions</header><text>Gifted funds may be counted toward the minimum capital investment requirement under subparagraph (B) only if such funds were gifted to the alien investor by the alien investor’s spouse, parent, son, or daughter (but not children (as defined in section 101(b)(1))), sibling, or grandparent and such funds were gifted in good faith and not to circumvent any limitations imposed on permissible sources of capital under this subparagraph. If a significant portion of the capital invested under subparagraph (A) was gifted to the alien investor, the Secretary shall require the alien investor’s petition under this paragraph to include records described in subclauses (I) and (II) of clause (ii) from the donor.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HCE80D418B77D45838D4BE9C0D20915E9"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Loan restrictions</header><text>Capital derived from indebtedness may be counted toward the minimum capital investment requirement under subparagraph (B) only if such capital is—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" id="H199C30CAB2EE4A46988DE432FBBC713D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>secured by assets owned by the alien investor; and</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HC41D09400EDD4914A99BE9C64BA18DAB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>issued by a banking or lending institution that is properly chartered or licensed under the laws of any State, territory, country, or applicable jurisdiction, and that is not sanctioned or restricted, which the Secretary shall determine after consulting with relevant commercial or government databases, such as those of the Department of the Treasury’s Office of Foreign Assets Control, Office of Terrorist Financing and Financial Crimes, and Financial Crimes Enforcement Network.</text>
							</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE7FB809D93C74849B69F5C8BDF57191C"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Threats to the national interest</header>
 <clause id="H4974DA72346C4BDEA2926B0136371628"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Denial or revocation</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall deny or revoke the approval of a petition, application, or benefit described in this paragraph, including the documents described in clause (ii), if the Secretary determines that the approval of such petition, application, or benefit is contrary to the national interest of the United States for reasons relating to threats to public safety or national security.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA5EBBB4673324CD9B14550C937183D90"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Documents</header><text>The documents described in this clause are—</text> <subclause id="H63E80D336B0C4FDEB2EDCB64E550CDDC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a certification, designation, or amendment to the designation, of a regional center;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA713DDE1838E440790EED229C60D9262"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a petition seeking classification of an alien as an alien investor under this paragraph;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H044D46145BE64CEE9A02C3C63A736503"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a petition to remove conditions under section 216A; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB8C359A1E74E4B03999049D15FC9063E"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an application for approval of a business plan in a new commercial enterprise under subparagraph (I).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HC7EE7474818A4BA0A9C16FDAF0C228D8"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Debarment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a regional center, new commercial enterprise, or job-creating entity has its designation or participation in the program under this paragraph terminated for reasons relating to public safety or national security, any person associated with such regional center, new commercial enterprise, or job-creating entity, including an alien investor, shall be permanently barred from future participation in the program under this paragraph if the Secretary of Homeland Security, in the Secretary’s discretion, determines, by a preponderance of the evidence, that such person was a knowing participant in the conduct that led to the termination.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD7608E9876384817838AD6F383F6F1C5"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>If the Secretary of Homeland Security determines that the approval of a petition, application, or benefit described in this paragraph should be denied or revoked pursuant to clause (i), the Secretary shall—</text>
 <subclause id="HF98F0630951B45C0A40DB703E310EEEA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>notify the relevant individual, regional center, or commercial entity of such determination; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H372FE63CADC04916814ED8EB4FD316CC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>deny or revoke such petition, application, or benefit or terminate the permanent resident status of the alien (and the alien spouse and alien children of such immigrant), as provided in clause (i) as of the date of such determination.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H2976C27B1577418AB1EB5E1A55D748B0"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Judicial review</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law (statutory or nonstatutory), including section 2241 of title 28, United States Code, or any other habeas corpus provision, and sections 1361 and 1651 of such title, no court shall have jurisdiction to review a denial or revocation under this subparagraph. Nothing in this clause may be construed as precluding review of constitutional claims or questions of law raised upon a petition for review filed with an appropriate court of appeals in accordance with section 242.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE3D433F529D942298F10500E504F0C59"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Fraud, misrepresentation, and criminal misuse</header>
 <clause id="H1CD369D3FDFD4278B332CD6F4FAC3613"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Denial or revocation</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall deny or revoke the approval of a petition, application, or benefit described in this paragraph, including the documents described in subparagraph (E)(ii), if the Secretary determines that such petition, application, or benefit was predicated on or involved fraud, deceit, intentional material misrepresentation, or criminal misuse.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7E0C1B3126054D2A93EA898BA46B4DCB"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Debarment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a regional center, new commercial enterprise, or job-creating entity has its designation or participation in the program under subparagraph (H) terminated for reasons relating to fraud, intentional material misrepresentation, or criminal misuse, any person associated with such regional center, new commercial enterprise, or job-creating entity, including an alien investor, shall be permanently barred from future participation in the program under subparagraph (H) if the Secretary of Homeland Security determines, by a preponderance of the evidence, that such person was a knowing participant in the conduct that led to the termination.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAA01360AA2624D0A95E1B90C45F4A7B0"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>If the Secretary of Homeland Security determines that the approval of a petition, application, or benefit described in this paragraph should be denied or revoked pursuant to clause (i), the Secretary shall—</text>
 <subclause id="H0AA85533C45B482C908C87EC458C10D3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>notify the relevant individual, regional center, or commercial entity of such determination; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HE556A65E2241435695BF30E5EBD1E60E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>deny or revoke such petition, application, or benefit or terminate the permanent resident status of the alien (and the alien spouse and alien children of such immigrant) as provided in clause (i) as of the date of such determination.</text>
							</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9AE357B932194B39AA7B59126B5F06A0"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Administrative appellate review</header>
 <clause id="HA6FE7E91F3AE4A6DBADD23F0CB2BF0A3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services shall provide an opportunity for an administrative appellate review by the Administrative Appeals Office of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services of any determination made under this paragraph, including—</text>
 <subclause id="HA0B1C9C7AB664C5DA055C9EFABEB2CF2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an application for regional center designation or regional center amendment;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H07FDE81C23874366BF7E33BA0879A2C3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an application for approval of a business plan under subparagraph (I);</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HF62611AD31504892BB5B5AA4DDBD39A9"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a petition by an alien investor for status as an immigrant under this paragraph;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H1BABF08D470844ADB49371CFDDB3349D"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the termination or suspension of any benefit accorded under this paragraph; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H69369BC8195643AA968B71725833DB7C"><enum>(V)</enum><text>any sanction imposed by the Secretary of Homeland Security pursuant to this paragraph.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H9ED159CA22CF4996B2B6D155D2723CEC"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Judicial review</header><text>Subject to section 242(a)(2), and notwithstanding any other provision of law (statutory or nonstatutory), including section 2241 of title 28, United States Code, or any other habeas corpus provision, and sections 1361 and 1651 of such title, no court shall have jurisdiction to review a determination under this paragraph until the regional center, its associated entities, or the alien investor has exhausted all administrative appeals.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H8E94BDCE8B9B4EAA86EBFACE6D1937AD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective dates</header>
 <paragraph id="H8FD948C8564C4B1A8821B4E66B64C275"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendment made by subsection (a) shall be effective at any time after the date of the enactment of this Act, as determined by the Secretary, and shall be effective not later than 90 days after such date of enactment.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9B1449E4A82644D7BA9C4A3C2F53788C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>Subparagraph (D) of section 203(b)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)</external-xref>), as inserted by subsection (a), shall not apply to a petition that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6D7CFF204B2A4F08BECE06E26E5E28DB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>was filed by an alien investor under such section 203(b)(5) prior to June 1, 2015;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58EEA713C1D04C739781EAA6FBF0AB45"><enum>(B)</enum><text>was filed by an alien investor under such section 203(b)(5) during the period beginning on June 1, 2015, and ending on the date of the enactment of this Act if such beneficiary is investing in the same commercial enterprise concerning the same economic activity as contained in an exemplar filed prior to June 1, 2015, or approved by the Secretary of Homeland Security at any time prior to the date of enactment of this Act, unless the Secretary determines that such approval or filing was based on fraud, misrepresentation in the record of proceeding, or is legally deficient; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD90D7C25622C44A2A2F769B8F244E44B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is filed under section 216A of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1186b">8 U.S.C. 1186b</external-xref>) if the underlying petition filed under section 203(b)(5) of such Act was filed prior to June 1, 2015, or approved before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB013B0216B414D52A77EBC5F4A48A782"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reauthorization and reform of the regional center program</header>
 <subsection id="H1308C67249BE4FC295A2CF1F099C91E9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Repeal</header><text>Section 610 of the Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153</external-xref> note) is repealed.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEA670A34475D474F82F7E20AF1C6C5DE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 203(b)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)</external-xref>), as amended by section 2, is further amended by inserting after subparagraph (G) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF07FAD02E3A34C02B71AA65E32C362BA" style="OLC">
					<subparagraph id="H3ECF47AF57D542FE8B00D9D5A5724F8E"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Regional center program</header>
 <clause id="HF80A981C057F4CC887363ED1B6AF4B4B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Visas under this paragraph shall be made available through September 30, 2022, to qualified immigrants (and the eligible spouses and children of such immigrants) pooling their investments with one or more additional qualified immigrants participating in a program implementing this paragraph that promotes economic growth, including prospective job creation and increased domestic capital investment, through regional centers operating within defined geographic areas and designated by the Secretary of Homeland Security based upon proposals for concentrating pooled investment within such areas.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB9CD2D7940F7460F960427D6B24FFB21"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Processing</header><text>In processing petitions under section 204(a)(1)(H) for classification pursuant to this subparagraph, the Secretary of Homeland Security—</text>
 <subclause id="H1F5D3734D6D1495D857BE0A311DDBA1A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>may process petitions in a manner and order established by the Secretary; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H10FBA9F4D35A461DABFB76B36A1C9242"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall deem such petitions to include records previously filed with the Secretary pursuant to subparagraph (I) if the alien petitioner certifies that such records are incorporated by reference into the alien’s petition.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H6D031EEC041149118E5F9A539F3FBF67"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Establishment of a regional center</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The manager of a prospective regional center shall file a proposal, as provided in clause (i), with the Secretary of Homeland Security requesting that the Secretary designate the regional center for purposes of this subparagraph. A regional center shall operate within a defined and limited geographic area, which shall be described in the proposal and shall be consistent with the purpose of concentrating pooled investment within such area. The proposal shall demonstrate that the pooled investment will have a significant economic impact on such area, and shall include—</text>
 <subclause id="H887EEA9329204E2AB9CF6B6ADB425B72"><enum>(I)</enum><text>reasonable predictions, supported by economically and statistically valid forecasting tools, concerning—</text>
 <item id="HB487B9EC6E1D42259A9843844F32707F"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the amount of investment that will be pooled;</text> </item><item id="HECF54A7A19CF4D2B87845202DC6FFED8"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the kinds of new commercial enterprises that will receive such investments;</text>
 </item><item id="HC177E64D8DCC440698B05AF7DBFC5B0A"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>details of the jobs that will be created directly or indirectly as a result of such investments; and</text>
 </item><item id="HF3B7B985E63D44E29574419D2D2CACC7"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>other positive economic effects such investments will have; and</text> </item></subclause><subclause id="HF05EC646DCE744989AA4301BAFBB6028"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a description of the policies and procedures in place reasonably designed to monitor new commercial enterprises and any affiliated job-creating entity to ensure compliance with—</text>
 <item id="H1B9795C694C9474DB28D2B82CCD9F70F"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>all applicable laws, regulations, and Executive orders of the United States, including immigration laws and securities laws; and</text>
 </item><item id="H36814E7D30F64F428C41B5AF8FE4B5F0"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>all securities laws of each State in which securities offerings will be conducted, investment advice will be rendered, or the offerors or offerees reside.</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause id="H97807729D4834195BBD3082F83FCFE9F"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Indirect job creation</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall permit aliens seeking admission under this subparagraph to satisfy only up to 90 percent of the requirement under subparagraph (A)(ii) with jobs that are estimated to be created indirectly through investment in accordance with this subparagraph. An employee of the new commercial enterprise or job-creating entity may be considered to hold a job that has been directly created.</text>
						</clause><clause id="H33D8F02415724E61BA78EDC3BE9F1721"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Compliance</header>
 <subclause id="H6BA19742E42646649533D22988255F14"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In determining compliance with subparagraph (A)(ii), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall permit aliens seeking admission under this subparagraph to rely on economically and statistically valid methodologies for determining the number of jobs created by the program, including—</text>
 <item id="H9CB3BD46DB054CFF8B0D38F427CECA2E"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>jobs estimated to have been created directly, which may be verified using such methodologies, except that the Secretary may request additional evidence to verify that the directly created jobs satisfy the requirements under subparagraph (A)(ii); and</text>
 </item><item id="H61B9531176F34654A70F0B4A5FEAF998"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>consistent with this subparagraph, jobs estimated to have been created indirectly through revenues generated from increased exports, improved regional productivity, job creation, and increased domestic capital investment resulting from the program.</text>
								</item></subclause><subclause id="HFDF4FDDE5FA74407A7C0BC667587181E"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Job and investment requirements</header>
 <item id="H642CD6F6CB714DBCAB931242831D19FC"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>Relocated jobs</header><text>In determining compliance with the job creation requirement under subparagraph (A)(ii), the Secretary may include jobs estimated to be created under a methodology whereby jobs are attributable to prospective tenants occupying commercial real estate created or improved by capital investments, but only if the number of such jobs estimated to be created has been determined by an economically and statistically valid methodology and such jobs are not existing jobs that have been relocated.</text>
 </item><item id="H827740094696412090E2B672DA53C619"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>Publicly available bonds</header><text>Alien investor capital may not be utilized, by a new commercial enterprise or otherwise, to purchase municipal bonds or any other bonds, if such bonds are available to the general public, either as part of a primary offering or from a secondary market.</text>
 </item><item id="H3B1D21B62E2A4BF0AB9B26F28FD08133"><enum>(cc)</enum><header>Construction activity jobs</header><text>The length of full-time construction activity jobs that last shorter than 24 months may be aggregated to satisfy the employment creation requirement under subparagraph (A)(ii) for alien investors participating in the program described in this subparagraph. A construction activity job may be considered a job that is created directly.</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause id="H1656EE62CEF7441CB70C42802970E059"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Amendments</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall—</text> <subclause id="H08C783F77AF94D8A8530A6E227AE8A13"><enum>(I)</enum><text>require a regional center to give advance notice to, and obtain approval from, the Secretary of significant proposed changes to its organizational structure, ownership, or administration, including the sale of such center or other arrangements in which individuals not previously subject to the requirements under subparagraph (K) become involved with the regional center, before any such proposed changes may take effect unless exigent circumstances are present in which case the regional center shall provide notice to the Secretary within 5 business days of such change;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H57A1B351D5AE40B6BA66D6FC98CC2DAE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>approve the changes referred to in subclause (I) only after—</text> <item id="HB80DDC593F654997B2772C839459B928"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>notice of any such proposed changes are made publicly available through a publicly accessible Web site of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services for a period of not fewer than 30 days; and</text>
 </item><item id="H0C0DEE1565DF4F0BA889ACFACA04C381"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the Secretary determines that the regional center would remain compliant with this subparagraph and with subparagraph (K); and</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H7DB0A5B3B2784DF8A8FD9C8CB66256A4"><enum>(III)</enum><text>notwithstanding the pendency of a request for approval of any amendment that has been filed pursuant to subclause (I), adjudicate business plans under subparagraph (I) and petitions under section 204(a)(1)(H).</text>
							</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF1CF494127D44266BEA0DE83EDA9F9CB"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Business plans for regional center investments</header>
 <clause id="H3BA61A96F15244F5BFCB77E40A4ED3EC"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Application for approval of an investment in a new commercial enterprise</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A regional center shall file an application with the Secretary of Homeland Security for each particular investment offering in or through an associated new commercial enterprise before any alien files a petition for classification under this paragraph by reason of investment in that offering, which shall include—</text>
 <subclause id="HBA48C644D56743A49A78EA3F0011FBF7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a comprehensive business plan for a specific capital investment project;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H680C4ACAF2144F1996E1816CD0D04AD0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a credible economic analysis regarding estimated job creation that is based upon economically and statistically valid methodologies;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H32F359567FBE4D53919D3229FDCDCF32"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any documents filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission under the Securities Act of 1933 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/77a">15 U.S.C. 77a</external-xref> et seq.) or with the securities regulator of any State, as required by law;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HCA4FF30D06544E6F8DC3D0C22A64F77E"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>any investment and offering documents, including subscription, investment, partnership, and operating agreements, private placement memoranda, term sheets, biographies for management, officers, directors, and any individual with similar responsibilities, the description of the business plan to be provided to potential alien investors, and marketing materials used or drafts prepared for use in connection with the offering, which shall contain references, as appropriate, to any—</text>
 <item id="H69D0CCA314704531AE98714CD3826F7D"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">investment risks associated with the new commercial enterprise and the job-creating entity;</text> </item><item id="HAD1CCF221EE645168F22840D2266FB11"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conflicts of interest that currently exist or may arise among the regional center, new commercial enterprise, job-creating entity, or the principals or attorneys of the aforementioned entities;</text>
 </item><item id="H95CC8E21E13B4336B07C24845BFA8B38"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>pending material litigation or bankruptcy, or adverse judgments or bankruptcy orders issued during the most recent 10-year period, in the United States or abroad, affecting the regional center, the new commercial enterprise, any affiliated job-creating entity, or any other enterprise in which any principal of the aforementioned entities held majority ownership at the time; and</text>
								</item><item id="HF6E35FEBF63C4190A5ED6A71B54A4901"><enum>(dd)</enum>
 <subitem commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H850BC37A5B0B48089E7C7AC56F67FC6D"><enum>(AA)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">fees, ongoing interest, or other compensation that has been paid, or will be paid, to any person in connection with the investment, including agents, finders, or broker dealers involved in the offering, and of which the regional center or new commercial enterprise has knowledge;</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="H84DD23B6235944348CDC9768E579CB2C" indent="up1"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>a description of the services performed, or which will be performed, by such person to entitle the person to such fees, interest, or compensation; and</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="H182B3FCED8764DA690364EBDDCB3BB95" indent="up1"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>the name and contact information of any such person;</text> </subitem></item></subclause><subclause id="H40127A8047A843D9939B08C39EA2D2BF"><enum>(V)</enum><text>a description of the policies and procedures, such as those related to internal and external due diligence, reasonably designed to cause the regional center, new commercial enterprise, and any affiliated job-creating entity, their agents, employees, advisors, and attorneys, and any persons in active concert or participation with the regional center, new commercial enterprise, or any affiliated job-creating entity to comply, as applicable, with the securities laws of the United States and the laws of the applicable States in connection with the offer, purchase, or sale of their securities;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H896AB39EB5F349AC92FBCBB00FD745CB"><enum>(VI)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a certification from the regional center and any issuer of securities that is affiliated with the regional center that their respective agents, employees, advisors, and attorneys, and any parties associated with the regional center or the issuer of securities that is affiliated with the regional center, are in compliance with the securities laws of the United States and the laws of the applicable States in connection with the offer, purchase, or sale of its securities, to the best of the certifier’s knowledge, after a due diligence investigation; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H28CFF7FE26824E90B0CA0F0D0F6A8136"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>documentation dem­on­strat­ing that the regional center consulted with a local economic development agency or municipality regarding the capital investment project, which shall address—</text>
 <item id="H1C185E016EF04154A6D5E03E0DDD6439"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the number and type of jobs anticipated to be created; and</text> </item><item id="HD00EF7EA6ACB4808A9BDE1C09428FC7F"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>whether the project is consistent with the agency or municipality’s plan for economic development in the region.</text>
								</item></subclause></clause><clause id="H5EF784A594C84009BD6D3D798AE3E8A1"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Effect of approval of a business plan for an investment in a regional center’s new commercial
 enterprise</header><text>The approval of an application under this subparagraph shall be binding for purposes of the adjudication of subsequent petitions seeking classification under this paragraph by immigrants investing in the same capital investment project through a new commercial enterprise, and of petitions by the same immigrants filed under section 216A, except in the case of fraud, misrepresentation, criminal misuse, a threat to public safety or national security, a material change that affects the program eligibility of the approved economic model, other evidence affecting program eligibility that was not disclosed by the applicant during the adjudication process, or a material mistake of law or fact in the prior adjudication.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5E4607D0FED343C28ECAAF1C0F1079A4"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Site visits</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> <subclause id="H56FE94A2A3F54B8DAB7AA6A4F0404523"><enum>(I)</enum><text>perform site visits to regional centers; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H8E0D17CEF2AA4D4A97BF52E86E720ACE"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">perform at least 1 site visit to each new commercial enterprise and job-creating entity, which—</text> <item id="H0A741635AA2E4A28B4761AA712571BF2"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>shall include a review for evidence of direct job creation in accordance with subparagraph (H)(v)(I); and</text>
 </item><item id="H4C8ADF79476F4ABA9CF3B6C4EB3C2EA9"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may occur at any time during the period between the filing of an application for approval of an investment in a new commercial enterprise under this subparagraph and the adjudication of the first petition for removal of conditions on lawful permanent resident status under section 216A(c) filed by an alien investing in such investment.</text>
								</item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE1F80419CD07473F9CCBCE1FBFE18214"><enum>(J)</enum><header>Regional center annual statements</header>
 <clause id="H0CDFBAEC52754A15A3A56333732A8D2D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each regional center designated under subparagraph (H) shall annually submit a statement to the Director of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services (referred to in this subparagraph as the <quote>Director</quote>), in a manner prescribed by the Secretary of Homeland Security, which shall include—</text>
 <subclause id="H71A1B02B142A4828AD5E3079F18FCEEE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a certification stating that, to the best of the certifier’s knowledge, after a due diligence investigation, the regional center, the new commercial enterprise, and any affiliated job-creating entity, are in compliance with clauses (i) and (ii) of subparagraph (K);</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H8C45DE08DE9546AC981338AB31F9C275"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a certification described in subparagraph (L)(ii)(II);</text> </subclause><subclause id="H7CDC9CB161334A47AB6C3333668C7AC8"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a certification stating that, to the best of the certifier’s knowledge, after a due diligence investigation, the regional center is in compliance with subparagraph (N)(iii);</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB4D5129FBD0A4F5A83D200E1B93499D2"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>a description of any pending material litigation or bankruptcy proceedings, or litigation or bankruptcy proceedings resolved during the preceding fiscal year, involving the regional center, new commercial enterprise, or any affiliated job-creating entity;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H40E522B4BBEB471F805716C594631CE7"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an accounting of all alien investor capital invested pursuant to subparagraph (H) in the regional center, new commercial enterprise, or job-creating entity;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H1F829E3164CA4B01A37B82E393492E98"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>for each new commercial enterprise associated with the regional center—</text> <item id="H86CB1CD3DA7F42A5AD20207CCA0F2470"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an accounting of the aggregate capital invested in the new commercial enterprise and job-creating entity by alien investors under this paragraph for each capital investment project being undertaken by the new commercial enterprise;</text>
 </item><item id="H2920503AC2644A788AB3B48231242464"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>a description of how such capital is being used to execute each capital investment project in the filed business plan or plans;</text>
 </item><item id="H699A7F86A4644F8B8F1E26BDFC68B556"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>evidence that 100 percent of such capital has actually been committed to each capital investment project;</text>
 </item><item id="HBA860D7C89634255A22ABC86F8227B95"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>detailed evidence of the progress made toward the completion of each capital investment project;</text> </item><item id="H6C98CFBB0682479087E8B13F90A5EC88"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>an accounting of the aggregate direct jobs created or preserved;</text>
 </item><item id="H089E5812DEA04546895FE278167A4A19"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>to the best of the regional center’s knowledge, for all fees, including administrative fees, loan monitoring fees, loan management fees, commissions and similar transaction-based compensation, collected from alien investors by the regional center, new commercial enterprise, any affiliated job-creating entity, or issuer of securities associated with the regional center, or any promoter, finder, broker-dealer, or other entity engaged by any of the foregoing to locate alien investors investing pursuant to subparagraph (H)—</text>
 <subitem id="HC9DA50CA9CE7429D8307BAC56CA6BD54"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>a description of all fees collected;</text> </subitem><subitem id="HA5ED8D7FE2784CC18CCC817B36EA5CAF"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>an accounting of the entities that received such fees; and</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="HA03BCDF53A82411893D58380F330563A"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>the purpose for which such fees were collected;</text> </subitem></item><item id="H05E2CF28CDA74FEE88499A0AF38BB19E"><enum>(gg)</enum><text>any documentation referred to in subparagraph (I)(i)(IV), if there has been a material change during the preceding fiscal year; and</text>
 </item><item id="H643879F6F61D4E1FA5A3D15F2BDDC533"><enum>(hh)</enum><text>a certification by the regional center that such statements are accurate, to the best of the certifier’s knowledge, after a due diligence investigation; and</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H83ACCDEBC5C54CDDB92AF0DA7C7F219A"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>a description of the regional center’s policies and procedures that are designed to enable the regional center to comply with applicable Federal labor laws.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HA25E13B37CE04D7DAEBAA2F08FDDE86F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Amendment of annual statements</header><text>The Director—</text> <subclause id="HF859E3646CAD4F008250F17D68D7BB37"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall require the regional center to amend or supplement an annual statement required under clause (i) if the Director determines that such statement is deficient; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE2A6FCF3E022478D8BFCCD0D0EEFD651"><enum>(II)</enum><text>may require the regional center to amend or supplement such annual statement if the Director determines that such an amendment or supplement is appropriate.</text>
							</subclause></clause><clause id="HA4E5F1AB2A234A92A13EB62442A562D8"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Sanctions</header>
 <subclause id="H6BC19AE4149347CBBA34F109A96A3E88"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Effect of violation</header><text>The Director shall sanction any regional center entity in accordance with subclause (II) if the regional center fails to submit an annual statement or if the Director determines that the regional center—</text>
 <item id="H53B122B9E8ED4ECBBDBA7456D1A9BEB6"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>knowingly submitted or caused to be submitted a statement, certification, or any information submitted pursuant to this subparagraph that contained an untrue statement of material fact; or</text>
 </item><item id="HDC84234FEDAB42C1BFEBCA30B36D552E"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>is conducting itself in a manner inconsistent with its designation, including any willful, undisclosed, and material deviation by new commercial enterprises from any filed business plan for such commercial enterprises.</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H3B2E032677624FD083F7642528C118E4"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Authorized sanctions</header><text>The Director shall establish a graduated set of sanctions based on the severity of the violations referred to in subclause (I), including—</text>
 <item id="HB67EE0722702480DB49DD9B92CB17390"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>fines equal to not more than 10 percent of the total capital invested by alien investors in the regional center’s new commercial enterprises or job-creating entities, the payment of which shall not in any circumstance utilize any of such alien investors’ capital investments, and which shall be deposited into the EB–5 Integrity Fund established under subparagraph (M);</text>
 </item><item id="HD43A8564999342E99513AA8C689295FD"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>temporary suspension from participation in the program described in subparagraph (H), which may be lifted by the Director if the individual or entity cures the alleged violation after being provided such an opportunity by the Director;</text>
 </item><item id="HEF4BC0CA6FA1445EB4334E8209DF60E8"><enum>(cc)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">permanent bar from program participation for one or more individuals associated with the regional center or new commercial enterprise or job-creating entity; and</text>
 </item><item id="H8CBF8869AD884DB9A368097A1D315E2D"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>termination of regional center designation.</text> </item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3AB8C75E30A94EA9A17FF9040E233345"><enum>(K)</enum><header>Bona fides of persons involved with regional center program</header> <clause id="H867AD7F851C849349F12BB64280D1E37"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No person shall be permitted to be involved with any regional center, new commercial enterprise, or job-creating entity if—</text>
 <subclause id="HF032FD49D794493E80E69F3429F4FEA4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the person has been found to have committed—</text> <item id="H8AF59CC6DBCF47EC994D99C2EBFCA10E"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>a criminal or civil violation involving fraud or deceit within the previous 10 years;</text>
 </item><item id="HFC160EFEB54D430FAB273FB881368DCD"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>a civil violation resulting in a liability in excess of $1,000,000 involving fraud or deceit; or</text> </item><item id="H09DF9869FF0E49E49BC9FD6434DADA93"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>a crime resulting in a conviction with a term of imprisonment of more than 1 year;</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H8BCDAB662FF649EB9E6FC9378C949443"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the person is subject to a final order, for the duration of any penalty imposed by such order, of a State securities commission (or an agency or officer of a State who performs similar functions), a State authority that supervises or examines banks, savings associations, or credit unions, a State insurance commission (or an agency of or officer of a State who performs similar functions), an appropriate Federal banking agency, the Commodity Futures Trading Commission, the Securities and Exchange Commission, a financial self-regulatory organization recognized by the Securities and Exchange Commission, or the National Credit Union Administration, which is based on a violation of any law or regulation that—</text>
 <item id="H60BCA65C37F54CA1A8918C8CAC86D55F"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>prohibits fraudulent, manipulative, or deceptive conduct; or</text> </item><item id="HB4719F0811B342C29C3A9DCBF017F6E2"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>bars the person from—</text>
 <subitem id="H71F04580F56F4343A1A6EFB486A50DA3"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>association with an entity regulated by such commission, authority, agency, or officer;</text> </subitem><subitem id="H109C9B38ADBD401D8EAD3E9CD1F544DB"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>appearing before such commission, authority, agency, or officer;</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="H39BD2687C331490FAD8391BE6AF8D9F1"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>engaging in the business of securities, insurance, or banking; or</text> </subitem><subitem id="H41A62D6BD8814B85837C9C862C3B5192"><enum>(DD)</enum><text>engaging in savings association or credit union activities;</text>
 </subitem></item></subclause><subclause id="H3216FBBE48C94378A6F0E875F7DF9D50"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the person is engaged in, has ever been engaged in, or seeks to engage in—</text> <item id="HD5C9C4D4CE92409D87145F58FA682577"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>any illicit trafficking in any controlled substance or in any listed chemical (as defined in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act);</text>
 </item><item id="H1F2F7A625200422190EDDD1B66C5AD6B"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>any activity relating to espionage, sabotage, or theft of intellectual property;</text> </item><item id="HCB9EDE3A7DD1443C992C3B168085CCDB"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>any activity related to money laundering (as described in section 1956 or 1957 of title 18, United States Code);</text>
 </item><item id="H3C57A8ADC2A14B188358EE0D837F7ABC"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>any terrorist activity (as defined in section 212(a)(3)(B));</text> </item><item id="H9F4DE4DC15F24ED7B40CDB4D8992889F"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>any activity constituting or facilitating human trafficking or a human rights offense;</text>
 </item><item id="HF4C09AAA828D486380B0DDC490B38DCC"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>any activity described in section 212(a)(3)(E); or</text> </item><item id="HE70C9754BD2A4C8494B4072FCBAE6AF2"><enum>(gg)</enum><text>the violation of any statute, regulation, or Executive order regarding foreign financial transactions or foreign asset control; or</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H3E6074BFA2F5405F8C12F024C5BB9FD7"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the person—</text> <item id="H0DCCB8173E9E40F6B265B4DD3D5C433E"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>is, or during the preceding 10 years has been, included on the Department of Justice’s List of Currently Disciplined Practitioners; or</text>
 </item><item id="H5AA7A53D1E6D4ED7AD6378CC3042063F"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>during the preceding 10 years has received a reprimand or otherwise been publicly disciplined for conduct related to fraud or deceit by a State bar association of which the person is or was a member.</text>
								</item></subclause></clause><clause id="H71D9D23790C4480CA644B2D18BECF4A0"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Foreign involvement in regional center program</header>
 <subclause id="HEF27733B72AD4036B4A0FDC56177E72E"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Lawful status required</header><text>No person may be involved with a regional center unless the person is a national of the United States or an individual who has been lawfully admitted for permanent residence (as defined in paragraphs (20) and (22) of section 101(a)).</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA163CBF4EED74D92A75DF06428C8458A"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Foreign governments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No foreign government entity may provide capital to, or be directly or indirectly involved with the ownership or administration of, a regional center, a new commercial enterprise, or a job-creating entity.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H89EB021527184EA294247E27B2515E8F"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Information required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall require such attestations and information, including the submission of fingerprints or other biometrics to the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and shall perform such criminal record checks and other background and database checks with respect to a regional center, new commercial enterprise, and any affiliated job-creating entity, and persons involved with such entities (as described in clause (v)), in order to determine whether such entities are in compliance with clauses (i) and (ii). The Secretary may require the information and attestations described in this clause from such entities, and any person involved with such entities, at any time on or after the date of the enactment of the American Job Creation and Investment Into Public Works Reform Act of 2017 and may perform such checks with respect to any job creating entity, and persons involved with such entity.</text>
						</clause><clause id="HCEC564E3E163405B902896C240D09FC8"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Termination</header>
 <subclause id="H7AF8898D35D04FED969871220CB4FA4D"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall suspend or terminate the designation of any regional center, or the participation under the program of any new commercial enterprise or job-creating entity under this paragraph if the Secretary determines that such entity—</text>
 <item id="H67EBCE413AD3413D8812B01B586D4D69"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>knowingly involved a person with such entity in violation of clause (i) or (ii);</text> </item><item id="H0F03F2051C5F45D3916736B8D3399EFB"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>failed to provide an attestation or information requested by the Secretary; or</text>
 </item><item id="H3A78EFF70D16479FA29C65AAA65EEC17"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>knowingly provided any false attestation or information under clause (iii).</text> </item></subclause><subclause id="H9F6EC339752D45E5AA1EBB00C4F15070"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, after the performance of the criminal record and other background checks described in clause (iii), shall notify a regional center, new commercial enterprise, or job-creating entity whether any person involved with such entities is not in compliance with clause (i) or (ii). If, 30 days after receiving such notification, the regional center, new commercial enterprise, or job-creating entity, as the case may be, fails to discontinue the prohibited person’s involvement with the regional center, new commercial enterprise, or job-creating entity, as applicable, the regional center, new commercial enterprise, or job-creating entity shall be deemed to have knowledge under subclause (I)(aa) that such person is in violation of clause (i) or (ii).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HF8223EE2190A4DDFAFF5B19178D9B025"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Persons involved with a regional center, new commercial enterprise, or job-creating entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of this subparagraph, a person is considered to be <quote>involved</quote> with a regional center, a new commercial enterprise, any affiliated job-creating entity, or other job-creating entity, as applicable, if he or she is, directly or indirectly, an owner or in a position of substantive authority to make operational or managerial decisions over pooling, securitization, investment, release, acceptance, or control of any funding that was procured pursuant to subparagraph (H). An individual may be in a position of substantive authority if he or she serves as a principal, representative, administrator, owner, officer, board member, manager, executive, general partner, fiduciary, or in a similar position at the regional center, new commercial enterprise, any affiliated job-creating entity, or other job-creating entity, respectively.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAB503366CCE54C1EB317857ED06DE35B"><enum>(L)</enum><header>Compliance with securities laws</header>
						<clause id="H28AB7F51BCEB470985E199D5CBA4206B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Jurisdiction</header>
 <subclause id="H1E8DC0461E8A423DB726C11CFC197ADC"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The United States has jurisdiction over the purchase or sale of any security offered or sold by any regional center or any party associated with a regional center for purposes of the securities laws. Subject matter jurisdiction shall also lie within the United States.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HEB290D0713934E359FE64DE603B2AEE3"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Compliance with regulations</header><text>Solely for purposes of section 5 of the Securities Act of 1933 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/77e">15 U.S.C. 77e</external-xref>), a regional center or any party associated with a regional center is not precluded from offering or selling a security pursuant to Regulation S under the Securities Act of 1933 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/77a">15 U.S.C. 77a</external-xref> et seq.) to the extent that such offering or selling otherwise complies with that regulation.</text>
							</subclause></clause><clause id="HC77019ABF824422AA77AE825C0D191E2"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Regional center certifications required</header>
 <subclause id="HBB9A377653394EB69E9719AD1528566C"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Initial certification</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security may not approve an application for regional center designation or regional center amendment unless the regional center certifies that, to the best of the certifier’s knowledge, after a due diligence investigation, the regional center is in compliance with and has policies and procedures, such as those related to internal and external due diligence, reasonably designed to confirm, as applicable, that all parties associated with the regional center are and will remain in compliance with the securities laws of the United States and of any State in which the offer, purchase, or sale of securities was conducted, or the issuer of securities was located, or the investment advice was provided by the regional center or parties associated with the regional center.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H83193ABA381549B99066A11290FB8B83"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Reissue</header><text>A regional center shall annually reissue a certification described in subclause (I) in accordance with subparagraph (J). Annual certifications under this subclause shall also certify compliance with clause (iii) by stating that—</text>
 <item id="H7496BE8D39944FBDA6387F7541E5363D"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the certifier is in a position to have knowledge of the offers, purchases, and sales of securities or the provision of investment advice by parties associated with the regional center;</text>
 </item><item id="HCA3A8B26E70B4B338B440BEDA30103A2"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>to the best of the certifier’s knowledge, after a due diligence investigation, all such offers, purchases, and sales of securities or the provision of investment advice complied with the securities laws of the United States and the securities laws of any State in which the offer, purchase, or sale of securities was conducted, or the issuer of securities was located, or the investment advice was provided; and</text>
 </item><item id="H7A21820D6B2E4099978F2B0FE5CFE07B"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>records, data, and information related to such offers, purchases, and sales have been maintained.</text> </item></subclause><subclause id="H4406DE3C3C304D33B7ED5385839189A6"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Effect of noncompliance</header><text>If a regional center, through its due diligence, discovered during a previous fiscal year that the regional center or any party associated with the regional center was not in compliance with the securities laws of the United States or the securities laws of any State in which the securities activities were conducted by any party associated with the regional center, the certifier shall—</text>
 <item id="H74EFBA01411F42E190A52530A95B7B61"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>describe the activities that led to noncompliance;</text> </item><item id="H02432B42ACBC427E88BF53CA775C15AB"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>describe the actions taken to remedy the noncompliance; and</text>
 </item><item id="H4AD10B125F6B4BEAA3C7D14B0EC502E2"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>certify that the regional center and all parties associated with the regional center are currently in compliance, to the best of the certifier’s knowledge, after a due diligence investigation.</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause id="HA9E87B595283439A8E5566F35D7C26C5"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Oversight required</header><text>Each regional center shall monitor and supervise all offers, purchases, and sales of, and investment advice relating to securities made by parties associated with the regional center to confirm compliance with the securities laws of the United States, and maintain records, data, and information relating to all such offers, purchases, sales, and investment advice during the 5-year period beginning on the date of their creation. Such records, data, and information shall be made available to the Secretary upon request.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H38E9B35D20364EB28428CDC2FD9C8681"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Suspension or termination</header><text>In addition to any other authority provided to the Secretary under this paragraph, the Secretary, in the Secretary’s discretion, may suspend or terminate the designation of any regional center, or impose other sanctions against the regional center, if—</text>
 <subclause id="H76BAC967B78B49A881158D9662D2E219"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the regional center is permanently or temporarily enjoined by order, judgment, or decree of any court of competent jurisdiction in connection with the offer, purchase, or sale of a security or the provision of investment advice, or any party associated with the regional center is so enjoined and the regional center knew, or reasonably should have known, that this is the case;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HBE1115000F54481C95648BEFB5F52DEF"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the regional center is subject to any final order of the Securities and Exchange Commission or a State securities regulator, or any party associated with the regional center is subject to such an order and the regional center knew, or reasonably should have known, that this is the case, if the order—</text>
 <item id="HA687F65787624E2294987597631D0787"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>bars such person from association with an entity regulated by the Securities and Exchange Commission or a State securities regulator; or</text>
 </item><item id="H185CAE731F544E6CB07A8D916164E707"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>constitutes a final order based on a finding of an intentional violation or a violation related to fraud or deceit in connection with the offer, purchase, or sale of, or investment advice relating to, a security; or</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="HDDD390A942F04064B47CBBD8CB8944D2"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the regional center submitted or caused to be submitted a certification described in clause (ii) that contained an untrue statement of a material fact or omitted to state a material fact necessary in order to make the statements made, in light of the circumstances under which they were made, not misleading, or any party associated with the regional center undertook such an action and the regional center knew, or reasonably should have known, that this is the case.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H41F61B0EE2784A14A03D6FF6AC3C5D73"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text>Nothing in this subparagraph may be construed to impair or limit the authority of the Securities and Exchange Commission under the Federal securities laws or any State securities regulator under State securities laws.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H48846010C14F4AA6A4A0B688DDDC11B4"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Defined term</header><text>In this subparagraph, the term <quote>party associated with a regional center</quote> means—</text> <subclause id="HF15901A0B5F04551A1ABB9E0FBF037A5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the regional center;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA4B7D8814B484D78AE79A7C5EAE3B415"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any new commercial enterprise or affiliated job-creating entity or issuer of securities associated with the regional center;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HF1E2A8C3A71A4A27977997A6277CE0F6"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the regional center’s and new commercial enterprise’s owners, officers, directors, managers, partners, agents, employees, promoters and attorneys; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H30D03F9B53CE4485ACF687B737A06332"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>any person in active concert or participation with the regional center or directly or indirectly controlling, controlled by, or under common control with the regional center.</text>
							</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE1BF5A3B3C79495F841CDE3998B90D12"><enum>(M)</enum><header>EB–5 integrity fund</header>
 <clause id="H9C3C8ACE900F4AE4BDE82BE95A451168"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the United States Treasury a special fund, which shall be known as the <quote>EB–5 Integrity Fund</quote> (referred to in this subparagraph as the <quote>Fund</quote>). Amounts deposited into the Fund shall be available to the Secretary of Homeland Security until expended for the purposes set forth in clause (iii).</text>
						</clause><clause id="HC3AE9F80DD1F4D4D97AB4E9B506A1315"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Fees</header>
 <subclause id="HF27CF325D53B40AD847CE50E15C93CEB"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Annual fee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on January 1, 2017, and each year thereafter, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall collect a fee of $25,000 for the Fund from each regional center designated under subparagraph (H). The fee shall be $10,000 if a regional center has 20 or fewer alien investors investing pursuant to subparagraph (H) in the immediately preceding fiscal year in its new commercial enterprises.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HDD9E585F7E5846E984716717E6771D40"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Petition fee</header><text>Beginning on October 1, 2016, the Secretary shall collect a fee of $2,000 for the Fund with each petition filed pursuant to section 204(a)(1)(H) for classification under this paragraph pursuant to subparagraph (H).</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H39980DC0672D4DEDABAF95B6269ED4A9"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Increases</header><text>The Secretary may prescribe regulations, as necessary, to increase the dollar amounts under this clause to ensure the Secretary’s continued ability to carry out the activities specified in clause (iii).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H26206612B28B4E239958B96DBCCD572C"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Permissible uses of fund</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> <subclause id="H17F14A0DFDB947DBAE19323045F9F7A3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>use not less than <fraction>1/3</fraction> of the amounts deposited into the Fund to conduct audits and site visits (with or without notice);</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA4102F1049FD45ECBC1BFE630C22D20E"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use not less than <fraction>1/3</fraction> of the amounts deposited into the Fund for investigations based outside of the United States, including—</text>
 <item id="H65A35223517245DC80A7C7E4D534D38C"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>monitoring and investigating program-related events and promotional activities; and</text> </item><item id="HF97AA1AEA6ED45B8B165667191F564D8"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>ensuring an alien investor’s compliance with subparagraph (D);</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="HD9344E4F22A8446C8FECDEACF6F80578"><enum>(III)</enum><text>use amounts deposited into the Fund—</text> <item id="H32255D8CF4AD44E0A9F04BA5B35DAB21"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>to detect and investigate fraud or other crimes; and</text>
 </item><item id="HA68262C5C97D4B44AA0C2BAE523E464A"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>to determine whether regional centers, new commercial enterprises, any affiliated job-creating entities, and alien investors (and their alien spouses and alien children, if any) comply with applicable immigration laws;</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H60A167E8BA2F4EB1B83A80EC7F1F17A8"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>use amounts deposited into the Fund to conduct interviews of the owners, officers, directors, managers, partners, agents, employees, promoters, and attorneys of regional centers, new commercial enterprises, and job-creating entities; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H44375AFB601D41C3ACC535A384B09B63"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">otherwise use amounts deposited into the Fund as the Secretary determines to be necessary, including monitoring compliance with the requirements under section 8 of the American Job Creation and Investment Into Public Works Reform Act of 2017.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H696FFE9AEFA443E1B30B8792835827A0"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Failure to pay fee</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall—</text> <subclause id="HDCC76A3E8E3B445FAD941F48BFDEFB36"><enum>(I)</enum><text>impose a reasonable penalty, which shall be deposited into the Fund, if a regional center does not pay the fee required under clause (ii)(I) within 30 days of the date on which such clause requires the Secretary to collect the fee; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H058A7ECBD9CD497B96F625A9A6D57A54"><enum>(II)</enum><text>terminate the designation of any regional center that does not pay the fee required under clause (ii)(I) within 90 days of the date on which such clause requires the Secretary to collect the fee.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H5269D12FE8924977878C3CD08EB9C9AE"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall submit an annual report to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives that describes how amounts in the Fund were expended during the immediately preceding fiscal year.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2B3FC96CC2264D50BD8E6A48A24437E4"><enum>(N)</enum><header>Direct and third-party promoters</header>
 <clause id="HF06B8D575029467A9274E9AD41F64A2B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Rules and standards</header><text>Direct and third-party promoters of a regional center, any new commercial enterprise, an affiliated job-creating entity, or issuer of securities affiliated with the regional center shall comply with the rules and standards prescribed by the Secretary of Homeland Security and any applicable Federal or State securities laws, to oversee regional center promotion, including—</text>
 <subclause id="H27E5EB80E93842C89B13EAF83B8FCC7E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>registration with U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services, which—</text> <item id="HEC88FACDEB8F4FEA974FFCE826262AAA"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>may be limited to identifying and contact information of such promoter and confirmation of the existence of the written agreement required by clause (iii); and</text>
 </item><item id="HACFF017DAD1A4D069F9BE69923270681"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>shall not include any requirement that U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services approve the registration of such promoter;</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="HBA232DA49963427BB772C1ED4701AE77"><enum>(II)</enum><text>minimum qualifications;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H10009F38C3754CDF98691DE71D1B07AE"><enum>(III)</enum><text>guidelines for offering investment opportunities and representing the visa process to prospective investors under the program established under subparagraph (H); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA8352409FA9647EDA75403A5C9E405C6"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>permissible fee arrangements.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HA6FE46CD12C845E3A70801136E81DE5C"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Effect of violation</header><text>If the Secretary determines that a direct or third-party promoter has violated clause (i), the Secretary shall suspend or permanently bar such individual from participation in the program described in this paragraph.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA2BE5B2E09A247A08EC8340B201917B1"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Compliance</header><text>Each regional center shall maintain a written agreement between the regional center, the new commercial enterprise, any affiliated job-creating entity, or any issuer of securities affiliated with the regional center, and each direct or third-party promoter operating on behalf of such entities or issuer that outlines the rules and standards prescribed under clause (i).</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBBB572959E2C416DA1EEC24FA9AF5D8F"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Disclosure</header><text>Each petition filed pursuant to section 204(a)(1)(H) for classification under this paragraph pursuant to subparagraph (H) shall include a disclosure, signed by the alien investor, that reflects all fees, ongoing interest, and other compensation paid to any person that the regional center or new commercial enterprise knows has received, or will receive, in connection with the investment, including compensation to agents, finders, or broker dealers involved in the offering, to the extent not already specifically identified in the business plan filed under subparagraph (I).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8AA9F2F0114D40A5882615F37232925C"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The list of such registered promoters may be made publicly available by the Secretary.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCC281D136CED4E3FB25319D6729771B7"><enum>(O)</enum><header>Treatment of good faith investors following program noncompliance</header> <clause id="H1952EE61EB0A40338BBEB8D23A47C608"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Termination or debarment of EB–5 entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in clause (v), upon the termination or debarment, as applicable, from the program under this paragraph of a regional center, new commercial enterprise, or job-creating entity, an otherwise qualified petition under section 204(a)(1)(H) or the conditional permanent residence of an alien who has been admitted to the United States pursuant to section 216A(a)(1) based on an investment in a terminated regional center, new commercial enterprise, or job-creating entity shall remain valid or continue to be authorized, as applicable, consistent with this subparagraph.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC54F276C760445FDA36B0F2EDB09BC92"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>New regional center or investment</header><text>The petition under section 204(a)(1)(H) of an alien described in clause (i) and the conditional permanent resident status of an alien described in clause (i) shall be terminated 180 days after the termination from the program under this paragraph of a regional center, a new commercial enterprise, or a job creating entity unless—</text>
 <subclause id="H9B9A694CD95C46E68A12F61ACBB37D07"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the case of the termination of a regional center—</text> <item id="H6DF8FB7802F84552B447C3D78718D101"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the new commercial enterprise associates with an approved regional center;</text>
 </item><item id="H19F8BFF3D9E14F04958F1A3DAB267F76"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such alien makes a qualifying investment in another new commercial enterprise associated with an approved regional center; or</text>
 </item><item id="H1CA648127C664BAFB549DB2EF8DB5D21"><enum>(cc)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such alien makes a qualifying investment in another new commercial enterprise under this paragraph not associated with a regional center; or</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="HA16B57F6A80D495D9CDAB0D847DE4F32"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of the debarment of a new commercial enterprise or job-creating entity, such alien invests in another new commercial enterprise associated with an approved regional center.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HEDEAC9E1765940B0954B40B122BAE5C0"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Removal of conditions</header><text>Aliens described in subclause (I)(bb), (I)(cc), or (II) of clause (ii) shall be eligible to have their conditions removed pursuant to section 216A beginning on the date that is 2 years after the date of the subsequent investment.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9CF60A14041641F19AFE791AD231DD1F"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>In case of enforcement action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in clause (v), if the Secretary, the Attorney General, or the Securities and Exchange Commission files a criminal or civil enforcement action in any United States District Court containing allegations that a regional center, new commercial enterprise, job-creating entity, or any person involved with the foregoing entities, committed fraud which affected an alien’s investment capital under subparagraph (A), or if a State authority or agency files such an action in a State court—</text>
 <subclause id="H1065ABCC40C24F4880F92ECF03836BF8"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for all related petitions for classification under this paragraph and petitions for removal of conditions described in section 216A—</text>
 <item id="H6A812D64AFFA43EFB31074A74328E10B"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary may hold such petitions in abeyance unless ordered to take action by the United States District Court overseeing such action, if applicable; and</text>
 </item><item id="H4944F68BD14F4871978C8BF9286C69A4"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States District Court overseeing such action, if applicable, may enter an order extending any deadlines applicable under this paragraph and to prevent age-out of derivative beneficiaries;</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H0C0B0C88A1484FB5B702E45A1A38C887"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the alien investor may—</text> <item id="H7A5F91C894D046A28172F9D1BC58C665"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">petition to amend the alien’s underlying petition for classification under this paragraph or the petition for removal of conditions described in section 216A(c) without such facts underlying the amendment being deemed a material change; and</text>
 </item><item id="H29382A34EC3C456F8D81073206E9AB52"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">retain the immigrant visa priority date related to the original petition; and</text> </item></subclause><subclause id="H5D759D75D1AC47C48D29D816405CAA4B"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any funds obtained or recovered by an alien investor, directly or indirectly, from claims against third parties, including insurance proceeds, or any additional investment capital provided by the alien after the enforcement action described in this clause is filed, may be deemed to be such alien’s investment capital for the purposes of subparagraph (A) if such investment otherwise complies with the requirements of this paragraph and section 216A.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H043A62F33CB94E95971C9E7E56C777EE"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary has reason to believe an alien was a knowing participant in the conduct that led to the termination of a regional center, new commercial enterprise, or job-creating entity, as described in clause (i), or was a knowing participant in the alleged wrongdoing that led to an enforcement action described in clause (iv)—</text>
 <subclause id="H950F1531092D4F1A91DD3D3FCB6912EB"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the alien shall not be accorded any benefit under this subparagraph; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H38FC7D15110447378C2CEB3B3DBD5843"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary shall notify the alien of such belief and, subject to section 216A(b)(2), shall deny or initiate proceedings to revoke the approval of such alien’s petition, application, or benefit (and that of any spouse or child, if applicable) described in this paragraph.</text>
							</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE853364EB8C74267B4DF95878785AA34"><enum>(P)</enum><header>Account transparency requirement</header>
 <clause id="HFB50EAAEF81C467D9674909BF421F19A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (iii), a new commercial enterprise shall deposit and maintain the capital investment of each alien investor in a separate account as described in this subparagraph, including funds held in escrow.</text>
						</clause><clause id="HD574774B1D914F87BA623FD2E1713879"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Requirements for Separate Accounts</header>
 <subclause id="H66CBC42FBCF441A383D32FE94CAF6F37"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Required information</header><text>Prior to, or within one business day of, the deposit of an alien investor’s capital investment in a separate account, the new commercial enterprise shall provide the following information to the alien investor whose capital investment will be or has been deposited into the separate account, the regional center associated with the new commercial enterprise, and the Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services:</text>
 <item id="HFA3466C238BA4EFB97B2706C2F8F013C"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>The name, address, and other contact information of the bank or other financial institution where the separate account is or will be maintained and the name of the authorized signatory required under subclause (II).</text>
 </item><item id="H8C190935BFEB4DB09C1DB51EF354789F"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>Sufficient information to enable the alien investor whose capital investment will be or has been deposited into the separate account, the regional center associated with the new commercial enterprise, and the Director to view online the balance in the separate account on an ongoing basis.</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="HB7DC9034C7CE42FD9094CC1970B949CC"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Authorized signatories</header><text>At least one of the authorized signatories to the separate account shall be an individual who is—</text> <item id="H01093727984C4E73B360C8D2D2536CB0"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>independent of, and not directly or indirectly related to, the new commercial enterprise, the regional center associated with the new commercial enterprise, the job creating entity, or any of the principals or managers of such entities; and</text>
 </item><item id="HBC968508CCCE4DA0BEA802FCE30580E4"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an officer at the bank or other financial institution where the separate account is maintained; licensed, active, and in good standing as an attorney, certified public accountant, or broker-dealer; or otherwise authorized by the Director to serve as a signatory.</text>
								</item></subclause></clause><clause id="H618217036ADF435B88833FB13B398183"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Transfers from a separate account</header>
 <subclause id="HF64D3F45114743459E7B79D676D18964"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The funds in a separate account may be transferred only—</text> <item id="HBA8C239F7595484EBF9ED7AF6AC311C5"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>to the alien investor who contributed the funds held in the separate account as a refund of that investor’s capital investment if otherwise permitted under this paragraph, to another separate account, or to a job creating entity or otherwise deployed into the capital investment project for which the funds were intended; and</text>
 </item><item id="H068D5E8750F948FFB4C7365B03DD7F3E"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>after at least one of the authorized signatories described in clause (ii)(II) has provided written consent for the proposed transfer.</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H5618A22CBE814607B3CED35E7B36CF35"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>Prior to, or within one business day of, funds being transferred from a separate account, the new commercial enterprise shall provide notice to the alien investor whose capital investment has been or will be transferred from the separate account, the regional center associated with the new commercial enterprise, and the Director, including—</text>
 <item id="HDE273C0920534DBF9FFC5F1E2A9E7A0E"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the amount of the funds that are to be or were transferred; and</text> </item><item id="H9335EA6A02A54DFA9D8FA5AD93AB2C64"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the destination of the transferred funds, including whether the funds are transferred to another separate account, or transferred directly to a job creating entity or otherwise deployed into the capital investment project for which the funds were intended.</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H4DDFDB9F4FBE40E58212E8495DA19FFA"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Transfer of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a transfer of funds from a separate account maintained by a new commercial enterprise to an affiliated job creating entity, the affiliated job creating entity shall maintain the funds in a separate account that meets the requirements of this section until the funds are deployed into the capital investment project for which they were intended. Within 30 days of the deployment of the funds into the capital investment project for which they were intended, an individual who is licensed, active, and in good standing as an attorney, certified public accountant, or broker-dealer, or an individual otherwise authorized by the Director to serve as a signatory, shall verify that the funds were deployed into the capital investment project for which they were intended and shall so notify the alien investor whose capital investment was invested, the regional center associated with the capital investment project, and the Director.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HE3064D39A3DC480DB81DA1E5F6E0B4FE"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Electronic mail authorized</header><text>Any notice or information to be provided under this section may be given via electronic mail.</text> </clause><clause id="H3620F193480F442E8C5336A5DC5D89CA"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subparagraph:</text>
 <subclause id="H4E47F0A5A59840BB9BB489219D2741B8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The term <quote>financial institution</quote> has the meaning given such term by section 20 of title 18, United States Code.</text> </subclause><subclause id="HC5A86F0E1FFA4A2DA43F5B976C084299"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The term <quote>separate account</quote> means an account—</text>
 <item id="H627A9D1E2A184B11B54266EB40BBF988"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>maintained in the United States by a new commercial enterprise at a federally regulated bank or at another financial institution in the United States that is insured; and</text>
 </item><item id="H5A9FE7B5E7434690B5AFDA4AF80243D5"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>that contains only the pooled investment funds of alien investors in a new commercial enterprise with respect to a single capital investment project.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="HD03E6D043E1641FE8FBA3B9048BB1625"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective dates</header>
 <paragraph id="HEF35A66C2D0943F5B4BFD6AF99581A8A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section shall be effective at any time after the date of the enactment of this Act, as determined by the Secretary, and shall be effective not later than 90 days after such date of enactment.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HF2FC0D798ABC49C7A6CB57A4FFB57AC5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header>
 <subparagraph id="H3987BA16743342E0B50844256FA87DF9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Clauses (iv) and (v) of subparagraph (H) of section 203(b)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)</external-xref>), as inserted by subsection (b), shall not apply to a petition that—</text>
 <clause id="HAFD180EB3F6448998C328CD12D25DD24"><enum>(i)</enum><text>was filed by an alien investor under such section 203(b)(5) prior to June 1, 2015;</text> </clause><clause id="HBA5E0CBF057A484BB791C4425FF4540D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>was filed by an alien investor under such section 203(b)(5) during the period beginning on June 1, 2015, and ending on the date of the enactment of this Act if such beneficiary is investing in the same commercial enterprise concerning the same economic activity as contained in an exemplar filed prior to June 1, 2015, or approved by the Secretary of Homeland Security at any time prior to the date of enactment of this Act, unless the Secretary determines that such approval or filing was based on fraud, misrepresentation in the record of proceeding, or is legally deficient; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB9532DB4A6164EAD9D4FC308A763E005"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is filed under section 216A of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1186b">8 U.S.C. 1186b</external-xref>) if the underlying petition filed under section 203(b)(5) of such Act was filed prior to June 1, 2015, or approved before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF226B1B9A87647CAB031B9A7708E6B76"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (P) of section 203(b)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)</external-xref>), as inserted by subsection (b), shall take effect 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act and shall apply to any application filed by a regional center for approval of an investment under subparagraph (I) of such section 203(b)(5), as so inserted, filed on or after such date.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H610B2F7FFAB642FB887545B2D70467BD"><enum>4.</enum><header>Other EB–5 visa reforms</header>
 <subsection id="H6CC977479C37421FB92E744DCE0CB404"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Type of investment</header><text>Section 203(b)(5)(A) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)(A)</external-xref>), is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H93153AC5384740B1B90356EA69E1DED5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>(including a limited partnership)</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA1321242A2CC46F69F57265D87CD07EE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>(C),</quote> and inserting <quote>(B), and which is expected to remain invested for not less than 2 years;</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9ABCF5D5141C459BBC433159B80043BF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in clause (ii)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDD3D371F00DA40AD94D120C5BC41B58B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and create</quote> and inserting <quote>by creating</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA609BA2C2664F8F99F8C0CB373BD4D0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, United States nationals,</quote> after <quote>citizens</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC3AC4B82772740DBBDC0B73F177F938D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Targeted employment areas</header><text>Section 203(b)(5)(B) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)(B)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H319082D4BD7B41FCB3E375C9B2A5C274" style="OLC">
					<subparagraph id="H206936BB815943AF8B0AA63DCA8801C7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Visa set-asides and area designations</header>
 <clause id="H4E7129FDF2FA415FACE64F7E1A1A23D0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Reserved visas</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the visas made available under this paragraph in each fiscal year—</text> <subclause id="HDDA3C937ED8F43399A907C594BA02ED9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>2,000 shall be reserved for immigrants who invest in rural areas;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H1C9CD85F5FEF4A90A60C6BAF7EA20D3E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>2,000 shall be reserved for immigrants who invest in priority urban investment areas; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H35BB7D967BBA41F2B51A2DA5B5589927"><enum>(III)</enum><text>2,000 shall be reserved for immigrants who invest in infrastructure projects.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HFBA851B305D944E7B7592BEE9D8D0C63"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall determine eligibility for designation as a targeted employment area and shall not be bound by the determination of any other governmental or nongovernmental entity.</text>
						</clause><clause id="H24AD83A9197C4EF3BCE832475B9AB20A"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Designation of infrastructure project, manufacturing project, and targeted employment area</header>
 <subclause id="HA1FF23DE58E446A5BCF812B5C62FF5F0"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Infrastructure project or manufacturing project</header><text>The designation of an infrastructure project or manufacturing project shall be made at the time of the investment.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H359E604BF33A400BB9D6A3D73FB1DF5C"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Targeted employment area</header><text>The designation of a targeted employment area—</text> <item id="H970EB5AD978E4D54B8BD2BA1F290C55E"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>may be made at the time of the investment or at the time an application is filed under subparagraph (I); and</text>
 </item><item id="H1ACEEBD8980F437D9732BE851791200F"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>shall be valid for a 2-year period.</text> </item></subclause><subclause id="H9F27762E890143509DBEF05C24A4AC8D"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Designations and renewals</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a process by which regional centers may request a designation under subclause (I) or (II). A designation under either such subclause shall be issued not later than 60 days after a request by a regional center and a designation under subclause (II) may be renewed for additional 2-year periods if the area continues to meet the definition of a targeted employment area. An alien investor who has made the required amount of investment in such an area during its period of designation shall not be required to increase the amount of investment based upon expiration of the designation. The Secretary shall establish a fee for the adjudication of a designation request at a level that is sufficient to ensure the full recovery of the costs of providing such adjudication within the required timeframe. Nothing in this clause shall be deemed to prohibit an investor from filing a petition before such designation is made.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H51E906F3502B4EC1AD9A2D1784151922"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Adjustment of minimum investment amount</header>
 <paragraph id="H82F4DEC2149B41CB9CF4214A3EB00681"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 203(b)(5)(C) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)(C)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H93D7E640A72948E397F80A6EEE2A5FAC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating clause (iii) as clause (iv);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H194A88C3AED84B7281EDB99000C98CA8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking clauses (i) and (ii) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HDF9859999EF44D4397121E3C770CB31F" style="OLC"> <clause id="HED8F991BF10F49A0A9772B0FE6E7CA59"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Minimum investment amounts</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this subparagraph, the amount of capital required under subparagraph (A) shall be—</text>
 <subclause id="H70EA40AC599143758DFE8BCB923F5A18"><enum>(I)</enum><text>$1,200,000 (except as provided in subclause (II)); or</text> </subclause><subclause id="H7233D673FF0E438B8BF9D3CFE76F5C5C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>$800,000 in the case of an investment in an infrastructure project, a manufacturing project, or a project that is physically located in a targeted employment area.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H30C7F48B9CDB40E8B8A541ED8E26CC7A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Authority to increase investment amounts</header><text>The Secretary may periodically prescribe regulations increasing the dollar amount specified under clause (i) if any such increase simultaneously affects each category of investment under clause (i) by the same percentage. The Secretary shall publish a notice in the Federal Register no later than the date that is 60 days prior to the date upon which the increase will take effect.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD54D78E0C45A47AC9B3E8EA67354E514"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Automatic adjustment of minimum investment amounts</header><text>Beginning on January 1, 2022, and on every fifth subsequent January 1, after notice in the Federal Register is published for not less than 60 days, the Secretary shall adjust each of the minimum amounts specified in clause (i) as follows:</text>
 <subclause id="H87F36881BC134096B32585810B7BE3EB"><enum>(I)</enum><header>No increases in previous 5 fiscal years</header><text>If the Secretary did not increase the minimum amount during the 5 prior fiscal years concluding with the fiscal year ending on September 30 of the prior calendar year, the amounts specified in clause (i) shall automatically be adjusted by the amount of the cumulative percentage change in the Consumer Price Index (CPI–U) for the previous 5 fiscal years, rounded to the nearest multiple of $10,000.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H2C557E82055C4318A0C3B06703BD2A9A"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Increases below CPI–U during previous 5 fiscal years</header><text>If the Secretary increased the minimum amount during the previous 5 fiscal years by an amount that is less than the cumulative percentage change in the CPI–U during the previous 5 fiscal years, the amounts specified in clause (i) shall automatically be adjusted by the amount of such cumulative percentage change for such period minus any increase previously prescribed by the Secretary by regulations, rounded to the nearest multiple of $10,000.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H78D50374FA5F4088B51013384CC99069"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Increases above CPI–U during previous 5 fiscal years</header><text>If the Secretary increased the minimum amount during the previous 5 fiscal years by an amount that is greater than the cumulative percentage change in the CPI–U during the previous 5 fiscal years, the amounts specified in clause (i) shall not be increased.</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD53472185569423D91BDF10E814C9770"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in clause (iv), as redesignated, by striking <quote>Attorney General</quote> and inserting <quote>Secretary</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H78DCB29F054F429B8F9CEF4EF73A721A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Redesignations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 203(b)(5) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2B26D65A9294460BB8E5A0CFC8ECA639"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (B), as amended by subsection (b), as subparagraph (C);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA3E9852FF704F0FB5E73338713DF148"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating the second subparagraph (C), as amended by paragraph (1), as subparagraph (B); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1CDA240CCBC54804BF89BF6E10C3D5A8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by moving subparagraph (B), as so redesignated, so that it appears after subparagraph (A).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6D9B4C95DEBA4634AB4381DF68798476"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Required checks</header><text>Section 203(b)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as amended by sections 2 and 3, is further amended by inserting after subparagraph (O) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H250B8CF7F6D740B790ADEF938BDA2E83" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H785342B937104065806F0982BC8B8AF4"><enum>(P)</enum><header>Required checks</header><text>An alien investor, alien spouse, or alien child may not be granted the status of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence under this paragraph unless the Secretary of Homeland Security has determined that such alien is not on the Department of the Treasury’s Office of Foreign Assets Control Specially Designated Nationals List.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H5B54C20D1C00457D92144D2B3548E5BA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header>
 <paragraph id="H5E268C940AE04536A7D4094E59DCECF9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 203(b)(5) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)</external-xref>), as amended by sections 2 and 3 of this Act, is further amended by striking the second subparagraph (D) (relating to definitions) and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H298D77EB9BA3414193F90D14AC6A43A6" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H13708D44F9234BF2932F3C92FABCE92B"><enum>(Q)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this paragraph:</text> <clause id="HBE403866265B4437A3447D7BDCF8795D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Affiliated job-creating entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>affiliated job-creating entity</quote> means any job-creating entity that is directly or indirectly controlled, managed, or owned by any of the persons involved with the regional center or new commercial enterprise under section 203(b)(5)(K)(v).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H86202639CB10402CA8DFA9337A643979"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Capital</header><text>The term <quote>capital</quote>—</text> <subclause id="HF98187F3D23D4A339D955C9D1BEFB018"><enum>(I)</enum><text>means cash and all real, personal, or mixed tangible assets owned and controlled by the alien investor, or held in trust for the benefit of the alien and to which the alien has unrestricted access;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HC22E1775CB2D4F0E866BD58E3C323AAE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall be valued at fair market value in United States dollars, in accordance with Generally Accepted Accounting Principles or other standard accounting practice adopted by the Securities and Exchange Commission, at the time it is invested under this paragraph; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB62565597A304B58BE8168EC0E0A2DF1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>shall not include assets acquired, directly or indirectly, by unlawful means, including any cash proceeds of indebtedness secured by such assets.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H65679ADE44D14DC8AA8D6006537D9755"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Certifier</header><text>The term <quote>certifier</quote> means a person in a position of substantive authority for the management or operations of a regional center, new commercial enterprise, affiliated job-creating entity, or issuer of securities, such as a principal executive officer or principal financial officer, with knowledge of such entity’s policies and procedures related to compliance with the requirements of this paragraph.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5D00E1FDF1C345259BF7CF51138E1311"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Full-time employment</header><text>The term <quote>full-time employment</quote> means employment in a position that requires at least 35 hours of service per week for at least a 24-month period, regardless of who fills the position. A position or job that is filled by more than 1 employee may be considered full-time employment for purposes of subparagraph (A)(ii).</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA5E2DBE852634FE69004757A94490D21"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Infrastructure project</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>infrastructure project</quote> means a capital investment project in a filed or approved business plan, which is administered by a governmental entity, such as a Federal, State, or local agency or authority, where the governmental entity is the job-creating entity which contracts with a regional center, or new commercial enterprise to receive capital investment under the regional center program described in subparagraph (H) from alien investors or the new commercial enterprise as financing for maintaining, improving, or constructing a public works project.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFCAD96B8EA95405F9161DBBBA513FB55"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Job-creating entity</header><text>The term <quote>job-creating entity</quote> means any organization formed in the United States for the ongoing conduct of lawful business, including a partnership (whether limited or general), corporation, limited liability company, governmental entity (whether a Federal, State, or local entity, authority, or instrumentality), or other entity that receives, or is established to receive, capital investment from alien investors or a new commercial enterprise under the regional center program described in subparagraph (H) and which is responsible for creating jobs to satisfy the requirement under subparagraph (A)(ii).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7220718DF02146898B342C9AF9315EEB"><enum>(vii)</enum><header>Manufacturing project</header><text>The term <quote>manufacturing project</quote> means a capital investment project in a filed or approved business plan, the purpose of which is to improve, construct, or operate a plant, factory, or mill, which primarily exists in order to produce or assemble a product in the United States.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC344312EA5C444D999AD94030D0FB16D"><enum>(viii)</enum><header>New commercial enterprise</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>new commercial enterprise</quote> means any for-profit organization formed in the United States for the ongoing conduct of lawful business, including a partnership (whether limited or general), corporation, limited liability company, or other entity that receives, or is established to receive, capital investment from alien investors under subparagraph (H).</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFF522F38611D41D0A2AAD10C442393A5"><enum>(ix)</enum><header>Priority urban investment area</header><text>The term <quote>priority urban investment area</quote> means an area consisting of a census tract or tracts, each of which is in a metropolitan statistical area and, using the most recent census data available, each of which has—</text>
 <subclause id="H00FD225E00744543BE21C99310B58EFF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an unemployment rate that is at least 150 percent of the national average unemployment rate;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HF6BE2BCAD2F04E42AF17AFC6713A61BE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a poverty rate that is at least 30 percent; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H24DB5493BC8C47AEB4E5066EAB96DB90"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a median family income that is not more than 60 percent of the greater of the statewide median family income or the metropolitan statistical area median family income.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HA4F1C57A48AE4E948281E8838F3A70F5"><enum>(x)</enum><header>Rural area</header><text>The term <quote>rural area</quote> means an area that—</text> <subclause id="H8D5F504B0D6742358B56180A283A8364"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is outside of the outer boundary of any city or town having a population of 20,000 or more (based on the most recent decennial census of the United States); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA9755332E77C4C26889089F587590A51"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is—</text> <item id="HBD7A9BF479844A75892E98C16BA2C505"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">outside of a metropolitan statistical area;</text>
 </item><item id="H32E4A53A50C84A3F91A3A3DB30C54F01"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">within an outlying county of a metropolitan statistical area; or</text> </item><item id="H6037954F29D3432A9A39B37F5810842D"><enum>(cc)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">within any census tract that is greater than 100 square miles in area and has a population density of fewer than 100 people per square mile.</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause id="H8CBEEB36F02F486AB5D43A9D27482CC0"><enum>(xi)</enum><header>Targeted employment area</header><text>The term <quote>targeted employment area</quote> means—</text> <subclause id="HF22841BF87C84B809872DB7954E9292E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a priority urban investment area;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H09E2F500C5B2480DBF4B4011DF721EA4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a rural area;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H4AFAE73C85724F26AF59E41CB2BBA12A"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any area within the geographic boundaries of any military installation that was closed, during the 25-year period immediately preceding the filing of an application under subparagraph (F) based upon a recommendation by the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Commission; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H766FCD8399FE4B4B83CE83AB7C24F0F1"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>an area consisting of a census tract or contiguous census tracts, each of which, using the most recent census data available—</text>
 <item id="H90A6DE47434C444B9F1776860CBB374C"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>is not located within a metropolitan statistical area; and</text> </item><item id="H3AB4CACE0522433FA2C2305C3E7B27C9"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>has a poverty rate that is at least 20 percent or a median family income that is not more than 80 percent of the statewide median family income.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD2E5FBEE852F4186B90B7B6244B5D424"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall issue appropriate regulations to account for the modified definition of targeted employment area in section 203(b)(5)(Q)(xi) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as added by paragraph (1), within 180 days of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H559C0CAD0CF54230A38D34AFCE3697FD"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Age determination for children of alien investors</header><text>Section 203(h) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(h)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H16A8CA65AD304ADA83210D4BBDAB99D2" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H6CD0751D213A45F3BD7FA043C5E7B158"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Age determination for children of alien investors</header><text>An alien who has reached 21 years of age and has been admitted under subsection (d) as a lawful permanent resident on a conditional basis as the child of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence under subsection (b)(5), whose lawful permanent resident status on a conditional basis is terminated under section 216A or subparagraph (O) of subsection (b)(5), shall continue to be considered a child of the principal alien for the purpose of a subsequent immigrant petition by the principle alien under subsection (b)(5) if the alien who was a child of the principle alien remains unmarried and the subsequent petition is filed by the principal alien not later than 1 year after the termination of conditional lawful permanent resident status. No alien shall be considered a child under this paragraph with respect to more than 1 petition filed after the alien reaches 21 years of age.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H75E284F9F0F8497093BE82C48580ACA5"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Enhanced pay scale for certain federal employees administering the employment creation program</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security may establish, fix the compensation of, and appoint individuals to designated critical, technical, and professional positions needed to administer sections 203(b)(5) and 216A of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)</external-xref> and 1186b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB87BAD2609CD4BE881665B55066F5385"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Concurrent filing of EB–5 petitions and applications for adjustment of status</header><text>Section 245 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1255">8 U.S.C. 1255</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H8A8DEF8AD06D48648796999C6C8A28A3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (k), in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>or (3)</quote> and inserting <quote>(3), or (5)</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H497ADB20C55545058CF0B5EC25A7C730"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H39E148C8CA9C40D785F94EB03F03E0D5" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HFB7BC88B43A64A5FBBC33F554E4EF3C7"><enum>(n)</enum><text>If the approval of a petition for classification under section 203(b)(5) would make a visa immediately available to the alien beneficiary, the alien beneficiary’s application for adjustment of status under this section shall be considered to be properly filed whether the application is submitted concurrently with, or subsequent to, the visa petition.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H66A61712016E4FE7B209EC019A945305"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Conforming Changes</header>
 <paragraph id="H3BCEF8ED24404D48B5B7C41215F74225"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 203(b)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality Act is amended by inserting <quote>, subject to section 203(b)(5)(C)(i),</quote> after <quote>classes specified in paragraphs (4) and (5)</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H57070B4F6DE84BF9B7BDCD7615A40BBD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 203(b)(5)(A) of the Immigration and Nationality Act is amended by striking <quote>Visas shall be made available</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to section 203(b)(5)(C)(i), visas shall be made available</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H97E28EFD38B14CFF963452878C81C03A"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Effective dates</header>
 <paragraph id="HFD19C45B3119414E96A7AC717E5F02A4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided under paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section shall be effective upon the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H06226FA878F24DEFBB9B4737D1757DC9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header>
 <subparagraph id="H5FD3C187B770445E9BBA2C05C11E767F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (c)(1) and subsection (e)(1) shall not apply to a beneficiary of a petition that—</text>
 <clause id="H6701F459B1D84B90B66DF2DA09AEBAD5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>was filed by an alien investor under section 203(b)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)</external-xref>) prior to June 1, 2015;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3C4C624D41F842E9BD86E3485F346F0C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>was filed by an alien investor under such section 203(b)(5) during the period beginning on June 1, 2015, and ending on the date of the enactment of this Act if such beneficiary is investing in the same commercial enterprise concerning the same economic activity as contained in an exemplar filed prior to June 1, 2015, or approved by the Secretary of Homeland Security at any time prior to the date of enactment of this Act, unless the Secretary determines that such approval or filing was based on fraud, misrepresentation in the record of proceeding, or is legally deficient; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFF5B838874A94732AC63C04E83A7F793"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is filed under section 216A of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1186b">8 U.S.C. 1186b</external-xref>) if the underlying petition filed under section 203(b)(5) of such Act was filed prior to June 1, 2015, or approved before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67117A2A0B52465391106FA634F8DF8A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reserved visas</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Items (aa) and (bb) of section 203(b)(5)(C)(i)(I) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)(C)(i)(I)</external-xref>), as added by this section, shall take effect beginning on October 1, 2016.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2063D2F2C36D47B79B0D3A27A6B90675"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Redesignation</header>
 <subparagraph id="H58F2F78248BC40B68B8E35B5D3765AA2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Petition amendment</header><text>Petitioners described in paragraph (2)(A) may apply to amend their petition to redesignate the targeted employment area upon which such petition was based to conform to the targeted employment area criteria described in section 203(b)(5)(Q) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)(Q)</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (e), if such application for amendment is filed with the Secretary prior to October 1, 2017.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BC859E1F051409FB457510CCFA7F1E0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Retention of priority date</header><text>If a petitioner applies to amend a petition in accordance with subparagraph (A)—</text> <clause id="HA63AB98E594441E781412DC990DC159D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the immigrant visa priority date related to the original petition shall be retained;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCAE6689E6D4F40FA99CA2E8A83C3056E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>changes made in the amended petition to redesignate such area shall not be deemed a material change; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H148A51544DE348ED876F39D05067A2C1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the minimum investment amount such petitioner is required to make shall not be affected by any such redesignation.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDD8CF92BB8F54F6CB42AFCDDE7827940" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5.</enum><header>Conditional permanent resident status for alien investors, spouses, and children</header>
 <subsection id="HC9511D54A72C421EABD91CA052813677"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 216A of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1186b">8 U.S.C. 1186b</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H6272EE244E7F41A69E0BECA57C9F55D1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Attorney General</quote> each place such term appears (except in subsection (d)(2)(C)) and inserting <quote>Secretary of Homeland Security</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H03E8CCA911A04A0C9914552C5F46FC28"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>entrepreneur</quote> each place such term appears and inserting <quote>investor</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H97FFEF05A0FD4AA0A32861BA955177E2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by amending paragraph (1) to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H9247C43C127B4ABBAB4B35E3B1DFC50C" style="OLC">
						<paragraph id="HEAFF2EBF95364C3FB8AF1AFB58120685"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Conditional basis for status</header>
 <subparagraph id="HC05187A292A8452DA25736ACBC3DD19A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), an alien investor, alien spouse, and alien child shall be considered, at the time of obtaining status of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence, to have obtained such status on a conditional basis subject to the provisions of this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81BADDC408934BF3979D5513781DF31B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>An alien investor (and his or her alien spouse or alien child) whose petition under subsection (f) is approved before the alien investor is lawfully admitted for permanent residence shall be granted the status of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence without conditions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF85EBF729C66445DBD66F11F51C752FF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <subparagraph id="HD10535862B3E424FA8A4241BE9CE428F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Entrepreneurship</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Investment</header-in-text></quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67F3B0260F884EC4B8B251E436C9DDFD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (1)(B) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="H8D26DAC922F44918A05DCB21FB5A5D4B" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HBC525092CE3F4B929E5710D3ED099D1D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the alien did not invest the requisite capital; or</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFBB048628BB84BF495DF69E4F496C018"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text> <subparagraph id="H9D82EA728FBE4A52B8892AB7033FAAC4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">of Timely Petition and Interview</header-in-text></quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D7982A6B70545BBA4F2EFFC2831C12F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> <clause id="H435BA31EAA1D4D119ABA065F367E14BD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>In order</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in paragraph (3)(D), in order</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5887C342EDB1430397016D5A68D2A2EF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text> <subclause id="HA82533754B234F018CC899CB89F3F246"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>must</quote> and inserting <quote>shall</quote>; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H937DC0A33C624F6AA7DA0491B97B1902"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>, and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H0C5F21B80C5D44DE9C12EB42E6618EA4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text>
 <subclause id="H768D92AD6DA34125AD17CAC95964FC8B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>must</quote> and inserting <quote>shall</quote>;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H6ED6A583FFD947789DEF21533CC73B7F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Service</quote> and inserting <quote>Department of Homeland Security</quote>; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H6BC159CEE79B489B8E47ED3D50689958"><enum>(III)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H17061ADC2165423380D3DCDA2C394941"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
							<quoted-block id="H0C8D4D5888AA497E8C7FE7C7232B85EC" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H833A66C1E66F43B0AFBF73FBB3C2B37C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary shall have performed a site visit to the new commercial enterprise and job-creating entity in which the alien investor invested capital under subparagraph (A) of section 203(b)(5) pursuant to subparagraph (I)(iii) of such section.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC85FBBB98C64047A4BE07CCF0DF463C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text> <clause id="H9C7457D224F24ADEB7B0D8073120EEF4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), in the undesignated matter following clause (ii), by striking <quote>the</quote> before <quote>such filing</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H67E07F93312E4055AF74B5D1C4BCB89D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (B) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="H12CBB4A0E6FF4ABC825D36F9CE6B408C" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HCB7F4D9D11504A37B6A629DCD6B7B5CD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Removal or extension of conditional basis</header> <clause id="H3D97224F9E1E42D494D47FAF1A00C872"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (ii), if the Secretary determines that the facts and information contained in a petition submitted under paragraph (1)(A) are true, including demonstrating that the alien complied with subsection (d)(1)(B)(i), the Secretary shall—</text>
 <subclause id="H87D23A4F62604C0EB48EC2BBD96258D0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>notify the alien involved of such determination; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HAFB2C03352314738AB298B3ECCB7BDEE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>remove the conditional basis of the alien’s status effective as of the second anniversary of the alien’s lawful admission for permanent residence.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H457E67FAD3394EB181462E56BA3C26E1"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>If the petition demonstrates that the facts and information are true and that the alien is in compliance with subsection (d)(1)(B)(ii)—</text>
 <subclause id="HFECC6D951B2A46F190148D153A098386"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Secretary, in the Secretary’s discretion, may provide one 1-year extension of the alien’s conditional status; and</text>
										</subclause><subclause id="HDCFB69C0F9844155ABA60F20880720F2"><enum>(II)</enum>
 <item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H8A114AD6FF7541F6BC5921D9C66E8510"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>if the alien files a petition not later than 30 days after the third anniversary of the alien’s lawful admission for permanent residence demonstrating that the alien complied with subsection (d)(1)(B)(i), the Secretary shall remove the conditional basis of the alien’s status effective as of such third anniversary; or</text>
 </item><item id="H124CAF97AF58447391CEB3EFA2BA1923" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>if the alien does not file the petition described in item (aa), the conditional status shall terminate at the end of such additional year.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H84CD065BD6E0430BB9397BAE219F8EC7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in subsection (d)—</text> <subparagraph id="H1EE315AB8A9C4B258367398BD8C0D6E7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text>
 <clause id="H4DF01C345CC940B6886AF2BDCEF933B6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (A) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="HD6E6C48FDC8345E69DE1A3C0DC24756C" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HA06A7AB83E904842AA861A83342C4DB5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>invested the requisite capital;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause><clause id="HAE7E7FCE31F54932BAC75088DB745205"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (B) as subparagraph (C); and</text> </clause><clause id="H2FABD5BA57484055BAC375A5E14787E9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (A) the following:</text>
							<quoted-block id="HB2B7AC5007A146778065A5E5730B99D5" style="OLC">
								<subparagraph id="H2FB0E52F9BA342D893FDF0B8E167E81E"><enum>(B)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF272E39FD7A14ABB99DB3012446C26FE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>created the employment required under section 203(b)(5)(A)(ii); or</text> </clause><clause id="H8B1AF03A1B73474FB77008BDDB433E1C" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is actively in the process of creating the employment required under section 203(b)(5)(A)(ii) and will create such employment before the third anniversary of the alien’s lawful admission for permanent residence; and</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB74C2F437B41410AB0325153F318F1FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by amending subparagraph (A) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="H4A0DD9CB1DE24E878FA514D83D461937" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H200EA6BB702A4A54ADE680331CE70055"><enum>(A)</enum><header>90-day period before second anniversary</header> <clause id="H6C1AAF18658B471496E27E0F5F2A1A40"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (ii) and subparagraph (B), a petition under subsection (c)(1)(A) shall be filed during the 90-day period before the second anniversary of the alien investor’s lawful admission for permanent residence.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDE633B894B9149328F59BB1723F838D4"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Aliens described in subclauses (I)(bb), (I)(cc), and (II) of section 203(b)(5)(O)(ii) shall file a petition under subsection (c)(1)(A) during the 90-day period before the second anniversary of the subsequent investment.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD3EED4334ADD4CDDA1FFFA731C530403"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text> <clause id="H56B2293A308D488FB9F3B97DF3D751BF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The interview</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
							<quoted-block id="H99E27FB24E364E23BC5D8A7A9CEF941C" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H76878727B377440FB5DA05D9C059A1CC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The interview</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </clause><clause id="HAF8CC605E6624F3583D5FC6F62F3B9E5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Service</quote> and inserting <quote>Department of Homeland Security</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD2C8D51EA3DA4805A4B38C3BE1756FA2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking the last sentence and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H74D766C45E18482FBD2EC9B6FD6DD1AD" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H4C637E8AD0B648CBBE6A7F951698131A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security, in the Secretary’s discretion, may waive the deadline for such an interview or the requirement for such an interview according to criteria developed by United States Citizenship and Immigration Services in consultation with its Fraud Detection and National Security Directorate, and United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement, except that such criteria shall not include reduction of case processing times or the allocation of adjudicatory resources. A waiver may not be granted under this subparagraph if the alien to be interviewed—</text>
 <clause id="HD7A6A527EB0C495ABB6303B7D7853986"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">invested in a regional center, new commercial enterprise, or job-creating entity that was sanctioned under section 203(b)(5); or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3061845348F142B393AF73C5AD119B9F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is in a class of aliens determined by the Secretary to be threats to public safety or national security.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H338DB88EF273403D9A21A979B5F5CDC8"><enum>(7)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (f) as subsection (g);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H300EBAB2D988402A914A302E881F07DF"><enum>(8)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (e) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="HC36436805A844A25890E01D4E57F0192" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HD5C1CEB36D7549C0A70FDE79AD244402"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Petition from qualified alien investor</header><text>An alien investor who invested the requisite capital and created the employment required under section 203(b)(5)(A)(ii) at least 24 months before admission, and is otherwise conforming to the requirements under section 203(b)(5), may file a petition, before admission for permanent residence, to be considered, at the time of obtaining status of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence, to obtain such status without conditions.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBA8DBF5ECD154E948786957409A500B7"><enum>(9)</enum><text>in subsection (g)(3), as redesignated, by striking <quote>a limited partnership</quote> and inserting <quote>any entity formed for the purpose of doing for-profit business</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9C9984E8695242DBB7483F03817732E7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective dates</header> <paragraph id="H2BFF72D0DCE44340AEDB6BDFD29B1666"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided under paragraph (2), the amendments made by subsection (a) shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H884EBE79671A4B45ADC6D53AEF6F25DE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header>
 <subparagraph id="H31D51044DF0E4943A5B9CA2791C7C43B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Site visits</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a)(5)(B)(iv) shall take effect not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDDA2045E82894C099C46CC6C5D13E727"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Petition beneficiaries</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall not apply to the beneficiary of a petition that is filed under section 216A of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1186b">8 U.S.C. 1186b</external-xref>) if the underlying petition filed pursuant to section 204(a)(1)(H) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1154">8 U.S.C. 1154(a)(1)(H)</external-xref>) was approved before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H51268F28B66249999557A1DB4568BBC4" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>6.</enum><header>Procedure for granting immigrant status</header>
 <subsection id="H279D9CAC47424881A7870105D78194EB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Filing order and eligibility</header><text>Section 204(a)(1)(H) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1154">8 U.S.C. 1154(a)(1)(H)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H989E001D857B471FA56252753BF151B8" style="OLC">
					<subparagraph id="HBDC8F9F31372470CB60DF5C1F3C885F1"><enum>(H)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H9FE8EFE537684BED9FC616EB10D88C52"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An alien desiring to be classified under section 203(b)(5) may file a petition with the Secretary of Homeland Security, but only if the alien is not under 18 years of age at the time of filing. An alien who seeks to pool the alien’s investment with one or more additional aliens seeking classification under section 203(b)(5) shall file for classification pursuant to section 203(b)(5)(H). An alien petitioning for classification pursuant to section 203(b)(5)(H) may only file a petition with the Secretary after the regional center has filed an application for approval of an investment under section 203(b)(5)(I).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H99060E0C5B6A41B19F831E6F7C1B1C38" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A petitioner shall establish eligibility at the time the alien files for classification under section 203(b)(5) and, if not eligible at the time of filing, shall be denied such classification even if the petitioner later becomes eligible under materially different facts or circumstances. Aliens asserting eligibility under a materially different set of facts that did not exist when the petition was filed shall file a new petition. A petitioner shall continue to be eligible for classification at the time such petition is adjudicated.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H3766E29E2B844980BC2C3FAF9CB084B1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective dates</header>
 <paragraph id="H461AA05C0AC94792ADB962BAC26D9177"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H671EE919E22649D897091BCD6D0CBB1F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicability to petitions</header> <subparagraph id="H2D37238DEFE447BE86E795A62A6D9CCC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Filing</header><text>Clause (i) of section 204(a)(1)(H) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1154">8 U.S.C. 1154(a)(1)(H)</external-xref>), as added by subsection (a), shall apply to any petition for classification pursuant to section 203(b)(5)(H) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)(H)</external-xref>) that is filed with the Secretary of Homeland Security on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H579EDD0C7B56454AA5C13027A228BD77"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>Clause (ii) of section 204(a)(1)(H) of such Act, as added by subsection (a), shall apply to any petition for classification pursuant to section 203(b)(5)(H) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)(E)</external-xref>) filed with the Secretary of Homeland Security at any time.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBBA37092F88743BEBF58317E82292B27" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>7.</enum><header>Timely processing</header>
 <subsection id="H40B8307274E44CBCB007F5DD721F0062"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Fee study</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services shall complete a study of fees charged in the administration of the program described in sections 203(b)(5) and 216A of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)</external-xref> and 1186b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HABF57405F5DE4ADAB19AD5AFAF8EC87D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Adjustment of fees To achieve efficient processing</header><text>Notwithstanding section 286(m) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1356">8 U.S.C. 1356(m)</external-xref>), and except as provided under subsection (c), the Director shall set fees for services provided pursuant to sections 203(b)(5) and 216A of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)</external-xref> and 1186b), as amended by this Act, and for adjudicating petitions filed pursuant to section 204(a)(1)(H) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1154">8 U.S.C. 1154(a)(1)(H)</external-xref>), as amended by this Act, at a level sufficient to ensure the full recovery only of the costs of providing such services, including the cost of attaining the goal of completing adjudications, on average, not later than—</text>
 <paragraph id="HBFB12DF5CCF64916836D7FB1FBAEC27B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>120 days after receiving a proposal for the establishment of a regional center described in section 203(b)(5)(H);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC98A3C39ECF34763A35DBEE79AB449C9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>120 days after receiving an application for approval of investment in a commercial enterprise described in section 203(b)(5)(I);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H57F6C0716232451B92013769249BAE2E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>150 days after receiving a petition from an alien desiring to be classified under section 203(b)(5)(H); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H47F789364C2045ECB20653C032D5DBC6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>180 days after receiving a petition from an alien for removal of conditions described in section 216A(c).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF4F4A7F9F9A64388962E7C982BE855B5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional fees</header><text>Additional fees in excess of the fee levels described in subsection (b) may be charged only to contribute—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC4182E6F88CA4015AE2F5C85ACFD980D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in an amount that is equal to the amount paid by all other classes of fee-paying applicants for immigration-related benefits, to the coverage or reduction of the costs of processing or adjudicating classes of immigration benefit applications that Congress, or the Secretary in the case of asylum applications, has authorized to be processed or adjudicated at no cost or at a reduced cost to the applicant; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBD9648CCC4D1440985BCE3A88C5204FE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in an amount that is not greater than 1 percent of the fee for filing a petition pursuant to section 204(a)(1)(H) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1154">8 U.S.C. 1154(a)(1)(H)</external-xref>), to make improvements to the information technology systems used by the Secretary to process, adjudicate, and archive applications and petitions under such section, including the conversion to electronic format of documents filed by petitioners and applicants for benefits under such section.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAEAD13202E9C49A9AEC035EF6705F3EE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Premium processing of EB–5 petitions and applications</header>
 <paragraph id="H2C6C9A0570E64B9EBE66F38BEF3161A1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Modification of existing premium processing provision</header><text>Section 286(u) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1356">8 U.S.C. 1356(u)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H296C6FB141664363B5C20BF905D48087" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="HC0BEBDA6A21440FA8BD3BF4FF09CA714"><enum>(u)</enum><header>Premium fee for employment-Based petitions and applications</header>
 <paragraph id="H8DCF4E613527460586969FAA672D5C2E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security is authorized to establish and collect a premium fee for employment-based petitions and applications. The fee under this paragraph shall be used to provide certain premium-processing services to business customers and to make infrastructure improvements in the adjudications and customer-service processes. For approval of the benefit applied for, the petitioner or applicant shall meet the legal criteria for such benefit. Except as provided under paragraph (2), the fee under this paragraph shall be set at $1,000, shall be paid in addition to any normal petition or application fee that may be applicable, and shall be deposited as offsetting collections in the Immigration Examinations Fee Account. The Secretary may adjust the fee under this paragraph in proportion to changes in the Consumer Price Index.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC8931328E6D24EAF9B9DACA8AC53C6E5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Alien investor petitions and applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish and collect a premium fee for expeditious processing of applications for regional center designation or regional center amendment under section 203(b)(5)(H), petitions under section 203(b)(5), petitions for removal of conditions on lawful permanent residence under section 216A(c), and applications under section 203(b)(5)(I) related to investment in a new commercial enterprise (as defined in section 203(b)(5)(Q)). A petitioner or applicant shall be permitted an opportunity to provide additional evidence identified by the Secretary in any such petition or application prior to a final determination. The premium fee for each such application or petition shall be set at an amount sufficient to adjudicate such application or petition within <fraction>1/2</fraction> of the relevant period set forth in section 6(b) of the American Job Creation and Investment Into Public Works Reform Act of 2017, and shall otherwise only be used to recover the costs of such processing, including the hiring of additional adjudicatory staff, shall be paid in addition to any normal petition or application fee that may be applicable, and shall be deposited as offsetting collections in the Immigration Examinations Fee Account.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3FA5F87A7187499C8C3490EC98ED30FC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Establishment of EB–5 premium processing</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish the premium processing of immigrant investor petitions and applications, as described in section 286(u) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1356">8 U.S.C. 1356(u)</external-xref>), as amended by paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA5990192F5804A51BF27BE8A39EE8E87"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Delay in adjudication</header><text>Nothing in this Act may be construed to limit the authority of the Secretary of Homeland Security to suspend the adjudication of any application or petition under section 203(b)(5) or 216A of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)</external-xref> and 1186b) or related petition under section 204(a)(1)(H) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1154">8 U.S.C. 1154(a)(1)(H)</external-xref>) pending the completion of a national security or law enforcement investigation relating to such application or petition.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H57870EA89474416EACB36DB2DE031C8D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Exemption from Paperwork Reduction Act</header><text>For a period of one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the requirements of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code, shall not apply to any collection of information required under this Act, under any amendment made by this Act, or under any rule promulgated by the Secretary of Homeland Security to implement this Act or the amendments made by this Act, to the extent the Secretary determines that compliance with such requirements would impede the expeditious implementation of this Act or the amendments made by this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB278098A11864E4FA7B739DAE43AABB7"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to require any modification of fees before the completion of—</text>
 <paragraph id="H84C4DA1F0E144A02AB7D4FCCAFEB6FD3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the fee study described in subsection (a); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3F2930712CB74D7CA27D5FEAAA9CC107"><enum>(2)</enum><text>regulations promulgated by the Secretary of Homeland Security, in accordance with subchapter II of chapter 5 and <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/7">chapter 7</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Administrative Procedure Act</quote>), to carry out subsections (b) and (c).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H964D64686A234679A1B9AE5A7CFFEDDD" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>8.</enum><header>Transparency</header>
 <subsection id="H2C182959CB0D450B88011FB0DB7A876F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Employees of the Department of Homeland Security, including the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary’s counselors, the Assistant Secretary for the Private Sector, the Director of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services, counselors to such Director, and the Chief of Immigrant Investor Programs at United States Citizenship and Immigration Services, shall act impartially and may not give preferential treatment to any entity, organization, or individual in connection with any aspect of the immigrant visa program described in section 203(b)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H958D105B2AD146A2B44739BA40D79C7F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Improper activities</header><text>Activities that constitute preferential treatment under subsection (a) shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H786C3EA0BAE141B6988163EE1F3CD57E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>working on, or in any way attempting to influence, in a manner not available to or accorded to all other petitioners, applicants, and seekers of benefits under the immigrant visa program described in section 203(b)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)</external-xref>), as amended by this Act, the standard processing of an application, petition, or benefit for—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H930E42615A5C4B63B334DBDCD5D60157"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a regional center established under subparagraph (H) of such section;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB1ECA276748B43428583FEE85E69101E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a new commercial enterprise (as defined in subparagraph (Q) of such section);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC86E725666C745CC9E9841D2A45CA8B5"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a job-creating entity (as so defined); or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0486DCA8CFE94808B1CEB7AB2868A173"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any person or entity associated with such regional center, new commercial enterprise, or job-creating entity; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H01ED8E3BE05E40D0884515D22E082E61"><enum>(2)</enum><text>meeting or communicating with persons associated with the entities described in paragraph (1), at the request of such persons, in a manner not available to or accorded to all other petitioners, applicants, and seekers of benefits under such immigrant visa program.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF80735187E21482A93F93EF1B2983171"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reporting of communications</header>
 <paragraph id="H893BCA0E2763473797E2EEE55FB39FDA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Written communication</header><text>Employees of the Department of Homeland Security, including the officials listed in subsection (a), shall include, in the record of proceeding for a case under section 203(b)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, actual or electronic copies of all case-specific written communication, including e-mails from government and private accounts, with non-Department persons or entities advocating for regional center applications or individual petitions under such section that are pending on or after the date of the enactment of this Act (other than routine communications with other agencies of the Federal Government regarding the case, including communications involving background checks and litigation defense).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H816CEE13F05141AF926AF2D71998DC4C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Oral communication</header><text>If substantive oral communication, including telephonic communication, virtual communication, and in-person meetings, takes place between officials of the Department of Homeland Security and non-Department persons or entities advocating for regional center applications or individual petitions under section 203(b)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)</external-xref>) that are pending on or after the date of the enactment of this Act (other than routine communications with other agencies of the Federal Government regarding the case, including communications involving background checks and litigation defense)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA016BC93AEA14263B68F53D2BC0FC034"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the conversation shall be recorded; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C0B1B2A8AE64F278756BBA0C8D51835"><enum>(B)</enum><text>detailed minutes of the session shall be taken and included in the record of proceeding.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H09EF0485E8E540B79CAF1E5DCD6BEA76"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notification</header>
 <subparagraph id="H56074C1C6F734AB49C838A2F9A12B29F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Secretary, in the course of written or oral communication described in this subsection, receives evidence about a specific case from anyone other than an affected party or his or her representative (excluding Federal Government or law enforcement sources), such information may not be made part of the record of proceeding and may not be considered in adjudicative proceedings unless—</text>
 <clause id="HCE634CD1B66240088214D6FC23D4ECE0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the affected party has been given notice of such evidence; and</text> </clause><clause id="H3DD961FB71DA4BA685B886F750F55BC8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if such evidence is derogatory, the affected party has been given an opportunity to respond to the evidence.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H14A7A6A1FC2641069200EEA8DCFCF2A2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Information from law enforcement, intelligence agencies, or confidential sources</header>
 <clause id="H96D3F009B01548E28FD331BB042B1C61"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Law enforcement or intelligence agencies</header><text>Evidence received from law enforcement or intelligence agencies may not be made part of the record of proceeding without the consent of the relevant agency or law enforcement entity.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H827682E523EB48FE94F23BAA3E75E34E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Whistleblowers, confidential sources, or intelligence agencies</header><text>Evidence received from whistleblowers, other confidential sources, or the intelligence community that is included in the record of proceeding and considered in adjudicative proceedings shall be handled in a manner that does not reveal the identity of the whistleblower or confidential source, or reveal classified information.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H71227AABD44645BBBA5EBE984B6C073A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consideration of evidence</header>
 <paragraph id="HF2714C74AABC4F0BB89EC2A0C9109D9E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No case-specific communication with persons or entities that are not part of the Department of Homeland Security may be considered in the adjudication of an application or petition under section 203(b)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)</external-xref>) unless the communication is included in the record of proceeding of the case.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFD75AB236FEF4C21B42AD3622DE374EC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security may waive the requirement under paragraph (1) only in the interests of national security or for investigative or law enforcement purposes.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3F1301CC205E46BDABB6C0891EFFC912"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Channels of communication</header>
 <paragraph id="H22266C8B72A64DD39566DA1DEC97111C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>E-mail address or equivalent</header><text>The Director of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services shall maintain an e-mail account (or equivalent means of communication) for persons or entities—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2EA359A1733646B7A2C679428A30DBA3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with inquiries regarding specific petitions or applications under the immigrant visa program described in section 203(b)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)</external-xref>); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3BD8E823A9442CCAEE6C05058AC0A62"><enum>(B)</enum><text>seeking non-case-specific information about the immigrant visa program described in such section 203(b)(5).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFEB5310EE6334BB6906410CF3C5A1B63"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Communication only through appropriate channels or offices</header>
 <subparagraph id="HFDE1505F93FD4010B988624E84D1EDDF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Announcement of appropriate channels of communication</header><text>Not later than 40 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services shall announce that the only channels or offices by which industry stakeholders, petitioners, applicants, and seekers of benefits under the immigrant visa program described in section 203(b)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)</external-xref>) may communicate with the Department of Homeland Security regarding specific cases under such section (except for communication made by applicants and petitioners pursuant to regular adjudicatory procedures), or non-case-specific information about the visa program applicable to certain cases under such section, are through—</text>
 <clause id="HD598A483C7B941529B2FB3363D5B3222"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the e-mail address or equivalent channel described in paragraph (1);</text> </clause><clause id="H656DBFD62527446F9391C01AE4FDB299"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the United States Citizenship and Immigration Services National Customer Service Center, or any successor to that Center; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H32F2F339390A4B8EB37F38B38BB71EA0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the United States Citizenship and Immigration Services Office of Public Engagement, Immigrant Investor Program Office, Stakeholder Engagement Branch, or any successors to those Offices or Branch.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94ADE10E701E4DE4B298288051830359"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Direction of incoming communications</header>
 <clause id="H95AB095931924A08BFD5084A377A768B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Employees of the Department of Homeland Security shall direct communications described in subparagraph (A) to the channels of communication or offices listed in subparagraph (A).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H87BBA056B42E47BD8DC2792628B638DC"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subparagraph may be construed to prevent—</text> <subclause id="HCAFE19C82F7C435E81106862A9E5D37B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any person from communicating with the Ombudsman of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services regarding the immigrant investor program under section 203(b)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)</external-xref>); or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H2D5A7CB52429444F96519496CBCF8911"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Ombudsman from resolving problems regarding such immigrant investor program pursuant to the authority granted under section 452 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/272">6 U.S.C. 272</external-xref>).</text>
							</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H187D908616764B12BB1AFD87632AA1DD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Log</header>
 <clause id="HD2FAFA800E3842CF9500FB09C5521967"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services shall maintain a written or electronic log of—</text>
 <subclause id="H2D79A2A632E84C418E33550A6C092361"><enum>(I)</enum><text>all communications described in subparagraph (A) and communications from Members of Congress, which shall reference the date, time, and subject of the communication, and the identity of the Department official, if any, to whom the inquiry was forwarded;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H032E0B21C3744E8CB7F5C0E8B7E9C396"><enum>(II)</enum><text>with respect to written communications described in subsection (c)(1), the date the communication was received, the identities of the sender and addressee, and the subject of the communication; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HF0BCE05CBEA64C0897D84A67CD175AFB"><enum>(III)</enum><text>with respect to oral communications described in subsection (c)(2), the date on which the communication occurred, the participants in the conversation or meeting, and the subject of the communication.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H2142C6DC322F443FA0205DAA495A3626"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Transparency</header><text>The log of communications described in clause (i) shall be made publicly available in accordance with section 552 of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Freedom of Information Act</quote>).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2681B3D1DE3A4FB2B316062CC578AC23"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Publication of information</header><text>If, as a result of a communication with an official of the Department of Homeland Security, a person or entity inquiring about a specific case or generally about the immigrant visa program described in section 203(b)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)</external-xref>) received generally applicable and non-case-specific information about program requirements or administration that has not been made publicly available by the Department, the Director of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services, not later than 30 days after the communication of such information to such person or entity, shall publish such information on the United States Citizenship and Immigration Services Web site as an update to the relevant Frequently Asked Questions page or by some other comparable mechanism.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3DE399C2F05E4A7FA6A2C039CE8CAB26"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Penalty</header>
 <paragraph id="HB17878E6FD2A4BA8A01B7FE8A944F820"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any person who intentionally violates the prohibition on preferential treatment under this section or intentionally violates the reporting requirements under subsection (c) shall be disciplined in accordance with paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF7BF6A301E90447FA356C8E768AD481A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sanctions</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish a graduated set of sanctions based on the severity of the violation referred to in paragraph (1), which may include, in addition to any criminal or civil penalties that may be imposed, written reprimand, suspension, demotion, or removal.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H62BCEC3A5BBC462D96F3728694FB1125"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to modify any law, regulation, or policy regarding the handling or disclosure of classified information.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7B8B198D0EB24F978D9288AAFDA8E3E5"><enum>(h)</enum><header>No creation of private right of action</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to create or authorize a private right of action to challenge a decision of an employee of the Department of Homeland Security.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H405973A1796C4A42B06E4C01A3832E92"><enum>9.</enum><header>Reports</header>
 <subsection id="HE9AD797CCEA949118136E9D45B819E5A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>GAO report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than December 31, 2019, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit a report to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives that describes—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA61C943545A949048F4F830778A98548"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the economic benefits of the regional center program established under section 203(b)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)</external-xref>), including the steps taken by United States Citizenship and Immigration Services to verify job creation;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4AAE0FE4734F41AE82EB722EA0FB37A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the extent to which United States Citizenship and Immigration Services ensures compliance by regional center participants with their obligations under the immigrant investor program;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB93E7BC0E8C04B0EA8A61045988EDB2D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the extent to which United States Citizenship and Immigration Services has maintained records of regional centers and associated commercial enterprises, including annual statements and certifications;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD232226FF2524306B6CA0FDA6B2C05A4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the steps taken by United States Citizenship and Immigration Services to verify the source of funds, as required under section 203(b)(5)(D) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as added by section 2 of this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H83712AEE0D544B5AB7AD01DDD6B68288"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the extent to which United States Citizenship and Immigration Services collaborates with other Federal and law enforcement agencies, particularly to detect illegal activity and threats to national security related to the regional center program;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7DD6CA6F6D524D198650018D4B4FDDEF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the extent to which United States Citizenship and Immigration Services has prevented fraud and abuse in regional center activities, including the designation of targeted employment areas in areas that otherwise have high employment;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD4F50DAE8E4B43D88C781C0BF8BE163C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the extent to which United States Citizenship and Immigration Services has used its authority to sanction, suspend, bar, or terminate regional centers or individuals affiliated with regional centers;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H289490B5C9EA472C82DC52F674A592F9"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the steps that have been taken to oversee direct and third-party promoters under section 203(b)(5)(N) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as added by section 3 of this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H048DFEFA8337401492B5966FBEB9C38A"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the extent to which employees of the Department of Homeland Security have complied with the ethical standards and transparency requirements under section 8 of this Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE76E9A1E040845B69B015BE899800CF3"><enum>(10)</enum><text>an accounting of the expenditure of amounts from the EB–5 Integrity Fund established under section 203(b)(5)(M) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as added by section 3 of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF55B671D2A5344F59020BCED857AF4BC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inspector General report</header><text>Not later than December 31, 2019, the Inspector General of the Intelligence Community, in coordination with the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security and after consultation with relevant Federal agencies, including United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement, shall submit a report to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives concerning the immigrant visa program set forth in section 203(b)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)</external-xref>) that describes—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA21C37EECE7942C5A70E7780300A4ED8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the vulnerabilities within the program that may undermine the national security of the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFA9DA6B1F47641CBAD84A5582AF0A494"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the actual or potential use of the program to facilitate export of sensitive technology;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFA1574464E92495EB0DC8ED6DB59F553"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the actual or potential use of the program to facilitate economic espionage;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBE09183925424E59B08F3F0F7084EEB6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the actual or potential use of the program by foreign government agents; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEA0AC5D4430E4A2D86A8556E23E2EB68"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the actual or potential use of the program to facilitate terrorist activity, including funding terrorist activity or laundering terrorist funds.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDD003194781A47DEB2D8416A6BFEFA01"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Review of job creation methodologies</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Bureau of Economic Analysis of the Department of Commerce, or another component within the Department of Commerce, as determined by the Secretary of Commerce, shall publish regulations to determine economically and statistically valid general economic methodologies that are in compliance with section 203(b)(5)(A)(ii) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)(A)(ii)</external-xref>).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H6262012CE23C48B7B1E190265A1FA3A6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header>
 <paragraph id="HA0B81D4DABDB4957B8F453B9915E50AF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Secretary of Commerce and after consultation with relevant Federal agencies, shall submit a report to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives that describes, with respect to the program under section 203(b)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)</external-xref>)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3978BDB23D804D3A93A17AD4B2ACD5CC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the percentage of completed and pending capital investment projects and the number of alien investors investing pursuant to such program in the States, metropolitan and micropolitan statistical areas, and counties in which such projects occurred in each fiscal year, within the scope of business plans filed pursuant to section 203(b)(5)(I) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)(I)</external-xref>), as added by this Act, both approved and awaiting approval—</text>
 <clause id="HABDF2D0001FA4877ABD24813262FDB90"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in rural areas;</text> </clause><clause id="HA20C774ECBD2460B9914157F330FBF88"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in rural areas where the median family income is 125 percent or more than the national average;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF2CD6E7CB1BD4E70994B84090F00E177"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in priority urban investment areas;</text> </clause><clause id="H57E19F82BCD645DD986105205E36F122"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>for infrastructure projects;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF6C308577FC244648E658A2D0EFAAB60"><enum>(v)</enum><text>for manufacturing projects; and</text> </clause><clause id="HC2BF0FE737BE4786B4F5F812B68823A5"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>in areas that are not described in any of the clauses (i) through (v);</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE73EF5BA59BB4F3A8C5E2319D3FBD2EB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether other Federal financial assistance and tax incentive programs, such as economic development programs administered by the Department of Agriculture, the Department of Housing and Urban Development, or the Community Development Financial Institutions Fund, are also used or available for use by projects described in subparagraph (A);</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H421F67F9066347909A3990125BCD8B70"><enum>(C)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H3A4A843275494044AB581E44C7167351"><enum>(i)</enum><text>what data is available to assess commuting patterns from high unemployment census tracts to project locations;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF3DB515E22954CE7B1756B444FB90C57" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>whether the consideration of such commuting patterns may be an appropriate factor for targeted employment area designations; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBE1BE753C4B347C5B387FB043A2D8A77" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>whether such data can be used to assess job creation in high unemployment census tracts;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80A6080527344A92832B4D5D9CAB4723"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether market demands to approve projects described in subparagraph (A) exceed the number of visas allowed under section 203(b)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57307B054A594ECDBE1C1E3DA1A2DC70"><enum>(E)</enum><text>whether other metrics or Federal data sets are available that capture underserved or undercapitalized communities that may provide an appropriate factor for targeted employment area designations; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17635024975646AA80667593D20DEC85"><enum>(F)</enum><text>what data is available to assess the percentage of jobs created through the investor visa program that are held by persons who reside in census tracts that have an unemployment rate of at least 150 percent of the national average.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6CBF5B7ED7C04AFDB6FAE851A6CF1D60"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public input</header><text>Not later than 60 days before the submission of the report required under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide the public with notice and an opportunity to comment on the draft report.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


