<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H7CB6606B8E8942B58FA8102A812FD41E" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4336 IH: College Completion and Success Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4336</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171109">November 9, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000587">Mr. Lewis of Minnesota</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000465">Mr. Ferguson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000580">Mr. Garrett</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001199">Mr. Smucker</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the institutional refunds provision of the Higher Education Act of 1965.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H97C959AA96A848B880D9892DF613E3AB" style="OLC">
 <section id="H88C473E419444812A4ECBB15C2465587" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>College Completion and Success Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H8622D38DEF4F48A882DABF1755AC0DCD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Institutional refunds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 484B of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1091b">20 U.S.C. 1091b</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HBAE6908506D843EC9E21EC3BD7CBBA5D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H419D0ABFF3EF46DD97C787BAA39581C8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1)—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="HC2591A16BB84412391D89729EC97AB62"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>If a recipient</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H47C453602BF948CBB3338F7B30D5DE42" style="OLC"> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H2FD79172B7CB4D13856C3F77C616DDA4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Consequence of withdrawal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a recipient</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H5DB65B26FC19459D85695A511DCEDC9A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H010CCF4AF82046AAAE5AFC3799714897" style="OLC"> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HE74B5BEC316E4FFD96958C360C49B21F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), a student—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H61DA90DBF5E143B290E3879B36C668A4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>who is enrolled in a program offered in modules is not considered withdrawn if the change in the student’s attendance constitutes a change in enrollment status within the payment period rather than a discontinuance of attendance within the payment period; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HDA2F0FDFA1E34B518FF3225660645C07"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is considered withdrawn if the student follows the institution’s official withdrawal procedures or leaves without notifying the institution and has not returned before the end of the payment period.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC495DA8006B24528B810D0CBC59A32C0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(B), by striking clauses (i) and (ii) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2C7AC624DAA94ED3ADA6E6D5E90B03AA" style="OLC"> <clause id="H819077C481154322AACC558EA7D4CA5B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>0 percent, if the day the student withdrew occurs when the student has completed (as determined in accordance with subsection (d)) 0 to 24 percent of the payment period or period of enrollment;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA3F47591EDFF4135B7C279AD33E4A54C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>25 percent, if the day the student withdrew occurs when the student has completed (as determined in accordance with subsection (d)) 25 to 49 percent of the payment period or period of enrollment;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBF3A1FAA50A5497FBF01706D75A88E6D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>50 percent, if the day the student withdrew occurs when the student has completed (as determined in accordance with subsection (d)) 50 to 74 percent of the payment period or period of enrollment; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC95ECE81E2B6473983DFF390C3D6686F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>75 percent, if the day the student withdrew occurs when the student has completed (as determined in accordance with subsection (d)) 75 to 99 percent of the payment period or period of enrollment.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H47D240238CA3498EBE1CF790DD1E9339"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text> <clause id="HA9D43D1DDC954ABE8F18E8609C20C0C6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>Secretary), the institution of higher education shall contact the borrower</quote> and inserting <quote>Secretary), the institution of higher education shall have discretion to determine whether all or a portion of the late or post-withdrawal disbursement should be made, under a publicized institutional policy. If the institution of higher education determines that a disbursement should be made, the institution shall contact the borrower</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H96A2ABBE8FE649CA874364EC0BDE2FBB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (B) by striking <quote>institution or the student, or both, as may be required under paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (b), to the programs under this title in the order specified in</quote> and inserting <quote>institution, as may be required under paragraph (1) of subsection (b), to the programs under this title in accordance with</quote>;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0073BABA1383422FAA84B38C9B2A11EE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by amending subsection (b) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H047BE7B6AC334FC7A505366E90AAA691" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HFD49EC22BF374A18A50E0B03F0B87C1E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Return of title IV program funds</header> <paragraph id="H62C4AD0BD39D48FFAE10598349404893"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Responsibility of the institution</header><text>The institution shall return not later than 60 days from the determination of withdrawal, in accordance with paragraph (3), the amount of grant and loan assistance awarded under this title that has not been earned by the student, as calculated under subsection (a)(3)(C).</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H00E5FA7055B440A59E17CB15F847BEC5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Responsibility of the student</header>
 <subparagraph id="HC56C8257FB9F403CADB426D183F47086"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The student is not responsible to return assistance that has not been earned; however, the institution may require the student to pay to the institution up to 10 percent of the amount owed by the institution in paragraph (1).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC225BF9579064BC9919992896580597D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent an institution from enforcing the published institutional refund policies of such institution.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF856F95C77474D6291B96D0011E9DD27"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Order of return of title IV funds</header>
 <subparagraph id="H4B70A64717FD4F7C9168420BAFB657D1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Excess funds returned by the institution in accordance with paragraph (1) shall be credited to awards under subparts 1 and 3 of part A for the payment period or period of enrollment for which a return of funds is required.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H285D83330383496780FBCC30413D9BBF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Remaining excesses</header><text>If excess funds remain after repaying all outstanding grant amounts, the remaining excess shall be credited in the following order:</text>
 <clause id="H952C4977A92B475A9E60D19A65B2FFD2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>To outstanding balances on loans made under this title to the student or on behalf of the student for the payment period or period of enrollment for which a return of funds is required.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2154E882185A48B7ABD806A00155AAB7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>To other assistance awarded under this title for which a return of funds is required.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H775CAF6F7272463CA2EEDCDC9B91CE52"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by amending subsection (c) to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF8E49B8E66324C6D89A06B8A7EF1EC6B" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="HAB3BACBCBFB34776B5BA7C4E997E0899"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Withdrawal date</header>
 <paragraph id="HCB36807981994CF4B98F644454BACA00"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>day the student withdrew</quote>—</text> <subparagraph id="H3733F67BBC9541569671594FC7791978"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for institutions not required to take attendance, is the date as determined by the institution that—</text>
 <clause id="H4E1FFD71B13249A9BD033EE7D400835E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the student began the withdrawal process prescribed and publicized by the institution, or a later date if the student continued attendance despite beginning the withdrawal process, but did not then complete the payment period; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H92F8DDC2003F4050A5B4721BE6F5857D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a student who does not begin the withdrawal process, the date that is the mid-point of the payment period for which assistance under this title was disbursed or another date documented by the institution; or</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56CD67F6B8A4471496737199F2A71320"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for institutions required to take attendance, is determined by the institution from such attendance records.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7475E6F87FAC4CACBF891A45CE5DDBC4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), if the institution determines that a student did not begin the withdrawal process, due to illness, accident, grievous personal loss, or other such circumstances beyond the student’s control, the institution may determine the appropriate withdrawal date under its own defined policies.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H93F7BA79C3B2474EB8A36B01DFD409E3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Attendance</header><text>An institution is required to take attendance if an institution’s accrediting agency or State licensing agency has a requirement that the institution take attendance for all students in an academic program throughout the entire payment period.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE415253F2FC44D7CB2B885DCE223E7EE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by striking subsections (d) and (e).</text> </paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

