<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFC3409D56C7D41A9B1ADDFAEF321F4AB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><form><distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 761</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170131">January 31, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000586">Mr. Renacci</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001275">Mr. Bucshon</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">the Budget</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the use of premiums paid to the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation as an offset for other Federal spending.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9BEA43E9C18147DAA29C300BA7EDD004" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6601F5CCE46F4D0A96C1585DD8FD0698" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pension and Budget Integrity Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H85641236FFF047EE890FF147AE42C5E6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on the use of premiums as an offset</header> <subsection id="H9BEED537B0134535AD8DF6F4300EE693"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the Senate and the House of Representatives, for purposes of determining points of order under the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/621">2 U.S.C. 621</external-xref> et seq.) or any concurrent resolution on the budget, any provision that increases, or extends the increase of, any premiums payable to the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation shall not be counted in estimating the level of budget authority, outlays, or revenues—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE62EAC67F2BF46C4BA49B5E197B7DA24"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the Senate, for any bill, joint resolution, amendment, amendment between the Houses, conference report, or motion; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD151391E7D814DF99248DE738506F848"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the House of Representatives, for any bill or joint resolution, or amendment thereto or conference report thereon.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA206EDBC93A9422BBDDD49728E9DCFB9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rules of Senate and House of Representatives</header><text>Congress adopts the provisions of this section—</text> <paragraph id="HF39E4EDBC1EA47F1AF98E6F2CAB3F34D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as an exercise of the rulemaking power of the Senate and the House of Representatives, respectively, and as such is deemed a part of the rules of each House, respectively, and supersede other rules only to the extent that they are inconsistent with such rules; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF05B2DC2BD0E403CADB34CB025E5BC75"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with full recognition of the constitutional right of either House to change the rules (so far as relating to the procedure of that House) at any time, in the same manner, and to the same extent as in the case of any other rule of that House.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

