<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1661B1E84DFD45B785447126432E2A43" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4494 IH: Congressional Accountability and Hush Fund Elimination Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4494</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171130">November 30, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000621">Mr. DeSantis</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000620">Mr. Delaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001290">Mr. Brat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001286">Mrs. Bustos</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000565">Mr. Loebsack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000571">Ms. Gabbard</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000816">Mr. Williams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000602">Miss Rice of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001096">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001189">Mr. Messer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000754">Mr. Cooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001301">Mr. Bergman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000607">Mr. Francis Rooney of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001071">Mr. Jody B. Hice of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000609">Mr. Palmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000299">Mr. Johnson of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000171">Mr. O'Halleran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001197">Ms. McSally</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000470">Mr. Tipton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001299">Mr. Banks of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000065">Mr. Yoho</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000606">Mr. Pittenger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001273">Mrs. Black</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000592">Mr. Rokita</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001243">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000459">Mr. Fleischmann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000588">Mr. Pearce</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000190">Mr. Norman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001179">Mr. Marino</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001191">Ms. Sinema</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000599">Mr. Posey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000567">Mr. Lance</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000820">Mrs. Mimi Walters of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001294">Mr. Blum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000598">Mr. Rothfus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000819">Mr. Walker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001297">Mr. Buck</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000579">Mr. Gallagher</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 to prohibit the use of public funds to pay
			 awards and settlements in connection with claims under such Act which
			 arise from sexual harassment, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H48F1A9C377BA4337B7C8670ADBAB1DA6" style="OLC">
 <section id="H0B83962889B14E129DA3B6447C98D9E0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Congressional Accountability and Hush Fund Elimination Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H6B54430BD7CE470285DC949E44650C4C" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibiting use of public funds to pay settlements and awards for claims under Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 which arise from sexual harassment</header> <subsection id="HF0BC5D46022F4406A71E21C3CB0608D8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header> <paragraph id="HAEE4AB0375964172B9AB12C0AFDF548D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 415 of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1415">2 U.S.C. 1415</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE16037E5C76641CEBB61ABA38FEBF157"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>subsection (c)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsections (c) and (d)</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8EB3E7EB2EC448DA28D3B9B1476CF08"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6B081D4706E94F8EA774CAD7E7686D8C" style="OLC">
							<subsection id="H5A7CA7C042F04B58BE497532B819A158"><enum>(d)</enum><header>No use of public funds for payments of awards and settlements in connection with acts of sexual
 harassment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No funds of the Treasury of the United States, including the account described in subsection (a), an account of the House of Representatives or Senate, or any other account of the Federal Government, may be used for the payment of an award or settlement in connection with a violation of section 201(a)(1) if the violation consists of an act of sexual harassment or sexual assault.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1271B6DDAF284A7E9EF74F534E2CF1EA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by paragraph (1) shall apply with respect to settlements and awards paid on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF0CA2A90D3254B4C832135CE2BEEA50B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment of amounts previously paid</header>
 <paragraph id="H870FAA949B844AA39F9B76B07B93F76E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Report by Office of Compliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Office of Compliance shall submit to Congress and make available to the public on the Office’s public website a report on all payments made with public funds prior to the date of the enactment of this Act for awards and settlements in connection with violations of section 201(a)(1) of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995, and shall include in the report the following information:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC4502496EB1549BE8F6D031759BFB599"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The amount paid for each such award or settlement.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96F4F12135CC45D3B32199884B4E0A37"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The source of the public funds used for the award or settlement, without regard to whether the funds were paid from the account described in section 415(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1415">2 U.S.C. 1415(a)</external-xref>), an account of the House of Representatives or Senate, or any other account of the Federal Government.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3AE57755F1C4CFA8D8DC561DC152404"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The identification of the employing office involved and any individual who committed the violation involved.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCECE490B6DA94E88A6A41281E82D7B45"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Protection of identity of individuals receiving awards and settlements</header><text>In preparing and submitting the report required under paragraph (1), the Office of Compliance shall ensure that the identity of any individual who received an award or settlement, or who made an allegation of a violation against an employing office, is not disclosed.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF6CE8284AFCC4BA6973267EF20051D73"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Repayment by perpetrators</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each individual who committed an act of sexual harassment or sexual assault for which an award or settlement described in paragraph (1) was paid with public funds at any time after the enactment of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 shall make a payment to the Treasury of the United States in an amount equal to the amount of the award or settlement involved, increased by an interest rate equal to the interest rate for a Federal Direct PLUS Loan on the date on which the award or settlement was paid in accordance with section 455(b)(8)(C) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(b)(8)(C)</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H27F7FDE90C8E49979ACDCCF5A728CB85"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibiting imposition of nondisclosure agreements in cases involving sexual harassment or sexual
			 assault</header>
 <subsection id="HC5F135EA18C94A0DBB57EF0D0A25DF36"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 401 of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1401">2 U.S.C. 1401</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H70C10B7C8B15408A9D3D960F42F91E9C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Except as otherwise provided</quote> and inserting <quote>(a) <header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Procedures available</header-in-text>.—Except as otherwise provided</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5BC3CD613A9C474193916C482726D10E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0CE17C6E908D4B4990133D9C828CF657" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HB887467C48A248A2B17B9CD1BBBF4E79"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibiting imposition of nondisclosure agreements as prerequisite for procedures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A nondisclosure agreement may not be imposed on any party as a condition of the initiation of any of the procedures available under this title for consideration of a violation of part A of title II if the violation consists of an act of sexual harassment or sexual assault.</text>
						</subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC98B7BEAFBCF4033A835D49AC0D234B3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment of existing agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any individual who received an award or settlement prior to the date of the enactment of this Act in connection with a violation of section 201(a)(1) of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 which consisted of an act of sexual harassment or sexual assault and who signed a nondisclosure agreement as a condition of receiving the award or settlement may, notwithstanding the terms of the agreement, make public any information relating to the award or settlement.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


