<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H024D854091314FF681B9CF4937E18330" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1833 IH: Investing in America’s Small Businesses Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1833</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170330">March 30, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To encourage initiatives for financial products and services that are appropriate and accessible
			 for millions of American small businesses that do not have access to the
			 financial mainstream.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H6963331C583946C1BA057C98F537DF93" style="OLC">
 <section id="H136F9C28E37D454D870CFE744AC38D75" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Investing in America’s Small Businesses Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H50CC9253ADF0458A96C70580DDD6110F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H3B5F7C2E87554C348E429FEEDF2BE1EF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Small businesses in underserved areas have for generations been unable to access affordable credit.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDE56C2E569DA4FF78FD0ACCC5735C8CF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A 2013 report commissioned by the U.S. Small Business Administration shows the major constraint limiting the growth, expansion, and wealth creation of small firms—especially women- and minority-owned businesses—is inadequate capital.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD0BF9BF3390A42C685A9D4D94E74FA60"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Small businesses revitalize communities by creating jobs, and also contribute to the local tax base, which helps finance investments in schools, hospitals, infrastructure, and public safety.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H52C56B32EB484B9B8AF6F8CFDD603EEC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A 2015 report from the Carsey School of Public Policy at the University of New Hampshire found that 79 percent of CDFI loan volume went to borrowers from underserved populations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCBE377B23B0A4FA581197EA023DD51CE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>During the financial crisis, CDFI loan funds expanded their activity to meet increased demand from borrowers that could not access traditional lending. From 2006 to 2009, the median fund deployment ratio grew 3.1 percent annually.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB5D22B8D752E4A5B8772A99EAEF9E63E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>After Superstorm Sandy, CDFIs launched disaster recovery loan programs and reached out to affected businesses and organizations to provide credit to help grocery stores and social service organizations re-open to help communities in need.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBE11B62DCC4A4B468AF6CD9AE5C9BA24"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A 2014 report by the Dardin School of Business at the University of Virginia found that despite serving predominately low-income markets, CDFI banks and credit unions had virtually the same level of performance as mainstream financial institutions.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H3CEBFA59FCBD49279B800FE53CE8433B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grants to establish loan-loss reserve funds for small business lending</header>
 <subsection id="H881B1808414C4B8AAAEDE9030D3AA47B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Community Development Banking and Financial Institutions Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4701">12 U.S.C. 4701</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2FD951465B6045AC9BEA73137F480DDD" style="OLC">
					<section id="H938322FE02AC43C58D253D74850EDA46"><enum>123.</enum><header>Grants to establish loan-loss reserve funds for small business lending</header>
 <subsection id="H875D9B996D5A403E92426A9417D11C88"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purposes of this section are—</text> <paragraph id="H6F02E0A469714E5EAAE680394DF1E692"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to make financial assistance available from the Fund in order to help community development financial institutions defray the costs of operating small business loan programs, by providing the amounts necessary for such institutions to establish their own loan loss reserve funds to mitigate some of the losses on such small business loan programs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6893DF08CCDA4DB98BC12CDC3E3F6F46"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to encourage community development financial institutions to establish and maintain small business loan programs that would help provide borrowers access to mainstream financial institutions and combat high cost small business lending; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H42D2489A93C74E77960392470A76AAC5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to encourage community development financial institutions to expand the development services they offer and to serve new investment areas and new targeted populations.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB74D9624206F493EBB5C7C9F2C3C62A2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants</header>
							<paragraph id="H06FC29AB694D4557AF34990EA97B5EE2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Loan-loss reserve fund grants</header>
 <subparagraph id="H456AF87347B54DE9B44B46AFB7778E33"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Fund shall make grants to community development financial institutions to enable such institutions to establish a loan-loss reserve fund in order to defray the costs of a small business loan program established or maintained by such institution.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8A6494AD08E4357999F5F2F0A124EF2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Application</header><text>A community development financial institution that wishes to receive a grant under this paragraph shall submit an application to the Administrator in such form and manner and containing such information as the Administrator may require.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2985C475D0F4B0EA576BD1BC1FDEE73"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Matching requirement</header><text>A community development financial institution shall provide non-Federal matching funds in an amount equal to 50 percent of the amount of any grant received under this paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C535FA817D8489CBD16E3BD114C06C8"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Any grant amounts received by a community development financial institution under this paragraph—</text> <clause id="H79A102243B55457582675AE3F51D5532"><enum>(i)</enum><text>may not be used by such institution to provide direct loans to small businesses;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H95796F024A4A4CBE9A7E21C38662C65D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may be used by such institution to help recapture a portion or all of a defaulted loan made under the small business loan program of such institution on or after the date of the enactment of this section; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1E032DE299114037A8DA7AF2C7AAAF6E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>may be used to designate and utilize a fiscal agent for services normally provided by such an agent.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H38385B5D20214449BC0C5888C0A69D6C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical assistance grants</header>
 <subparagraph id="H3E7BE3B6F2D342C8942CC3BD27C6B3DA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Fund shall make technical assistance grants to community development financial institutions to create, support, or maintain a small business loan program. Any grant amounts received under this paragraph may be used for—</text>
 <clause id="H5166CA286E514E5B96673CBCD213FF3E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>technology, staff support, staff capacity building, and other costs associated with establishing, supporting, or maintaining a small business loan program; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2963EF3C4E5642BAA8004983926364F8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>establishing, supporting, or maintaining technical assistance programs for borrowers.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA2C77C40907A4EAC879B8D0B71BC2255"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Application</header><text>A community development financial institution that wishes to receive a grant under this paragraph shall submit an application to the Administrator in such form and manner and containing such information as the Administrator may require.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCB6F2614B99A4664B85486E0A87F61B7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>For each fiscal year for which grants are made under this section, the Administrator shall submit a report to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate containing a description of the activities funded and amounts distributed under this section for such fiscal year, as well as measurable results of such actions.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H1C2D5D1A43F349369C6A73EF8919E798"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <paragraph id="H66C3BCFFC7CC49D29DB044F555DE5EC8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Fund $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 to 2023 to carry out this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H86A963FE05AA4CF7905FB19B8EF7061B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Fund $2,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 to 2023 for the administrative costs of carrying out this section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H02F788D703E64DB087F5C019CC80FA12"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text> <paragraph id="H9E4EC32AA4244063BDF28D9051A13774"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Small business</header><text>The term <quote>small business</quote> has the meaning given the term <quote>small business concern</quote> under section 3(a) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632(a)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC893CF1866014A1EA7E54BF5A1723F3A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Small business loan program</header><text>The term <quote>small business loan program</quote> means a loan program wherein a community development financial institution offers loans to small businesses that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF621A97493204FBBA4539D3A0EED1D20"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are made in amounts not exceeding $50,000;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7EC586B9423947789179323543CBB0D9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have no pre-payment penalty; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD33675C889684140A335121455DA0629"><enum>(C)</enum><text>meet any other affordability requirements as may be established by the Administrator.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H6109D1CF21744F7C995C33F169A2A2B6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for the Riegle Community Development and Regulatory Improvement Act of 1994 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 121 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H09150A8D9A1B42D59DC5587272D0E75A" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 122. Grants to establish loan-loss reserve funds.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 123. Grants to establish loan-loss reserve funds for small business lending.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


