<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H449BE5141A7444A0BBEFB56F93B8B309" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 736 IH: Black Box Privacy Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 736</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170130">January 30, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001037">Mr. Capuano</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require automobile manufacturers to disclose to consumers the presence of event data recorders,
			 or <quote>black boxes</quote>, on new automobiles, and to require manufacturers to provide the consumer with the option to
			 enable and disable such devices on future automobiles.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HD1C10E025BE64A4CA59630C9E31163B7" style="OLC">
 <section id="HD80E1409AD6E469298A03037E0B86310" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Black Box Privacy Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H872B5303FE99443EA4879745547C0EE3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HEB2660836E654554B348D8B3CF22D1EF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Consumers have the right to know that event data recorders are installed in their vehicles, that they are capable of collecting data recorded in automobile accidents, and how such data may be used.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDA711BF4702D41A19F835331FE58C2A9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>From the standpoint of consumer privacy rights, most consumers are not aware that their vehicles are recording data that not only may be used to aid traffic safety analyses, but has the potential of being used against them in a civil or criminal proceeding, or by their insurer to increase rates.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HAD219C4D17D843B1B7E3ED53D1027A78"><enum>3.</enum><header>Disclosure of event data recorders on Automobiles and motorcycles</header>
 <subsection id="H02F71F7499DF418CA257A992C7B7FD0D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Labeling disclosure for automobiles</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3 of the Automobile Information Disclosure Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1232">15 U.S.C. 1232</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H3ECFB44469484F59A0AE2256AC6B8773"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (g)(4)(B) by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC2246AA3B724D91B6C5FD67669AD1DE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (h), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H09AAD75A0D144DF78FF4437307002554"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H67D7B7E874464B0C865EDA7955F441E0" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="HB2ADE658D45D455FA63A493446350FD6" indent="down1"><enum>(i)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H632009D3E3A14F98937AC4A50CC4507A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the presence and location of an event data recorder;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6597819E72784A34A32FF20C799E5566" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the type of information recorded by the event data recorder and how such information is recorded; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCCAA39D1A7054C5D8E85CA8CFFCB1CA8" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>that the information recorded by the event data recorder also may be used in a law enforcement proceeding.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4813DE71C27F4CFDB80A77079105DE3F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Labeling disclosure for motorcycles</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Automobile Information Disclosure Act is further amended by adding after section 3 the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3403B5342A2242D3BE1EB23CB0BF1108" style="OLC">
 <section id="HD78C7799A6E548F9B80DBFB866876CC9"><enum>3A.</enum><header>Disclosure of event data recorders on motorcycles</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Every manufacturer of new motorcycles distributed in commerce shall, prior to the delivery of any new motorcycle to any dealer, or at or prior to the introduction date of new models delivered to a dealer prior to such introduction date, securely affix to the new motorcycle a label on which such manufacturer shall disclose—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7CE950B38EA94301855B8BA2D136D4A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the presence and location of an event data recorder;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5061B8EBAAF34D99909D72D5A66785BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the type of information recorded by the event data recorder and how such information is recorded; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6D2B1ECDE6B9452686AD88BAD68063A0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>that the information recorded by the event data recorder also may be used in a law enforcement proceeding.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H30274536CF9A41CDB94FA44F70705C6F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1231">15 U.S.C. 1231</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDEFC6A1E88BF462BA6040F4F6A854C46" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HAE51D43F795749D9BFCB84AEFE515BAC"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>event data recorder</term> means any device or means of technology installed in an automobile that records information such as automobile or motorcycle speed, seatbelt use, application of brakes or other information pertinent to the operation of the automobile or motorcycle, as applicable.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H9CEE340519484482B2B934C1E9F684E8"><enum>(j)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>motorcycle</term> means a vehicle having a seat or saddle for the use of the rider, designed to travel on not more than three wheels in contact with the ground, and weighing less than 1,500 pounds.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF807A55D5AD74F279CAA0B919D048200"><enum>(k)</enum><text>The term <term>new motorcycle</term> means a motorcycle the equitable or legal title to which has never been transferred by a manufacturer, distributor, or dealer to an ultimate purchaser.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCA5367D696CF4E1E96E776B9BAAC9940"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Within 180 days following the enactment of this Act, the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration shall prescribe regulations setting forth a uniform method by which a manufacturer shall provide the disclosures required by the amendments made by this section.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HE8A5038C8390410DA641638140FAD476"><enum>4.</enum><header>Requirement for event data recorders on New Automobiles</header>
 <subsection id="HA71C06A86AF348968534AEFE7B6D759E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/301">chapter 301</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3F4F5ECB37DA42DD954522398B864F55" style="USC">
 <section id="HDD0A0B79C586407184D072FC436F75B8"><enum>30129.</enum><header>Event data recorders</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No person may manufacture for sale, sell, offer for sale, introduce or deliver into interstate commerce, or import into the United States, an automobile manufactured after 2015 (and bearing a model year of 2016 or later) that is equipped with an event data recorder, unless such event data recorder includes a function whereby the consumer can control the recording of information by the event data recorder.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4227AAA70E5548D392B3C6B5DC0231B2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 30165(a)(1) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/301">chapter 301</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>30129,</quote> after <quote>30127,</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H924807518EC241A6856B23A6A991E933"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Table of contents amendment</header><text>The table of contents for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/301">chapter 301</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding after the item relating to section 30128 the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4538BBFDCBAE4D7B90FDB62B11EC0AA2" style="USC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">30129. Event data recorders.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="HA485E48077D0435FA0F4494D2CB7237B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Ownership and unlawful retrieval of event data recorder data</header>
 <subsection id="H5FDE8A09F97F4EB7A71B3C6515734F17"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Ownership Rights; Conduct Prohibited</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any event data recorder in an automobile or motorcycle and any data recorded on any event data recorder in an automobile or motorcycle shall be considered the property of the owner of the automobile or motorcycle. It shall be unlawful for any person other than the owner of the automobile or motorcycle to download or otherwise retrieve data that is recorded on any event data recorder except under one of the following circumstances:</text>
 <paragraph id="HEC3B481100664B9D8B73B34D4C6FE664"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The owner of the automobile or motorcycle or the owner’s agent or legal representative consents to the retrieval of the information.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5646610FD4C3422EB7120A8E69034A26"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In response to an order of a court having jurisdiction to issue the order.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEED2073154A44C8FA9740090BD4E2EC9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The data is retrieved by a dealer, or by an automotive technician for the purpose of diagnosing, servicing, or repairing the automobile or motorcycle.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA13BA43599C343AF9ECD03A8866D4671"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment of Violations as Unfair or Deceptive Acts or Practices</header><text>A violation of subsection (a) shall be treated as a violation of a rule defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice prescribed under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H71EECE7C4D3445C9849C14135BD2F866"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement by the Federal Trade Commission</header><text>The Federal Trade Commission shall enforce this section in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41</external-xref> et seq.) were incorporated into and made a part of this section.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H606E5FC095EB46299ADCA309937E54E1"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">As used in this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H059FB88C4A8A401D8245C17C9CB6CD75"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>consumer</term> has the meaning given the term <term>ultimate purchaser</term> in section 2 of the Automobile Information Disclosure Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1231">15 U.S.C. 1231</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H37CC3DACA6E54948891149AAB349D16A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>dealer</term> has the meaning given that term in section 30102(a) of title 49, United States Code.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H69B78D57F8FD463BBB7F26F7DE7F2142"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>event data recorder</term> means any device or means of technology installed in an automobile that records information such as vehicle speed, seatbelt use, application of brakes or other information pertinent to the operation of the automobile.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H868FC330C81543C19F9F3DAE1D8B886A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The terms <term>manufacturer</term>, <term>new automobile</term>, and <term>new motorcycle</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 2 of the Automobile Information Disclosure Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1231">15 U.S.C. 1231</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H31A87AC1BAB84B7F9463A995A8B6E5D4"><enum>7.</enum><header>Effective Date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act and the amendments made by this Act shall take effect 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


