<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB0D295CA61164C14A2EDE3684C9E2616" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3726 IH: Stark Administrative Simplification Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3726</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170911">September 11, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001158">Mr. Marchant</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001181">Mr. Meehan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to create alternative sanctions for technical
			 noncompliance with the Stark rule under Medicare, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H4792C764BA174A588721532C3D3D7D1E" style="OLC">
 <section id="HD7D5A872BA6E4A468DAA6BEBE70DF31D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stark Administrative Simplification Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HB5CA2B257E48412C854A40EACA310FB4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Alternative sanctions for technical noncompliance with Stark rule under Medicare</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1877 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395nn">42 U.S.C. 1395nn</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDCA13927D51C4E63B55C2471684D7E4F" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="H9F265FC926C246378F6F07E10A1A28A5"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Self-Disclosure protocols</header>
 <paragraph id="H6A8D34525323482191FFE84F517CAD5C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Beginning one year after the date of the enactment of this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="HF5B658ADA0A94410A5F487EACCCD7C8A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an entity or individual may voluntarily disclose a compensation arrangement with actual or potential inadvertent technical noncompliance with subsection (a)(1) (as defined in paragraph (3)(G)) pursuant to either the self-referral disclosure protocol (defined in paragraph (2)) or the alternative protocol for technical noncompliance under paragraph (3);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H210F8EDCD34F45D8B7AB3864763D018F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disclosures voluntarily withdrawn from the alternative protocol for technical noncompliance may be submitted to the self-referral disclosure protocol; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H320C05EF0F4D47D3A805CFFB68FCADAA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an entity that, prior to the establishment of the alternative protocol for technical noncompliance, disclosed to the self-referral disclosure protocol a compensation arrangement that was in inadvertent technical noncompliance with subsection (a)(1), may elect, not later than one year after such alternative protocol is established, to withdraw such disclosure from the self-referral disclosure protocol and instead submit the disclosure to such alternative protocol.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD8DBA9FDDD0E4CB0AD362E53F6FAEF46"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Self-referral disclosure protocol</header><text>The term <term>self-referral disclosure protocol</term> or <term>SRDP</term> means the protocol specified in section 6409 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H672758113B6B46EA95542586B26F9B4E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Alternative protocol for inadvertent technical noncompliance</header> <subparagraph id="HF2D2A19CDBEB4604A1198D6A67ADB03C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish, not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this subsection, an alternative protocol for technical noncompliance (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>APTN</quote>) to enable entities to disclose arrangements that were previously in inadvertent technical noncompliance with subsection (a)(1) and, upon the Secretary’s acceptance of the disclosure, make payment of a civil monetary penalty. Payment of such civil monetary penalty for an arrangement shall resolve only overpayments due and owing as a result of such arrangement’s inadvertent technical noncompliance with this section. The provisions of section 6409 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref> shall not apply to this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC3FBCD87CCC4AB2A4511D862990B3D9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Disclosure requirements</header><text>Arrangements disclosed to the APTN must—</text> <clause id="H0943248721FC44049E251FC1A0975548"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">involve only inadvertent technical noncompliance with subsection (a)(1) that was ended by termination or expiration of the arrangement, or by action of the parties to the arrangement to resolve the technical noncompliance, prior to the date of submission of the disclosure to the APTN;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD59E7784DDD547DBBB37CFA1CBB386E9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be made in the form and manner specified by the Secretary on the public Internet website of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services and include descriptions of—</text>
 <subclause id="H7FA3D2FBAB7F4E9EB7087A8061A13C4E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the compensation arrangement that was in technical noncompliance with subsection (a)(1);</text> </subclause><subclause id="H4F408574CFB84C1FB57A1E8C5900DBF2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>how and when the technical noncompliance with subsection (a)(1) was ended or the arrangement was otherwise terminated; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD16ECD4287BD4BC3A6AF5E2C79E7AB30"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the remuneration paid under the compensation arrangement being disclosed was—</text> <item id="HB4B6DEFA89B54806A5D8BAC2A26112C0"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>consistent with the fair market value of the items and services that were provided under the compensation arrangement; and</text>
 </item><item id="HFEAC06118D8E4DEEB939AC1196394FFC"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>not determined in a manner that directly or indirectly takes into account the volume or value of referrals or other business generated between the parties;</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause id="H37244FB387224FD781D925E4F08519FC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>include a form settlement agreement provided by the Secretary signed by the entity; and</text> </clause><clause id="H74BA1DBDE30A418393BD2AD8D2313E6B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>include a certification from the entity that, to the best of the entity’s knowledge, the information provided is truthful information and is based on a good faith effort to bring the matter to the Secretary’s attention.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2EF5F4B78904A6BBD6B9DD07A530DAB"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Acceptance or rejection of disclosure by the secretary</header><text>The following rules shall apply to the acceptance or rejection of a disclosure under the APTN:</text> <clause id="H092736F4D95449B2B54DB231315E09C5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Secretary shall accept or reject a complete, accurate, and timely disclosure.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H47DD514AB8A9438985DC202F14AEE28C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Upon receipt of a disclosure, the Secretary shall notify the disclosing party of such receipt.</text> </clause><clause id="HFD322EFDC63445CB95B3927856BAAE7F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The Secretary may request additional information from the disclosing party.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H339B38C02BE34DC68E282144CCBD7086"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon acceptance by the Secretary, the Secretary shall notify the disclosing party in writing of such acceptance.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE82471F0B0A24B4893A499E3947DC323"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The disclosure shall be rejected if—</text> <subclause id="HC98539CD93194BDB82660959BBFA9AAC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the disclosing party fails to furnish the additional information requested by the Secretary in such form and manner as the Secretary may specify; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB9F63831B39C4C17BF521801A949E33F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the Secretary’s sole determination, the noncompliance disclosed did not meet the disclosure requirements specified in subparagraph (B).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HF4BEC739984D449AA9BC7A7C347A3B13"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The disclosure shall be accepted if the Secretary—</text> <subclause id="H1E5471BC1EA84881BFB3F477D5B909B7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>has issued a written notice to the disclosing party that the disclosure is determined to satisfy the requirements for disclosures under this section; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H901FC0602100464E962C7BFAB0B6C83F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>has not rejected a complete, accurate, and timely disclosure that satisfies each of the requirements for disclosures under this section and 180 calendar days have passed since notification of receipt by the Secretary of the disclosure.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HAC9DD322A8664922A750D37A387FF581"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>In determining whether to accept a disclosure, the Secretary may reasonably rely on the information and certifications included in the disclosure.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3BB08C6E83C478CA6760BF5F19E6B43"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Withdrawal of disclosure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prior to acceptance or rejection of a disclosure by the Secretary, an entity may voluntarily withdraw such disclosure from the APTN.</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8EE8E41CBB6481CBB0D67105EA86610"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Civil monetary penalties pursuant to the alternative protocol for technical noncompliance</header>
 <clause id="HBCA9BB16AF4649A182B06E2DFE5E61FC"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to clause (ii), for each arrangement disclosed under this subsection and accepted under subparagraph (C), the Secretary shall impose a single civil monetary penalty of—</text>
 <subclause id="HAB8F8CD177C54B03BB5EF4409D39C29E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>$5,000, in the case in which disclosure of the inadvertent technically noncompliant compensation arrangement was submitted to the Secretary not later than the date that is one year after the initial date of inadvertent technical noncompliance with subsection (a)(1); or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H74492B1DCD8B4BF9937C81BF0782DF81"><enum>(II)</enum><text>$10,000, in the case in which the disclosure of the technically noncompliant compensation arrangement was submitted to the Secretary—</text>
 <item id="H552A6FAF577146578F3409D29282DBB2"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>after the date that is more than one year after the initial date of the entity’s inadvertent technical noncompliance with subsection (a)(1); and</text>
 </item><item id="H3A42EB3775F24F829B9489B698343E6B"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>not after the date that is 3 years (or, in the case of a disclosure submitted after the 5th year for which this subsection applies, the date that is 2 years) from the initial date of the entity’s inadvertent technical noncompliance with subsection (a)(1).</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause id="H5205D23EFCBD4ECDB08EB1361C92C2BE"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Special rule for entities that disclosed to the aptn after withdrawing a disclosure from the srdp</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an entity that elects under paragraph (1)(C) to withdraw a disclosure from the self-referral disclosure protocol and instead submit the disclosure to the APTN under this subsection, in determining the applicable civil monetary penalty under clause (i), the date of disclosure to the self-referral disclosure protocol (as defined in paragraph (2)) shall be substituted for the date of disclosure to the APTN.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9CE1629E5EC40BC81E1A30EA291DED2"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Relation to advisory opinions</header><text>The APTN shall be separate from the advisory opinion process set forth in regulations implementing subsection (g) of this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4117A85937514549B18A7F4F9B8C7519"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Publication on internet website of aptn information</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall post information on the public Internet website of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services to inform relevant stakeholders of how to disclose and make payment of a civil monetary penalty for inadvertent technical noncompliance with subsection (a)(1).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H989BC6F3B1364CEC89913AE7448071A4"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <clause id="H7D9D4FC6297F40969A26D4B0E3B0263A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Technical noncompliance</header><text>The term <term>technical noncompliance with subsection (a)(1)</term> means, with respect to a compensation arrangement, that—</text>
 <subclause id="HDBC6F91272EC47F28701AE0947F606D7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the arrangement is not signed by one or more parties to the arrangement;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H48A281CD15D244DF8BBC066924F31DAE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>following the expiration of the arrangement, the arrangement was a holdover arrangement for a period longer than permitted in regulations issued by the Secretary; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HEC0482DD4BAB442F9904AB3D53D320D5"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the contemporaneous written documentation evidencing the terms of the arrangement identifies the parties to the arrangement and the items, services, space, or equipment, as applicable, but is not sufficient to satisfy the writing requirement of an applicable exception.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="H0D6EE3D2DB294F66B60B3748DCE747CD"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Inadvertent</header><text>The term <term>inadvertent</term> means, with respect to a compensation arrangement that is in noncompliance, that an entity that is a party to the compensation arrangement did not know or should not have known of the noncompliance.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA36085ADCEBB46B08C06A5AAD1BC45C7"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Administration</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">Chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code, shall not apply to this subsection.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57BBA79CC9974DA584AACE941F0FC536"><enum>(J)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may implement the provisions of this paragraph by program instruction or otherwise.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


