<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF43391C185BF4F509468143D9891C7E7" key="S" public-private="public" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3210 RS: Securely Expediting Clearances Through Reporting Transparency Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 264</calendar><congress>115th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3210</legis-num><associated-doc role="report">[Report No. 115–185]</associated-doc><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20170727">July 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSGA00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><action stage="Reported-in-Senate"><action-date>November 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Reported by <sponsor name-id="S345">Mr. Johnson</sponsor>, with an amendment</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Director of the National Background Investigations Bureau to submit a report on the
			 backlog of personnel security clearance investigations, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HE2449C3830B349158A7E0A05BEC3CED8" style="OLC">
 <section changed="deleted" committee-id="SSGA00" id="H63886E7B730A4250B7AAE9D92E8B185B" reported-display-style="strikethrough" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Securely Expediting Clearances Through Reporting Transparency Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SECRET Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section changed="deleted" committee-id="SSGA00" id="H5518DF68C35C4884900A2C26C431BD22" reported-display-style="strikethrough" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on backlog of personnel security clearance investigations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and quarterly thereafter for 5 years, the Director of the National Background Investigations Bureau of the Office of Personnel Management shall submit to Congress a report on the backlog of security clearance investigations that includes—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC99F9C40F36744F7BE5D193C1CCB94C2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the size of the personnel security clearance investigation process backlog; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD29A03FBE56D402CAC40D2B36B603ECC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the average length of time, for each sensitivity level, to carry out an initial investigation and a periodic investigation.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section changed="deleted" committee-id="SSGA00" id="H56C2C1003FE748F19F3A71ADB849F06F" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report on Security Clearance Investigations of personnel of the Executive Office of the President</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the National Background Investigations Bureau of the Office of Personnel Management shall submit to Congress a report that explains the process for conducting and adjudicating security clearance investigations for personnel of the Executive Office of the President, including White House personnel.</text>
 </section><section changed="deleted" committee-id="SSGA00" id="H9A0C5B7938144963969C6AE8B3D8EE9E" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report on duplicative costs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the National Background Investigations Bureau of the Office of Personnel Management shall submit to Congress a report on the cost of duplicating resources under the control or direction of the National Background Investigations Bureau for implementation of the plan referenced in section 951(a)(1) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/1564">10 U.S.C. 1564</external-xref> note).</text></section></legis-body>
	<legis-body display-enacting-clause="no-display-enacting-clause">
 <section changed="added" committee-id="SSGA00" id="id5bef54c2c882462bab7749c16ab1be26" reported-display-style="italic" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Securely Expediting Clearances Through Reporting Transparency Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SECRET Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section changed="added" committee-id="SSGA00" id="id0009bce40267474986838d64de912e3f" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on backlog of personnel security clearance investigations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and quarterly thereafter for 5 years, the Director of the National Background Investigations Bureau of the Office of Personnel Management shall submit to Congress a report on the backlog of security clearance investigations that includes, for the most recent full calendar quarter—</text>
 <paragraph id="id720c22f21b5b44fb86de5d8f1d6b36e0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the size of the personnel security clearance investigation process backlog, including, for each sensitivity level—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id5c7148520c8e4933a52eb9006369bcea"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of interim clearances granted;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id728ebe54a63a4519beadcc2e3ddd5bc5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of initial investigations for Federal employees;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1aa5e6e40c83482c819b239b87bdbfea"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number of periodic reinvestigations for Federal employees;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaf3864b1f57245e9b19f3ac491afa08c"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the number of initial investigations for employees of Federal contractors;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida81ff2f82562462aa15faed380ae76d8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the number of periodic reinvestigations for employees of Federal contractors;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3eb806aac12848659b73a79f381cbd7d"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the number of initial investigations for employees of, and employees of contractors of, the Department of Defense;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf345de92ad764ea1b0a1e0ca8bd5c3f6"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the number of periodic reinvestigations for employees of and employees of contractors of the Department of Defense;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8bfaadb86a2c44e59954fe9c18d10fe4"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the number of Federal employees conducting background investigations; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id166a569003ea438c916534d8bced40bc"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the number of employees of Federal contractors conducting background investigations;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5beca435b2984b508beb0b124de95c3b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the average length of time, for each sensitivity level, to carry out an initial investigation and a periodic reinvestigation;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6710260f4aa8450dbdb95e79280f10be"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a discussion of the factors contributing to the average length of time to carry out an initial investigation and a periodic reinvestigation;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5569A1D3AC2E474E9A9554DA2618378D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a backlog mitigation plan, which shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="idD27894CE3A7746B188F409C8E859E7A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the identification of the cause of, and recommendations to remedy, the backlog;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id84EBF51D8C004F83A239BEBF9EBD1D9D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the steps the Director shall take to reduce the backlog;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ideacfbde12ff14ee995e88119a5f7ce51"><enum>(C)</enum><text>process reforms to improve efficiencies in, and the quality of, background investigations; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id70E8868F1915428495A8DDA584307383"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a projection of when the backlog will be sufficiently reduced to meet required timeliness standards; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idcbf0de81551e4f41ae8be2925cca22b0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a description of improvements in information and data security.</text> </paragraph></section><section changed="added" committee-id="SSGA00" id="id6e7744cf4aad4e9fbf137749d979baf7" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report on security clearance investigations of personnel of the executive office of the president</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Administration of the Executive Office of the President shall submit to Congress a report that explains the process for conducting and adjudicating security clearance investigations for personnel of the Executive Office of the President, including White House personnel.</text>
 </section><section changed="added" committee-id="SSGA00" id="id3cbec58a5aad4f2abf4204bad210b65a" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report on duplicative costs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in consultation with the other members of the Suitability and Security Clearance Performance Accountability Council established under Executive Order 13467 (73 Fed. Reg. 38103), shall submit to Congress a report on the cost of duplicating resources under the control or direction of the National Background Investigations Bureau for implementation of the plan referenced in section 951(a)(1) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/1564">10 U.S.C. 1564</external-xref> note).</text>
 </section><section changed="added" committee-id="SSGA00" id="idD28F86657E1147E2B4040463B1F3036F" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report on continuous evaluation and reciprocity</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of National Intelligence and the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall submit to Congress a report that provides—</text>
 <paragraph id="id8eeaefc085444e2aaacce6a1b93cfd8d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the status of implementing continuous evaluation Governmentwide, including—</text> <subparagraph id="idf4e2fe3a69f94f6485673919733f7613"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of agencies with continuous evaluation programs and how many of those programs are currently meeting the investigative standards;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8458cb4c858a43c0891b7853de3e3911"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a risk assessment of replacing current reinvestigation requirements with continuous evaluation programs by 2020;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5db2ed795df94d029d90ecd707799dd5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a discussion of the barriers for agencies to implement continuous evaluation programs, including any requirement under a statute, regulation, Executive Order, or other administrative requirement; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9a1bc38f8cac470a97bfd8dcff3295af"><enum>(D)</enum><text>plans, including timelines, for implementing continuous evaluation Governmentwide and phasing out periodic reinvestigations;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9b251ffc14e540568373543993a9adb9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a detailed explanation of efforts by agencies to meet requirements for reciprocal recognition to access classified information, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id3579faf5421445aa80c50ea5e9fe0e64"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the range of the length of time for agencies to grant reciprocal recognition to access classified information;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9497a7669418404b95dbaad7c6ef15bf"><enum>(B)</enum><text>additional requirements for reinvestigations or readjudications, by agency; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide17d88da6128466ab4e232d9fed8f7c3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other barriers to the timely granting of reciprocity, by agency, including any requirement under a statute, regulation, Executive Order, or other administrative requirement;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0b9653ba3a5a4e488c2a7b855be347dc"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommendations, including timelines, to improve the background investigation process to—</text> <subparagraph id="ide1cde1c58ed2443e9ae72a36d61078d4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>simplify the Questionnaire for National Security Positions (Standard Form 86) and increase customer support for applicants completing such questionnaire;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3510fb703bd24c6db41afb983ef89417"><enum>(B)</enum><text>use remote and virtual techniques and centralized locations during field investigation work;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idebc1e44d843b426c95d770247493f32a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>use secure and reliable digitization of information obtained during the clearance process; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id34b840e19e6148149f4c53399985ad0d"><enum>(D)</enum><text>build the capacity of the background investigation labor sector; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id40de13824d064f53a804a66737312927"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a review of whether the schedule for processing security clearances under section 3001 of the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3341">50 U.S.C. 3341</external-xref>) should be modified.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section changed="added" committee-id="SSGA00" id="id174c4eccef7445b49939bac34153a7d3" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>6.</enum><header>Review and update of position designation guidance</header>
 <subsection id="id8a9e7d25c73b4b848844f0a6b56b6a94"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="id9e9294ab38e74c4e921832a923ba2ecb"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given the term in Executive Order 13467 (73 Fed. Reg. 38103), or any successor thereto;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6DC4B422BB5642889EB8EBE4F1FB9683"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="idf337bdaab93f41fd820dab2ec781238b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idba8d4d549a194f0d9f8f14240109116a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd5eca416ee304435ae0fdcf03fe9d8fc"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>background investigation</term> means any investigation required for the purpose of determining the—</text> <subparagraph id="idc99a7b07649d47f1841b5ed71a874b27"><enum>(A)</enum><text>eligibility of a covered individual for logical and physical access to Federally controlled facilities or information systems;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9dc1a3e4685f4d4d873a9c88d331551c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>suitability or fitness of a covered individual for Federal employment;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id81f3212a921e417095f37753e381897a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>eligibility of a covered individual for access to classified information or to hold a national security sensitive position; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id87644f5ae61a4a7fa43ebe730529d64c"><enum>(D)</enum><text>fitness of a covered individual to perform work for or on behalf of the United States Government as a contractor employee; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide51f0b6e6e854659b277729d415be9b0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>covered individual</term> means an individual who—</text> <subparagraph id="id1f52645cebc7458f822f8e3dfba24a4a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>performs work for or on behalf of an agency; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcb14af0587c24783be0815c691727438"><enum>(B)</enum><text>seeks to perform work for or on behalf of an agency.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id618E8E0C26C348459A51BBBA67BA9335"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review and updating</header> <paragraph id="id057F35F3DCF24B46949AD963AE90BD03"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial review and update of guidance</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the President shall review and, if appropriate, update the guidance the President issues to assist agencies in determining—</text>
 <subparagraph id="ided54b4942dba440889ff0af1c245739e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>position sensitivity designation; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8747c3687d4843d1a5bb55c2d06e36db"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the appropriate background investigation to initiate for each position designation.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id25ff1430dc5746f0a6fe349c665818ed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reviews and revisions of position designations</header><text>Not less frequently than every 4 years, the President, acting through relevant agencies (as determined by the President) and in accordance with the guidance described in paragraph (1), shall review and, if necessary, revise the position designation of positions within agencies.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf86ffefce270480883c278c5f4f591f9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text>Not later than 30 days after completing a review under subsection (b)(2), the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on—</text>
 <paragraph id="id02ce5d2f9df4465fbc0c013d7ba00b1a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any issues identified in the review; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id54eeb8ddc3ad4359a29902fb3a6c155a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of position designations revised as a result of the review.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4d7ef4f6f80843aca1358bd762da926a"><enum>(d)</enum><header>No change in authority</header><text>Nothing in this section limits or expands the authority of any agency to designate a position as sensitive or as requiring its occupant to have access to classified information.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement><action-date>November 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment</action-desc></endorsement></bill>


