<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HBFCD1162AC7C40F9B179A3C5BB7E8697" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2595 IH: Strengthening the Department of Homeland Security Secure Mail Initiative Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2595</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170523">May 23, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="W000810">Mr. Woodall</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to provide for an option under the Secure Mail
			 Initiative under which a person to whom a document is sent under that
			 initiative may elect to have the United States Postal Service use the Hold
			 for Pickup service or the Signature Confirmation service in delivering the
			 document, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HDEEF0A974BF9431880F4CB663AC5EB4F" style="OLC">
 <section id="HBCD4B032116E4085B0DD13F2C4C59417" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthening the Department of Homeland Security Secure Mail Initiative Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HE2CE3A944F334F9C9234D73F69656C8E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7549868A196C43E9BB847AE6126D7B50"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the terms <term>Hold for Pickup service</term> and <term>Signature Confirmation service</term> means the services described in sections 508.7.2.1 and 503.8.1.1.a, respectively, of the Domestic Mail Manual (or any successor services);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H33F386532F884878B4AC17A1F66D7F72"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>Immigration Examinations Fee Account</term> means the account established under section 286(m) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1356">8 U.S.C. 1356(m)</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBF88A356B438420C92B26C7D53B21C1C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>Postal Service</term> means the United States Postal Service; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1225EF9F58724FED9BAA3406075EE9F6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H3BED127398C14CE483A690178CDF93E4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Offering Hold for Pickup and Signature Confirmation services under the Secure Mail Initiative</header>
 <subsection id="H20F2AEDC090B420D9D1EE67006A3B130"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall provide for an option under the Secure Mail Initiative (or any successor program) under which a person to whom a document is sent under that initiative may elect, except as provided in subsection (e), to have the Postal Service use the Hold for Pickup service or the Signature Confirmation service in delivering the document.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HE8ECE24957144F679C003F167EB9CE5F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Fee</header>
 <paragraph id="H1111A92CE01F458392EF3F0C21F68410"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in accordance with section 286(m) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1356">8 U.S.C. 1356(m)</external-xref>), shall require the payment of a fee from a person electing a service under subsection (a), which shall be set at a level that ensures recovery of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEC83BE4347924F3491E00F4EEAAB7C33"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the full costs of providing all such services; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE3115391433C43F29E2BE17A1736D113"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any additional costs associated with the administration of the fees collected.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF1799D30FD843468452B305FCBF4352"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Allocation of funds</header><text>Of the fees collected under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H790956BD075E4D5994BB79C8BA49807A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>deposit as offsetting receipts into the Immigration Examinations Fee Account the portion representing—</text>
 <clause id="HCB80BC43F8504A8A96D063E194EA82A6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the cost to the Secretary of providing the services under subsection (a); and</text> </clause><clause id="H84B1E8FBD7B745359DFFAE9B993B11D3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any additional costs associated with the administration of the fees collected; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6EEA651652C24A78BEAE499234C81734"><enum>(B)</enum><text>transfer to the Postal Service the portion representing the cost to the Postal Service of providing the services under subsection (a).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCA095A155E6B48FAACDBEACC57787DAD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Postal Service may promulgate regulations that—</text> <paragraph id="HA37B7B06719445528ABCF877D2928A5E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>subject to paragraph (2), minimize the cost of providing the services under subsection (a); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9C0A6EA5373342F2BB0FD376BFBEE598"><enum>(2)</enum><text>do not require the Postal Service to incur additional expenses that are not recoverable under subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H88EE5882AC5F4AEC9529A674FD2911CC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notice of changes</header><text>The Postal Service shall notify the Secretary of any changes to the Hold for Pickup service or the Signature Confirmation service.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H542A1C6967304BA981E0D98B7C331F09"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of private carrier</header>
 <paragraph id="H963D18D9817A4669805908137D701B21"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Secretary determines that a private carrier that offers substantially similar services to the Hold for Pickup and Signature Confirmation services would provide better service and value than the Postal Service provides under subsection (a), the Secretary may, in accordance with paragraph (2) of this subsection—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE2173C34FAA3431984EB3EF214264B70"><enum>(A)</enum><text>discontinue use of the services of the Postal Service under subsection (a); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B8519EAAC874CC59EDC353CF6BA4D9A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enter into a contract with the private carrier under which a person to whom a document is sent under the Secure Mail Initiative (or any successor program) may elect to have the private carrier use one of the substantially similar services in delivering the document.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H47263D17A2584E8094C3C1EE29647535"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The Secretary may not exercise the authority under paragraph (1) unless the Secretary—</text> <subparagraph id="HF6B37B6CC0F7491189F8A2427E092F8A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determines, and notifies the Postal Service, that the private carrier offers services that are substantially similar to the Hold for Pickup and Signature Confirmation services;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22D8C00F9AE447B98471249F8A4D5AA0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides for an option under the Secure Mail Initiative (or any successor program) under which a person to whom a document is sent under that initiative may elect a service under paragraph (1)(B);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H228D53C5F21F43EE9454CA871E684F6F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>requires the payment of a fee from a person electing a service under paragraph (1)(B), which shall be set at a level that ensures recovery of—</text>
 <clause id="H6E8F5865457740B182B70E14D8111EEB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the full cost of contracting with the private carrier to provide all such services; and</text> </clause><clause id="H2550677A88184F97BE05270312B83CDC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any additional costs associated with the administration of the fees collected; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H27406E96FF084A40858722C64D0049A4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>deposits the fees collected under subparagraph (C) as offsetting receipts into the Immigration Examinations Fees Account.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE224BCB7BD4940C1BDD68961D61E712B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that describes—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB2705C80CD55499AB17794FC5E6BB804"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the implementation of the requirements under section 3;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFD5F2A974FF7409DB30BB6DA72258E18"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the fee imposed under subsection (b) or (e)(2)(C), as applicable, of section 3; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H80CA5EC3D9F94B6DB6F5AE81699CE499"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the number of times during the previous year that a person used a service under subsection (a) or (e)(1)(B) of section 3.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


