<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H140C74A3B7034D84BE51A20850A89E58" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1665 IH: Disaster Declaration Improvement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1665</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170322">March 22, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000619">Mr. Rodney Davis of Illinois</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001286">Mrs. Bustos</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To ensure that Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency considers severe local
			 impact in making a recommendation to the President for a major disaster
			 declaration.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HB72AF17644FF4893AD6E9D03ADAF4226" style="OLC">
 <section id="HF041D290D05F42A589AC2BA681488034" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Disaster Declaration Improvement Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H53A6AADCED91419BBAA5E195E0147137"><enum>2.</enum><header>Local impact</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In making recommendations to the President regarding a major disaster declaration, the Administrator shall give greater weight and consideration to severe local impact. Further, the Administrator shall make corresponding adjustments to the Agency’s policies and regulations regarding such consideration. Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator shall report to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate on the changes made to regulations and policies and the number of declarations that have been declared based on the new criteria.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


