<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HDE291C1345BF4DBABEA43DAF3DD7A77A" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 877 IH: Vietnam Helicopter Crew Monument Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 877</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170206">February 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000369">Mr. Amodei</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="A000374">Mr. Abraham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001269">Mr. Barletta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000806">Mr. Webster of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001275">Mr. Bucshon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000583">Mr. Thomas J. Rooney of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000602">Miss Rice of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster of New Hampshire</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001064">Mr. Heck</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001243">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001072">Mr. Hill</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000554">Mr. LoBiondo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001284">Mrs. Brooks of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000586">Mr. Renacci</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001096">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001185">Mr. Sean Patrick Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001289">Mr. Byrne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000583">Mr. Loudermilk</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001179">Mr. Marino</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001192">Mr. Stewart</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001051">Mr. Carter of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000593">Mr. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000804">Mr. Wittman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000591">Mrs. Roby</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000588">Mr. Pearce</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000815">Mr. Wenstrup</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of the Army to place in Arlington National Cemetery a monument honoring the
			 helicopter pilots and crewmembers who were killed while serving on active
			 duty in the Armed Forces during the Vietnam era, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HB9A4653F70964876BDF8578006AEA37F" style="OLC">
 <section id="H5C2B2F193F95438A854F3B9356FFE3CC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Vietnam Helicopter Crew Monument Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HE151B5CDAAE941D6897476E4863F6307"><enum>2.</enum><header>Placement of monument honoring helicopter pilots and crewmembers who were killed while serving on active duty in the Armed Forces during the Vietnam era</header> <subsection id="H0229E243AD034EB7A04E9EFD16D7137A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the requirements of subsection (c), the Secretary of the Army shall place in Arlington National Cemetery a monument honoring helicopter pilots and crewmembers who were killed while serving on active duty in the Armed Forces during the Vietnam era.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H015D317137064233A10A34437E855EB1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Design</header><text>The monument placed under subsection (a) shall measure 4 feet in height, 5 feet in width, and 1 foot in depth, and shall be based on a design approved by the Secretary of the Army and the Vietnam Helicopter Pilots Association.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H26778A9BDDFD4F9CBE6FA964C973F45A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Agreement for construction and maintenance</header><text>The Secretary of the Army may only place a monument under subsection (a) if the Secretary enters into an agreement with the Vietnam Helicopter Pilots Association under which the Association agrees to pay all costs necessary for preparation of the site for the monument (including the activities authorized under subsection (d)(2)) and to construct, install, and maintain the monument, and to such other provisions as the Secretary may require.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H65830908508E440CA5E0E6FA41F5E62B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Site and replacement of existing memorial</header>
 <paragraph id="H266ED9672CBB4857B52E57935B045C16"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The monument described in subsection (a) shall be placed where the Vietnam Helicopter Pilots Association Memorial Tree stood on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1075AFCC643248A38898B5740DB0A78C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Removal of existing memorial</header><text>In placing the monument described in subsection (a) in the place specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Secretary of the Army may remove the Vietnam Helicopter Pilots Association Memorial Tree that was in such location on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


