<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H8958C7C873864F238FDB462ED057A80E" key="H" public-private="public"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2581 RH: Verify First Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 108</calendar>
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2581</legis-num>
<associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 115–161, Part I]</associated-doc>
<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20170522">May 22, 2017</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001269">Mr. Barletta</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000586">Mr. Renacci</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000184">Mrs. Noem</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001274">Mr. Brooks of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000575">Mr. Rogers of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<action>
<action-date date="20170602">June 2, 2017</action-date>
<action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="B001273">Mrs. Black</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000583">Mr. Smith of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000533">Mr. Duncan of Tennessee</cosponsor> </action-desc>
</action>
<action>
<action-date date="20170602">June 2, 2017</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc>
<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction> 
</action>
<action>
<action-date date="20170602">June 2, 2017</action-date>
<action-desc>The <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on May 22, 2017</action-instruction>
</action>
<action display="yes">
<action-desc display="yes"><pagebreak/></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to require the provision of social security numbers as a condition of receiving the health insurance premium tax credit.<pagebreak/></official-title>
</form> 
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HWM00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H3018F17E69884E3D959C78AB061D2973">
<section id="HEC800D3DF910482EABAB5BCD272936B0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Verify First Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H96922116B091486DA24D6F9ED72DEA9D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Verification of status in United States as condition of receiving advance payment of health insurance premium tax credit</header> <subsection id="H494219A7414041F397F95D3C22326FD0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Application to current health insurance premium tax credit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">Section 36B</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as in effect for months beginning before January 1, 2020, is amended by redesignating subsection (g) as subsection (h) and by inserting after subsection (f) the following new subsection:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5316C73D5C9A418F956D64B819DB9720" style="OLC">
<subsection id="H74D83723B5E34A70B63A000EF0B99A80"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Verification of status in United States for advance payment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No advance payment of the credit allowed under this section with respect to any premium under subsection (b)(2)(A) with respect to any individual shall be made under section 1412 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act unless the Secretary has received confirmation from the Secretary of Health and Human Services that the Commissioner of Social Security or the Secretary of Homeland Security has verified under section 1411(c)(2) of such Act the individual’s status as a citizen or national of the United States or an alien lawfully present in the United States using a process that includes the appropriate use of information related to citizenship or immigration status, such as social security account numbers (but not individual taxpayer identification numbers).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HCAB5E9EFA03246258674BFBE653C1B99"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application to new health insurance premium tax credit</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">Section 36B</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended by the American Health Care Act of 2017 and in effect for months beginning after December 31, 2019, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF29F0921101245A782C52481BE9D1800" style="OLC">
<subsection id="H70DFFB4B1F3547E88B43B687554775CC"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Verification of status in United States for advance payment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No advance payment of the credit allowed under this section with respect to any amount under subparagraph (A) or (B) of subsection (b)(1) with respect to any individual shall be made under section 1412 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act unless the Secretary has received confirmation from the Secretary of Health and Human Services that the Commissioner of Social Security or the Secretary of Homeland Security has verified under section 1411(c)(2) of such Act the individual’s status as a citizen or national of the United States or a qualified alien (within the meaning of section 431 of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1641">8 U.S.C. 1641</external-xref>)) using a process that includes the appropriate use of information related to citizenship or immigration status, such as social security account numbers (but not individual taxpayer identification numbers).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HC267B578EB4444BF83BF48FA0EE521BA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendment on continuous health insurance coverage provision</header><text>Section 2710A(b)(1) of the Public Health Service Act, as added by section 133 of the American Health Care Act of 2017, is amended by adding after subparagraph (C) the following: </text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HEE1427ECC080464CAE44A4BC3530D0C8" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<quoted-block-continuation-text quoted-block-continuation-text-level="paragraph">In the case of an individual who applies for advance payment of a credit under section 1412 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act and for whom a determination of eligibility for such advance payment is delayed by reason of the requirement for verification of the individual’s status in the United States under section 1411(c)(2) of such Act, the period of days beginning with the date of application for advance payment and ending with the date of such verification shall not be taken into account in applying subparagraph (B). The Secretary shall establish a procedure by which information relating to this period is provided to the individual.</quoted-block-continuation-text><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="HEB2296EDA2314C989F22C533F22B6EAB" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Delay permitted in coverage date in case of delay in verification of status for individuals applying for advance payment of credit</header><text>Section 1411(e) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18081">42 U.S.C. 18081(e)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H32957D312A8847D281F9BD8480A0EC8F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by inserting after <quote>applicant’s eligibility</quote> the following: <quote>(other than eligibility for advance payment of a credit under section 1412)</quote>; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBCEA1AE3CE0D43AFAA729A30A4792EDB" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HFA350D3F4C9646A68C51C44891BF72D6" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="HFD0ECA027BEA432983AE78BC1B06E523"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Delay permitted in coverage date in case of delay in verification of status for individuals applying for advance payment of credit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an individual whose eligibility for advance payments is delayed by reason of the requirement for verification under subsection (c)(2), if, for coverage to be effective as of the date requested in the individual’s application for enrollment, the individual would (but for this paragraph) be required to pay 2 or more months of retroactive premiums, the individual shall be provided the option to elect to postpone the effective date of coverage to the date that is not more than 1 month later than the date requested in the individual’s application for enrollment. </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H517B5224D3284E7EA2E519CC5FCFEF70"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective dates</header>
<paragraph id="H73A92606B01D4E62A4F73F9224CBFB20"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application to current health insurance premium tax credit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by subsection (a) is contingent upon the enactment of the American Health Care Act of 2017 and shall apply (if at all) to months beginning after December 31, 2017.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0A3A5DBB3FFC4509A0D7D0017F1FEA1D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application to new health insurance premium tax credit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by subsection (b) is contingent upon the enactment of the American Health Care Act of 2017 and shall apply (if at all) to months beginning after December 31, 2019, in taxable years ending after such date.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD07DA40E73E544BD992F52CC2691EC10"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Conforming amendment on continuous health insurance coverage provision</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (c) is contingent upon the enactment of the American Health Care Act of 2017 and shall take effect (if at all) as if included in such Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H507BD1FA33BA496C871E2D86BC08BAAF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Flexibility in coverage date in case of delay in verification of status</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by subsection (d) is contingent upon the enactment of the American Health Care Act of 2017 and shall apply (if at all) to applications for advance payments for months beginning after December 31, 2017.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
</legis-body>
<endorsement display="yes">
<action-date date="20170602">June 2, 2017</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc>
<action-date date="20170602">June 2, 2017</action-date>
<action-desc>The <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill> 


