<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H14717FE649054AEB81DE387E1F140D52" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 303 IH: Retired Pay Restoration Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 303</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170105">January 5, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 10, United States Code, to permit additional retired members of the Armed Forces who
			 have a service-connected disability to receive both disability
			 compensation from the Department of Veterans Affairs for their disability
			 and either retired pay by reason of their years of military service or
			 combat-related special compensation.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HB0A2AEA7CEDF40AA92F8B6CF922FD9D0" style="OLC">
 <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H66207D5CE1E646F3B8D6585BAE648664" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Retired Pay Restoration Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H94677B02C41048638F7657C55AEC2BFA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and sense of Congress</header> <subsection id="H71B32B53DD6646D4AA2136F9F62FA772"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H062F119A81CA4A3184D791144E12B0CA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>For more than 100 years before 1999, all disabled military retirees were required to fund their own veterans’ disability compensation by forfeiting one dollar of earned retired pay for each dollar received in veterans’ disability compensation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4C6B4888754A45FEABB70BC46B28D35A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Since 1999, Congress has enacted legislation to progressively expand eligibility criteria for relief of the retired pay disability offset and reduce the burden of financial sacrifice on disabled military retirees.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H59AE7697276341CDB2BAAC87C132DD2E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Absent adequate funding to eliminate the sacrifice for all disabled retirees, Congress has given initial priority to easing financial inequities for the most severely disabled and for combat-disabled retirees.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2D3EED20BB5E496999115EA0EB795767"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the interest of maximizing eligibility within cost constraints, Congress effectively has authorized full concurrent receipt for all qualifying retirees with 100-percent disability ratings and all qualifying retirees with combat-related disability ratings, while phasing out the disability offset to retired pay over 10 years for retired members with noncombat-related, service-connected disability ratings of 50 percent to 90 percent.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H59CA587FB6B34B87AFF0767822B639AE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In pursuing these good-faith efforts, Congress acknowledges the regrettable necessity of creating new thresholds of eligibility that understandably are disappointing to disabled retirees who fall short of meeting those new thresholds.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCB59F3704C12418E8233DCA335B91D7C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Congress is not content with the status quo.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1300C8EFC81940B896D471E4DF2C9D80"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that military retired pay earned by service and sacrifice in defending the United States should not be reduced because a military retiree is also eligible for veterans’ disability compensation awarded for service-connected disability.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HE042F0A46CF6441FAE33795EE6B3D0F6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Eligibility for payment of both retired pay and veterans’ disability compensation for certain
			 additional military retirees with compensable service-connected
			 disabilities</header>
			<subsection id="HAC309059D56E44C29750A5180910A841"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Extension of Concurrent Receipt Authority to Retirees With Service-Connected Disabilities Rated
 Less Than 50 Percent</header><text>Section 1414(a) of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HDCABDB2CCFAC4246A041503D99E9A51D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Compensation</header-in-text></quote> in the subsection heading and all that follows through <quote>Subject</quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Compensation</header-in-text>.—Subject</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9A6D7090823746A3B0EF797326A38145"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1C05B2988B4C4B4B89F0F4D6D4E8F6E4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amendments To reflect conclusion of Phase-In of Concurrent Receipt of Retired Pay and Veterans’ Disability Compensation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1414 of title 10, United States Code, is further amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2CEE03BB50A240099F46B0F60235496D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), as amended by subsection (a) of this section, by striking the final sentence;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5B37359D2D514178AC83A332EB8890F4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subsection (c) and redesignating subsections (d) and (e) as subsections (c) and (d), respectively; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H196E687FDF6D4BF887B40E11C15B5D22"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (d), as so redesignated, by striking paragraphs (3) and (4).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEBE605E7B3624AF1B6866414876C242A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Specification of qualified retirees for concurrent receipt purposes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1414 of title 10, United States Code, is further amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE2628D8076364E9EB33195BC0DF87E70"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), as amended by subsections (a) and (b)—</text> <subparagraph id="H0F29D34601984C52B501FF4ECC65814F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>a member or</quote> and all that follows through <quote>is entitled</quote> and inserting <quote>an individual who is a qualified retiree for any month is entitled</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE83B111CF5B046D5AAE230DD92794753"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>retired pay and veterans’ disability compensation</quote> after <quote>both</quote>;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEDDD02CC1FD4477983196297073D03DE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H83D30819325447B58C4C952468978FEC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection">Special Rules</header-in-text></quote> in the subsection heading and all that follows through <quote>is subject to</quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection">Special Rules for Chapter 61 Disability Retirees</header-in-text>.—In the case of a qualified retiree who is retired under chapter 61 of this title, the retired pay of the member is subject to</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB33ECE81EDF6487EB27E5D12FE0639E2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking paragraph (2); and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H77DCC79D2A5D45B8B23DF945D9363918"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (d), as redesignated and amended by subsection (b), by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block id="HD6F6C36692F64058AF2EBBF80191458A" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H3845797BEF634DAE96EB75C956C4B9B7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified retiree</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified retiree</term> means a member or former member of the uniformed services who, with respect to any month—</text> <subparagraph id="HC2E5DF06D1BB4172B7FF6D017A95E9AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is entitled to retired pay, other than in the case of a member retired under chapter 61 of this title with less than 20 years of service creditable under section 1405 of this title and less than 20 years of service computed under section 12732 of this title; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70F2A05A49FB4AE5BBF101A7C003B563"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is entitled to veterans’ disability compensation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H831A264192A5440CB295DC32723DA562"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clerical Amendments</header> <paragraph id="HF28998B028564D94A01DC7AE266E4AA2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Section heading</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The heading of section 1414 of title 10, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H3460CD4C715F425180B2C1959FFC1260" style="USC">
						<section id="HF58442975DC24F06AFDF21E6FED2ACC1"><enum>1414.</enum><header>Members eligible for retired pay who are also eligible for veterans’ disability compensation:
			 Concurrent payment of retired pay and disability compensation</header></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9F5C797127914F0FB71B672255B4E472"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Table of sections</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The item relating to such section in the table of sections at the beginning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/71">chapter 71</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H90B415E8DCBC47ABB4D3A9FF0054C577" style="OLC">
						<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
							<toc-entry level="section">1414. Members eligible for retired pay who are also eligible for veterans’ disability compensation:
			 Concurrent payment of retired pay and disability compensation.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1BDFB02B71A04B78919B8781EB572AAD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1413a(f) of title 10, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>Subsection (d)</quote> and inserting <quote>Subsection (c)</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H7EC95F8B2995431EBA6412177490E0EB"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effective Date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect as of January 1, 2018, and shall apply to payments for months beginning on or after that date.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


