<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE81081FEA0AA45DABD59E33C2125C696" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3094 IH: On-the-Job Training Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3094</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170628">June 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001038">Mr. Crowley</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize a national grant program for on-the-job training.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H308BB2D1CA40406294AF912C9B5AF1F8" style="OLC">
 <section id="H835334FD31DA4208892C249647445DC5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>On-the-Job Training Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H246B40961C634EBEB8EA6131ABEAD093" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>On-the-job training</header> <subsection id="H5E15DDE91C164EF2B18311217904E235"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle D of title I of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act is amended by inserting after section 172 the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6A75AC3D8B59463FA44EF30342662340" style="OLC">
					<section id="H7F96F8CB3653464A9919F2C000D45249"><enum>173.</enum><header>On-the-job  training</header>
 <subsection id="H7CFECEC79A5944B096DC84638998F614"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>federally recognized tribal organization</term> means an entity described in section 166(c)(1).</text> </subsection><subsection id="H7E415FB5B61D47F388504D8E068181E9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From the amount made available under subsection (i), and subject to subsection (e)—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2DABA39B5D7540DFB2731CFA7349F63A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary shall make grants on a discretionary basis to eligible entities described in subsection (c) for adult on-the-job training, or dislocated worker on-the-job training, carried out under section 134 and for State functions described in subsection (g); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4C474A5915864A28AE9D5A51C0835335"><enum>(2)</enum><text>using an amount that is not more than 10 percent of the funds made available under subsection (i), the Secretary shall make grants to such eligible entities for developing on-the-job training programs, including providing capacity building activities for local staff who will be engaged in the development of the programs, in consultation with the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8DD9FC47060A44B0B5F4F785AA94A219"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>The following entities are eligible to receive a grant under this section:</text> <paragraph id="H1FC27F6FFEFD4C04A533D48E6A7C0959"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8DA2F67D0D714293BDECE678611AFAAD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Units of local government and local boards.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBED022423461439AA86E8ECEE6AF8242"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Indian tribes.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5907F215B0174F20BBB8A2D04A397AB6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Institutions of higher education.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8858A50920EE41B88A2E338852D3A143"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Business trade associations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H01A4A1447CD64D25AB7C0E17B2D2988D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Local educational agencies.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H83CC771A11B44D99A5F994282BE830E1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under subsection (b), an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require. In preparing such an application for a grant under subsection (b)(1), a local board shall consult with the corresponding State.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H82CE206DB768407898E894A3BFB8FD82"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reimbursement of wage rates</header><text>Notwithstanding the limitation in section 101(31)(B), in making the grants described in subsection (b)(1) the Secretary may allow for higher levels of reimbursement of wage rates the Secretary determines are appropriate based on factors such as—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB7B62503A49E4CE299541C9916404A0F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>employer size, in order to facilitate the participation of small- and medium-sized employers;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H121372592DEB4B86A9C7B1E2A1361EED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>target populations, in order to enhance job creation for persons with barriers to employment; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF35CA0C6551C47888D80B1B9D1346C2F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the number of employees that will participate in the on-the-job training, the wage and benefit levels of the employees (before the training and anticipated on completion of the training), the relationship of the training to the competitiveness of the employer and employees, and the existence of other employer-provided training and advancement opportunities.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2B2B7A0E8FE54DA9A1A8BD32A2513700"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Administration by Secretary</header><text>The Secretary may use an amount that is not more than 1 percent of the funds made available under subsection (i) for the administration, management, and oversight of the programs, activities, and grants, funded under subsection (b), including the evaluation of, and dissemination of information on lessons learned through, the use of such funds.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H970B6194BB8D4B9FAD609CB6B8531F46"><enum>(g)</enum><header>State oversight and monitoring</header><text>A local board that receives a grant under subsection (b)(1) and is located in a State, shall provide not less than 5 percent of the grant funds to the State for State functions described in sections 136(f), 184, and 185.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB1E8CCC71FF94223977FBF8F1D8CB65F"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect the manner in which subtitle B is implemented, for activities funded through amounts appropriated under section 137.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB8FE2E603A254BF7BCC8CA8EBE2A5C54"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2015 and each subsequent fiscal year.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H407ACE4B5EE84CDFBF89975A91182934"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 172 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7F291CEA88D54D3FA938E5B6A7C7C671" style="OLC">
					<toc>
						<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 173. On-the-job training.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


