<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB528F09AC84F40B38DA7842C867B3036" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2407 IH: United States Citizenship and Immigration Services Authorization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2407</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170511">May 11, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000289">Mr. Goodlatte</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish United States Citizenship and Immigration
			 Services, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H0DD8CF264BD84AD5A56E34D8DF8E187A" style="OLC">
 <section id="HC980E6F79D1D47CEBBA2F13F9CFA5EF2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>United States Citizenship and Immigration Services Authorization Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H4B1C70BBC959415B87C6F517DAF12BEC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 451 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/271">6 U.S.C. 271</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE4AE9ABD0D094245A827D96E8947DED6" style="OLC">
				<section id="H409A345B45204E19A34CC467FBAEEB01"><enum>451.</enum><header>Establishment of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services</header>
 <subsection id="H434C67E029354B4DBC8068497CEEAEE8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established within the Department an agency to be known as <quote>United States Citizenship and Immigration Services</quote>. The mission of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services is to efficiently adjudicate petitions and applications for immigration benefits for foreign nationals seeking lawful immigration status in the United States and for individuals seeking to become citizens of the United States in a manner that detects and prevents fraud, protects the jobs and working conditions of American workers, and ensures the national security and welfare of the American people.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA2C8E28D3D904EAD8FD5076A063F89E2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Director</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There shall be at the head of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services a Director of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services (in this section referred to as the <quote>Director</quote>) who shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2DE5D18DD13446E18D0FEE19F87E2D15"><enum>(1)</enum><text>report directly to the Secretary;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H926F5FE041D5440AB959219614F61FA7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>have at least 5 years of management experience;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCD1311C35E534CA39E8B9ED35675FDB2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>establish the policies and priorities of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9C7FE5E958BF4ADC852C1A0A05FF6059"><enum>(4)</enum><text>advise the Secretary of any policy or operation that affects, in a significant manner, the mission of another Department component agency;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3A7E324E6831404E9AFCE61516468AF7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>carry out the adjudication of immigration and naturalization benefits applications and petitions within the Director’s statutory authority; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC06A6D21B2CC4E22A10A2C4A7BF6E8FF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>carry out further duties prescribed by statute, or as assigned or delegated by the Secretary, which are within the statutory authority of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4E0AA7C00B0D4D8B9110E5A2B8B702F1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Deputy director</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There shall be a Deputy Director of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services who shall assist the Director in carrying out the Director’s duties.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDA5C209951174C398108943C20E41D5D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Office of the chief counsel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established within United States Citizenship and Immigration Services an Office of the Chief Counsel. There shall be at the head of the Office of the Chief Counsel a Chief Counsel who shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC7FB38D30C354F64A61C74ECFD67DAE9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide specialized legal advice, opinions, determinations, draft regulations, and other assistance to the Director with respect to legal matters affecting United States Citizenship and Immigration Services; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5828A5C97A0C4842B19A809DBBACD594"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">represent United States Citizenship and Immigration Services in visa petition appeal proceedings when applicable.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7CEEE5C2AC3A476C9D51D66CCEB457F2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Office of policy and strategy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established within United States Citizenship and Immigration Services an Office of Policy and Strategy. There shall be at the head of the Office of Policy and Strategy a Chief who shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF0D8D51757944E899C7464BE04E23BDD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop United States Citizenship and Immigration Services policy recommendations for the Director;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4BC0750B40404D0B9DA32C404F35E21C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop strategy for policy implementation; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4C363D97B3664C5B9EF2F7981F238D42"><enum>(3)</enum><text>carry out additional duties as assigned or delegated by the Director, which are within the statutory authority of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H692EF8E7656240D09D14E0E757C6F0BB"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Office of citizenship</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established within United States Citizenship and Immigration Services an Office of Citizenship. There shall be at the head of the Office of Citizenship a Chief who shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE320CB9CAC254BE4AC5BCE11E85664A0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promote instruction and training on citizenship responsibilities, as well as assimilation, for eligible aliens who are interested in becoming naturalized citizens of the United States; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6CABD0B3C04A4BC6949F25595B2180A0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">carry out additional duties as assigned or delegated by the Director, which are within the statutory authority of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H87AB349F52B6457891EC8E4DEE432E5E"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Fraud detection and national security directorate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established within United States Citizenship and Immigration Services a Fraud Detection and National Security Directorate. There shall be at the head of the Fraud Detection and National Security Directorate an Associate Director who shall seek to prevent immigration benefits from being granted to individuals who pose a threat to national security or public safety, or who defraud the immigration system, in a manner that is consistent with the immigration laws (as such term is defined in section 101(a)(17) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(17)</external-xref>)).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF728BB3D7E8043DBABC93947758C0074"><enum>(h)</enum><header>External affairs directorate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established within United States Citizenship and Immigration Services an External Affairs Directorate. There shall be at the head of the External Affairs Directorate an Associate Director who shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB1D71AC6D5F44C4CAC65A737945C9317"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">oversee and coordinate official United States Citizenship and Immigration Services communications to both internal and external audiences, including applicants, petitioners, and beneficiaries of petitions for immigration benefits provided by United States Citizenship and Immigration Services, the legislative branch, and the general public; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCBC52E05D6564E94A33E5BA5A6FDC6AF"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">carry out additional duties as assigned or delegated by the Director, which are within the statutory authority of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H28AC306C26D8455B983B7BE11C7BE41C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Immigration records and identity services directorate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established within United States Citizenship and Immigration Services an Immigration Records and Identity Services Directorate. There shall be at the head of the Immigration Records and Identity Services Directorate an Associate Director who shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD8AB0B29DCD14F778DA1039F76B0AF24"><enum>(1)</enum><text>manage the operation of an employment eligibility verification system as provided for by section 404 of the Illegal Immigration and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (U.S.C. 1324a note) or any successor system;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB55D1ADF3C8746B9AA217215833EBCB2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>manage the operation of the Systematic Alien Verification for Entitlements Program, or its successor program, designed to assist Federal, State, and local benefit-issuing agencies, institutions, and licensing agencies in determining the immigration status of benefit applicants so only those legally entitled to benefits receive them;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA7BC8B11A8844FACA08B66830A0CA482"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">manage the biometric services provided to United States Citizenship and Immigration Services components;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H56C712D64EA34416BC0FB7E94B8D9B04"><enum>(4)</enum><text>manage immigration records and provide information regarding such records to stakeholders; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2C7664E5E7D04AAB8515E2FE9252BB07"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">carry out further duties as assigned or delegated by the Director, which are within the statutory authority of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9E98B55D8EF444249F0D30C79E1DB641"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Field operations directorate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established within United States Citizenship and Immigration Services a Field Operations Directorate. There shall be at the head of the Field Operations Directorate an Associate Director who shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA3B051F2773F443DBD799A9D91279C1A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">oversee all United States Citizenship and Immigration Services field offices;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB499603BA53E4006A079FF5CCDBC84FA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>oversee the adjudication of immigration benefits and naturalization applications and petitions, applicant interviews, naturalization ceremonies, and background checks for applicants, petitioners, and beneficiaries of petitions for benefits;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H00BA9E80E3F749C9B8077E3929B6319C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure the integrity of processing that occurs at the field offices; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8FE905ABF6214596BE454966A1E21E52"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">carry out further duties as assigned or delegated by the Director, which are within the statutory authority of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H375717F3DFA04729A29CCA0194AE2339"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Refugee, asylum and international operations directorate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established within United States Citizenship and Immigration Services a Refugee, Asylum and International Operations Directorate. There shall be at the head of the Refugee, Asylum and International Operations Directorate an Associate Director who shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HACBC4C55FA444A6D9692F39062A993FF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>oversee refugee application adjudication and interviews;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H01D09C19842A4A248C751187493C499C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>oversee asylum application adjudication and interviews;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H37C5C860B7844FEDB67EE1B7DB6193FA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure the integrity of application processing that occurs under the Refugee, Asylum and International Operations Directorate’s authority; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB68F55264C4348458F244FC998E24BCD"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">carry out further duties as assigned or delegated by the Director, which are within the statutory authority of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7F74CF12506242F68989CF9EF8684D27"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Service center operations directorate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established within United States Citizenship and Immigration Services a Service Center Operations Directorate. There shall be at the head of the Service Center Operations Directorate an Associate Director who shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA6F38CBE02C54D50956697A62796CE4E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">oversee and manage the United States Citizenship and Immigration Services Service Centers responsible for adjudicating petitions that do not require applicant interviews;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H06886645089648FF8B8038DA079494B1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure the integrity of processing that occurs at the Service Centers; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDB096343109C49B285B8888000FC7F09"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">carry out further duties as assigned or delegated by the Director, which are within the statutory authority of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H44D325ABB3A24DCE8C7E79FEA2CDCDE4"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Management directorate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established within United States Citizenship and Immigration Services a Management Directorate. There shall be at the head of the Management Directorate an Associate Director who shall carry out management duties as assigned or delegated by the Director, which are within the statutory authority of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB91FC73CB02D4DA6B4F7F0F7D2608E24"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Office of professional responsibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established within United States Citizenship and Immigration Services an Office of Professional Responsibility. There shall be at the head of the Office of Professional Responsibility a Chief who shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6BC8175E00834752AA43660EB3883488"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure compliance with all United States Citizenship and Immigration Services programs and policies relating to corruption, misconduct, or mismanagement;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H649C107B1AD34AE8A4055AF3AFDF11B0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">investigate allegations of misconduct involving officials or employees of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0C29D8AA36B1441DAC1B4378BBC21DB6"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">carry out further duties as assigned or delegated by the Director, which are within the statutory authority of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2BFB3B015AB24934840D12D1EE62E864"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Authority To establish additional offices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director may establish other offices, directorates, and officers, including Associate Directors, as the Director determines necessary to carry out the duties of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services, which are within the statutory authority of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H81CF1E660F044D44B58CFBF6427FBF9F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Administrative Appeals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, all appellate functions of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services shall be carried out by the Secretary of Homeland Security, who shall establish a component within the Department of Homeland Security to carry out such functions.</text>
 </section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H85CB647845DF4CAF909ACAA69D2E27FD"><enum>4.</enum><header>Repealed provisions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Sections 459, 460, and 461 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/276">6 U.S.C. 276</external-xref>, 277, and 278) are repealed.</text>
		</section><section id="H70076614CED74F01B2F9D97C3CF81550"><enum>5.</enum><header>Conforming and clerical amendments</header>
			<subsection id="HEF3CA3A2D2F24280A065E2668626BCAC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Conforming Amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="HFCCA55FBD21B4DF5BBB6B3B4A9D5A010"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Immigration and Nationality Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>United States Citizenship and Immigration Services</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H730B550ED9E34694A1FFE4DEA033DE95"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Homeland Security Act of 2002</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/101">6 U.S.C. 101</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>United States Citizenship and Immigration Services</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2C8AEA5E785A4AE8880EBC58C8102445"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Title 5</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5314 of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>the Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services</quote> and inserting <quote>United States Citizenship and Immigration Services</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEB5348629E8146BF960E73907507AB62"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Inspector General Act of 1978</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (e) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-act" parsable-cite="usc-act/Inspector General Act of 1978 /8I">section 8I</external-xref> of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc-appendix" parsable-cite="usc-appendix/5/8I">5 U.S.C. App. 8I</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services</quote> and inserting <quote>United States Citizenship and Immigration Services</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H20D2CBC5CAEC46F9873D1B876375AABB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H9B66FE3C55AD415CB88AC349122C6E70"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking the item relating to section 451 and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB1226E3869AC4FB1BCA6EFAECC24D136" style="OLC">
						<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
							<toc-entry level="section">451. Establishment of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services. </toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 <continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">and</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C11D32939844B729D2098F5AAC6DD2F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the items relating to sections 459, 460, and 461.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H9890B5CBA33E4BCA9EC272625F877F9A"><enum>6.</enum><header>E-verify permanent authorization</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subsection (b) of section 401 of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a</external-xref> note) is amended by striking the last sentence.</text>
		</section><section id="H0A73F80D1FE141D798D64923FE0B128D"><enum>7.</enum><header>Transparency</header>
 <subsection id="H918AE132315B4A42AF0D7C39537617B8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Officials and employees of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services shall act impartially and may not give preferential treatment to any entity, organization, or individual in connection with the adjudication of any immigration benefit under the authority of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFDCBB712CF4B40ED91864F1C45AAEC0A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Improper activities</header><text>Activities that constitute preferential treatment under subsection (a) shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H238979845CF84F039943E2E4DD089DD3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">working on, or in any way attempting to influence, in a manner not available to or accorded to all other petitioners, applicants, and seekers of benefits, the adjudication of immigration benefits under the authority of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE679FBADB55C4498A95FE1B28E884327"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">meeting or communicating with persons associated with the entities described in paragraph (1), at the request of such persons, in a manner not available to or accorded to all other petitioners, applicants, or seekers of benefits, regarding the adjudication of immigration benefits under the authority of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H82F159F93B184816B8B2EFA85F05BA4E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reporting of communications</header>
 <paragraph id="H7A6316EFB1D94E25A4DAEDA4EBB777A9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Written communication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Employees of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services shall include, in the record of proceeding for a case under the authority of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services, actual or electronic copies of all case-specific written communication, including e-mails, from government and private accounts, with non-Department persons or entities advocating for benefit applications or petitions under the authority of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services that are pending on or after the date of the enactment of this Act (other than routine communications with other agencies of the Federal Government regarding the case, including communications involving background checks and litigation defense).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H67AF32F910AB4AC5966F1DD86C5FFCAF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Oral communication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If substantive oral communication, including telephonic communication, virtual communication, and in-person meetings, takes place between officials of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services and non-Department persons or entities advocating for benefit applications or petitions under the authority of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services that are pending on or after the date of the enactment of this Act (other than routine communications with other agencies of the Federal Government regarding the case, including communications involving background checks and litigation defense)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0DA616E921524F278EED21C455D94BDA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the conversation shall be recorded; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2318789501A45CDA9620171354094A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>detailed minutes of the session shall be taken and included in the record of proceeding.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E6D3DB6BDC74B80980A0D99EFF25F9A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notification</header>
 <subparagraph id="HE9F2B5985F424F6DA0FACE1BAE1548B7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Director of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services, in the course of written or oral communication described in this subsection, receives evidence about a specific case from anyone other than an affected party or his or her representative (excluding Federal Government or law enforcement sources), such information may not be made part of the record of proceeding and may not be considered in adjudicative proceedings unless—</text>
 <clause id="H095A5EAAACAD4C4290EF0AEEAA0F4B22"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the affected party has been given notice of such evidence; and</text> </clause><clause id="HCE6E2FC7E54249B886885B33B0D40871"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if such evidence is derogatory, the affected party has been given an opportunity to respond to the evidence.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02B50E197E214CC7934EF2BA1DFD1CBD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Information from law enforcement, intelligence agencies, or confidential sources</header>
 <clause id="H87EBD5B36EBC49708D79F6F730D98444"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Law enforcement or intelligence agencies</header><text>Evidence received from law enforcement or intelligence agencies may not be made part of the record of proceeding without the consent of the relevant agency or law enforcement entity.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6954DDDFFFF9483AB90E7E5E0B387D35"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Whistleblowers, confidential sources, or intelligence agencies</header><text>Evidence received from whistleblowers, other confidential sources, or the intelligence community that is included in the record of proceeding and considered in adjudicative proceedings shall be handled in a manner that does not reveal the identity of the whistleblower or confidential source, or reveal classified information.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H82AF6E441DF146AE8AC8DA2EC08B6481"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consideration of evidence</header>
 <paragraph id="HB85FE934FA8E4B56BD1D23CB493CA3AF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No case-specific communication with persons or entities that are not part of the Department of Homeland Security may be considered in the adjudication of an application or petition under the authority of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services unless the communication is included in the record of proceeding of the case.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA4470D27D61846C0B880DA6030FA6B30"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The Director may waive the requirement under paragraph (1) only in the interests of national security or for investigative or law enforcement purposes.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAAFDA9254B5648D992D70C91319E676E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Penalty</header>
 <paragraph id="HD155D52A91E64236A15D4003B0209478"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any person who intentionally violates the prohibition on preferential treatment under this section or intentionally violates the reporting requirements under subsection (c) shall be disciplined in accordance with paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H000842EB35B746668C7058EEE79D0E5D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sanctions</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director shall establish a graduated set of sanctions based on the severity of the violation referred to in paragraph (1), which may include, in addition to any criminal or civil penalties that may be imposed, written reprimand, suspension, demotion, or removal, as permitted by statute.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H82DC896236664EB897998947D1569BC7"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to modify any law regarding the handling or disclosure of classified information.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA86DFC27658F4BAF8B1E98AD4CDCD566"><enum>(g)</enum><header>No creation of private right of action</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to create or authorize a private right of action to challenge a decision of an employee of the Department of Homeland Security.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HBE321F69A56A4161AD817676123E6791"><enum>8.</enum><header>Fee for International Adoption</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In the case of the rule related to the United States Citizenship and Immigration Services Fee Schedule published on October 24, 2016 (81 Fed. Reg. 73292), any provision of that rule that pertains to the fee provided for the Application for Certificate of Citizenship, Forms N–600/600K shall have no effect in the case of an application filed on behalf of an adopted child, and the applicable fee for such application shall remain the fee in effect prior to the effective date of the rule. United States Citizenship and Immigration Services shall refund any fee paid prior to the date of the enactment of this Act for an application filed on behalf of an adopted child pursuant to the fee schedule published on October 24, 2016, to the extent that the amount paid exceeded the amount of such fee prior to the effective date of the rule described in the previous sentence.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


