<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF862028DBD274D958349DAE5A314232B" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1009 : OIRA Insight, Reform, and Accountability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code>
		<congress>115th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1009</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date date="20170302">March 2, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To amend title 44, United States Code, to require the Administrator of the Office of Information
			 and Regulatory Affairs to review regulations, and for other purposes. </official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H756F37875A1F49B1A38B60088324ABFC" style="OLC">
 <section id="H5C3E4035B2D54EC59935B12D6E758EC9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>OIRA Insight, Reform, and Accountability Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H0CF808F4DCAA4EA980354500F2077584"><enum>2.</enum><header>Office of information and regulatory affairs</header> <subsection id="HAE45D4D4BE1748D2B1D62484BE18817B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendment</header><text>Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new sections:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H3D163618F74940778B0E41D033D5D011" style="USC">
					<section id="H4FE1F95AE458483BAA1D4822F24D0CD4"><enum>3522.</enum><header>Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs Regulatory Working Group; regulatory plan; Unified
			 Agenda</header>
						<subsection id="HA6E4ADFE992242268D32F6668AF12F0F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Regulatory working group</header>
 <paragraph id="H03AFB53D019340F096EA3A20FE2F2912"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment; members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs shall convene a working group to be known as the Regulatory Working Group, whose members shall consist of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H71B7ECAA3C374984BC819A9026FE1B75"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Administrator.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H577820F13D434527A8ADB994FA62ED3C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Representatives selected by the head of each agency that the Administrator determines to have significant domestic regulatory responsibility.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE57C606F4F4847589E7D4854F8F43960"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Other executive branch officials as designated by the Administrator.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0EC616F3D03048309ECE97A4B36E5B5C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Chair</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chair of the Regulatory Working Group shall be the Administrator, who shall periodically advise Congress on the activities of the Regulatory Working Group.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H170A72E5F2654880AF53D9B5D915FD1C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Regulatory Working Group shall serve as a forum to assist agencies in identifying and analyzing important regulatory issues, including, at a minimum—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H71A2355407AC416FA02193BE980EAE66"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the development of innovative regulatory techniques;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F0C2EC6D0AF45A6B0E48E866F82A664"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the methods, efficacy, and utility of comparative risk assessment in regulatory decisionmaking;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C2A0D26228C48A38E9C8E6C3C84F539"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the development of streamlined regulatory approaches for small businesses and other entities; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38D8F1C0380E4B0192EA2E56E7AC0C78"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the methods used to ensure agencies coordinate with State, local, and Tribal governments.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7762F3BE05E7400EA3ACAEBF1F0D5390"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Regulatory Working Group shall meet not less than quarterly and may meet as a whole or in subgroups of members with an interest in particular issues or subject areas.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB50CC606EB8F406BA4D4B8A267446271"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Analytical studies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To inform the discussion of the Regulatory Working Group, the Regulatory Working Group may request analytical studies and reports by the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, the Administrative Conference of the United States, or any other agency.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFF05795214F04627B7AD79C5C7B3CCAC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulatory plan</header>
							<paragraph id="HE2F5E3C6E21642E0BB869AF0FA94420F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <subparagraph id="HB4F995A95424418BA60E79ECFDC5C0E3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Deadline for and description of regulatory plan</header><text>Not later than June 1 of each year, the head of each agency shall approve and submit to the Administrator a regulatory plan that includes each significant regulatory action that the agency reasonably expects to issue in proposed or final form in the following fiscal year or thereafter and the retrospective review described in paragraph (2). The regulatory plan shall also contain, at a minimum, the following:</text>
 <clause id="HF0D2073D3FF34C209B380F839F86BDE7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A statement of the regulatory objectives and priorities of the agency.</text> </clause><clause id="HB5D400A318D64FF3A1A84B8B5FA83F4E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A summary of each planned significant regulatory action including, to the extent possible, alternatives to be considered and preliminary estimates of the anticipated costs and benefits of such action.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE6D27C9A1188485AA05662D49C8C30C5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A summary of the legal basis for each such action, including whether any aspect of the action is required by statute or court order.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H73B66DAD68E0468689FADD7FEE003490"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A statement of the need for each such action and, if applicable, how the action will reduce risk to public health, safety, or the environment, as well as how the magnitude of the risk addressed by the action relates to any other risk within the jurisdiction of the agency.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBA3C045E3D1F4D5D999C79501686939F"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A summary of the agency’s plan to coordinate with State, local, and Tribal governments throughout the regulatory process.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEA6FC40DB5F04AABB9E78A8178D14D70"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of any action taken by the agency to ensure that each planned significant regulatory action is not duplicative or conflicting with any other existing or planned regulatory action.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H036B793B9CC341D0AEDE0DF06F9E97DA"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>The schedule for each such action, including a statement of any applicable statutory or judicial deadline.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF9C361B6F3AB41009B350936D71596FF"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>The name, email address, and telephone number of a knowledgeable agency employee the public may contact for additional information about each such action.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H041C106A5304404F8989FAE9A4849ADA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Circulation of regulatory plan</header><text>Not later than 10 days after receiving the regulatory plan under subparagraph (A), the Administrator shall circulate the regulatory plan to any other agency the Administrator determines may be affected by the plan.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H69F696B48425423F91F7B3314D2FBA02"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Agency notification to OIRA of conflicting significant regulatory actions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of an agency shall promptly notify the Administrator in writing if any planned significant regulatory action in the regulatory plan of another agency may conflict with the policy or action taken or planned by that agency. The Administrator shall forward any notification received under this subparagraph to the other agency involved.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2003F05DB24342E38A87B25695AFEA86"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Notification of conflicting significant regulatory actions</header><text>The Administrator shall notify the head of an agency in writing if any planned significant regulatory action conflicts with any policy or action taken or planned by another agency.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC2EAE4FCA4EE41028C44757764B99A60"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Requirement to publish in Unified Agenda</header><text>Each regulatory plan submitted by the head of an agency under subparagraph (A) shall be included in the October publication of the Unified Agenda described under subsection (c).</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB91E8A4596064A28BC6EC2A207F05B32"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Retrospective review</header>
 <subparagraph id="H52346394BDFE43BCB39C922C66CCAEA5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>List of Outdated Regulations</header><text>The head of each agency shall include in the regulatory plan submitted under paragraph (1)(A) a list of regulations that have been identified by the agency (including any comments submitted to the agency) as unjustified, unnecessary, duplicative of other regulations or laws, inappropriately burdensome, or otherwise recommended for removal.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21BBBA4ABFC0410EB5D738C02F938C3E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Description of Retrospective Review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of each agency shall include in the regulatory plan submitted under paragraph (1)(A) a description of any program or other effort to review existing regulations to determine whether any such regulations should be modified or eliminated in order to increase the effectiveness in achieving the regulatory objectives of the agency or to reduce the burden of regulations. The agency shall include any statutory requirements that require the agency to promulgate or continue to impose regulations that the agency believes are unnecessary or outdated by reason of changed circumstances.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8837E2E3E80F41A4A895D7FB16C7D245"><enum>(C)</enum><header>OIRA Coordinated Review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of each agency shall submit the program descriptions required in subparagraph (B) to the Administrator. The Administrator shall work with other interested entities and agencies, including through the processes established under subsection (d), to review the list of regulations identified under subparagraph (A) and such entities may assist OIRA and the agencies with identifying regulations or groups of regulations that—</text>
 <clause id="H97E689E9696B4107B382890DE12621F5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>impose significant or unique burdens on governmental entities and that are no longer justified; or</text> </clause><clause id="H9D115AAA470442BB8523C9D36274490A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>affect a particular group, industry, or sector of the economy.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD325EDCDF6814915A8881AE17CB1A44F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Unified Agenda</header>
 <paragraph id="HBD66EFC0BF5D4C8597A58F0F93EF7CB9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Submission of regulations under development or review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than March 15 and September 15 of each year, the head of each agency shall submit to the Administrator an agenda of each regulation under development or review in accordance with any guidance issued under this section. Each agenda shall include, to the extent practicable, the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1DE712EF0F14481999472779769C5D66"><enum>(A)</enum><text>For each regulation—</text> <clause id="HF10C62FC232A475BB3B29A63139ADEF7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a regulation identifier number;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H620535B471E14528AB9FC5BD9157BDD2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a brief summary of the regulation;</text> </clause><clause id="HB74C8C5C47424F9BBCDCECA67B9297DB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a citation to the legal authority to issue the regulation;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7337418E2DC141EF96D63B32D5ECA465"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any legal deadline for the issuance of the regulation;</text> </clause><clause id="HB7C18DF12A7C4EAAB4128D6DC563D1C0"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the name and phone number for a knowledgeable agency employee; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H64562BA6F86542AA8C131C45BF87E7E9"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the stage of review for issuing the regulation.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBC6ECCD558148DDADFFB5CE7DD50038"><enum>(B)</enum><text>For each regulation expected to be promulgated within the following 18 months—</text>
 <clause id="H7A0AB95177324C46B1761113991DEF9A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a determination of whether the regulation is expected to be a significant regulatory action or an economically significant regulatory action;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H301DD934512A4C6AB01EAC62114C959E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any available clear summary of the expected costs or benefits; and</text> </clause><clause id="H82759A5964B149CB8055BAC47BA35E70"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">efforts to coordinate with State, local, and Tribal governments.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFE3A18B3278429497D81B62D91FBC11"><enum>(C)</enum><text>For any regulation included in the immediately previous agenda, an explanation of why the regulation is no longer included.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H98E9CE8B4E37493FB7584D3EAEF07C26"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publication of Unified Agenda required</header><text>Not later than April 15 and October 15 of each year, the Administrator shall compile and publish online each agenda received under paragraph (1) (to be known as the Unified Agenda).</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="HF34983564B01488FBDBEDD9240A98163"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Guidance</header>
 <subparagraph id="H06D69DDBC24C4A8EBC55F75226AA8825"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall issue guidance for agencies on the manner of submission under this subsection and on meeting the requirements of this subsection, including a standard definition for each stage of review and any other definition that would assist the public in understanding the different terms used by agencies to submit the agenda required under paragraph (1).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7EA07E58FED042048408E81483505D62"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>The Administrator shall periodically review compliance with this section and issue guidance or recommendations to assist agencies in complying with this section.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBA4CB1F35FC24EF9B53C93C39B64FB8D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Coordination with State, local, and tribal governments and the public</header>
 <paragraph id="H7567FB5DCB7F4E579A01131BE403E106"><enum>(1)</enum><header>State, local, and tribal governments</header><text>The Administrator shall meet not less than quarterly with representatives of State, local, and tribal governments to identify both existing and proposed regulations and policies that may uniquely or significantly affect those government entities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H33923339E51E41588205C0882AF346EA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public</header><text>The Administrator shall periodically convene conferences with representatives of businesses, nongovernmental organizations, and the public to discuss regulatory issues of common concern.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE74A82173D9C4643A82AA74C294A7E7B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Best practices</header><text>The Administrator shall, in consultation with the Regulatory Working Group and the entities described in subsection (d), periodically develop advice and guidance for agencies on best practices of the development of regulations.</text>
						</subsection></section><section id="H2E711E4C6C7D4A9E82E9104D567F6D3C"><enum>3523.</enum><header>OIRA coordinated review of significant regulatory actions</header>
						<subsection id="H81D5BFAD1AE64573B24D365B6214E770"><enum>(a)</enum><header>OIRA review</header>
 <paragraph id="H046F46CFEACC4660A607E96E4E21A1B1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall conduct a Governmentwide coordinated review of significant regulatory actions to ensure that such regulations are consistent with applicable law and that a regulatory action by one agency does not conflict with a policy or action taken or planned by another agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H295AB04B4DAB44A89CBEAB04E481A4BA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Periodic agency submission of planned regulatory actions</header><text>The head of each agency shall provide to the Administrator, at such time and in such a manner as determined by the Administrator, a list of each planned regulatory action with an identification of whether each such regulatory action is a significant regulatory action.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HDC312DC172484BDC82234A9E926A065F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Review of significant regulatory action required</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HE723E23B07114726AA0C1C32996E409A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall make a determination of whether any planned regulatory action submitted under this section is a significant regulatory action and shall review each such significant regulatory action in accordance with this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H086836CDD9324E3EA23270561D29F3C9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Not subject to review</header><text>Any planned regulatory action determined by the Administrator not to be a significant regulatory action is not subject to review under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA7C6997746D8460394242373A1206C9A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Notification required</header><text>Not later than 10 days after a planned regulatory action has been determined to be a significant regulatory action, the Administrator shall notify the head of the relevant agency of such determination.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B37E01A97C4424F8D4BEFF8782F6374"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Waiver of review for significant regulatory action</header><text>The Administrator—</text> <subparagraph id="H0159B1D453704EFB8816B50D2E0DCF89"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may waive review of any planned regulatory action designated as a significant regulatory action; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H32BB10C93DEC4DD5AF9EAEBC600AC70F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall publish online a detailed written explanation of any such waiver.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7A604CFCC6C14574944507C8DDF28E31"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Agency consultation with OIRA</header> <paragraph id="H8E24ACABB20B4ADF96A455E20AA1DA24"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An agency may consult with OIRA at any time on any regulatory action. OIRA shall maintain a log of each agency consultation with OIRA before submitting the significant regulatory action for review under this section, including the date of the consultation, the name of each agency official involved with the consultation, and a description of the purpose of the consultation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8D7867801E9B4AC0BB718261FFEB969A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regulation identifier number</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of an agency shall make every effort to obtain a regulation identifier number for the regulatory action that is the subject of the consultation before consulting with OIRA.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H91912F49DDAD40869FD41524489525EF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consultation information required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the head of an agency is unable to obtain the regulation identifier number as described in paragraph (2), the head of the agency shall provide the regulation identifier number to OIRA as soon as the number is obtained with a list of any previous interactions with OIRA relating to the regulatory action that is the subject of the consultation.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCCCCE4BEFE1644748B7808D3C9E711C8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Agency submission of significant regulatory action for review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before issuing a significant regulatory action, the head of an agency shall submit the significant regulatory action to the Administrator for review and shall include the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H9E5ED30A20EE4C16A1CA6DA3666B951A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The text of the significant regulatory action.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H11CFE9DE0A07414CA53A35C023762F6F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A detailed description of the need for the significant regulatory action.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H09AE96220D1A4AE88CCB624220B34A17"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An explanation of how the significant regulatory action will meet the identified need.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDA3752DAD8EB40C9BAD816529DE8E9CC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An assessment of potential costs and benefits of the significant regulatory action.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC3A707F40E9A4E1D905E45E12DF1E6D6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An explanation of the manner in which the significant regulatory action is consistent with a statutory mandate and avoids undue interference with State, local, and tribal government functions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0FFA312A20254C3A8F84121C26C07E2A"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An explanation of agency efforts to coordinate with State, local, and Tribal governments throughout the regulatory process.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2D15B0CC051042DBB0F6A0CBFED21974"><enum>(7)</enum><text>For an economically significant regulatory action, if any of the following was developed during the decisionmaking process of the agency:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6D40459B131E48A79B84697F400C2EC2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An assessment of and quantification of costs and benefits of the significant regulatory action.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A5625680415489FAAA953E933135D29"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of and quantification of costs and benefits of potentially effective and feasible alternatives, including any underlying analysis.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1EA52FA5F1947A6BFFFC0E595F8D89D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An explanation of why the planned significant regulatory action is preferable to any identified potential alternatives.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3C6783AE2772488BB4C78DA91BE18BAA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Deadlines for review</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H570986E7A52E4AFEA23A687C3989741E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Review coordination</header><text>To the extent practicable, the head of each agency shall work with the Administrator to establish a mutually agreeable date on which to submit a significant regulatory action for review.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB8E692A0A4844E6DAEC9CBE7D0A7AA50"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Expedited review</header><text>When an agency is obligated by law to issue a significant regulatory action before complying with the provisions of this section, the head of the agency shall notify the Administrator as soon as possible. To the extent practicable, OIRA and the agency shall comply with the provisions of this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H233A27E769954474AAD2189527F5558B"><enum>(3)</enum><header><enum-in-header>10</enum-in-header>-day review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a significant regulatory action that is a notice of inquiry, advance notice of proposed rulemaking, or other preliminary regulatory action prior to a notice of proposed rulemaking, within 10 business days after the date of submission of the such action to the Administrator, OIRA shall complete the review.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H9EDCE149A10C4F5DAB2566BAA11CC859"><enum>(4)</enum><header><enum-in-header>90</enum-in-header>-day review</header>
 <subparagraph id="H95A1470F0227450F874C7C8AE2D8146C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), for any other significant regulatory action not described in paragraph (3), within 90 days after the date of submission of the action, OIRA shall complete the review.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6398D787466B443681496C4AF8F4BE2A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception 45-day review</header><text>If OIRA has previously reviewed the significant regulatory action described in subparagraph (A) and, since that review, there has been no material change in the facts and circumstances upon which the significant regulatory action is based, OIRA shall complete the review within 45 days after submission of the action.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HAC15AFB977554AD7AC24B9D106474776"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Extension</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any review described under this subsection may be extended for any number of additional 30-day periods upon mutual agreement of the Administrator and the head of the agency. For each 30 day extension, the Administrator shall make publicly available online a written explanation, including the reasons for the extension and an estimate of the expected conclusion date.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H424FFCFF2D6541EB94E12EE27AAFCD92"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Return</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Administrator determines OIRA is unable to conclude a review within the time period described under this subsection, the Administrator may return the draft of the significant regulatory action to the agency with a written explanation of why OIRA was unable to complete the review and what additional information, resources, or time OIRA would need to complete the review.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6C740647541543E8920F9D10E2806A7E"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>An agency may withdraw the regulatory action from OIRA review at any time prior to the completion of the review.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0625FDE537C841458EFCE61241385DC2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Compliance review</header><text>The Administrator shall review any significant regulatory action submitted under subsection (c) to determine the extent to which the agency—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDC060CF99C3043E8BD35D0E2A145C746"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identified the problem that the significant regulatory action is designed to address (including, where applicable, the failures of private markets or public institutions that warrant new agency action);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0D0CA071255C4A98B538D8829081DE5A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assessed the significance of the problem the regulatory action is designed to address;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7DE9B0AA7DF84199960FE44EF29CCAD5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>examined whether existing regulations or laws have created or contributed to the problem that the regulatory action is designed to correct and whether those regulations or laws should be modified to achieve the intended goal more effectively;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEB09E7B1BD814336A549B14C6279F27C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>identified and assessed available alternatives to direct regulation, including providing economic incentives to encourage desired behaviors, such as user fees or marketable permits, or providing information upon which choices can be made by the public;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB4F8835B09EB44A790AFB35803510095"><enum>(5)</enum><text>considered, to the extent reasonable, the degree and nature of the risks posed by various substances or activities within the jurisdiction of the agency;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2BCE7B76A9F741CD80AD21A571E90981"><enum>(6)</enum><text>designed the regulatory action to be the most cost-effective manner to achieve the regulatory objective;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H08147B384C5849BCA6A806AB59296AEC"><enum>(7)</enum><text>considered incentives for innovation, consistency, predictability, flexibility, distributive impacts, equity, and the costs of enforcement and compliance by the Government, regulated entities, and the public;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC836C7D12F324CB987A2C8D74B254785"><enum>(8)</enum><text>assessed costs and benefits of the regulatory action and made a reasoned determination that the benefits justify the costs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H51F6D553C73F49D081B74E4560401667"><enum>(9)</enum><text>used the best reasonably obtainable scientific, technical, economic, and other information concerning the need for and consequences of the regulatory action;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1C09956BFFF74693B88D983ACE960EAA"><enum>(10)</enum><text>identified and assessed alternative forms of regulation and, to the extent feasible, specified performance objectives rather than behavior or manner of compliance;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H492201CAC9C04E979CD8C275BCEF0C19"><enum>(11)</enum><text>sought comments and suggestions from impacted State, local, and tribal officials on any aspect of the regulatory action that might significantly or uniquely affect those governmental entities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H21BAC74A7926472AAA12C96FC0108DC5"><enum>(12)</enum><text>assessed the effects of the regulatory action on State, local, and tribal governments, including specifically the availability of resources to carry out the regulatory action, and minimized the burdens that uniquely or significantly affect such governmental entities, consistent with achieving regulatory objectives;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HED2F9884D56D4058BDC8D63124A69DA7"><enum>(13)</enum><text>harmonized the regulatory action with the regulatory and other functions of State, local, and tribal governments;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF3E7737E21264309A454FC65EB933436"><enum>(14)</enum><text>avoided conflicts with or duplication of other existing regulations;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB87B11509540425DAB8EA9C488DCA21D"><enum>(15)</enum><text>tailored the regulatory action to impose the least burden on society, including individuals, businesses of differing sizes, and other entities (including small communities and governmental entities), consistent with obtaining the regulatory objectives, and taking into account, among other things and to the extent practicable, the costs of cumulative regulations;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBCA78947E1D441CAA03D95596CCD7878"><enum>(16)</enum><text>drafted the regulatory action to be simple and easy to understand, and minimized the potential for uncertainty and litigation arising from such uncertainty;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0FAC61B9668D426FAB5478483CA8C435"><enum>(17)</enum><text>met all applicable Executive order requirements;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6E64667018C0496F8E5724C8DCC17422"><enum>(18)</enum><text>met all applicable statutory requirements; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9951956564694F9AA1559946D9764163"><enum>(19)</enum><text>complied with all applicable guidance.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H34D4643DC7F94F23A5849A2D23C8AE2B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Quality review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For any significant regulatory action submitted under subsection (c), OIRA shall review the extent to which the agency conducted a meaningful and complete analysis of each of the factors described in subsection (e), considering best practices, methods observed through reviewing other agencies, comments from stakeholders, and other resources that may improve the quality of the process.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEB5124E2D42D4EA392D6B058BFDA219C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Interagency consultation</header><text>The Administrator shall identify each agency potentially affected, interested, or otherwise likely to provide valuable feedback on a significant regulatory action submitted under subsection (c) and facilitate a meaningful interagency consultation process. The Administrator shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB9D71C00CD284B66BF862D1233B16B8A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide each identified agency with a copy of the draft regulatory action;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H825A56ECDED14133A973E554F55D5F63"><enum>(2)</enum><text>allow each identified agency to review the draft regulatory action for a sufficient period of time, not less than 10 business days;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H74557FC598E8471E9F2597F9AF656586"><enum>(3)</enum><text>solicit written comments from such agency; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H25322D29A73B48099A8851854435A33A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>as appropriate, facilitate conversations between agencies.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H65FB46FF35AC419C8724DDF0A17BF571"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Stakeholder consultation</header><text>For all substantive communications between OIRA and individuals not employed by the executive branch regarding a regulatory action submitted to the Administrator for review under this section, the Administrator shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6B45212A70D7438F8F6040450F2D853B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>invite the issuing agency to any meeting between OIRA personnel and individuals not employed by the executive branch;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8CD4CDA44CCF44DEBDC7E7C01F33F5C9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 10 business days after receipt of any written communication submitted by any individual not employed by the executive branch, make such communications available to the public online; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2E0B1340620740A4991F4154FD0E36A8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>make available to the public online a log, which shall be updated daily, of the following information:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H47CABF40D14B41EAA4158ABA94663F4A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The status of each regulatory action.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2C3489F7E6C4DD3A948CF612EB7EA58"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A copy of any written communication submitted by any person not employed by the executive branch.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H998BCB19A5974AA997A4D0F9D2441777"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The dates and names of persons involved in any substantive oral communication and the subject matter discussed during such communication.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3EE5EC39C8F1498E843EF3F7294A026B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Conclusion of review</header>
 <paragraph id="H06737C5A7957478A9DA47AF68ED0BA75"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Provision to agency</header><text>Upon completion of the review, the Administrator shall provide the head of an agency with the results of the OIRA review in writing, including a list of every standard, Executive order, guidance document, and law reviewed for compliance and the results for each.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC7007931E20145EB924C3B1E301B20EF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Changes during review period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As soon as practicable and before publication in the Federal Register of a significant regulatory action for which OIRA concluded review under this section, the head of the submitting agency shall make available to the Administrator a redline of any changes the agency made to the regulatory action during the review period. To the extent practicable, the agency shall identify any change made at the suggestion or recommendation of any other agency, member of the public, or other source. To the extent practicable, the agency should identify the source of any such change.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB7D5A4F7F1AD447093BE12AC92F1173C"><enum>3524.</enum><header>Disclosure of regulatory review</header>
 <subsection id="HAA816182371B461695D89199D8E89122"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On the earlier of the date on which an agency publishes a significant regulatory action reviewed under section 3523 in the Federal Register, the agency otherwise makes the significant regulatory action publicly available, or the agency announces a decision not to publish the regulatory action, the Administrator shall make available to the public online—</text>
 <paragraph id="H816EF7A443B748E9BC9833FA874113AE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all information submitted by an agency under section 3523;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBC90F80E02524185A8CAE52060BF72D9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the results of the review provided to the agency under section 3523;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9C20B4C8376B4F20BE9C36F5D10CC730"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the redline of any changes made by the agency during the course of the review provided under section 3523(i)(2);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEAF2B58C51254BF1B514C055161FB408"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all documents exchanged between senior level officials at OIRA and the agency during the review; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC0D6851C06F34696BE793DD6000A6DE4"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of each consultation described under section 3523(b).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H216F3A105A234416A5313192075B644E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Agency disclosure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each agency that submits a significant regulatory actions to OIRA under section 3522 or 3523 shall maintain on the website of the agency the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H717F6DD722B0458D96C46162BC896453"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A list of each active regulatory action, including the status of the regulatory action or a link to each entry on the unified agenda.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD4B684AE2F5B44549CEC889C04202116"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The most recent regulatory plan of the agency.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB0F37F0B395546D08986BF06E471EAEB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A link to each record disclosed under subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H96DB4266E62440AAA30FCD8A2FB698C9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Plain language requirement</header><text>All information provided to the public shall, to the extent practicable, be in plain, understandable language.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF154CDB49ECC439D810C99EA4C588372"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Recordkeeping</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall ensure any record associated with a significant regulatory action submitted to OIRA under section 3522 or 3523 is easily accessible for a period of time consistent with approved records disposition schedules for the agency, in a manner that all records associated with a significant regulatory action can be promptly submitted to Congress upon request.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H09BE2CC125914D769739E7832FD64570"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/44/3521">section 3521</external-xref> the following new items:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H832810B81980457EA64D66889820ACE7" style="USC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="item">3522. Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs Regulatory Working Group; regulatory plan;
			 Unified Agenda.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="item">3523. OIRA coordinated review of significant regulatory actions.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="item">3524. Disclosure of regulatory review.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD458A83984E74B3B90303C5861EBEA69"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Section 3502 of title 44, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HBE9CA624F3DA411F80097414EB42F6B6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (13)(D), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB5F641B897254BB7BC7BEB37AF745658"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (14), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H14936D98B95D457F85164976B4CE7901"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H88A5939BF10A4E4B942736DC2F6A4521" style="USC">
 <paragraph id="H86902C97F4864F0AB980D0510F63F1E3"><enum>(15)</enum><text>the term <term>Administrator</term> means, unless otherwise indicated, the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H66CA34D69BE24D21A9D8435AF75B85C7"><enum>(16)</enum><text>the term <term>economically significant regulatory action</term> means any regulatory action described under subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (21);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H30F2AB25635E47F6A64A222F79B979F2"><enum>(17)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>OIRA</term> means the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H92FC02FE429547AE9A01DF6796850D40"><enum>(18)</enum><text>the term <term>regulation</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="HDDFF2E66B79F4F8C9CAEB9CE15E05BFF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means an agency statement of general applicability and future effect, which the agency intends to have the force and effect of law, that is designed to implement, interpret, or prescribe law or policy or to describe the procedure or practice requirements of an agency; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF423D1ACA3C4CACB5B3A644B53070BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include such a statement if—</text> <clause id="H2930D288A31C4833854C326741A64F9C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>issued in accordance with the formal rulemaking provisions of sections 556 and 557 of title 5;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H340E9A31B78E4A7295D6B79833CB2213"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the statement pertains to a military or foreign affairs function of the United States, other than procurement regulations and regulations involving the import or export of nondefense articles and services;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H253489B6C34B481F8214675ABA432BD6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the statement is limited to an agency organization, management, or personnel matters; or</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HB6F5359825E64F64BCB1BE9FE2CEE3E9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the statement is exempted as a regulation by the Administrator and a written explanation of the exemption, including the date of the decision and the reasons for exempting the specific statement, is made publically available online;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H746F0EC64E3B49B3B4EE3F98BF81AA23"><enum>(19)</enum><text>the term <term>regulation identifier number</term> means a unique identification code for regulations, which is designed to assist tracking regulations through the course of development;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD51245A06BF94AF4BC7A2452C201C391"><enum>(20)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>regulatory action</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HBD4DFF8503C7420FA8D6060BD4966960"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any substantive action by an agency normally published in the Federal Register that promulgates or is expected to lead to the promulgation of a final regulation, including notices of inquiry, advance notices of proposed rulemaking, and notices of proposed rulemaking; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3B260F67332462092998306791BDB24"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any agency statement of general applicability and future effect, other than a substantive action described in subparagraph (A), which sets forth a policy on a statutory, regulatory, or technical issue or an interpretation of a statutory or regulatory issue;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9FA0856FBC946F3925A6C66110F4E88"><enum>(21)</enum><text>the term <term>significant regulatory action</term> means any regulatory action that is likely to result in a regulation that may—</text> <subparagraph id="H4322263646E94E66B32894532CBC99A2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have an annual effect on the economy of $100,000,000 or more;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2A5871EEF6848AE80A7547A3DC800F2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>adversely affect in a material way the economy, a sector of the economy, productivity, competition, jobs, the environment, public health or safety, or State, local, or tribal governments or communities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F9513D31C4A4AD98DCCD93F3B20E6FD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>create a serious inconsistency or otherwise interfere with an action taken or planned by another agency;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE4B5408AEAC4165AEFBBC6F9BF7D2E6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>materially alter the budgetary impact of entitlements, grants, user fees, or loan programs or the rights and obligations of recipients therein; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H605F8F891E7B46F59842848FA2F01E56"><enum>(E)</enum><text>raise novel legal or policy issues arising out of legal mandates;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H53AD440D584F433BB044C6A731DEADF3"><enum>(22)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>small business</term> has the meaning given the term <term>small-business concern</term> in section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE95D1582B46047B09E72291DB1472347"><enum>(23)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, each territory or possession of the United States, and each federally recognized Indian tribe.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEA543AE856AF43A8877E916F842078E4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Deadline for issuance of guidance</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs shall issue any guidance required by section 3522 of title 44, United States Code, as added by subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H94B5E05C750A40808C13F64234AF0F8C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Section 3524 of title 44, as added by subsection (a), shall take effect 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HC0DD19DE9AF84F89965BCB780DCA03E8"><enum>3.</enum><header>No additional funds authorized</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to carry out the requirements of this Act and the amendments made by this Act. Such requirements shall be carried out using amounts otherwise authorized.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
	<attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20170301">Passed the House of Representatives March 1, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill>


