<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC9FB1700EEC5429A9EBDBC14C385D7E1" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3535 IH: Ruffey Rancheria Restoration Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3535</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170728">July 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To restore Federal recognition to the Ruffey Rancheria of California, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H259D4A8FD1E14D8982A43D3436FF1B62" style="OLC">
 <section id="H3C51701557824AB49CB8B42B2D9C7FA7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ruffey Rancheria Restoration Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H441C65DA7D704906B0F0F7777D966055"><enum>2.</enum><header>Restoration of federal recognition, rights, and privileges</header> <subsection id="HA2A22DEEDCA24F19BFEC69AB00765B45"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Federal recognition</header><text>Federal recognition is hereby restored to the Tribe. Except as otherwise provided in this Act, all laws and regulations of general application to Indians and nations, tribes, or bands of Indians that are not inconsistent with any specific provision of this Act shall be applicable to the Tribe and its members.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H844547AD76874BA192BAE2BBE812ACFF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Restoration of rights and privileges</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (d), all rights and privileges of the Tribe and its members under any Federal treaty, Executive order, agreement, or statute, or under any other authority which were diminished or lost under the Act of August 18, 1958 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/85/671">Public Law 85–671</external-xref>; 72 Stat. 619), are hereby restored, and the provisions of such Act shall be inapplicable to the Tribe and its members after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H367CE9B935D04FABB123FE0FB96382BD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Federal services and benefits</header>
 <paragraph id="H176FC0A06E9E48F3BD31334BDB8CE0AC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Without regard to the existence of a reservation, the Tribe and its members shall be eligible, on and after the date of the enactment of this Act, for all Federal services and benefits furnished to federally recognized Indian Tribes or their members. For the purposes of Federal services and benefits available to members of federally recognized Indian tribes residing on a reservation, members of the Tribe residing in the Tribe’s service area shall be deemed to be residing on a reservation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6BE3DAECB0D74B76BA8D834888879EB9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Relation to other laws</header><text>The eligibility on the part of the Tribe and its members for, or receipt of, services and benefits under paragraph (1) shall not be considered as income, resources, or otherwise when determining the eligibility for or computation of any payment or other benefit to such tribe, individual, or household under—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCBE0040702884CD58382E315E2D6476C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any financial aid program of the United States, including grants and contracts subject to the Indian Self-Determination Act; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4A5BB9547E449DCBB6CFAD094F1757E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other benefit to which such tribe, household, or individual would otherwise be entitled under any Federal or federally assisted program.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H83811391E338453681C42ED8C907753C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Hunting, fishing, trapping, gathering, and water rights</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall expand, reduce, or affect in any manner any hunting, fishing, trapping, gathering, or water rights of the Tribe and its members.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H41BA073F8E41468D85A1D9372C5E2F23"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Certain rights not altered</header><text>Except as specifically provided in this Act, nothing in this Act shall alter any property right or obligation, any contractual right or obligation, or any obligation for taxes levied.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HE2D976973C0348DC9A4A6C2A54D152CA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Transfer of land to be held in trust</header>
 <subsection id="HB4BEA258F00F4C52981EAD6DE9052854"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Lands To be taken in trust</header><text>Upon application by the Tribe, the Secretary shall have the authority under this section to accept into trust for the benefit of the Tribe not more than 441 acres of real property located in Siskiyou County, California, after the property is conveyed or otherwise transferred to the Secretary and if, at the time of such conveyance or transfer, there are no adverse legal claims to such property, including outstanding liens, mortgages, or taxes.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H66D3FB84EB3C4D9582F074668E87A0F2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Former trust lands of the ruffey rancheria</header><text>Subject to the conditions specified in this section, real property eligible for trust status under this section shall include Indian owned fee land held by persons listed as distributees or dependent members in the distribution plan approved by the Bureau of Indian Affairs and published in the Federal Register on April 11, 1961, or such distributees’ or dependent members’ Indian heirs or successors in interest.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6E1E9A43C1E54066BE30BA87F844CC0B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Lands To be part of the reservation</header><text>Any real property taken into trust for the benefit of the Tribe pursuant to this Act shall be part of the Tribe’s reservation.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H032F3C4E1284403093FD4B7CCA79D2D8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Lands To be nontaxable</header><text>Any real property taken into trust for the benefit of the Tribe pursuant to this section shall be exempt from all local, State, and Federal taxation as of the date that such land is transferred to the Secretary.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H6BB0953A2AC94BA9AE4E98822450F60F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Membership rolls</header>
 <subsection id="H82919DEEBA9E48A4A884DEC4CCA48C41"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Compilation of tribal membership roll</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall, after consultation with the Tribe, compile a membership roll of the Tribe.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HD407C043D24441148E0D0224C3B1B6B7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Criteria for enrollments</header>
 <paragraph id="HCEA439E0DB14448FA81C28E282B10708"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Preconstitution roll</header><text>Until a tribal constitution is adopted pursuant to section 6, an individual shall be placed on the Ruffey Rancheria membership roll if the individual is living, is not an enrolled member of another federally recognized Indian tribe, and if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9ACD28E4D61F4FA985E487DB8A84BBF3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such individual’s name was listed on the Ruffey Rancheria distribution list compiled by the Bureau of Indian Affairs and approved by the Secretary and published in the Federal Register on April 11, 1961, under <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/85/671">Public Law 85–671</external-xref>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B6A1596A7054AFC98A761A95C874C19"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such individual was not listed on, but met the requirements that had to be met to be listed on the Ruffey Rancheria distribution list;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H543B32C70F7A4F0E85E6B54F69545F54"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such individual is of Indian ancestry and enumerated on any documents prepared by or at the direction of the Bureau of Indian Affairs for the Etna, Etna Mills, Fort Jones, Meamber, Ager, Bogus Creek, Hornbrook, Cleveland, or Sunnyside Districts, Siskiyou County, California, vicinities, or on any Federal census for Etna, Etna Mills, or Etna Township, Siskiyou County, California; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74D9DDB472644623A9DCAA39E83A9AB5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the individual is a lineal descendant of an individual, living or dead, identified in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4869114A243240B39CDA73EA722ECA77"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Roll after adoption of constitution</header><text>After adoption of a tribal constitution under section 6, such tribal constitution shall govern membership in the Tribe.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEB3B29B243144B25ADD4575AE6CB0CAD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conclusive proof of ruffey rancheria ancestry</header><text>For the purpose of subsection (b), the Secretary shall accept any available evidence establishing Ruffey Indian ancestry. The Secretary shall accept as conclusive evidence of Ruffey Indian ancestry information contained in the census of the Indians from Etna, Fort Jones, Meamber, Cleveland, or Sunnyside Districts, Siskiyou County, California, vicinities, prepared by or at the direction of Special Indian Agent C. E. Kelsey, in any roll or census of Etna, Etna Mills, Fort Jones, Ager, Bogus Creek, Hornbrook, or Salmon River Indians prepared by or at the direction of the Bureau of Indian Affairs or the U.S. Census, or in the Ruffey Rancheria distribution list compiled by the Bureau of Indian Affairs and approved by the Secretary and published in the Federal Register on April 11, 1961.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H98D4462C8DBC4B2FB50D1831C2DD372D"><enum>5.</enum><header>Interim government</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Until a new tribal constitution and bylaws are adopted and become effective under section 6, the governing body of the Tribe shall be an Interim Council. The initial membership of the Interim Council shall consist of the members of the Executive Council of the Tribe on the date of the enactment of this Act, and the Interim Council shall continue to operate in the manner prescribed for the Executive Council under the tribal constitution of the Tribe adopted on December 19, 2014, to the extent that such constitution is not contrary to Federal law. Any new members filling vacancies on the Interim Council shall meet the enrollment criteria set forth in section 4(b) and be elected in the same manner as are Executive Council members under the tribal constitution adopted December 19, 2014.</text>
		</section><section id="HAB08E78C5AAC4727BF1E2AF1C21D298D"><enum>6.</enum><header>Tribal constitution</header>
 <subsection id="HED5090C57FC44D52B2B8E4A20DFC8F8B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Election; time; procedure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After the compilation of the tribal membership roll under section 4, upon the written request of the Interim Tribal Council, the Secretary shall conduct, by secret ballot, an election for the purpose of ratifying a final constitution for the Tribe. The election shall be held consistent with sections 16(c)(1) and 16(c)(2)(A) of the Act of June 18, 1934 (commonly known as the Indian Reorganization Act; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5123">25 U.S.C. 5123(c)(1)</external-xref> and 5123(c)(2)(A), respectively). Absentee voting shall be permitted regardless of voter residence.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H419C1E3EFF214B8C95B9F98BD06EA789"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Election of tribal officials; procedures</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the Tribe ratifies a final constitution under subsection (a), the Secretary shall conduct an election by secret ballot for the purpose of electing tribal officials as provided in such tribal constitution. Such election shall be conducted consistent with the procedures specified in subsection (a) except to the extent that such procedures conflict with the tribal constitution.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H1C06E23C2C0D4012A8DF7745F21BD08D"><enum>7.</enum><header>Limitations on Indian gaming on acquired lands</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In addition to any other requirements under applicable Federal law, gaming conducted pursuant to an exception under section 20(b)(1)(b) of the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2719">25 U.S.C. 2719</external-xref>) shall not be conducted on any land taken into trust by the United States for the benefit of the Tribe unless the Secretary determines, on the date that the land is taken into trust, that the Tribe—</text>
 <paragraph id="H59FD016556B742628C2A4BEA13444D81"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has received a written determination by the Secretary that the land is eligible to be used for gaming under section 20 of the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA586B14117644F58BC8E4246F84E5440"><enum>(2)</enum><text>demonstrates—</text> <subparagraph id="H1DF6598938D44E7FA38129F5521C80F2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a substantial, direct, modern connection to the land taken into trust; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H935FC82D06284E9696F53A8A141CC709"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a substantial, direct, aboriginal connection to the land taken into trust.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HC8E986C5916D4601827EF499CC5175CE"><enum>8.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="H58A03CF29D0F4F2B803AE6F62F6C28A7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Tribe</term> means the Ruffey Rancheria of California.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H20BB4EC2AE5A4327B6D0867B431AD572"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEE8BDCFA561F4799AA1FF252E651FC47"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Interim Council</header><text>The term <term>Interim Council</term> means the governing body of the Tribe specified in section 6.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8C278C4625C0493A9ED74EEF8AAEEAA1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Member</header><text>The term <term>member</term> means any person meeting the enrollment criteria under section 4(b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H74656B5972C64767BD171C311677190C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of California.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5FA72C6F43FE429B9C916D0E7641F8EA"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Reservation</header><text>The term <term>reservation</term> means those lands acquired and held in trust by the Secretary for the benefit of the Tribe pursuant to section 3.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF10DC15E05FB4370AF144FDE97DE9200"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Service area</header><text>The term <term>service area</term> means the counties of Siskiyou and Shasta, in the State of California.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE6BE398B2934447AB3E4D439F407FF04"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Substantial, direct, modern connection to the land</header><text>The term <term>substantial, direct, modern connection to the land</term> means those lands within a 25-mile radius of land included in a request by the Tribe under section 3(a) made within 5 years following the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB88F46D422544DB4AA2FBAF8A5FBBF52"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Substantial, direct, aboriginal connection to the land</header><text>The term <term>substantial, direct, aboriginal connection to the land</term> means those lands that the Secretary determines are within a 25-mile radius of culturally significant sites to the Tribe, the area in which the language of the Tribe was spoken; or the historical presence of the Tribe on the land.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


