<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD52D71A801A6487AB2A96D8FCBFA2023" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1351 RH: Strengthening Oversight of TSA Employee Misconduct Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
		<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 161</calendar>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1351</legis-num>
		<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 115–226]</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20170302">March 2, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HHM00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<action>
			<action-date>July 17, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the
			 Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
			<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction>
			<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on March 2, 2017</action-instruction>
		</action>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-desc display="yes"><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To amend title 49, United States Code, to direct the Administrator of the Transportation Security
			 Administration (TSA) to make certain improvements in managing TSA’s
			 employee misconduct, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body changed="added" committee-id="HHM00" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H2609C8D2057B4DA98A730D7A8751B6F3" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <section id="H271CFDEDA3CD4DD8B4DAB9725FC63E3E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthening Oversight of TSA Employee Misconduct Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H183A8A534E914A8A9416037E9CF194F1" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>TSA Misconduct Inspection Plan</header> <subsection id="H6DE74CFD490947A7B89F63A90004DCA2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 44935 of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H61382DDABE26454C99AC4D83D25AA0C3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating the second subsection (i) (relating to accessibility of computer-based training facilities) as subsection (k); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H701E38B2EF964CAE812CDBD16834F87F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HHM00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB78B415C555B463D9D4F3E2238B1DF27" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H00E7086780314E33B0A7255BC94CCB09"><enum>(l)</enum><header>TSA misconduct inspections</header> <paragraph id="HBBD7FC28C476404C9504AB69EF3B8B5D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) shall—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HD620D105B50B4D668F34122666638132"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">designate a senior official to implement a plan to oversee unannounced inspections at airports of agency actions taken to address TSA employee misconduct, including actions taken by managers at airports to address any such misconduct through corrective actions, up to and including removal from Federal service, in accordance with Department of Homeland Security and TSA policies;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA7391A09AEA462894E3301949F82409"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on a biannual basis thereafter until September 30, 2023, the official specified in subparagraph (A) shall certify to the Administrator that the unannounced inspections referred to in such paragraph were completed across a sufficient number of airports such that all airports are—</text>
 <clause id="H40DC42C4F5924DBEB0D5F44897ED42E5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inspected before such date; and</text> </clause><clause id="H0DD327E2E1634D42BCA975813E3BA57F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provided adequate information regarding agency actions taken to address TSA employee misconduct;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HEFC4F99607984195AC6CCF89A0BC75E6"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">designate a senior official other than the senior official designated pursuant to subparagraph (A) to review the results of such unannounced inspections to identify causes of any variances and overall trends in the way actions are taken in response to TSA employee misconduct and develop corrective actions and recommendations, up to and including removal from Federal service, as appropriate; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE13113BF0CAE4FA48ABB4EB5D5143F3B"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">direct the official described in subparagraph (C) to implement the corrective actions and recommendations specified in such subparagraph.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H419C84B0FF47485490D88D0868D95F0B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consolidation and coordination</header><text>Unannounced inspections under paragraph (1) of certain locations may be consolidated and coordinated with other relevant TSA offices, as determined appropriate by the Administrator of the TSA.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1F813F22ECFA4B40841E0E602F74878D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Extension</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the TSA may extend the final date specified in paragraph (1)(B) for completing the unannounced inspections under paragraph (1) for not more than one additional fiscal year if exigent circumstances warrant. If the Administrator determines that such an extension is necessary, the Administrator shall provide to the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs,. the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate written justification regarding such circumstances prior to granting such extension.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H347F9CA41BC840D8BA62EC54681F3F77"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Department of Homeland Security review</header>
 <subparagraph id="HDCB44F4ABDE34CFE92B928C57D3DBD5B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On a biannual basis, the official specified in paragraph (1)(C) shall provide to the Chief Human Capital Officer of the Department of Homeland Security the results of unannounced inspections conducted pursuant to such paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8D5EB7E0B85F43009318430EC43BE131"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Identification</header><text>The Chief Human Capital Officer of the Department of Homeland Security may review the results of the unannounced inspections conducted pursuant to paragraph (1)(A) to, as appropriate, identify trends and make recommendations, to the Administrator of the TSA to address employee misconduct.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4075C6192774465CA9C6D80C632A833E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The Administrator of the TSA shall coordinate with the Chief Human Capital Officer of the Department of Homeland Security to implement any recommendations made pursuant to subparagraph (B) within the timeframes established by the Chief Human Capital Officer.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFA2D3A58C5242BEB4D1307611F62147"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Information to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the TSA shall make the results of the unannounced inspections, including any recommended corrective actions for addressing variances, identified under this subsection readily available to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2FAF6AE6C8B84BB1A6B8EE60B8F826CC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HACA4CAE97EE04FCDB46DECED3550668C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C902FA70BBF477B9A74A99231D1E678"><enum>(C)</enum><text>as appropriate, personnel of the Department of Homeland Security, as determined by the Administrator.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B30DD9B67D4494AAD8AE36786A3BEC2"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC1EA9A4F71A34D5995A78131D9A2309D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Actions</header><text>The term <quote>actions</quote> means consequences for employee misconduct, up to and including removal from Federal Service, established by TSA policy.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE5E57C70CA5A40A5B4CEB843B23BB9F0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Unannounced inspections</header><text>The term <quote>unannounced inspections</quote> means a review of information without providing advanced notice to the party under review.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H98A16247C5BB4D7A892652FB015308A7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No additional funds authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to carry out the requirements of this Act and the amendments made by this Act. Such requirements shall be carried out using amounts otherwise authorized.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
	<endorsement display="yes">
		<action-date>July 17, 2017</action-date>
		<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the
			 Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill>


