<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H72EDA0397E2542FB92C011CAC53DE278" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3788 IH: Northeast Gasoline Supply Reserve Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3788</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170914">September 14, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000379">Mr. Kennedy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001170">Ms. Shea-Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001037">Mr. Capuano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001165">Mr. Sires</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000482">Mr. Michael F. Doyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster of New Hampshire</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to provide for a Northeast Gasoline Supply Reserve,
			 and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H6FEBB6D5E62B4A79B245F1C724F29B88" style="OLC">
 <section id="H0B55E4F1847046DE85C322008A826CB5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Northeast Gasoline Supply Reserve Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H4C8741CF23E44E6193E7DB9F61EB308C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Northeast Gasoline Supply Reserve</header> <subsection id="HC6D07A54B22545C3AC3DB0DA4C02D883"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Northeast gasoline supply reserve</header><text>Title I of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6201">42 U.S.C. 6201</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H3A893C1665FF463EAE7F2DEB6EDE74CC" style="OLC">
					<part id="H6F8FA4B28E304D0FAFD3021BDFFFE589"><enum>E</enum><header>Northeast Gasoline Supply Reserve</header>
 <section id="H9D82B30737204FC7B212DA59A1C74566"><enum>191.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this part, the following definitions apply:</text> <paragraph id="HEE22DDCE90084B9C83C7E72A5AC5E6FB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Refined petroleum product</header><text>The term <term>refined petroleum product</term> means gasoline and such other products as the Secretary determines, by rule, appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF8A0A03C9F8F430C97074ED42B7DCE54"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reserve</header><text>The term <term>Reserve</term> means the Northeast Gasoline Supply Reserve established under this part.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H77C1CA18FE9343FD96D66C8689974FB4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Northeast</header><text>The term <term>Northeast</term> means the States of New Jersey, New York, Vermont, Pennsylvania, Connecticut, Rhode Island, Massachusetts, Maine, New Hampshire, and any other contiguous State that the Secretary determines appropriate.</text>
							</paragraph></section><section id="H43425AE0BB334D9EB21C83DD182C0A08"><enum>192.</enum><header>Establishment</header>
 <subsection id="H9A3372CE0C124444BBAB5F1EDF81D1B6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish, maintain, and operate in the Northeast a Northeast Gasoline Supply Reserve, which shall be a component of the Strategic Petroleum Reserve established under part B of this title.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4183B76D85D048108C80A5B344AE973F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>A Reserve established under this part shall contain no more than 1 million barrels of refined petroleum products.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H83C932B51BB049AA806C74C4114B6098"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application of provisions</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this part, the authorities and requirements of part B of this title shall apply to the Reserve.</text>
							</subsection></section><section id="H1D55293ABAF9470594A569275671909B"><enum>193.</enum><header>Conditions for release; plan</header>
 <subsection id="HC103AF647F0E4D599F6780543BA6EC9B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sale of products</header><text>The Secretary may sell refined petroleum products from the Reserve upon a finding by the President that there exists, or is likely to exist within the next 30 days, a severe energy supply interruption. Such a finding may be made only if the President determines that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC3FE06E5B1F54E718B6DECEF03416EA5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a dislocation in the refined petroleum product market has resulted or is likely to result from such interruption; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H94FEB428CCD945188F780374ABD19321"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a circumstance, other than that described in paragraph (1), exists that constitutes a regional supply shortage of significant scope and duration and that action taken under this section would assist directly and significantly in reducing the adverse impact of such shortage.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD7D952EE13894EB0B5DA2E54DCCC6C1A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Release of petroleum</header><text>After consultation with potentially affected parties, the Secretary shall determine procedures governing the release of refined petroleum products from the Reserve. The procedures shall provide that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDC774547F741485C83E91FB602613E30"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary may—</text> <subparagraph id="H926A102F66164990A4BF48C99550F03B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>sell refined petroleum products from the Reserve through a competitive process; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H936E4B398F974AC6937430F673988781"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enter into exchange agreements for the refined petroleum products that results in the Secretary receiving a greater volume of such products as repayment than the volume provided to the acquirer;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F242FA9935449C3B3E8C56EC6A76901"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in all sales or exchanges described in paragraph (1), the Secretary shall receive revenue or its equivalent in refined petroleum products that provides the Department with fair market value;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC2E5E4CC3DB443EFA931D624B887044E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>at no time may refined petroleum products be sold or exchanged resulting in a loss of revenue or value to the United States; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3850E9BBBE9D46ED815832CC923FDAD2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Secretary shall only sell or dispose of refined petroleum products in the Reserve to entities customarily engaged in the sale and distribution of such products.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD42A22C9BCAD4814AEE239361E4E97AA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Plan</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall transmit to the President and, if the President approves, to Congress a plan describing—</text>
 <paragraph id="H97CA2850A80E4DE587518FFB0C424C95"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the proposed acquisition of storage and related facilities or storage services for the Reserve, including the potential use of storage facilities not currently in use;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCC885CC8371440D6AEA3478502A5AEB6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the proposed acquisition of refined petroleum products for storage in the Reserve;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7CB871F52F294CAC924B369CA299995B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the anticipated methods of disposition of refined petroleum products from the Reserve;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFFE125C716D3495090116BAB7B26F348"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the estimated costs of establishment, maintenance, and operation of the Reserve;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H348AB6FF5E7C4D4C98D1A984CF9009D5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>efforts the Department will take to minimize any potential need for future drawdowns and ensure that distributors and importers are not discouraged from maintaining and increasing supplies to the Northeast; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7C0E4510FEE04E0AB809032945A48208"><enum>(6)</enum><text>actions to be taken to ensure quality of the refined petroleum products in the Reserve.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H144EF0713C6E42FDA1CE02F113723D53"><enum>194.</enum><header>Products for storage in the Reserve</header> <subsection id="H459B0B6B49D94A5BB6515FC480F804D0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may acquire, place in storage, transport, or exchange refined petroleum products acquired by purchase or exchange.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDF93977C20E14F7894C516AE43E27D12"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Objectives</header><text>The Secretary shall, to the greatest extent practicable, acquire refined petroleum products for the Reserve in a manner consonant with the following objectives:</text>
 <paragraph id="H006F6ABC781A409DA1BFFBD5892F73E3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Minimization of the cost of the Reserve.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H79FC1B213F374BAFB0D7087FAA830E95"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Minimization of the Nation’s vulnerability to a severe energy supply interruption.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H27337FAD2967413B961A07F5385CE3B8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Minimization of the impact of an acquisition of refined petroleum products on supply levels and market forces.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB38FCD775D204A6786BBA78A6D4199EC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Encouragement of competition in the petroleum industry.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H981280C407764B9681E0662297AE17DF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text>The Secretary shall develop, with public notice and opportunity for comment, procedures consistent with the objectives of this section to acquire refined petroleum products for the Reserve. Such procedures shall take into account the need to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H35405FA588A04311AF3B7DD998E92F64"><enum>(1)</enum><text>maximize overall domestic supply of refined petroleum products (including quantities stored in private sector inventories);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4F220827686C4B1A83D55A353608777D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>avoid incurring excessive cost or appreciably affecting the price of refined petroleum products to consumers;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE0F45502AB1430E91B01337598444CD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>minimize the costs to the Department of Energy in acquiring such refined petroleum products;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCBE34FC771EA498480798271EC0276A7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>protect national security;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC8BE04C70E4D46BB849CC470B558841B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>avoid adversely affecting current and futures prices, supplies, and inventories of refined petroleum products; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4A9E6AFD905643B39DE12657BCC0150E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>address such other factors that the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H377B51990F954CB5A177757997C6D7D1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Severe energy supply disruption</header><text>If the Secretary finds that a severe energy supply interruption may be imminent, the Secretary may suspend the acquisition of refined petroleum products for the Reserve and may sell any refined petroleum product acquired for, and in transit to, the Reserve.</text></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H64310E67A4E34057A69F8A1B2A2D0B96"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for title I of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act is amended by striking the items relating to the second part D, including section 181 of such part, and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H659F03EB7EA5462BB2E5C6A656A58AEA" style="OLC">
					<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="H3A893C1665FF463EAE7F2DEB6EDE74CC" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
						<toc-entry idref="H6F8FA4B28E304D0FAFD3021BDFFFE589" level="part">Part E—Northeast Gasoline Supply Reserve</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry idref="H9D82B30737204FC7B212DA59A1C74566" level="section">Sec. 191. Definitions.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry idref="H43425AE0BB334D9EB21C83DD182C0A08" level="section">Sec. 192. Establishment.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry idref="H1D55293ABAF9470594A569275671909B" level="section">Sec. 193. Conditions for release; plan.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry idref="H144EF0713C6E42FDA1CE02F113723D53" level="section">Sec. 194. Products for storage in the Reserve.</toc-entry>
					</toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


