<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H03C8D1848D7D44D8B53ED7FF3EE42114" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3857 IH: Protecting Advice for Small Savers Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3857</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170927">September 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001189">Mr. Messer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000475">Mr. Trott</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000599">Mr. Posey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000816">Mr. Williams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001305">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001074">Mr. Hollingsworth</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000392">Mr. Kustoff of Tennessee</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to establish standards of conduct for brokers and
			 dealers that are in the best interest of their retail customers.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HA0224D2BAF284229A794E3181486BE02" style="OLC">
 <section id="H56FF555310044FEEA4D6E17DD2843E99" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Advice for Small Savers Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PASS Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H57620ACD78B34FBEB08FAA942E17A660"><enum>2.</enum><header>Repeal of Department of Labor Fiduciary Rule</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The final rule of the Department of Labor titled <quote>Definition of the Term <quote>Fiduciary</quote> Conflict of Interest Rule—Retirement Investment Advice</quote> and related prohibited transaction exemptions published April 8, 2016 (81 Fed. Reg. 20946), shall have no force or effect.</text>
		</section><section id="H7ABCBC71D3584DD2BA00A979DFEE4CD5" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Standards of conduct for brokers and dealers</header>
			<subsection id="HE7FB036A79E84D7F9E409D6A55378AB9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Standard of conduct for brokers and dealers when making recommendations to retail customers</header>
 <paragraph id="HB371B4A5935443AE88708695BF8818C3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The second subsection (k) of section 15 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78o">15 U.S.C. 78o(k)</external-xref>) (relating to standards of conduct) is amended to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HABFA65D3C6034B19ABA473483093389F" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="H9F2493A75E784C31AACF6169F1079908"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Standard of conduct for recommendations to retail customers</header>
 <paragraph id="HD977BBACC7E44A8BBA808A7A884AA6C1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The standard of conduct for a broker or dealer (or registered representative) when providing recommendations to a retail customer is as follows:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4247EC6C136D4E1888467DDEFAB625C5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Recommendation to retail customer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When a broker or dealer (or registered representative) makes a recommendation to a retail customer, the recommendation shall be in the retail customer’s best interest at the time it is made by—</text>
 <clause id="H9BAD6408B8594C3586CF6673FF042161"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reflecting reasonable diligence; and</text> </clause><clause id="H0954F8CBF2224ECBA835DE697377B86F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reflecting the reasonable care, skill, and prudence that a broker or dealer (or registered representative) would exercise based on the customer’s investment profile.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E1D5D8A51A34B9195512F277381FD3D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Disclosure to retail customer</header>
 <clause id="HBFF8410821EE4DD2A9554CB1DD0D4429"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Before a broker or dealer (or registered representative) executes a transaction for the first time for each retail customer based on a recommendation to such retail customer, such broker or dealer (or registered representative) shall disclose prior to the point of sale to such customer, in a clear and concise manner—</text>
 <subclause id="H377F4D2E0CB74CACA59D2C55C40757F2"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the type and scope of services the broker or dealer (or registered representative) provides;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H8FD6E41BA269469786EB5C15CC5E901B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the standard of conduct that applies to the relationship;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H9DA8376072074504B32FB6A32F486FE3"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the types of compensation the broker or dealer (or registered representative) receives; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H29961D3A4D9C421C8C3763EA82BA1292"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>any material conflict of interest.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H87C9D93A66CC43BBB2689BE77A57280E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Content of disclosure</header><text>The Commission may issue regulations determining the content of the disclosure required in clause (i). Such regulations may provide for a disclosure of fees received by the broker or dealer, whether from the retail customer or a third party, prior to the execution of the transaction.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9ADED9927E54478B555EE074E4F1190"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Material conflict of interest</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A broker or dealer (or registered representative) shall avoid, disclose, or otherwise reasonably manage any material conflict of interest with a retail customer.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE9FFE53AA83435981E0B02C8DC592BB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nonviolation of standard of conduct</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following is not, by itself, a violation of the standard of conduct described in paragraph (1):</text> <subparagraph id="H722DE18247644CDB98247175D9E783F1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The receipt of compensation, including transaction-based compensation, by a broker or dealer (or registered representative) or any affiliate of such broker or dealer (or registered representative).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEAE74BE90CB3425D876A488B107DDC53"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The recommendation by a broker or dealer (or registered representative) to a retail customer of principal transactions (including cross transactions), or the recommendation of affiliated, unaffiliated, or proprietary products or services, or a limited range of products or services.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H48BA70B8009041EEB888A3BB75664DE7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>No requirement to recommend least expensive product</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection shall require a broker or dealer (or registered representative) to recommend the least expensive security or investment strategy (however quantified) or to analyze all possible securities, other products, or investment strategies before making a recommendation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5F82C4CD885147718A90093E24833A9C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="H0D40CA038A7A42788AE22E69F78AD5F6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>compensation</term> includes commissions or sales charges, or other fees or variable compensation, for or related to the sale of securities or for the servicing of customer accounts, whether paid by the retail customer or received from a third party.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9767822BED644664A666A46254C9DD1A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Customer’s investment profile</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>customer’s investment profile</term> has the meaning of such term as described in Rule 2111 of the Financial Industry Regulatory Authority as of the date of the enactment of this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B00D973F1764EE5B8C9BAC299E81C4C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Institutional account</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>institutional account</term> has the same meaning given such term in Rule 4512 of the Financial Industry Regulatory Authority as of the date of the enactment of this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H79D3DAE3B396425DB19B618F36AAD9CA"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Material conflict of interest</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>material conflict of interest</term> means a financial interest of a broker or dealer (or registered representative) that a reasonable person would expect to affect the impartiality of a recommendation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2EEFFD8F505446B58708D9F77062D210"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Reasonable diligence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>reasonable diligence</term> has the meaning of such term as described in Rule 2111 of the Financial Industry Regulatory Authority as of the date of the enactment of this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D2E5EF1F8004FABA3F915DE1491890F"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Recommendation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>recommendation</term> means either of the following recommendations (under the meaning ascribed to such term in Rule 2111 of the Financial Industry Regulatory Authority) for which the broker or dealer (or registered representative) making the recommendation receives or will receive compensation:</text>
 <clause id="HD17978F6CD534AA8BD7C770A3EAE9AF8"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A non-discretionary recommendation to buy, hold, or sell securities, or to follow an investment strategy involving securities, for taxable or non-taxable accounts.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8FEB1127388A457EBF36C285213AA796"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A non-discretionary recommendation to rollover or transfer assets in an employer-sponsored retirement plan to an individual retirement account.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BF9D138755C4CD186106B9650814A4F"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Retail customer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>retail customer</term> means a natural person or legal entity, or the legal representative of such natural person or legal entity, in each case other than an institutional account, who—</text>
 <clause id="H86B1A47CFF8049F5992A446BBEB44E0B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>receives a recommendation from a broker or dealer (or registered representative); and</text> </clause><clause id="H40393769983541F18B4109F3F3BE2FE4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>implements such recommendation with such broker or dealer primarily for personal, family, retirement, or household purposes.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD90314087054177992FD9DE11E32137"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Supersession</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provisions of this subsection shall supersede and preempt State law, other than a State law that regulates insurance products that are not securities, insofar as they may now or hereafter relate to a broker or dealer, or registered representative of a broker or dealer.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="HF8CE0562B4014B4EA370A2D34463E36C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Fiduciary status under ERISA, the Internal Revenue Code, the Investment Advisers Act of 1940, or
 other fiduciary regimes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The fact that a person may owe, or may in fact comply with, the standard of conduct under this subsection shall not mean or create any presumption that such person is a <quote>fiduciary</quote> under the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1001">29 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref> et seq.), <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4975">section 4975</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80b">15 U.S.C. 80b</external-xref> et seq.), or any other Federal, State, or local statutory or regulatory fiduciary regime.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCFD58D9A0EF2491B943D5C50B3B11A90"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by paragraph (1) shall apply to brokers and dealers (or registered representative) on the date that is 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4CBB089F3472489284394E91F561F9E9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rulemaking authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 913 of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H092366F67AAD4E4DADF465112E5B6BA4" style="OLC">
					<section id="HBC78A323E8D049948FFA2DC4814019D9"><enum>913.</enum><header>Obligations of brokers and dealers and other persons and entities</header>
						<subsection id="H1CDB63D3F1184AE7B40BEE5350C5F1BF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header>
 <paragraph id="HE1698A359D1F43E4BE4B238261910E84"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rulemaking by the Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission may issue regulations as the Commission determines is necessary to facilitate compliance by brokers and dealers (including their registered representative) with the obligations of such brokers and dealers (and their registered representative) under the second subsection (k) of section 15 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 only if such rulemaking does not impose any obligation related to standard of care on a broker or dealer (or its registered representative) that is in addition to, duplicative of, or inconsistent with, the obligations set forth in such subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD6060959979D4D15A19E78F93D5D40E9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rulemaking by the Secretary of Labor and the Secretary of the Treasury</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After the date of the enactment of the PASS Act of 2017, the Secretary of Labor and the Secretary of the Treasury shall not promulgate any regulation under the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1001">29 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref> et seq.) or <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4975">section 4975</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, respectively, defining the circumstances under which a person is considered a fiduciary that would impose any obligation on a broker or dealer (or its registered representative) or on a life insurer fulfilling the term <term>insurance company</term> as defined in section 3(a)(2) of the Securities Act of 1933 (or its agents or distributors) that is in addition to, duplicative of, or inconsistent with, the obligations set forth in such subsection (k) of section 15 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78o">15 U.S.C. 78o</external-xref>).</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6D41F9EED7D44D73847385067D5F819B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exemption available to certain persons with respect to manufacture or sale of annuities</header>
 <paragraph id="H9D9D6D00BD0D4CE49F24316541938F71"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the manufacture or sale of annuities within paragraphs (2) or (8) of section 3(a) of the Securities Act of 1933 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/77c">15 U.S.C. 77c(a)</external-xref>) or section 989J of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/77c">15 U.S.C. 77c</external-xref> note), a person regulated by a State insurance regulator may rely on the exemptions in section 408(b)(21) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1108">29 U.S.C. 1108(b)(21)</external-xref>) and <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4975">section 4975(d)(24)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (as added by the PASS Act of 2017) only if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H683FA8B36A80493680F9F554A58CA17B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such person adopts and implements practices on a nationwide basis for the sale of annuity contracts that meet or exceed the minimum requirements set forth in the second subsection (k) of section 15 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78o">15 U.S.C. 78o</external-xref>) and such person is subject to regulation or examination by a State insurance regulator for purposes of assessing market conduct; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B108B6123914F548CAF805B0E7B246F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such person complies with a standard substantially similar to such subsection (k) and is regulated by a State insurance regulator with respect to annuities within paragraphs (2) or (8) of section 3(a) of the Securities Act of 1933 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/77c">15 U.S.C. 77c(a)</external-xref>) or section 989J of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/77c">15 U.S.C. 77c</external-xref> note).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BFAEAB56D124EC0ABAE530F0A2F1759"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination and cooperation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the request of any State insurance regulator, the Commission or the Financial Industry Regulatory Authority shall provide such reasonable assistance to the requesting Authority as needed in connection with the coordination or implementation of this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H483CD8EC40904B04B0DC65ACD4BC8B02"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definition of State insurance regulator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As used in this subsection, the term <term>State insurance regulator</term> means the principal insurance regulatory authority of a State, the District of Columbia, any territory of the United States, Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, the Virgin Islands, and the Northern Mariana Islands.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H854967BD4DF14292BD1DCD379D4C4C83"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional exemptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person who complies with a standard substantially similar to the second subsection (k) of section 15 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78o">15 U.S.C. 78o</external-xref>) may rely on the exemptions in section 408(b)(21) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1108">29 U.S.C. 1108(b)(21)</external-xref>) and <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4975">section 4975(d)(24)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (as added by the PASS Act of 2017) only if such person is—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H7CA0B10F711C4D2FA201AD1D01777671"><enum>(1)</enum><text>registered as an investment adviser under the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80b-1">15 U.S.C. 80b–1</external-xref> et seq.) or under the laws of the State in which the person maintains its principal office and place of business; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD6E80B9775434391AD213CA94B28164E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a bank or similar financial institution supervised by the United States or a State, or a savings association (as defined in section 3(b)(1) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813(b)(1)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H245EE190AABB45A3A2B49DD194DCFE88"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exemption from prohibited transactions for brokers and dealers, and other persons and entities,
			 when making recommendations to retail customers</header>
 <paragraph id="H54CAA631EE8446599271313BD3440633"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 408(b) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1108">29 U.S.C. 1108(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H31BACB9E7F41446C9754F72FE02EC79E" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HDA10B8BAFA614C7DA22910C7CBF7850A"><enum>(21)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any transaction involving a recommendation made by a broker or dealer (including its registered representative), or other persons or entities, that is subject to the requirements of the second subsection (k) of section 15 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78o">15 U.S.C. 78o(k)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEC43FDC6E4B3412E8411CE821C20ECF8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4975">Section 4975(d)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF48E696EA0274C918616DC43F1BF7AFC" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H3E13FDE0C575480986B70727A1AC82E3"><enum>(24)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any transaction involving a recommendation made by a broker or dealer (including its registered representatives), or other persons or entities, that is subject to the requirements of the second subsection (k) of section 15 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78o">15 U.S.C. 78o(k)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H62EA95D2543B4619BA2F2A31B358CC93"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Repeal of certain provisions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following provisions are hereby repealed:</text> <paragraph id="H6AADDA6518624AD8A8D438F5144F80BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The second subsection (l) and subsection (m) of section 15 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78o">15 U.S.C. 78o</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H456187B872054D329E8C7B4AFF7E4059"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsections (g), (h), and (i) of section 211 of the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80b-11">15 U.S.C. 80b–11</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


