<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB61BA130D25A456090C5DE2881172F53" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3554 IH: Streamlining Income-driven, Manageable Payments on Loans for Education Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3554</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170728">July 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001106">Mr. Costello of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001181">Mr. Meehan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to provide for the automatic recertification of income
			 for income-driven repayment plans, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H5892082BCC4E4C8E8B5BE72A0ED72E8E" style="OLC">
 <section id="H8E58792416C1435DAB15EE912420E9A3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Streamlining Income-driven, Manageable Payments on Loans for Education Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SIMPLE Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H91D8902912624800ABAA876FC6C9600D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Automatic income monitoring procedures after a total and permanent disability discharge</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 437(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087">20 U.S.C. 1087(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB52E9101A852477088599E4194F0D831" style="OLC">
				<paragraph id="HDBBFA2B4F67A454AAA0099BB7A24F11A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Automatic income monitoring</header>
 <subparagraph id="H4F0698B7FA9B48A9BA4D7ACFE7FF5DE1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Streamlining Income-driven, Manageable Payments on Loans for Education Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall establish and implement, with respect to any borrower described in subparagraph (B), procedures to—</text>
 <clause id="H9209E63B430840AD8808BC6644A6F081"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">obtain (for each year of the income-monitoring period described in subparagraph (B) and without further action by the borrower) such information as is reasonably necessary regarding the income of such borrower (and the borrower’s spouse, if applicable) for the purpose of determining the borrower’s continued eligibility for the loan discharge described in subparagraph (B) for such year, and any other information necessary to determine such continued eligibility of the borrower for such year, except that—</text>
 <subclause id="HF3DC6B225EF745008DFB3C1E2009BAAE"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a borrower whose returns and return information indicate that the borrower has no earned income for any year of such income-monitoring period, such borrower shall be treated as not having earned income in excess of the poverty line for such year; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H0168A6DD5DEC443F885C2CE72EC46BA8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>this clause shall be subject to clause (ii);</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HD43AC24191A2439D9735854E4B56E8A5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">allow the borrower, at any time, to opt out of clause (i) and prevent the Secretary from obtaining information under such clause without further action by the borrower; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF73670C42B3C4BCE9ED92443DBC5482F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide the borrower with an opportunity to update the information obtained under clause (i) before the determination of the borrower’s continued eligibility for such loan discharge for such year.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7FFB762462B546D4989E8EEAFEBAE424"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (A) shall apply—</text> <clause id="HE0CD9672AC9E4817B5B6F8CF603BAEF0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to each borrower of a covered loan (defined in section 455(d)(8)) that is discharged under this subsection or section 464(c)(1)(F) due to the permanent and total disability of the borrower; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0A18032C2A2241009410BA959BC1A42B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">during the income-monitoring period under this subsection, defined in this paragraph as the period—</text> <subclause id="H43F6D70E4FDC46D28F47EF4BA3AC59D1"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">beginning on the date on which such loan is so discharged; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H146E1BC85F4B4337A6B8DE388EB62B4F"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">during which the Secretary determines whether a reinstatement of the obligation of, and resumption of collection on, such loan may be necessary.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BF9047498204A0F82C25CEE277A4018"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Availability of returns and return information</header><text>Returns and return information may be obtained under subparagraph (A)(i) only to the extent authorized by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">section 6103(l)(13)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8BEE181F4684440699D2961097B2858C"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <quote>returns and return information</quote> has the meaning given the term in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">section 6103</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section><section id="H7E451B8824644E2583AE1833BCA14344"><enum>3.</enum><header>Notification and automatic enrollment procedures for borrowers who are delinquent on loans and for borrowers who rehabilitated defaulted loans</header> <subsection id="H8B4B3A14774C4B78B629A44C608F1F55"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendments</header> <paragraph id="HD1B061B44EAF45C1907B531B162B5B10"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notification and automatic enrollment procedures</header><text>Section 455(d) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(d)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4BC77EE565C744EA993C14B003E3831A" style="OLC">
						<paragraph id="H337A747A39E0471594A70B72ED8C4148"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Notification and automatic enrollment procedures for borrowers who are delinquent on loans</header>
							<subparagraph id="H74E44CD9BC1A44FBAE5BB33027DF8950"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Authority to obtain income information</header>
 <clause id="H68D7FD0059A84921A1F2C791D10B1E7A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any borrower who is at least 60 days delinquent on a covered loan, the Secretary may obtain such information as is reasonably necessary regarding the income and family size of the borrower (and the borrower's spouse, if applicable).</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEB5609F02D034452ABC0C9931BC2E0B0"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Availability of returns and return information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Returns and return information (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">section 6103</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) may be obtained under this subparagraph only to the extent authorized by section 6103(l)(13) of such Code.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H033E138C80694CC09FE888F8CFAE5DB9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Borrower notification</header><text>With respect to each borrower of a covered loan who is at least 60 days delinquent on such loan and who has not been subject to the procedures under this paragraph for such loan in the preceding 120 days, the Secretary shall, as soon as practicable after such 60-day delinquency, provide to the borrower the following:</text>
 <clause id="HE7A5E952383B442F8EBF0490A67206AB"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notification that the borrower is at least 60 days delinquent on at least 1 covered loan, and a description of all delinquent covered loans, nondelinquent covered loans, and noncovered loans of the borrower.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H24D48F13C8734F3BBE887282F7D61359"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A brief description of the repayment plans for which the borrower is eligible and the covered loans and noncovered loans of the borrower that may be eligible for such plans, based on information available to the Secretary.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9A6A6890662B44349C07D768A37F6335"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Clear and simple instructions on how to select the repayment plans.</text> </clause><clause id="H9AD8366F501447EFBE7C610EC74027E1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The amount of monthly payments for the covered and noncovered loans under the repayment plans for which the borrower is eligible, based on information available to the Secretary, including, if the income information of the borrower is available to the Secretary under subparagraph (A)—</text>
 <subclause id="H0B08596C493F4FBABE87FB738CCA5549"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the amount of the monthly payment under each income-driven repayment plan for which the borrower is eligible for the borrower's covered and noncovered loans, based on such income information; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H4BAC36071499492D8F8A9EA414B7CD19"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the income, family size, tax filing status, and tax year information on which each monthly payment is based.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H578B5E1BC7BF43A3A7FDD536C13E5F33"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An explanation that in the case of a borrower for whom adjusted gross income is unavailable—</text> <subclause id="H8ADE48A1947240C48BC855CDB2F4463D"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the borrower selects to repay the covered loans of such borrower pursuant to an income-driven repayment plan that defines discretionary income in such a manner that an individual not required under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6012">section 6012(a)(1)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to file a return with respect to income taxes imposed by subtitle A of such Code may have a calculated monthly payment greater than $0, the borrower will be required to provide the Secretary with other documentation of income satisfactory to the Secretary, which documentation the Secretary may use to determine an appropriate repayment schedule; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HD6F17D77FBCD49DA970028C87BE7C901"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the borrower selects to repay such loans pursuant to an income-driven repayment plan that is not described in subclause (I), the borrower will not be required to provide the Secretary with such other documentation of income, and the borrower will have a calculated monthly payment of $0.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H7642CBFF2D8E48C2BAA9E2CAE0694DD3"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>An explanation that the Secretary shall take the actions under subparagraph (C) with respect to such borrower, if—</text>
 <subclause id="H00A567A2E2224B4D92E874F6004232CC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the borrower is 120 days delinquent on one or more covered loans and has not selected a new repayment plan for the covered loans of the borrower; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA4F9DF7EBB8446F082DE0E850FBA5C8C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the case of such a borrower whose repayment plan for the covered loans of the borrower is not an income-driven repayment plan, the monthly payments under such repayment plan are higher than such monthly payments would be under an income-driven repayment plan for such loans.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H255AFA2BF6AE498F9AE5D73BB2641970"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Instructions on updating the information of the borrower obtained under subparagraph (A).</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68507283228543E99175DFE0E66A49BA"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Secretary's initial selection of plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to each borrower described in subparagraph (B) who has a repayment plan for the covered loans of the borrower that meets the requirements of clause (vi)(II) of subparagraph (B) and has not selected a new repayment plan for such loans in accordance with the notice received under such subparagraph, and who is at least 120 days delinquent on such a loan, the Secretary shall, as soon as practicable—</text>
 <clause id="HFB771C6DD754407FA4EDD4919750D1F5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in a case in which any of the borrower's covered loans are eligible for an income-driven repayment plan—</text>
									<subclause id="H119396C8ED8B412FB209F6363E8D948E"><enum>(I)</enum>
 <item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC6B1693761744BC98AC732E048E405D9"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide the borrower with the income-driven repayment plan that requires the lowest monthly payment amount for each covered loan of the borrower, compared to any other such plan for which the borrower is eligible; or</text>
 </item><item id="H58194A51A9894927B521443CFBD87DFE" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if more than one income-driven repayment plan would offer the borrower the same lowest monthly payment amount, provide the borrower with the income-driven repayment plan that has the most favorable terms for the borrower;</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H6764A0536DDA4E59823DD295FD10F953"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the plan selected under subclause (I) is not the income-driven repayment plan that would have the lowest monthly payment amount if the borrower were eligible for such plan for the borrower’s covered loans and noncovered loans, notify the borrower of the actions, if any, the borrower may take to become eligible for such income-driven repayment plan; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H81F4DC6F8F6143798485248841D66441"><enum>(III)</enum><text>authorize the borrower to change the Secretary’s selection of a plan under this clause to any plan described in paragraph (1) for which the borrower is eligible; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H8EC931BC07D24D6CA8936F32993C421E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in a case in which none of the borrower’s covered loans are eligible for an income-driven repayment plan, notify the borrower of the actions, if any, the borrower may take for such loans to become eligible for such a plan.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4967D26D075E4FDD8E3C2D482358AC7A"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Secretary's additional selection of plan</header>
 <clause id="H5767D930143D48078EEA06A7EF08618C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to each borrower of a covered loan who selects a new repayment plan in accordance with the notice received under subparagraph (B) and who continues to be delinquent on such loan for a period described in clause (ii), the Secretary shall, as soon as practicable after such period, carry out the procedures described in clauses (i) and (ii) of subparagraph (C) for the covered loans of the borrower, if such procedures would result in lower monthly repayment amounts on such loan.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9DB5D8E435C9440FBF712D7658EB4DF8"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Description of period</header><text>The duration of the period described in clause (i) shall be the amount of time that the Secretary determines is sufficient to indicate that the borrower may benefit from repaying such loan under a new repayment plan, but in no case shall such period be less than 60 days.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF63DDB312340480C9BE55BDFEB4539ED"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Opt-out</header><text>A borrower of a covered loan shall have the right to opt out of the procedures under this paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H10C2C3B562D24F4CBC2E7B152C53167A"><enum>(F)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Procedures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish procedures as are necessary to effectively implement this paragraph.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5BFF111C56034951A319D0A203249D17"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Notification and automatic enrollment procedures for borrowers who are rehabilitating defaulted loans</header> <subparagraph id="HC6E186C21EF74E3CB12754ADF5CF77C3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Authority to obtain income information</header> <clause id="HDE030861A92F4E17934C09C49CE00D70"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any borrower who is rehabilitating a covered loan pursuant to section 428F(a), the Secretary may obtain such information as is reasonably necessary regarding the income and family size of the borrower (and the borrower's spouse, if applicable).</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA388AC3219804C8DB2EC4C6650BD79FB"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Availability of returns and return information</header><text>Returns and return information (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">section 6103</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) may be obtained under this subparagraph only to the extent authorized by section 6103(l)(13) of such Code.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCEF413EA83174806AA4E150BEA504933"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Borrower notification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after a borrower makes the 6th payment required for the loan rehabilitation described in subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall notify the borrower of the process under subparagraph (C) with respect to such loan.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D80A408A9C04BDAA1F185B57E8E66FA"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Secretary's selection of plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to each borrower who has made the 9th payment required for the loan rehabilitation described in subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall, as soon as practicable after such payment—</text>
 <clause id="HC2665482D3794AFD8292810E1187BF9C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in a case in which any of the borrower's covered loans, without regard to whether the loan has been so rehabilitated, is eligible for an income-driven repayment plan—</text>
									<subclause id="H479AC591598541628F4B02DC1F691F05"><enum>(I)</enum>
 <item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE31D96B06169415FA6C80D82BC156B23"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide the borrower with the income-driven repayment plan that requires the lowest monthly payment amount for each covered loan of the borrower, compared to any other such plan for which the borrower is eligible; or</text>
 </item><item id="H78A0163CDB6D405FBB745B04F8D73F68" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if more than one income-driven repayment plan would offer the borrower the same lowest monthly payment amount, provide the borrower with the income-driven repayment plan that has the most favorable terms for the borrower; and</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H6804B1AE4C6C45B496CCCD07749398AC"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the plan selected under subclause (I) is not the income-driven repayment plan that would have the lowest monthly payment amount if the borrower were eligible for such plan for the borrower’s covered loans and noncovered loans, notify the borrower of the actions, if any, the borrower may take to become eligible for such income-driven repayment plan; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HDBE37E562E7C4F9DBB115225D1953B06"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in a case in which none of the borrower’s covered loans are eligible for an income-driven repayment plan, notify the borrower of the actions, if any, the borrower may take for such a loan to become eligible for such a plan.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE3963B64CCC485B9E9AC1AF2DE2C2E1"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Opt-out</header><text>A borrower of a covered loan shall have the right to opt out of the procedures under this paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A610B47C1CB446BB2206955B2D31E11"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text>The Secretary shall establish procedures as are necessary to effectively implement this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H42FDB27BC2F749FC9AF421C86E179E8E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 455(d) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(d)</external-xref>), as amended by paragraph (1), is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE939828709144604B03F7E1E242DD233" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H941FD252116344CBBCC8DCFE32BBB4F6"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="HF9CEF06CD8C9492781C6F11DE281438B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Covered loan</header><text>The term <term>covered loan</term> means—</text>
 <clause id="H6CA8042B9AA942E3BD9CD772C98E1D83"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a loan made under this part;</text> </clause><clause id="H5D0C1B37EA5D44BB8146C846EC717E1F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a loan purchased under section 459A; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAAD5B4633B834224AC757AE98C108B51"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a loan that has been assigned to the Secretary under section 428(c)(8) or part E.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8AAC6C4144F141BDB7D8586A89725057"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Income-driven repayment plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>income-driven repayment plan</term> means a plan described in subparagraph (D) or (E) of paragraph (1).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A0075DC36D64CA4B75CDB76DA29BD46"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Noncovered loan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>noncovered loan</term> means a loan made, insured, or guaranteed under this title that is not a covered loan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6D6C7896134F453B85AEFBED0731C5D0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Changing plans</header><text>Section 493C(b)(8) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1098e">20 U.S.C. 1098e(b)(8)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBF0DC6F3200F443C8D8DE22617AF8D4A" style="OLC">
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H5BC185789D4141CFBBA5EC3D39CFEB70"><enum>(8)</enum><text>a borrower who is repaying a loan made, insured, or guaranteed under part B or D pursuant to income-based repayment may elect, at any time, to terminate repayment pursuant to income-based repayment and repay such loan under any repayment plan for which the loan is eligible in accordance with the requirements of part B or part D, respectively; and</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H998AFA30FDFA4E91891B3B91EF900070"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date; application</header>
 <paragraph id="H9B29091D34A640A4A8903B5D8D1A00B7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Automatic enrollment</header><text>The amendments made by paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a) shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H33554E19A5B348D3BB8593FB360D634C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>take effect as soon as the Secretary of Education determines practicable after the Secretary finalizes the procedures under section 5, but not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H383434F6E8054705A3EC43658C6D61F8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>apply to all borrowers of covered loans (as defined in section 455(d)(8) of the Higher Education Act of 1965, as added by subsection (a)).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2CF3B13B548470590A3E6BF61D34132"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Changing plans</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a)(3) shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H49B4BE4C136143B2A1409CF5B54A15D7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Automatic recertification of income</header> <subsection id="HC0E3F668C5BB42B395699FCABBD64BBB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Income contingent repayment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 455(e) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(e)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H3461E0BC96F34146AD4D3E1CA2BACDAE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H82F0A877190B45EC9AED17CEE9AE959E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>does not reasonably reflect the borrower's current income</quote> and inserting <quote>whose income has decreased relative to the adjusted gross income available to the Secretary</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCE15F27D726E4EB3B9BDB650746A7937"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, consistent with the procedures established under paragraph (8)(B)(iv)</quote> before the period at the end; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A0B8AACF17040E1B26702B75CAF4EA3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H083B087FF86340AE861FF0F54CD2D2C2" style="OLC">
						<paragraph id="HAF365E1C16C44939B47AA09D25AFF39D"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Automatic recertification</header>
 <subparagraph id="H43C8B45109034528A99CF001C881205F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>covered loan</term> has the meaning given the term in subsection (d)(8).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4717D0EA16884465B4136B004226702A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning as soon as the Secretary determines practicable after the Secretary finalizes the procedures under section 5 of the <short-title>Streamlining Income-driven, Manageable Payments on Loans for Education Act</short-title>, but not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of such Act, the Secretary shall establish and implement, with respect to any borrower described in subparagraph (C), procedures to—</text>
 <clause id="H44656B6B28B64E42882172989915FD10"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">obtain (for each year of repayment and without further action by the borrower) such information as is reasonably necessary regarding the income of such borrower (and the borrower’s spouse, if applicable), for the purpose of determining the repayment obligation of the borrower for such year, including information with respect to the borrower’s family size in accordance with the procedures under section 5 of the <short-title>Streamlining Income-driven, Manageable Payments on Loans for Education Act</short-title>, subject to clause (ii);</text>
 </clause><clause id="H71C7C4819A294E7ABB3853E393B34F88"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">allow the borrower, at any time, to opt out of clause (i) and prevent the Secretary from obtaining information under such clause without further action by the borrower;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5B9C4757A4AD47C39B09E54C5B274198"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide the borrower with an opportunity to update the information obtained under clause (i) before the determination of the annual repayment obligation of the borrower; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H289255049E0E4E59A2C2457247EEE469"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a borrower for whom adjusted gross income is unavailable—</text> <subclause id="HEC6332F2F4EB48FFA95F5DBEF3ECD14A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>if the borrower has selected to repay the covered loans of such borrower pursuant to an income contingent repayment plan that defines discretionary income in such a manner that an individual not required under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6012">section 6012(a)(1)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to file a return with respect to income taxes imposed by subtitle A of such Code may have a calculated monthly payment greater than $0, the borrower will be required to provide the Secretary with other documentation of income satisfactory to the Secretary, which documentation the Secretary may use to determine an appropriate repayment schedule; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H72F24E7C59EC43C09826860619014421"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if the borrower has selected to repay such loans pursuant to an income contingent repayment that is not described in subclause (I), the borrower will not be required to provide the Secretary with such other documentation of income, and the borrower will have a calculated monthly payment of $0.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0FC1797F8CEB4BEAB7BB512136E7118A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Subparagraph (B) shall apply to each borrower of a covered loan who, on or after the date on which the Secretary establishes procedures under such subparagraph—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H57C0AA96873941409DF7CE2311BCA98C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>selects, or for whom the Secretary selects under subparagraph (C) or (D) of paragraph (6) or paragraph (7)(C) of subsection (d), or section 428(m)(1), an income contingent repayment plan; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HE9365934AE264D788ADDF9064066C0C4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>recertifies income and family size under such plan.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE4068FE26114965B1123B2D8569D7E3"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Availability of returns and return information</header><text>Returns and return information (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">section 6103</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) may be obtained under subparagraph (B)(i) only to the extent authorized by section 6103(l)(13) of such Code.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H11D17DDD97BB4B80BA9AF6A50F2D1A02"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Other requirements</header><text>The procedures established by the Secretary under this paragraph shall be consistent with the requirements of paragraphs (1) through (7), except as otherwise provided in this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H987F0A4264B0493A87A4B619D2BEC2B2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Income-Based repayment</header><text>Section 493C(c) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1098e">20 U.S.C. 1098e(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H84AF633C31AF47C6B77AC0E90190C2FA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The Secretary shall establish</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H73F97486CF73468591A0464B5DAD6EF1" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H196D8AD18EA34C0A8DFCA3621CAC054B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC322300963A84B9D85F149A648B0121C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The Secretary shall consider</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7B25E4CB6B424F1D9FDE11F23AC9B48E" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HB3BC607DEBD4440DBC4A5D962B6D81FC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Procedures for eligibility</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H8CE1A16CF50C48049D7339CD303F9FF2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consider</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDE37F7156D1845828F38C166E1C68C56"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>428C(b)(1)(E).</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HDE89DC2DB3C345B88995537EC086AFC6" style="OLC"> <text>428C(b)(1)(E); and</text><subparagraph id="H4AA25D4EEA644F00857A77A90D379457"><enum>(B)</enum><text>beginning as soon as the Secretary determines practicable after the Secretary finalizes the procedures under section 5 of the <short-title>Streamlining Income-driven, Manageable Payments on Loans for Education Act</short-title>, but not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of such Act, carry out, with respect to borrowers of any covered loan (as defined in section 455(d)(8)), procedures for income-based repayment plans that are equivalent to the procedures carried out under section 455(e)(8) with respect to income contingent repayment plans.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H531209EABCAB43AC8BD8C595FB5942FF"><enum>5.</enum><header>Study and procedures on determining family size</header>
 <subsection id="HA9C393CA343248FCB2D914F7FEA4BE2F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Education shall—</text> <paragraph id="H714215F1DCF0410483AA89D557211269"><enum>(1)</enum><text>jointly with the Secretary of the Treasury, conduct a study, which meets the specifications described in subsection (b), on the effect of using data from the Internal Revenue Service on the deduction for personal exemptions provided by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/151">section 151</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 for a proxy for family size in an income-driven repayment plan, and publish such study in the Federal Register;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H46E54120DC3B4B70AC31A601121296BE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use the results of the study conducted under paragraph (1) to develop procedures for determining family size for the automatic recertification of income for an income-driven repayment plan in a manner that minimizes burdens and unintended harm to borrowers;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC9A19D5731A84539A0A7ABAD5BE5ADBD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>publish the procedures developed under paragraph (2) in the Federal Register; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H894E7458478F4BAC8C790E33F0E11FAE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>after a notice and comment period on such procedures, use such comments to finalize the procedures.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H894194950FC04C3F8C6BC6FE0F1D977A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Specifications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The study conducted under subsection (a)(1) shall—</text> <paragraph id="HCA31E22FFA4648A7B995B09EE969B1D7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine how closely such personal exemptions match the family size that borrowers report on their income-driven repayment plan request form;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE0E2526D963A439EB3063F278BA18504"><enum>(2)</enum><text>compare the borrower’s actual monthly payment amount with the monthly payment amount borrowers would have using family size information derived from tax returns; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H05A9F011284B411C99DBD39E85CC4559"><enum>(3)</enum><text>use data from more than one year, where possible, to analyze how much family size changes over time.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0F5F5AA7D60A45C59FC9D1D27E6735E3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>income-driven repayment plan</term> has the meaning given the term in section 455(d)(8) of the Higher Education Act of 1965, as amended by this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H0F2355A23A4D4A9393D64F49149F772E"><enum>6.</enum><header>Disclosure of tax return information to carry out certain higher education loan programs</header>
 <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H025A4446DD054CBCA50144A5DAC00B37"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (13) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">section 6103(l)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H47EDAF36A58B4D27B0DC178990845EFB" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="HF304F4692EAD40768097598C9819B4A5"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Disclosure of returns and return information for purposes of student loan administration</header>
 <subparagraph id="HFAC0172C72A043ADB0BDB38728B18D96"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, subject to such requirements and conditions as the Secretary may prescribe, shall upon written request from the Secretary of Education disclose to officers and employees of the Department of Education returns and return information with respect to a taxpayer who has received an applicable student loan.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB35334EC3CC0479FBB983AB467D6EC01"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Restriction on use of disclosed information</header><text>Return information disclosed under subparagraph (A) may be used by officers and employees of the Department of Education only for the purposes of, and to the extent necessary for purposes of—</text>
 <clause id="HFB8B015D4C294C15930893E356966365"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">carrying out income monitoring under section 437(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087">20 U.S.C. 1087(a)</external-xref>),</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEB507B1842C945E880FCF4642A62EE39"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishing the appropriate income contingent repayment amount in connection with an applicable student loan,</text>
 </clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE350F13A2F8A421191B7AB332C047661"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishing the appropriate repayment amount under an applicable income-driven repayment plan (as defined in section 455(d)(8) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(d)</external-xref>)) in connection with an applicable student loan for—</text>
 <subclause id="HBE3EB57CEC3A4AE9806948EF6FE0BA29"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">borrowers who have selected such a plan, and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H647001F2D15A46BA996345E8FC35749B"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of any recertification under section 455(e)(8) or 493C(c)(2)(B) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(e)</external-xref>; 1098e(c)), borrowers who are enrolled in such a plan,</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="HCD15AB12B4D8420595FB4161BCC70F7F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of borrowers who are at least 60 days delinquent on an applicable student loan—</text> <subclause commented="no" id="H5FF2ECC0FD28459880E5265BA2ABE798"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing notice of eligibility for an income-driven repayment plan (as so defined) pursuant to section 455(d)(6)(B) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(d)</external-xref>), and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H90458B9EE0E84396851210F9781FB757"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">automatic enrollment in such an income-driven repayment plan after such borrowers are at least 120 days delinquent on such a loan pursuant to section 455(d)(6)(C) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(d)</external-xref>), and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HCBA4612A5D804FA1AE6B061219E75055"><enum>(v)</enum><text>in the case of borrowers who are rehabilitating defaulted loans, providing notice of eligibility for an income-driven repayment plan (as so defined) and automatic enrollment in such a plan pursuant to section 455(d)(7) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(d)</external-xref>).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H671414D54CB94872800ECE283F0AAE17"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Disclosure to certain contractors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Officers and employees of the Department of Education may disclose the information described in subparagraph (A) to persons awarded contracts by the Secretary of Education under section 456 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087f">20 U.S.C. 1087f</external-xref>) to the extent necessary for the purposes described in subparagraph (B).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDEA504A931EB40A3A63B7E00C4CDF864"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Spousal information for married individuals filing separate returns</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, in the case of a married individual filing a separate return, the term <quote>taxpayer</quote> includes the spouse of that individual if the Secretary of Education requests information from the spouse of that individual and the individual and the spouse have consented in writing.</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H279F3B180CD840A4B838644FA1932863"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Applicable student loan</header>
 <clause id="HD6945DEC25164F27B1FDD899C9DDB7DC"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>applicable student loan</term> means—</text> <subclause id="H6948CDD63C8242C9B7DCF41CCD7E952F"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any loan which is made, insured, or guaranteed under a program authorized under part B or D of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1071">20 U.S.C. 1071</external-xref> et seq.; 1087a et seq.), and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HF36AF5FC18384694B94F4E331FE600EB"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any loan which is made under part E of such title IV (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087aa">20 U.S.C. 1087aa</external-xref> et seq.) which is in default and has been assigned to the Department of Education.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="H5359FE6077194E74AE1760D8D3653646"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subparagraph (B)(iv), the term <term>applicable student loan</term> shall not include any loan made, insured, or guaranteed under part B of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1071">20 U.S.C. 1071</external-xref> et seq.) unless such loan is in default and has been assigned to the Department of Education.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H4583A00E33DC4A5180CFB006127F0310"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="H3C586DB0D1C548ECAD8F4900108F05B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 6103(a)(3) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>(13),</quote> after <quote>(12),</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H555A66072757457CB39514B0E9782C1B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 6103(p)(4) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>(13),</quote> after <quote>(l)(10),</quote> each place it occurs.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFC06F0B52B3745AFB1C4E2FF59565929"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to disclosures made after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


