<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA78BEE503B114F45825380166FD22906" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2285 IH: School-Based Respiratory Health Management Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2285</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170502">May 2, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000582">Mr. Roe of Tennessee</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H000874">Mr. Hoyer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to increase the preference given, in awarding certain allergies and reversible lower airway disorders-related grants, to States that allow trained school personnel to administer rescue medications for allergies and reversible lower airway disorders, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H937A3BE47A6047F0923D2475A7953DFE" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7CFAA8BD532F422E923F8FE1FA54E2FF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>School-Based Respiratory Health Management Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HFA91286768D3442D86F33F4FE5DEFCC8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Additional preference to certain States that allow trained school personnel to administer rescue medications for allergies and reversible lower airway disorders</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 399L(d) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280g">42 U.S.C. 280g(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9154C7A4D4C64FA0901C89EAD03A8320"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H2D7D70DE18404F3BB2FD44319FDCCEBA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (F) to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H227747925BDD48CE8E982674F1252244" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="HE92DB1E0E6D3404FAB218F66E220720C"><enum>(F)</enum><header>School personnel administration of rescue medications for allergies and reversible lower airway disorders</header><text>In determining the preference (if any) to be given to a State under this subsection, the Secretary shall give additional preference to a State that provides to the Secretary the certification described in subparagraph (G) and that requires that each public elementary school and secondary school in the State—</text> <clause id="H15CA1DA9AA91480BA01BFE55691B705E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has in place a plan for having on the premises of the school during all operating hours of the school a school nurse or one or more other individuals who are trained personnel of the school; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H45AED6BDF1634961AF7502A5DEA5EC71"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has in place under the direction of a school nurse a comprehensive school-based allergies and reversible lower airway disorders management program that includes—</text> <subclause id="HE862F62363B94D7E98774ABE8E84C6B4"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a method to identify all students of such school with a diagnosis of allergies and reversible lower airway disorders;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H1AEE05C0A51441669F4C39F8B873209C"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an individual student allergies and reversible lower airway disorders action plan for each student of such school with a diagnosis of allergies and reversible lower airway disorders;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H3DBF7A93886341ADA9C2C4E7DC593146"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">allergies and reversible lower airway disorders education for school staff who are directly responsible for students who have been identified as having allergies or reversible lower airway disorders, such as education regarding basics, management, trigger management, and comprehensive emergency responses with respect to allergies and reversible lower airway disorders;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H70CB5465C6F3422880D50734DF664BD3"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">rescue medications for allergies or reversible lower airway disorders and emergency policies that are specific to the school;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HC36BDDA135AF4A0B802AD228E6AD3656"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">efforts to reduce the presence of environmental triggers of allergies and reversible lower airway disorders; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H79F245B775244E1F8E172EFE686EC909"><enum>(VI)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a system to support students with a diagnosis of allergies or reversible lower airway disorders through coordination with family members of such students, primary care providers of such students, and others as necessary.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H38C8DF0326D542B1B85A923D7D213009"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (G), by inserting <quote>or rescue medication for allergies or reversible lower airway disorders to a student reasonably believed to have a diagnosis of allergies or reversible lower airway disorders,</quote> after <quote>to a student reasonably believed to be having an anaphylactic reaction</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0CC94F75184049999226E456853449F7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text> <subparagraph id="HC482F53168974F1BA862FB7F6B1ABABD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)—</text> 
<clause id="H93AEEA0B9ED64A1D915D676151F67843"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The term</quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="clause" style="OLC"><enum-in-header>(i)</enum-in-header></header-in-text> The term</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="HCF16FDC2768E4FB8985B4C87F8824CC7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following new clause:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD276B944935A42F2BB438513CE347AB2" style="OLC"> 
<clause id="H86F6EBDFD2104652B00B86080C8C75DE" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>rescue medications for allergies and reversible lower airway disorders</term> includes at least short-acting bronchodilators.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H245D523117D04BB2B086C83DAD6BB15C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E)—</text> 
<clause id="H94F04F0C1D184F0DAF875F7318CC59D9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by inserting <quote>, such as the school nurse</quote> after <quote>individual</quote>;</text></clause> <clause id="H5AD9DB52D41B4193B727B4E18F1CC873"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (i)—</text> 
<subclause id="HAF0D5974808F4CFE97422D04510A3645"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>school nurse or</quote> before <quote>principal</quote>; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HD8D646C4F8FF44A296AFAA2BA3B3F160"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>and rescue medications for allergies and reversible lower airway disorders</quote> before <quote>on a voluntary basis</quote>;</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H23FD3115A1D7470DABCF6BD816AC5121"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause (ii), by inserting <quote>and rescue medications for allergies and reversible lower airway disorders</quote> before the semicolon; and</text></clause> <clause id="H1AFD77B02B9345968F83EDDFEFF294E8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause (iii), by inserting <quote>and rescue medications for allergies and reversible lower airway disorders</quote> before <quote>meets appropriate medical standards</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

