<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HDB82AA2F2E8D40D0A9F7FF2B177691E6" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4567 IH: DHS Overseas Personnel Enhancement Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4567</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171206">December 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000132">Mr. Vela</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require a Department of Homeland Security overseas personnel enhancement plan, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H736A47EBF5624A92BD38366D371E6312" style="OLC">
 <section id="H2B7EC54E883743FA818ACF8E012DDAF6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>DHS Overseas Personnel Enhancement Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H484375D8355B4403831DFE8789924B9F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Overseas personnel briefing</header> <subsection id="HF64B8174B3574C0688255EC1B30364FB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after submission of the comprehensive three-year strategy required under section 1910 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall brief the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate regarding Department of Homeland Security personnel with primary duties that take place outside of the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6B8456594FF44D849D619FA4E0ECD2CB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The briefing required under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="H35387574E3F041029C258456D97C0A55"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A detailed summary of each type of personnel position with primary duties that take place outside of the United States and how each such position contributes to the Department of Homeland Security’s counterterrorism mission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD661F88EB067421796B8F9E32A330924"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Information related to how the geographic and regional placement of such positions contributes to the Department’s counterterrorism mission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC89DCDDF1CC341BF85F6F0DFDF752963"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Information related to the position-specific training received by such personnel before and during placement at a foreign location.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAE1695C0D3914570B05E883E64ADE8E5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Challenges that may impede the communication of counterterrorism information between Department personnel at foreign locations and Department entities in the United States, including technical, resource, and administrative challenges.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H9929B269E88B4CFCAE2BE3FE7D80FD6A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Overseas personnel enhancement plan</header>
 <subsection id="H8CA7A1B49C294DD682FFA49140992823"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the briefing required under section 2, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a plan to enhance the effectiveness of Department of Homeland Security personnel at foreign locations.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4AF732AFC1CD4F0AA241DAD30B019DBB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Plan requirements</header><text>The plan referred to in subsection (a) shall include proposals to—</text> <paragraph id="H0CD6FAD29BBA4D7B9335EE8D13E11D9E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>improve efforts of Department of Homeland Security personnel at foreign locations, as necessary, for purposes of providing foreign partner capacity development and furthering the Department’s counterterrorism mission;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7225667BDE054E6E9D2BB48EFBB02642"><enum>(2)</enum><text>as appropriate, redeploy Department personnel to respond to changing threats to the United States;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6BE501C851C34F7B837D17F32BC8819E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>enhance collaboration among Department personnel at foreign locations, other Federal personnel at foreign locations, and foreign partners; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCC316419A57943D38E45F117829A8422"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improve the communication of counterterrorism information between Department personnel at foreign locations and Department entities in the United States, including to address technical, resource, and administrative challenges.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


