<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H765DD80589F94F30B8167357EB423CEC" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1698 IH: Iran Ballistic Missiles and International Sanctions Enforcement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1698</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170323">March 23, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000487">Mr. Royce of California</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001165">Mr. McCarthy</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H000874">Mr. Hoyer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To expand sanctions against Iran with respect to the ballistic missile program of Iran, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H81C8F36BD6A94702BC6D66587E08BFB0" style="OLC">
		<section id="HCBB0AA66B4084CB5BEF7526163F0B3A6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Iran Ballistic Missiles and International Sanctions Enforcement Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HB82D91CF3C2F4FD9A86B2E32824E4C6F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sanctions relating to efforts by the Government of Iran with respect to ballistic missile-related goods, services, and technologies</header> <subsection id="HA071502363E14981812876A732205826"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H39158900221041B3830530365901ACA4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231 (2015)—</text> <subparagraph id="HA3DC616C96704149964509DDDB38C00B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>calls upon Iran <quote>not to undertake any activity related to ballistic missiles designed to be capable of delivering nuclear weapons, including launches using such ballistic missile technology</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7212AF68B9204CEE85318E85A1F88719"><enum>(B)</enum><text>calls upon member states to <quote>take the necessary measures to prevent, except as decided otherwise by the UN Security Council in advance on a case-by-case basis, the supply, sale, or transfer of arms or related materiel from Iran</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA30A892A2961448C82F968D62BB6F12B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The United States maintains bilateral sanctions against Iran for its efforts to manufacture, acquire, possess, develop, transport, transfer or use ballistic missiles or ballistic missile launch technology, and its acquisition of destabilizing types and amounts of conventional weapons.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF4648AA5C5DC458FA438EA32F30FB87E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>According to the 2016 Worldwide Threat Assessment, the United States intelligence community judges <quote>that Tehran would choose ballistic missiles as its preferred method of delivering nuclear weapons, if it builds them. Iran’s ballistic missiles are inherently capable of delivering [weapons of mass destruction], and Tehran already has the largest inventory of ballistic missiles in the Middle East. Iran’s progress on space launch vehicles—along with its desire to deter the United States and its allies—provides Tehran with the means and motivation to develop longer-range missiles, including ICBMs.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H043B001FDC40482598F6683F6DAE71BE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Since the passage of United Nations Security Council 2231, Iran has conducted numerous tests of ballistic missiles designed to be capable of delivering nuclear weapons, and has acquired destabilizing types of conventional weapons.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8FE84802C73F4A7C9BA84513470898AB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Iran has pursued the ability to indigenously produce ballistic missile and cruise missile goods, services, and technologies.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEBACA06A8A94483C84EA566F9B54A860"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States to prevent Iran from undertaking any activity related to ballistic missiles designed to be capable of delivering nuclear weapons, including launches using such ballistic missile technology.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H21CA0A46F201469F8642471FC273E6F9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report on supply chain of Iran’s ballistic missile program</header>
 <paragraph id="H9A2D0F8B369A4012B047BD38FBC1A761"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that contains the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H34E147B6CF7C43659834C28C045A56F0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An analysis of the foreign and domestic supply chain in Iran that directly or indirectly significantly facilitates, supports, or otherwise aids the Government of Iran’s ballistic missile program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE2BD479E796B48C99194B346EA4AC499"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of the geographic distribution of the foreign and domestic supply chain described in subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9CBBBCA1F1BE438BA8B88B4ECA5637D2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An assessment of the Government of Iran’s ability to indigenously manufacture or otherwise produce the goods, services, or technology necessary to support its ballistic missile program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57892B7B114C4EA295A171859AC5A9A4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An identification of foreign persons that have, based on credible information, directly or indirectly facilitated or supported the development of the Government of Iran’s ballistic missile program, including the foreign and domestic supply chain described in subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA68E1111F93C4A5AADDDCDFCB6C90141"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0553B7B2839747B296E3086C6636A693"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Investigations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section (4)(e) of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/172">Public Law 104–172</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) is amended by inserting <quote>or 5(b)</quote> after <quote>section 5(a)</quote> each place it appears.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6B9CF7A73AAF43C4998BD04490238EAC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Sanctionable activities with respect to weapons of mass destruction</header><text>Paragraph (1) of section 5(b) of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/172">Public Law 104–172</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H387BCA5C84554D6EB2367B48C5269986"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Exports, transfers, and transshipments</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Weapons of mass destruction; ballistic missiles; conventional weapons</header-in-text></quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H02054C63D2CE45B598B3A4BAF24A7F6A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Except as</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE124FB744CBE470BAF08C4AE97727F68" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H92C6043FB2A14CBF8BD192BFA22F2FD1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Weapons of mass destruction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9FDFA1160C6F465294F7403CC3162670"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(A) on or after the date of the enactment of the Iran Threat Reduction and Syria Human Rights Act of 2012</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA4CC9ACD55AA4728BD01C9F244C8D637" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H04B41312E8AA4E80903F1942ACB36C3B"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on or after the date of the enactment of the Iran Ballistic Missiles and International Sanctions Enforcement Act</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEF828D3622984E7592EC1DCFF62FB464"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (A)(i) (as so redesignated);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2AF5FF9193804D39BC812466B2D579A6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(B) knew</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8295FCC5BB5243A7AE5983DEBCDF68EF" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H980E1469E2BC4B2DA0DA36AF4A4BBC1B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">knew</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H70CDDA2F0B8E4998BB74E0892E67097B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(i) the export</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFF76589E39CB441A833F0723882B3BE7" style="OLC">
 <subclause id="H92830BCB75C44A43AFA28F039BBDFAA0"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the export</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAD3906728754401CB08F343505810F23"><enum>(7)</enum><text>by striking <quote>would likely</quote> and inserting <quote>may</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC044C537CC1D4D25949694160589013F"><enum>(8)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(ii) the export</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H98E6071DBD3649CEB40E78010CF272F1" style="OLC"> <subclause id="HF485F4A0CD8D4AA7A68A6AD3888FAEC5"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the export</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE503E4B564E4A6BB78C9ECA5EC2808F"><enum>(9)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(I) acquire</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H45BA5AEC0B1941C1B03628F28785FD7E" style="OLC"> <item id="H13612CCA714A4815810EE3ADFD34249C"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">acquire</text></item><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE6A354CE77F44436B8883E959AA2A17E"><enum>(10)</enum><text>by striking <quote>; or</quote> at the end of subparagraph (A)(ii)(II)(aa) (as so redesignated);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCFB32E8381B149DFB573737E8858694F"><enum>(11)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (A)(ii)(II)(aa) (as so redesignated) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC732CE8A51474D41AC1C8ED9C3D5E301" style="OLC">
 <item id="H54C497BFEC7C4F76A28D0044D981BC9B"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">acquire or develop ballistic missiles or ballistic missile launch technologies; or</text></item><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7FC817F09EEA40EBA436E87CE25B4D0A"><enum>(12)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(II) acquire</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H395433A628364A6496217F1D1FA439F8" style="OLC">
 <item id="H503FECDD9220422989E509AE15641D7A"><enum>(cc)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">acquire</text></item><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB25962B6694B4781B16BF9BB1C009FD2"><enum>(13)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of subparagraph (A)(ii)(II)(cc) (as so redesignated) and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H723879BE940C48968DD5F654EF49CC5E"><enum>(14)</enum><text>by adding at the end of subparagraph (A) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5F961B2465C64057B2AB24AE39C63115" style="OLC"> <clause id="H6A8A01B2C76A465A8EBB8BFE119CC8C9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">knowingly exports or transfers, or permits or otherwise facilitates the transshipment or re-export of, any goods, services, technology, or other items to Iran that materially contributes to the ability of Iran to—</text>
 <subclause id="H8ACB56933ACA4FE7A72D5F3C2C80DBC5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>acquire or develop ballistic missiles or ballistic missile launch technologies; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="H2DCA9F7F7D5E4C97AC74AE5FAC3AAFAA"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">acquire or develop destabilizing numbers and types of advanced conventional weapons (as such term is defined in paragraphs (1) and (2) of section 1608 of the Iran-Iraq Arms Non-Proliferation Act of 1992).</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H23E6FB1593E04DF983A52A1DCCD54B26"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Sanctionable activities with respect to ballistic missiles</header><text>Paragraph (1) of section 5(b) of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/172">Public Law 104–172</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note), as amended by subsection (e), is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA808202E93894D03B3B624D577832B4D" style="OLC">
					<subparagraph id="H2192E72B1A8847E7AE8CE3E43F3299F2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional ballistic missile-related goods, services, and technology</header>
 <clause id="H6FCA3A711381408EB121B2CC3C80A189"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Additional authority</header><text>The President shall impose the sanctions described in paragraph (8), (10), or (12) of section 6(a), as the case may be, with respect to—</text>
 <subclause id="H1D8418AED15C49BCAA9F397A872C198F"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an agency or instrumentality of the Government of Iran if the agency or instrumentality, on or after the date of the enactment of this subparagraph, seeks to develop, procure, or acquire goods, services, or technology that materially contributes to efforts by the Government of Iran with respect to ballistic missile-related goods, services, and technologies as described in clause (iii);</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H1E7AB3027BF943FBA7FAF40C16EFF0B2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a foreign person or an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state if the person or agency or instrumentality knowingly, on or after the date of the enactment of this paragraph, provides material support to the Government of Iran that materially contributes to efforts by the Government of Iran with respect to ballistic missile-related goods, services, and technologies as described in clause (iii); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD0616CDB23884005915BC926CCE788FD"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a foreign person that the President determines knowingly engages in a significant transaction or transactions with, or provides significant financial services for, a foreign person or an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state described in subclause (I) or (II) with respect to ballistic missile-related goods, services, and technologies as described in clause (iii).</text>
							</subclause></clause><clause id="HFA5588DDE60B44CE95B51ACCF5B7132E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Determination on Ballistic Missile Tests</header>
 <subclause id="HC0AC9C850087423FAE8DDDBC3FB7767B"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date on which the President receives credible information that the Government of Iran has conducted a test of a ballistic missile, the President shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a determination of whether or not the test of such missile fails to comply with, violates, or is in defiance of United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231 (2015).</text>
							</subclause><subclause id="H0A25143107DE4CD2A2781D6870EDD3D8"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Report</header>
 <item id="H6AA157559F5B44F582CC855C820EF086"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the President determines pursuant to subclause (I) that the test of a ballistic missile fails to comply with, violates, or is in defiance of United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231 (2015), the President shall transmit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report that—</text>
 <subitem id="HF9339F2527824926877A46F9C5451E3C"><enum>(AA)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifies each Iranian person that the President determines is responsible for ordering, controlling, or otherwise directing the missile test described in subclause (I);</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="H58C821C89D634F4BAB91FBBDA1313386"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>determines whether the persons described in sub-item (AA) have been designated for their activities in support of Iran’s ballistic missile program, and if not, so designated, the reasons therefor; and</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="H0EC47A152B044E2E8F9A2B1AB07A4E8A"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>describes the steps the President is taking to respond to the ballistic missile test described in subclause (I).</text>
 </subitem></item><item id="HBA15CBCD560E44B381DE9EE03747230B"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>Form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by item (aa) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</text>
								</item></subclause></clause><clause id="H1D791B5C161240F08BF0CE98A02CA8AF"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Efforts by the Government of Iran with respect to ballistic missile-related goods, services, and
 technologies described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subclauses (I) and (II) of clause (i), efforts by the Government of Iran with respect to ballistic missile-related goods, services, and technologies described in this subsection are efforts by the Government of Iran to manufacture, acquire, possess, develop, transport, transfer, test or use ballistic missiles or associated goods, services, or technology by the Government of Iran in violation of section 3 of Annex B of United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231 (2015), including efforts by the Government of Iran to manufacture, acquire, possess, develop, transport, transfer, purchase—</text>
 <subclause id="H811F3ECA9FCF4DB885E8EFA0B417E7F1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>goods, services, or technology listed on the Missile Technology Control Regime Equipment and Technology Annex of October 8, 2015, and subsequent revisions that have been acquired outside of the Procurement Working Group; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD3E0E82F356F4D4BADE9DA218B2C3F75"><enum>(II)</enum><text>goods, services, or technology not described in the matter preceding subclause (I) or subclause (I) but which nevertheless the President determines would be, if such goods, services, or technology were United States goods, services, or technology, prohibited for export to Iran because of their potential to make a material contribution to the development of ballistic missile systems or ballistic missile launch technologies.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HD9770F5BFD2A45848F829B9987C7091D"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Procurement Working Group defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In clause (iii)(I), the term <quote>procurement working group</quote> means the Procurement Working Group of the Joint Commission established under Annex IV of the applicable provisions in Annex A of United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231 (2015).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7C1CFA479A5542D08F467F99A991B352"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Sanctionable activities with respect to conventional weapons</header><text>Paragraph (1) of section 5(b) of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/172">Public Law 104–172</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note), as amended by subsections (e) and (f), is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0EF466098B944A828DE2DB18566B70D7" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H2BE06DE0FE544219986916F88DB80CFE"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Conventional weapons</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall impose the sanctions described in paragraph (8) or (12) of section 6(a), as the case may be, with respect to a foreign person or an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state if the President determines that the person or agency or instrumentality knowingly, on or after the date of the enactment of this paragraph, imports, exports, or re-exports to, into, or from Iran, whether directly or indirectly, any significant arms or related materiel prohibited under Annex B of United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231 (2015).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7344703DBF6948B393F7C2F57D953292"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Exception and definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) of section 5(b) of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/172">Public Law 104–172</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note), as amended by subsections (e), (f), and (g), is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0EFC35B7C2704D8BA8D6AD2F9DCF5203" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H0021EED960D54284A307540B0C66519B"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may not impose sanctions under subparagraph (B) or (C) with respect to a foreign person or a United States person if the President determines that the person has exercised due diligence in establishing and enforcing official policies, procedures, and controls to ensure that the person does not sell, supply, or transfer to or from Iran materials the sale, supply, or transfer of which would subject a person to the imposition of sanctions under subparagraph (B) or (C), as the case may be, or conduct or facilitate a financial transaction for such a sale, supply, or transfer.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD028A00F2F1C40FD98C8177BEC933C66"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In subparagraphs (B) and (C) of this paragraph:</text> <clause id="H0E06A39D024A41198E4E2363DF38D634"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Agency or instrumentality</header><text>The term <quote>agency or instrumentality</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 1603(b) of title 28, United States Code.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H1C5D2B32BF4044BF9DF1B54D91599018"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Foreign state</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>foreign state</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 1603(a) of title 28, United States Code.</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HE648830D06E34FACB476BC66CE98DE2A"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Government of Iran</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Government of Iran</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 561.404 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, as such section was in effect on January 1, 2016.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9CBBA4B50EA7437CB1EC2BA748B56395"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Significant transaction or transactions; significant financial services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <quote>significant transaction or transactions</quote> and <quote>significant financial services</quote> shall be determined, for purposes of sections 101 and 102, in accordance with section 561.404 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, as such section 561.404 was in effect on January 1, 2016.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEB86D184930849B7B13832E88BE7C61D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 6(a) of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/172">Public Law 104–172</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H05245110B5BE4573A34E89E31A6DAE4E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (10) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7311019AB83E47C0A08EDBB84137647F" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HB07C09800E634FD6B3655F005AA2FB0C"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Inadmissibility to United States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may direct the Secretary of State to deny a visa to, and the Secretary of Homeland Security to exclude from the United States and, if the individual has been issued a visa or other documentation, revoke, in accordance with section 221(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1201">8 U.S.C. 1201(i)</external-xref>) of the visa or other documentation any alien that—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HD5ECCC648879426F9B145022367B469C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is designated pursuant to subparagraph (B) or (C) of section 5(b)(1); or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6B1A18B338E04247B10E9D81287D17C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the President determines is a corporate officer or principal of, or a shareholder with a controlling interest in, a sanctioned person.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2BC43C8E7B7A42A9BD5E1C175B5EB6F6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (12) as paragraph (13); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H180440994F5E43BB8247799FF1EAFA5F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (11) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4A53AAAE9AFD4079B7F9F0533567C168" style="OLC">
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H24F646401BDE4E0D98887C0453FBD650"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Export sanction</header><text>In the case of an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state, no item on the United States Munitions List or Commerce Munitions List may be exported to that foreign state for a period of two years.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF3AE9BC74F2E42B0BEC3937782CE4589"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The sanctions that are required to be imposed under this section and the amendments made by this section are in addition to other similar or related sanctions that are required to be imposed under any other provision of law.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HE63C78B8534C4B71A432A5A9F6C3E4AE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report on sanctionable activities</header>
 <subsection id="HBDF92909E92C45B4B017599E942B677A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 90 days thereafter, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that contains the following information:</text>
 <paragraph id="H36575C7760714641987486BE789E4668"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Any credible information regarding Iran’s attempts to develop, procure, or acquire goods, services, or technology with respect to which sanctions may be imposed pursuant to subparagraphs (B) and (C) of section 5(b)(1) of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/172">Public Law 104–172</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note), as added by section 3 of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD9E765FAE29F4AD382F93E84A097A750"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any credible information regarding Iran’s acquisition or attempted acquisition of significant arms and related material in violation of paragraph 5 of Annex B of United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231 (2015).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H60568666011448E785DB43CD7B0EE81A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any credible information regarding Iran’s export or attempted export of significant arms and related material in violation of paragraph 5 of Annex B of United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231 (2015).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3C0310D1CD1248729902D183CFF0F62D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any approval granted by the United Nations Security Council for the export of significant arms and related material identified under paragraph 5 of Annex B of United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231 (2015).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7F4727E6FEA948218A1BAE7061262844"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HCCDA7397E6344B67AD8062847143B9B0"><enum>4.</enum><header>Regulatory authority</header>
 <subsection id="H2F30CB54AFD546AFAD6CEBF30CC1DF47"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall, not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, promulgate regulations as necessary for the implementation of this Act and the amendments made by this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB5A89C5B301244219F94E8CF68FFBAEB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notification to Congress</header><text>Not less than 10 days before the promulgation of regulations under subsection (a), the President shall notify the appropriate congressional committees of the proposed regulations and the provisions of this Act and the amendments made by this Act that the regulations are implementing.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HCB18D399091D489E965A48C995518BE9"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HFF8B8EB87D83459F9B0D683470C7D2DC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H00EC22E5C2254DFAA3E2CD42394522CC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Credible information</header><text>The term <quote>credible information</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 14 of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/172">Public Law 104–172</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE067DEE8D920479E8B18C41DCABF2498"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Government of Iran</header><text>The term <quote>Government of Iran</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 561.404 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, as such section was in effect on January 1, 2016.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


