<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="HE2F4FF44503443D9AAA421FB36DC5DCA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 38 EH: Concealed Carry Reciprocity Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>115th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 38</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend title 18, United States Code, to provide a means by which nonresidents of a State whose residents may carry concealed firearms may also do so in the State.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H7CA5C92385CE44C4BDC9FC3E399D3B2C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3183D2BD6F9B46C28681D4EB3D321605" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Concealed Carry Reciprocity Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <title id="HBAA72A8DF14143819E5A1D9FAB35109F"><enum>I</enum><header>Concealed Carry Reciprocity Act of 2017</header> <section id="H6402E0A09BAC4688AC3B692190C62572"><enum>101.</enum><header>Reciprocity for the carrying of certain concealed firearms</header> <subsection id="H4CA266AC7BF94CF7BE8E328DD5F8A75F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/44">Chapter 44</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/926C">section 926C</external-xref> the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H4076636BEC3F416FAC01725ECB9DEE26" style="USC"> 
<section id="H5A27A7EA01CE48DB81B2B78B358F88FE"><enum>926D.</enum><header>Reciprocity for the carrying of certain concealed firearms</header> 
<subsection id="H1DD051E8D32F462FACB79BBCD5A73AC1"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any provision of the law of any State or political subdivision thereof (except as provided in subsection (b)) and subject only to the requirements of this section, a person who is not prohibited by Federal law from possessing, transporting, shipping, or receiving a firearm, who is carrying a valid identification document containing a photograph of the person, and who is carrying a valid license or permit which is issued pursuant to the law of a State and which permits the person to carry a concealed firearm or is entitled to carry a concealed firearm in the State in which the person resides, may possess or carry a concealed handgun (other than a machinegun or destructive device) that has been shipped or transported in interstate or foreign commerce, in any State that—</text> <paragraph id="HF3108C7EDA8B4B7DBF4D5D952F9AE013"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has a statute under which residents of the State may apply for a license or permit to carry a concealed firearm; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H619FFCA363964B33B10E4015D06D7D08"><enum>(2)</enum><text>does not prohibit the carrying of concealed firearms by residents of the State for lawful purposes.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE6067635F9CF428280F9B7F36744818B"><enum>(b)</enum><text>This section shall not be construed to supersede or limit the laws of any State that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H72BA468AC7254AB5BF8D9C1305E8D083"><enum>(1)</enum><text>permit private persons or entities to prohibit or restrict the possession of concealed firearms on their property; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEEB35B046EFF4AD28B2ACABC4A7E8C63"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prohibit or restrict the possession of firearms on any State or local government property, installation, building, base, or park.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0A4B2FD4E16C499583343E25AE3A8254"><enum>(c)</enum> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD276EF9ABC5242D78667452551008C83"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A person who carries or possesses a concealed handgun in accordance with subsections (a) and (b) may not be arrested or otherwise detained for violation of any law or any rule or regulation of a State or any political subdivision thereof related to the possession, transportation, or carrying of firearms unless there is probable cause to believe that the person is doing so in a manner not provided for by this section. Presentation of facially valid documents as specified in subsection (a) is prima facie evidence that the individual has a license or permit as required by this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7D62B6D660604CDEB5577EC1880CAC2E" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>When a person asserts this section as a defense in a criminal proceeding, the prosecution shall bear the burden of proving, beyond a reasonable doubt, that the conduct of the person did not satisfy the conditions set forth in subsections (a) and (b).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H10B17DC240B640E88FE8DF356B9D7AA7" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>When a person successfully asserts this section as a defense in a criminal proceeding, the court shall award the prevailing defendant a reasonable attorney’s fee.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF47410049D514F9D98C8862ADE772705"><enum>(d)</enum> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H81638CF8D2C94D2BA8B1346CF739B3C0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A person who is deprived of any right, privilege, or immunity secured by this section, under color of any statute, ordinance, regulation, custom, or usage of any State or any political subdivision thereof, may bring an action in any appropriate court against any other person, including a State or political subdivision thereof, who causes the person to be subject to the deprivation, for damages or other appropriate relief.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0A22451430154F7CA730B1C41D4C84A7" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The court shall award a plaintiff prevailing in an action brought under paragraph (1) damages and such other relief as the court deems appropriate, including a reasonable attorney’s fee.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC0DC859C785849CCA659F2CAEF7F3672"><enum>(e)</enum><text>In subsection (a):</text> 
<paragraph id="H7DE191ED57BC4835AB3B6A060ABDCF5F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>identification document</term> means a document made or issued by or under the authority of the United States Government, a State, or a political subdivision of a State which, when completed with information concerning a particular individual, is of a type intended or commonly accepted for the purpose of identification of individuals.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H33AD79ACC9E74FBAA1C20B1604FC89AE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>handgun</term> includes any magazine for use in a handgun and any ammunition loaded into the handgun or its magazine.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE8B533F0316F4D58ADA6FEE790F3C450"><enum>(f)</enum> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H4DDA7776CF0E428FAB59C6B2EFEB83FF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A person who possesses or carries a concealed handgun under subsection (a) shall not be subject to the prohibitions of section 922(q) with respect to that handgun.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H85A6C767C2E349798069A87C8D6D74D4" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A person possessing or carrying a concealed handgun in a State under subsection (a) may do so in any of the following areas in the State that are open to the public:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB12F240938874FA8816C6C802F4589DE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A unit of the National Park System.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE7053F56D50B422CAE46965821510989"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A unit of the National Wildlife Refuge System.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HADD24CF19C0C4FD981D4985862CD736A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Public land under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Land Management.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H268BCDA0670F4E1CA1BACE28C71D9BC3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Land administered and managed by the Army Corps of Engineers.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB32CAB06DF1140EDB459E48567EEE98E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Land administered and managed by the Bureau of Reclamation.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9103EC159E1D499BBCEFA31F4E4B9626"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Land administered and managed by the Forest Service.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD3BBCA3F728B44108F60D05365D27BE7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 926C the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBAACAE66E40249429C5B488F1BCC0941" style="USC"> <toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="H4076636BEC3F416FAC01725ECB9DEE26" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration"> <toc-entry idref="H5A27A7EA01CE48DB81B2B78B358F88FE" level="section">926D. Reciprocity for the carrying of certain concealed firearms.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HEA81B85090BC4714B11729D78AABEDD2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Severability</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, if any provision of this section, or any amendment made by this section, or the application of such provision or amendment to any person or circumstance is held to be unconstitutional, this section and amendments made by this section and the application of such provision or amendment to other persons or circumstances shall not be affected thereby.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC5EAB7DE55E344D0AEB0E9F3D743C2E6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H7E35B88A3BA14689BA911EC4307731ED" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>102.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this title prohibits a law enforcement officer with reasonable suspicion of a violation of any law from conducting a brief investigative stop in accordance with the Constitution of the United States.</text></section> 
<section id="H4A53F1CC98694FFCAE1EE10CA79A2B98"><enum>103.</enum><header>Certain off-duty law enforcement officers and retired law enforcement officers allowed to carry a concealed firearm, and discharge a firearm, in a school zone</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 922(q) of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H55B6D9E798764CFB97416BD8DC7D1B85"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(B)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7ACC5D68CDAF4154A6207CE93378BA5B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of clause (vi); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD7EA6FD7A8FF4C66B1BB19068D54A1FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating clause (vii) as clause (ix) and inserting after clause (vi) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3A9DC0B7BD59437E928BE60137305E5C" style="OLC"> 
<clause id="H76EDC42F820D48CE9C4ED95136934457" indent="up2"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by an off-duty law enforcement officer who is a qualified law enforcement officer (as defined in section 926B) and is authorized under such section to carry a concealed firearm, if the firearm is concealed;</text></clause> <clause id="HF548D8AFCB42413E8D7DC0CD63F8B674" indent="up2"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by a qualified retired law enforcement officer (as defined in section 926C) who is authorized under such section to carry a concealed firearm, if the firearm is concealed; or</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H83C76F3C788646598D7AD4D50B056AA6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(B)—</text> <subparagraph id="H92D61803AC0B47648FE11F17B6E95773"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of clause (iii);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1CA8ABD5C6144ADAA501422172165A42"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of clause (iv) and inserting a semicolon; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H633A007785E048C591E96A4B40358982"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9E79986D8F784B1B9F0DA65D2AEAE293" style="OLC"> 
<clause id="H94227FD079D143EFA8217C36D2BF3D55" indent="up2"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by an off-duty law enforcement officer who is a qualified law enforcement officer (as defined in section 926B) and is authorized under such section to carry a concealed firearm; or</text></clause> <clause id="H098941C3F5BE4998B69E200CB73C6980" indent="up2"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by a qualified retired law enforcement officer (as defined in section 926C) who is authorized under such section to carry a concealed firearm.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H5DD5E5040CE74035A3C1E5BE29105564"><enum>104.</enum><header>Interstate carrying of firearms by Federal judges</header> 
<subsection id="H6E609D3B95254BE2B43DAC2015FCAAEB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/44">Chapter 44</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, as amended by section 101(a) of this Act, is amended by inserting after section 926D the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H833E3E6AAB674B3DAFA52B10F75A4674"> <section id="H47943A10C7DA43C7A6671BC362944FEF"><enum>926E.</enum><header>Interstate carrying of firearms by Federal judges</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any provision of the law of any State or political subdivision thereof, a Federal judge may carry a concealed firearm in any State if such judge is not prohibited by Federal law from receiving a firearm.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H72A69B60086E45FD88A2DE8632345383"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for such chapter, as amended by section 101(b) of this Act, is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 926D the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H21C4CA1DBC0049D2AAA475435B35C809"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">926E. Interstate carrying of firearms by Federal judges.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></title> <title id="HF3A7C8921FB34AB5A0C56881BAF98C15"><enum>II</enum><header>Fix NICS Act</header> <section id="H98C949CEEB0E4FF6A0089D04A3EFCDA5" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>201.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This title may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fix NICS Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H65AF175A3E8F4FCFBBDA8A1D27DB59DE" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>202.</enum><header>Accountability for Federal departments and agencies</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 103 of the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40901">34 U.S.C. 40901</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H5ED3960C0FEB4BF4BB8F4F2007D4C5D1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (e)(1), by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF0549CF60509443B96DFD1DA381ED7CF" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="HF521DD2EE72B442D9423190314F9400C"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Semiannual certification and reporting</header> 
<clause id="H466E44381FBE45A2932910C3B0FA5F00"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The head of each Federal department or agency shall submit a semiannual written certification to the Attorney General indicating whether the department or agency is in compliance with the record submission requirements under subparagraph (C).</text></clause> <clause id="H171554E64DFF458DBA6BA8B89EA70E25"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Submission dates</header><text>The head of a Federal department or agency shall submit a certification to the Attorney General under clause (i)—</text> 
<subclause id="H3E2B58789E444436ABA0EF96F410109C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>not later than July 31 of each year, which shall address all relevant records, including those that have not been transmitted to the Attorney General, in possession of the department or agency during the period beginning on January 1 of the year and ending on June 30 of the year; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HF5B4F8C8ED3046AD95F46FA14974A645"><enum>(II)</enum><text>not later than January 31 of each year, which shall address all relevant records, including those that have not been transmitted to the Attorney General, in possession of the department or agency during the period beginning on July 1 of the previous year and ending on December 31 of the previous year.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HA8C47797FD6341ACBD62949E4324A40E"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>A certification required under clause (i) shall state, for the applicable period—</text> <subclause id="H23A3266443494A64A81B1FEFD50503B0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the total number of records of the Federal department or agency demonstrating that a person falls within one of the categories described in subsection (g) or (n) of section 922 of title 18, United States Code;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HF8F0E2C50A2C493EB20461A6672200A0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for each category of records described in subclause (I), the total number of records of the Federal department or agency that have been provided to the Attorney General; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HA717ECF5AD78446891CC258EF9C1FCB4"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the efforts of the Federal department or agency to ensure complete and accurate reporting of relevant records, including efforts to monitor compliance and correct any reporting failures or inaccuracies.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2431945AB8AC4E1CADA6FDB58F327E55"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Implementation plan</header> 
<clause id="H3AF4647B506746E0BE2D8D88E91FB679"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this subparagraph, the head of each Federal department or agency, in coordination with the Attorney General, shall establish a plan to ensure maximum coordination and automated reporting or making available of records to the Attorney General as required under subparagraph (C), and the verification of the accuracy of those records, including the pre-validation of those records, where appropriate, during a 4-year period specified in the plan. The head of each Federal department or agency shall update the plan biennially, to the extent necessary, based on the most recent biennial assessment under subparagraph (K). The records shall be limited to those of an individual described in subsection (g) or (n) of section 922 of title 18, United States Code.</text></clause> <clause id="H1671AC59F2B64AB58292EA55E02128E2"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Benchmark requirements</header><text>Each plan established under clause (i) shall include annual benchmarks to enable the Attorney General to assess implementation of the plan, including—</text> 
<subclause id="HA785509217ED43EEA8B376042022A121"><enum>(I)</enum><text>qualitative goals and quantitative measures;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H511D921C7F414492B6CB8D7817BDBCF2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>measures to monitor internal compliance, including any reporting failures and inaccuracies;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H47C05CDDA9464E2EB7BED64E38B07704"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a needs assessment, including estimated compliance costs; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HC160F7DC275448448D99E4D4C6CC7047"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>an estimated date by which the Federal department or agency will fully comply with record submission requirements under subparagraph (C).</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H75BA297314BE48A088B6F95391EF2517"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Compliance determination</header><text>Not later than the end of each fiscal year beginning after the date of the establishment of a plan under clause (i), the Attorney General shall determine whether the applicable Federal department or agency has achieved substantial compliance with the benchmarks included in the plan.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5596D7AF354B41BB89B76AB526DF570A"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Accountability</header><text>The Attorney General shall publish, including on the website of the Department of Justice, and submit to the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a semiannual report that discloses—</text> 
<clause id="HC01298C56B2A46BDA76B209E4C4809E6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the name of each Federal department or agency that has failed to submit a required certification under subparagraph (F);</text></clause> <clause id="H2BCFC7F8A3CC4DAAB3C27C55A79E597E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the name of each Federal department or agency that has submitted a required certification under subparagraph (F), but failed to certify compliance with the record submission requirements under subparagraph (C);</text></clause> 
<clause id="HFB8E8B4F083A44AEB5A48C1AAD8FE30C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the name of each Federal department or agency that has failed to submit an implementation plan under subparagraph (G);</text></clause> <clause id="H3A3AA9DB8E3749F9A2F6E29B195AC632"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the name of each Federal department or agency that is not in substantial compliance with an implementation plan under subparagraph (G);</text></clause> 
<clause id="HCA8CB0148ADE4E6FA4E652F44EE96C90"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a detailed summary of the data, broken down by department or agency, contained in the certifications submitted under subparagraph (F);</text></clause> <clause id="H94DA247846824644ABDD680DEEB307F9"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>a detailed summary of the contents and status, broken down by department or agency, of the implementation plans established under subparagraph (G); and</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H0977972CBA814BA9AEB9A5A69974786F"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the reasons for which the Attorney General has determined that a Federal department or agency is not in substantial compliance with an implementation plan established under subparagraph (G).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFB6AD42F83F8404BAF34A3901CD705A3"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Noncompliance penalties</header><text>For each of fiscal years 2019 through 2022, each political appointee of a Federal department or agency that has failed to certify compliance with the record submission requirements under subparagraph (C), and is not in substantial compliance with an implementation plan established under subparagraph (G), shall not be eligible for the receipt of bonus pay, excluding overtime pay, until the department or agency—</text> 
<clause id="H9E68746519364BF7B0014B078EA4142F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>certifies compliance with the record submission requirements under subparagraph (C); or</text></clause> <clause id="H1718F58A58FE43C4BD9601F7AA1A6E97"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>achieves substantial compliance with an implementation plan established under subparagraph (G).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H075F03063E6E431EB67842C139E3F303"><enum>(J)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Attorney General may use funds made available for the national instant criminal background check system established under subsection (b) to provide technical assistance to a Federal department or agency, at the request of the department or agency, in order to help the department or agency comply with the record submission requirements under subparagraph (C).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H008EEE2F0B094CDB89471980C06B0BE6" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(K)</enum><header>Biennial assessment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Every 2 years, the Attorney General shall assess the extent to which the actions taken under the title II of the Concealed Carry Reciprocity Act of 2017 have resulted in improvements in the system established under this section.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAB1F62884B0F45A898E85B024DA87D31"><enum>(L)</enum><header>Application to Federal courts</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph—</text> <clause id="HAEBBBEF9A09B4A94B71EAB407C01D247"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the terms <term>department or agency of the United States</term> and <term>Federal department or agency</term> include a Federal court; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA96FC64963D249EA897F428914314E1D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall perform, for a Federal court, the functions assigned to the head of a department or agency.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9057B489C31043A8ACF1431BADB353C3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (g), by adding at the end the following: <quote>For purposes of the preceding sentence, not later than 60 days after the date on which the Attorney General receives such information, the Attorney General shall determine whether or not the prospective transferee is the subject of an erroneous record and remove any records that are determined to be erroneous. In addition to any funds made available under subsection (k), the Attorney General may use such sums as are necessary and otherwise available for the salaries and expenses of the Federal Bureau of Investigation to comply with this subsection.</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H3CEC303810BF4C3C83D8F64323DBFA00"><enum>203.</enum><header>NICS Act Record Improvement Program</header> 
<subsection id="HF1DC56F26A19491EB0D653172290CF70"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirements To obtain waiver</header><text>Section 102 of the NICS Improvement Amendments Act of 2007(<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40912">34 U.S.C. 40912</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H01EBBD12002A442DBC4DAE31E17EEB0F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), in the first sentence—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H12D2B35BA7F3444F888AF699D27EBE0C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the Crime Identification Technology Act of 1988 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14601">42 U.S.C. 14601</external-xref>)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 102 of the Crime Identification Technology Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40301">34 U.S.C. 40301</external-xref>)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0884728A2288466BA50416A9186182CD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>is in compliance with an implementation plan established under subsection (b) or</quote> before <quote>provides at least 90 percent of the information described in subsection (c)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC268B9B118864C7286446C73BF1E1691"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1)(B), by inserting <quote>or has established an implementation plan under section 107</quote> after <quote>the Attorney General</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H75967A0B16A742D8BDF952B1039152CF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation assistance to States</header><text>Section 103 of the NICS Improvement Amendments Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40913">34 U.S.C. 40913</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HCB8A4C3E96DA4E7489B467A0E86EAA7E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(3), by inserting before the semicolon at the end the following: <quote>, including through increased efforts to pre-validate the contents of those records to expedite eligibility determinations</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2E1966C6CD6E475892739218703F9022"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (e), by striking paragraph (2) and inserting the following: </text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCE76228F5FAE41ECBB6EA676F76996AD" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H4BFA2A7EE281413196218B1DEB4B1A73"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Domestic Abuse and Violence Prevention Initiative</header> 
<subparagraph id="H4831B18C353144A088CCF992985FDF51"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>For each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022, the Attorney General shall create a priority area under the NICS Act Record Improvement Program (commonly known as <quote>NARIP</quote>) for a Domestic Abuse and Violence Prevention Initiative that emphasizes the need for grantees to identify and upload all felony conviction records and domestic violence records.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H87877CA3B026431CA85B9E1A868792B6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>The Attorney General—</text> 
<clause id="H9CFE382EAA9640178A446FC426C18A9D"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may use not more than 50 percent of the amounts made available under section 207 of the Concealed Carry Reciprocity Act of 2017 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022 to carry out the initiative described in subparagraph (A); and</text></clause> <clause id="HA46E33839BE848C78BFB0BA21EEC82A8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall give a funding preference under NARIP to States that—</text> 
<subclause id="HF6810C793A734FD49734C24EBB95DC3D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>have established an implementation plan under section 107; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H480E03CC86DB4E0EBA48A293B6F90C33"><enum>(II)</enum><text>will use amounts made available under this subparagraph to improve efforts to identify and upload all felony conviction records and domestic violence records described in clauses (i), (v), and (vi) of section 102(b)(1)(C) by not later than September 30, 2022.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1DC279CC29854E81A575B0AE908090E9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD34885534ACD416699C0AD80537E7F71" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HD577BCDDDC0949DEAD700D5F11F2EE62"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Attorney General shall direct the Office of Justice Programs, the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives, and the Federal Bureau of Investigation to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0CD27A2C9734443E8DA503D07AA78C5C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assist States that are not currently eligible for grants under this section to achieve compliance with all eligibility requirements; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8BAB5DD109C944BDA4630EF2802FB35F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide technical assistance and training services to grantees under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HB415EC4D46BB4D71881CAF3FBB0A9E53"><enum>204.</enum><header>National Criminal History Improvement Program</header> 
<subsection id="H41027B5E8AD54B01B532D5A7E8608433"><enum>(a)</enum><header>State grant program for criminal justice identification, information, and communication</header><text>Section 102 of the Crime Identification Technology Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40301">34 U.S.C. 40301</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H34F685705234412DA0723E6C8DEF23B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(3)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1CBC907688164287B4A90AC9B8C2F933"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (C), (D), and (E) as subparagraphs (D), (E), and (F), respectively; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1BFC763D47A84676AC3952EC45CE275D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (B) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0B860AC0CA354287BC9BEE31407CC918" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="H6970F4F2E19A43A2ADF0EDF84987CF0C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identification of all individuals who have been convicted of a crime punishable by imprisonment for a term exceeding 1 year</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H31B732CA99C14DA3B3CC7EB5287AC7E3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(6)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H53FF9FD51901474AB151E36A8CA768AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/922">18 U.S.C. 922</external-xref> note)</quote> and inserting <quote>(<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40901">34 U.S.C. 40901(b)</external-xref>)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA74C8F2AFB7040288EE9746EE1CC734A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting before the semicolon at the end the following: <quote>, including through increased efforts to pre-validate the contents of felony conviction records and domestic violence records to expedite eligibility determinations, and measures and resources necessary to establish and achieve compliance with an implementation plan under section 107 of the NICS Improvement Amendments Act of 2007</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H420539DBD2914D659FC7191A2A98E269"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (d), by inserting after <quote>unless</quote> the following: <quote>the State has achieved compliance with an implementation plan under section 107 of the NICS Improvement Amendments Act of 2007 or</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H51E6A5B270DA43B29D1D7AC4D485CBD0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants for the improvement of criminal records</header><text>Section 106(b)(1) of the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40302">34 U.S.C. 40302(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HAFAA0D225EA54B179233CB6C6C293AD0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A)—</text> <subparagraph id="HF69F866D00B54BC8A7E73487D993B9CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>as of the date of enactment of this Act</quote> and inserting <quote>, as of the date of enactment of the Concealed Carry Reciprocity Act of 2017,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0C66887A6A984922BC68763C23AD0B35"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>files,</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>files and that will utilize funding under this subsection to prioritize the identification and transmittal of felony conviction records and domestic violence records,</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9C613755C74648BC99CCD465EFBA23FD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB2098634F348467186B1FD31B8BBA3CD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)—</text> <subparagraph id="HD2B9614445DD4DD7B261F89BDCBDB4A2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>upon establishment of the national system,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5D47A7A62E114A2CBCF7E1CB1F824564"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H73C4139248904B6CBBA9D140B65D2180"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following—</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3AF8639F40014CD2B9660DFDA4196AA8" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="HEFB75770060D4F378C65CBBFF597987C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to establish and achieve compliance with an implementation plan under section 107 of the NICS Improvement Amendments Act of 2007.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H7C6F75EDDA4B4EC788F5BECA53E3976E"><enum>205.</enum><header>Improving information sharing with the States</header> <subsection id="H3E769EF9C02E4FD4A5C274630EE4EED0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title I of the NICS Improvement Amendments Act of 2007 (34 U.S. 40911 et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5994FB741A5D484BA779953E4F38221F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0B452B8A2E2A45129DD5E65782A57DB6"><enum>107.</enum><header>Implementation plan</header> 
<subsection id="H428DAA7937FB48679CC2616D78FB4752"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the Concealed Carry Reciprocity Act of 2017, the Attorney General, in coordination with the States and Indian tribal governments, shall establish, for each State or Indian tribal government, a plan to ensure maximum coordination and automation of the reporting or making available of appropriate records to the National Instant Criminal Background Check System established under section 103 of the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40901">34 U.S.C. 40901</external-xref>) and the verification of the accuracy of those records during a 4-year period specified in the plan, and shall update the plan biennially, to the extent necessary, based on the most recent biennial assessment under subsection (f). The records shall be limited to those of an individual described in subsection (g) or (n) of section 922 of title 18, United States Code.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HCEBF45F7B2C241E5B1E6D861A58DEFF0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Benchmark requirements</header><text>Each plan established under this section shall include annual benchmarks to enable the Attorney General to assess the implementation of the plan, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="H347DDB8E6293416F95DA266A5EFE27A2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>qualitative goals and quantitative measures; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H12853F308F5A4D759D08B7D20C39F963"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a needs assessment, including estimated compliance costs.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFA07B06F9A8F466FA890B08A004ADE33"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Compliance determination</header><text>Not later than the end of each fiscal year beginning after the date of the establishment of an implementation plan under this section, the Attorney General shall determine whether each State or Indian tribal government has achieved substantial compliance with the benchmarks included in the plan.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HCC9D9F73BB1E4E379641622C6E7F89B1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Accountability</header><text>The Attorney General—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDEBDB9BB47F845889D9B9D757D840E7B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall disclose and publish, including on the website of the Department of Justice—</text> <subparagraph id="H7934E8F5E83D4426A8CD5AB87419D6FC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name of each State or Indian tribal government that received a determination of failure to achieve substantial compliance with an implementation plan under subsection (c) for the preceding fiscal year; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H281504A899CA4FE788BCCB6BCF0F9AED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of the reasons for which the Attorney General has determined that the State or Indian tribal government is not in substantial compliance with the implementation plan, including, to the greatest extent possible, a description of the types and amounts of records that have not been submitted; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H04C68136B1BA4F8D86855560920BC136"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if a State or Indian tribal government described in paragraph (1) subsequently receives a determination of substantial compliance, shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HACAFDDC9F5DC4A3FBB56ED71E3A91962"><enum>(A)</enum><text>immediately correct the applicable record; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7B8B7B6BFB704777839242E1EAA5542F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than 3 days after the determination, remove the record from the website of the Department of Justice and any other location where the record was published.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H57E730DD38054BE79FA3E06326847DAD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Incentives</header><text>For each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022, the Attorney General shall give affirmative preference to all Bureau of Justice Assistance discretionary grant applications of a State or Indian tribal government that received a determination of substantial compliance under subsection (c) for the fiscal year in which the grant was solicited.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H30EE2798CF9E469BA97761D73517AF57"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Biennial assessment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Every 2 years, the Attorney General shall assess the extent to which the actions taken under title II of the Concealed Carry Reciprocity Act of 2017 have resulted in improvements in the National Instant Criminal Background Check System established under section 103 of the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40903">34 U.S.C. 40903</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H5065904192924D8A8FFF940CDE16A019" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>108.</enum><header>Notification to law enforcement agencies of prohibited purchase of a firearm</header> 
<subsection id="H22CBE57988074EEAAD800BA467166634"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a background check conducted by the National Instant Criminal Background Check System pursuant to the request of a licensed importer, licensed manufacturer, or licensed dealer of firearms (as such terms are defined in section 921 of title 18, United States Code), which background check determines that the receipt of a firearm by a person would violate subsection (g) or (n) of section 922 of title 18, United States Code, and such determination is made after 3 business days have elapsed since the licensee contacted the System and a firearm has been transferred to that person, the System shall notify the law enforcement agencies described in subsection (b).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF0F81AF0EDE5464EAE0B449D0F767AFB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Law enforcement agencies described</header><text>The law enforcement agencies described in this subsection are the law enforcement agencies that have jurisdiction over the location from which the licensee contacted the system and the law enforcement agencies that have jurisdiction over the location of the residence of the person for which the background check was conducted, as follows:</text> 
<paragraph id="H0DE6864D2DCD441B988936E37B908E59"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The field office of the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H825FCE2144914B9782CDFCCFF4111691"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The local law enforcement agency.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H58EF7707B23A4A0995FBF56A3ECCC2A6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The State law enforcement agency.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HED0C424E9B1C46B3A81383553850B2E7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the NICS Improvement Amendments Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/180">Public Law 110–180</external-xref>; 121 Stat. 2559) is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 106 the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5B27E99E527F4CB0A4C4CF06BC9F5F16" style="OLC"> 
<toc> 
<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 107. Implementation plan.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 108. Notification to law enforcement agencies of prohibited purchase of a firearm.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
<section id="HB22168795B3742C49B85F56FF051364E"><enum>206.</enum><header>Attorney General report on use of bump stocks in crime</header> 
<subsection id="HF3B8878FBDCF4653AB5F1CBC057A72B5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Using amounts made available for research, evaluation, or statistical purposes, within 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall prepare and submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate a written report that—</text> <paragraph id="H2235E37326634CC484B49EC7CC8BDEEA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specifies the number of instances in which a bump stock has been used in the commission of a crime in the United States;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6D262869B38540C18DAFF85007E7908C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specifies the types of firearms with which a bump stock has been so used; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAD8F3F9145E9414493E6A0B331050DFC"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contains the opinion of the Attorney General as to whether subparagraphs (B)(i) and (C)(i) of section 924(c)(1) of title 18, United States Code, apply to all instances in which a bump stock has been used in the commission of a crime of violence in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBBB9F2543D5A44AA8317A0FD2C92CB10"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition of bump stock</header><text>In this section, the term <term>bump stock</term> means a device that—</text> <paragraph id="H7A650F568855458F991D582113337BF8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>attaches to a semiautomatic rifle (as defined in section 921(a)(28) of title 18, United States Code);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9259685CA57E4DF8AC0462D2FDB80D92"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is designed and intended to repeatedly activate the trigger without the deliberate and volitional act of the user pulling the trigger each time the firearm is fired; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H74A4088A34724A10A9E81C666CD6B2D4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>functions by continuous forward pressure applied to the rifle’s fore end in conjunction with a linear forward and backward sliding motion of the mechanism utilizing the recoil energy when the rifle is discharged.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H38C608FF298F4462802DF5ADCE0F703F" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>207.</enum><header>Authorizations of appropriations</header> 
<subsection id="HEC2CDB1840344A0E8C3509FEB77060D2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated $100,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022 to carry out, in accordance with the NICS Act Record Improvement Program and the National Criminal History Improvement Program, the activities under—</text> <paragraph id="HF945B0F9E7DD45E3916F4353AFC3E3F4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>section 102 of the NICS Improvement Amendments Act of 2007;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFFEAE9B4A8B74AD588CAA36CE9681F2C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 103 of the NICS Improvement Amendments Act of 2007;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE51FA593F1DE461CB01589E3383C7A53"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 102 of the Crime Identification Technology Act of 1998; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H17BF25D686F64A63A5D1C98645658405"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 106(b) of the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3FA0173ECE8F4CA095AD39833B1CD693"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional authorizations</header><text>Section 1001(a) of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10261">34 U.S.C. 10261(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD52FF9D09E3F48A48E38B884A48D4551"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="HF5C08F76528848B3A465D8B14E9E5B2C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>$33,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$31,000,000</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H730B31207922451D8CB71C3858ECEB47"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>1994 and 1995</quote> and inserting <quote>2018 through 2022</quote>; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE0A44EF073564836A997334EDBA64388"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, in addition to any amounts otherwise made available for research, evaluation or statistical purposes in a fiscal year</quote> before the period; and </text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7AE467FD840242E495D14841F5BD1F9A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> <subparagraph id="H41334486510A45B598C36FDE8981B728"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>$33,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$27,000,000</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3E24723D137145DEB72856D537C62BAE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>1994 and 1995</quote> and inserting <quote>2018 through 2022</quote>; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H984D61ACE54B42028A921F050D78A72F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, in addition to any amounts otherwise made available for research, evaluation or statistical purposes in a fiscal year</quote> before the period.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></title> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20171206" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives December 6, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> 
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> 
</bill> 


