<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H065DEA7DE8EA42F7AA6249D11DA66D3C" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 472 IH: Safe Recovery and Community Empowerment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 472</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170112">January 12, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000820">Mrs. Mimi Walters of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000059">Mr. Calvert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001048">Mr. Hunter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000487">Mr. Royce of California</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000409">Mr. Rohrabacher</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Fair Housing Act to better protect persons with disabilities and communities.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H7BA039A8756F432891333F6B140B0EEC" style="OLC">
 <section id="HAD35EBBC10A64A7F99919A30665B0BE3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safe Recovery and Community Empowerment Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HBBE8C068F3A74ADBB2AA73D7E74BD707"><enum>2.</enum><header>Zoning and licensing of residential recovery facilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Fair Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3601">42 U.S.C. 3601</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by inserting after section 807 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3607">42 U.S.C. 3607</external-xref>) the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAA0E12D7FE2B440CAAEBE2847FA17B43" style="traditional">
 <section id="H93BAAFFDE3E44196A27FA06129C4A490"><enum>807A.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this title, or other Federal law, relating to protections for persons with disabilities, prohibits any local, State, or Federal government body from—</text>
 <paragraph id="H64DFF83BAA61443081ABB66278A087A8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">requiring by law, regulation, or ordinance a reasonable minimum distance between residential recovery facilities within a particular area zoned for residential housing, provided that the limitation—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H02B3868FAEE346E7871F1A360BB4B885"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is necessary to preserve the residential character of the zoned area; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4406509CAA44ED28667C4352137F63A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>allows for some residential recovery facilities to be located within the zoned area; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2052CADD6CBB49539AEF53888AA9719A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>requiring that a residential recovery facility and its owner or operator—</text> <subparagraph id="H685CCC47228944BEBB7E048A59C76E2C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">obtain an operating license or use permit; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H835588FA990845AFAA17D2E1F3838BAF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">satisfy a set of consumer protection standards, which may include a maximum capacity requirement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section><section id="H38D8B10DB1FB42D0A576585B853CF066"><enum>3.</enum><header>Residential recovery facility residents’ bill of rights</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Residential recovery facilities receiving direct or indirect payments or reimbursements or other remunerations from Medicare, Medicaid, or any other Federal healthcare program, or via private insurance purchased on a Federal exchange or subsidized by the Federal Government, for either housing, recovery services, or testing or monitoring for drugs or alcohol, shall ensure the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H64294D1A1E83438D983EF943B7B7749B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each residential recovery facility resident residing in the home or receiving addiction treatment services be provided a safe living environment completely free from illicit drugs, alcohol, firearms, harassment, abuse, or harm.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDD76EA047E5D473987E05CF95F5DE8FA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Residential recovery facility residents live in a licensed, or registered residence that has committed to following standards approved by States and localities, if such standards are in place.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HD94D1E458DA748A8B9B3D29D21D250D7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 802 of the Fair Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3602">42 U.S.C. 3602</external-xref>) is amended by adding to the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB8F60A03736C4DD6BB1CBF62AC42D284" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H1177F4E7473342D4BDFD8D7F80F006F0"><enum>(p)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><quote>Current, illegal use of a controlled substance</quote> means the discrete, occasional, frequent, or ongoing illegal use of a controlled substance at the present time or in the reasonably recent past.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD658C039B7D144408093B55A77ECD96D"><enum>(q)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><quote>Residential recovery facility</quote> means a residence that provides housing to individuals in recovery from drug or alcohol addiction with the promise of providing a clean and sober environment in return for direct or indirect payment to an owner, operator, or compensated staff person, including payment to a third party, a portion of which is then provided to the residential recovery facility owner or operator for their services.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


