<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H62C74DA42A0D4C1E85D85E2BEB7EDA74" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4577 IH: Domestic Explosives Detection Canine Capacity Building Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4577</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171206">December 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000575">Mr. Rogers of Alabama</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001269">Mr. Barletta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000625">Mr. Donovan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a working group to determine ways to develop a domestic canine breeding network to
			 produce high quality explosives detection canines, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H2B722C7C9F4D487D8B978FEF16D2CA46" style="OLC">
 <section id="H80FD703AB9084318A5ED024D070137EB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Domestic Explosives Detection Canine Capacity Building Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H95810A9CF0B748F3A2FFC991AAB2AE95"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="H99E6A528056B4DB6BF7A3156F264F12B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Behavioral standards</header><text>The term <quote>behavioral standards</quote> means standards for the evaluation of explosives detection working canines for certain factors, including canine temperament, work drive, suitability for training, environmental factors used in evaluations, and canine familiarity with natural or man-made surfaces or working conditions relevant to the canine’s expected work area.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H917758D9F630438A8E4A6D96ABBA4D60"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Medical standards</header><text>The term <quote>medical standards</quote> means standards for the evaluation of explosives detection working canines for certain factors, including canine health, management of heredity health conditions, breeding practices, genetics, pedigree, and long-term health tracking.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H83F38B6F987F4510A02F3353DFB49435"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Technical standards</header><text>The term <quote>technical standards</quote> means standards for the evaluation of explosives detection working canines for certain factors, including canine search techniques, handler-canine communication, detection testing conditions and logistics, and learned explosive odor libraries.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HCAC1521C5601485893A8AD65DDA4C77C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Domestic capacity development</header>
 <subsection id="H28ADDDC87348478E9967D96876EC6C22"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, shall establish a working group to determine ways to develop a decentralized domestic canine breeding network to produce high quality explosives detection canines and modernize canine training standards.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE6D1184D75C240F7BAE11541843DA10B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Working group composition</header><text>The working group established under subsection (a) shall be comprised of representatives from the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H18C6A3026DA54466A94307F720D98060"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Transportation Security Administration.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H900C41F703F74F62BB1D7BF0AFF4EDC7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Science and Technology Directorate of the Department of Homeland Security.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H779C600C31394B5CAA1B1842065C6C09"><enum>(3)</enum><text>National domestic canine associations with expertise in breeding and pedigree.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H20F3B2A6F9694E4081DD08C8600AF113"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Universities with expertise related to explosives detection canines and canine breeding.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCB9542C60EFC41FF9311580FD20DEB09"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Domestic canine breeders and vendors.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDFC0A7C7DD1E47CAAA85689D95B72AC5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Preliminary standards and recommendations</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the establishment of the working group under subsection (a), such working group shall submit to the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration preliminary behavioral standards, medical standards, and technical standards for the domestic canine breeding network and canine training described in such subsection, including recommendations on how the Transportation Security Administration can engage stakeholders to further the development of such network and training.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H61F7928DBF8E47C9AD8CF9270E40AF5F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Strategy</header><text>Not later than 180 days after submission of recommendations to the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration under subsection (c), the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a strategy for expanding the domestic canine breeding network described in subsection (a), based on such recommendations.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H6FA00A94049845EBB9149AE9D0D2C8F6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Acquiring baseline capacity</header>
 <subsection id="HF635735201DA40ABBF02FD94A42A1656"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the submission of recommendations to the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration under section 3, the Administrator shall issue baseline behavioral standards for explosives detection canines.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H491121D952444CBDB123A498D1DDA9AF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Standards</header><text>The baseline behavioral standards issued pursuant to subsection (a), and the preliminary medical standards and technical standards issued pursuant to section 3, shall be incorporated into all statements of work for the Transportation Security Administration explosive detection canine contracts and reflect the detection capabilities required to effectively mitigate terrorist threats. Such standards may be revised by the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, as necessary.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HA3370724DB24419AB0C705E6137B0D4A"><enum>5.</enum><header>Nonapplicability of Federal Advisory Committee Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) shall not apply to the working group established under this Act.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


