<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H23DC8A82A956440A97F797D3D880B44B" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2038 IH: Budgeting for Opioid Addiction Treatment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2038</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170406">April 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish a stewardship fee on the production and
			 importation of opioid pain relievers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H01008C467FF9493F8304181E532EAC96" style="OLC">
 <section id="H5987CF33C95E4D37813A3D00609C45CB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Budgeting for Opioid Addiction Treatment Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HDAEE2CA86C7442E0A366336DB103FD95"><enum>2.</enum><header>Stewardship fee on opioid pain relievers</header> <subsection id="HF80AA1BF9A4B40B98D8A4799A96CE3CC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter E of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/32">chapter 32</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block act-name="" id="HED8285E4019F43438B9AE27A63E88FD9" style="OLC">
					<section id="H805FCAE870814B5BB04E0B15A6A95EC6"><enum>4192.</enum><header>Opioid pain relievers</header>
 <subsection id="HF4D280E659EB4C8BA6D780C3EC63D77C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is hereby imposed on the sale of any active opioid by the manufacturer, producer, or importer a fee equal to 1 cent per milligram so sold.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H175D98A2709E4F1EBFF6A1EA9B990A1C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Active opioid</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="HFD0B77EDEFAF4604B1F699DF4F7E86F9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>active opioid</term> means any controlled substance (as defined in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act, as in effect on the date of the enactment of this section) which is opium, an opiate, or any derivative thereof.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDA66EA31C5B14781812185719B77A49A"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Exclusion for certain prescription medications</header><text>Such term shall not include any prescribed drug which is used exclusively for the treatment of opioid addiction as part of a medically assisted treatment effort.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H25CA26212DCB475CA89A36414896A3E0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exclusion of other ingredients</header><text>In the case of a product that includes an active opioid and another ingredient, subsection (a) shall apply only to the portion of such product that is an active opioid.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="HA221437D5CB0457F96484626DBFA877B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="H1E2EE0AE4A8E4740A8F51EC30C2AEF32"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The heading of subchapter E of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/32">chapter 32</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subchapter" style="OLC">Medical devices</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subchapter" style="OLC">Other medical products</header-in-text></quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1AF1B2BC75614035BD60AEF0D445B9CD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The table of subchapters for chapter 32 of such Code is amended by striking the item relating to subchapter E and inserting the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H44413FD4B5264243A1C07140AAF73826" style="OLC">
						<toc>
							<toc-entry bold="off" level="subchapter">Subchapter E. Other medical products</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H87E0ABAD89E748FF8B503A837ED70B63"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The table of sections for subchapter E of chapter 32 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H5D96BA15FD61428699E328DCE7EE72E9" style="OLC">
						<toc>
							<toc-entry idref="H805FCAE870814B5BB04E0B15A6A95EC6" level="section">Sec. 4192. Opioid pain relievers.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H806121758E454211B486499D7B4C26C5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to sales on or after the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HB51372BFA1A441969479006BCC2E8EB6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rebate or discount program for certain cancer and hospice patients</header>
 <paragraph id="H2A1A73CE20D74F72A00276E95DF62F90"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with patient advocacy groups and other relevant stakeholders as determined by such Secretary, shall establish a mechanism by which—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC0F7CCA43EE6488DBD18D82586696B9A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any amount paid by an eligible patient in connection with the stewardship fee under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4192">section 4192</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (as added by this section) shall be rebated to such patient in as timely a manner as possible, or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC795FD7B04E64C0B8515D3565CCE683A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>amounts paid by an eligible patient for active opioids (as defined in section 4192(b) of such Code) are discounted at time of payment or purchase to ensure that such patient does not pay any amount attributable to such fee,</text>
					</subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">with as little burden on the patient as possible. The Secretary shall choose whichever of the
			 options described in subparagraph (A) or (B) is, in the Secretary's
			 determination, most effective and efficient in ensuring eligible patients
 face no economic burden from such fee.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H10C2985E2888490D9646A5927588B64C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible patient</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>eligible patient</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HFA4EE1C2A2B04D8C9CEC6F0E0F0A35D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a patient for whom any active opioid (as so defined) is prescribed to treat pain relating to cancer or cancer treatment;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC68C33589FC741EDBEC0247FF9103088"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a patient participating in hospice care; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H468FDA1CC813449788CE427166540470"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the case of the death or incapacity of a patient described in subparagraph (A) or (B) or any similar situation as determined by the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the appropriate family member, medical proxy, or similar representative or the estate of such patient.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H5833C57AB42C4E59B42D604C4A56C8AB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Block grants for prevention and treatment of substance abuse</header>
 <subsection id="H2967426334EA4A8F8B753A2BB13FED41"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants to States</header><text>Section 1921(b) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300x-21">42 U.S.C. 300x–21(b)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, and, as applicable, for carrying out section 1923A</quote> before the period.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HC3BB41ED2C614D74948184700F461A35"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Nonapplicability of prevention program provision</header><text>Section 1922(a)(1) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300x-22">42 U.S.C. 300x–22(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>except with respect to amounts made available as described in section 1923A,</quote> before <quote>will expend</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HABE5DCAD452947D9B4629C347560D04F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Opioid treatment programs</header><text>Subpart II of part B of title XIX of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300x-21">42 U.S.C. 300x–21</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by inserting after section 1923 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD52D853A67964B2AA856549949529DB0" style="OLC">
 <section id="H45D997D6A9224E12BD0FD3574222C607"><enum>1923A.</enum><header>Additional substance abuse treatment programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A funding agreement for a grant under section 1921 is that the State involved shall provide that any amounts made available by any increase in revenues to the Treasury in the previous fiscal year resulting from the enactment of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4192">section 4192</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, reduced by any amounts rebated or discounted under section 2(d) of the <short-title>Budgeting for Opioid Addiction Treatment Act</short-title> (as described in section 1933(a)(1)(B)(i)) be used exclusively for substance abuse (including opioid abuse) treatment efforts in the State, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA9C8D58F331044AF8625169A09DB16E3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">treatment programs—</text> <subparagraph id="H3E5B1C9F3F044419919805D1178189F9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishing new addiction treatment facilities, residential and outpatient, including covering capital costs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEFA56BE9FCE24D76A17100C73B1DEC03"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishing sober living facilities;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3AB599324F144268B1AF016851433062"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recruiting and increasing reimbursement for certified mental health providers providing substance abuse treatment in medically underserved communities or communities with high rates of prescription drug abuse;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02D06FD9D608434FBFCFDA7C50177519"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expanding access to long-term, residential treatment programs for opioid addicts (including 30-, 60-, and 90-day programs);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB121EFA982524F088C77AA8C0689B021"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishing or operating support programs that offer employment services, housing, and other support services to help recovering addicts transition back into society;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7EEA476E510F49F0B96D48985F0AFEBB"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishing or operating housing for children whose parents are participating in substance abuse treatment programs, including capital costs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFCF3C12C2B7C462997F5CB6ABC7A9C60"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishing or operating facilities to provide care for babies born with neonatal abstinence syndrome, including capital costs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5BBB76BAA3574BBE8519CC4E0F1B9311"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other treatment programs, as the Secretary determines appropriate; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H24A08A2021A24B9DAF17468F7FEB6139"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recruitment and training of substance use disorder professionals to work in rural and medically underserved communities.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD0BCD8E949424E3CA4DB5F1399CAE2CE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Additional funding</header><text>Section 1933(a)(1)(B)(i) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300x-33">42 U.S.C. 300x–33(a)(1)(B)(i)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, plus any increase in revenues to the Treasury in the previous fiscal year resulting from the enactment of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4192">section 4192</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, reduced by any amounts rebated or discounted under section 2(d) of the <short-title>Budgeting for Opioid Addiction Treatment Act</short-title></quote> before the period.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HF6BA459628174A9CA6EF3BAFAD7C4173"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date described in section 2(c), the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to Congress a report on the impact of the amendments made by sections 2 and 3 on—</text>
 <paragraph id="H1444DC256BC54610BE9DFEC4E924D23D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the retail cost of active opioids (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4192">section 4192</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as added by section 2);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD34AAF030796414EAD9C6C20D4327132"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">patient access to such opioids, particularly cancer and hospice patients, including the effect of the discount or rebate on such opioids for cancer and hospice patients under section 2(d);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H787D662FA24447AE8B482914E8C2AEB3"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the increase in revenue to the Treasury resulting from the enactment of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4192">section 4192</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is used to improve substance abuse treatment efforts in accordance with section 1923A of the Public Health Service Act (as added by section 3); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC76CD49BE6C144A1B9F17BCF5F827C48"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">suggestions for improving—</text> <subparagraph id="H5712F2707B7F41C597C8A66C061F991B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">access to opioids for cancer and hospice patients; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4DE5B5AC58B34D3093E257B6F19D15F8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">substance abuse treatment efforts under such section 1923A.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

