<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H16C683ABC464441B980AB294CCBFF745" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3328 RH: Cuban Airport Security Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 220</calendar><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3328</legis-num><associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 115–308, Part I]</associated-doc><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170720">July 20, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001165">Mr. Sires</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><action><action-date>September 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><action><action-date>September 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc>The Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name> and <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to
			 be printed<pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require a study regarding security measures and equipment at Cuba’s airports, require the
			 standardization of Federal Air Marshal Service agreements, require efforts
			 to raise international aviation security standards, and for other
			 purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H3946B4C59E444EB1A1BA491094372B1E" style="OLC">
 <section id="H6C92E18FA4D94FB194C82E249FC85E23" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cuban Airport Security Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H71B41908521A49BC87E25C65479C97E8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Flights between the United States and Cuba</header> <subsection commented="no" id="H1060E057905949D792B7359680988A29"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall brief the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, and the Comptroller General of the United States on the following aspects of security measures at each of Cuba’s ten international airports:</text>
 <paragraph id="H7B29E18C1A834128909E6F9AB5047941"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Details about the type of equipment used at screening checkpoints and an analysis of such equipment’s capabilities and weaknesses.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE0F2DAEF5C634E648161A01732E8D2F7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Information about each such airport’s canine program, if used.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H111829D91C1C4A98AD3883A8A69BA8EE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The frequency of training for screening and security personnel.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF30409B0F2A048DA9BE55D0AA21573B8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Access controls in place to ensure only credentialed personnel have access to the secure and sterile areas of such airports.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA7DB2C6932AB481AA89E295D93EC8EB6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An assessment of the ability of known or suspected terrorists to use Cuba as a gateway to entering the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H16F6328AA89F400F8D0E0AA6A1168976"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Security of such airports’ perimeters.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H76C92777637A44F48A547443B7FB297B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A mitigation assessment regarding Man Portable Air Defense Systems.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0A423BF301B34C38A73A88A0340B9161"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The vetting practices and procedures for airport employees.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBD3E29743229498DB6EC306F876897A7"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Any other information determined relevant to the security practices, procedures, and equipment in place at such airports.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1F94C397AE0143D2B5D88420EE6034AF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Public disclosure of certain agreements</header>
 <paragraph id="H9D7134ABFFF246B5B8E8444835428E44"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Disclosure required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No United States air carrier that has entered into a covered agreement may employ a Cuban national pursuant to 31 CFR 515.573 after the date that is 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act unless the air carrier has publicly disclosed the full text of the covered agreement.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB4DF9903D85245B19AE7567AB8922955"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Hiring and training requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law or regulation, to the extent practicable, Cuban nationals referred to in paragraph (1) shall not have been recruited, hired, or trained by entities that are owned, operated, or controlled, in whole or in part, by Cuba’s Council of State, Council of Ministers, Communist Party, Ministry of the Revolutionary Armed Forces, Ministry of Foreign Affairs, or Ministry of the Interior.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF2ED4C2246054EEC9EDB88A05838CD4B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered agreement</header><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>covered agreement</quote> means a formal agreement between a United States air carrier with passenger air service between any location in Cuba and any location in the United States and the Empresa Cubana de Aeropuertos y Servicios Aeronauticos or any other entity associated with the Government of Cuba.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HFC6C11A7454D48BEAA2798E02AD63507"><enum>3.</enum><header>Federal Air Marshal Service agreements</header>
 <subsection id="H4BE5E9E637924A468F5548C5E6F6E2A1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Standardization</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of the Act, the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall develop a standard working document to serve as the basis for all negotiations and agreements that begin after such date between the United States and foreign governments or partners regarding Federal Air Marshal coverage of flights to and from the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H70D9ADED00134BA19B7D33C46BA301D2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Written agreements</header><text>All agreements between the United States and foreign governments or partners regarding the presence of Federal Air Marshals on flights to and from the United States pursuant to subsection (a) shall be written and signed by the Secretary of Homeland Security or the Secretary’s designee.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H99D251D526AF4A1BAB40B7DAD9735018"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Congressional notification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate any agreement entered into under this section within 30 days of such agreement being signed.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H40890D686261441C9D487065A0C0F20C"><enum>4.</enum><header>International Civil Aviation Organization</header>
 <subsection id="H903C5750978A41AFA3D246FF97D2464E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the United States Ambassador or the Chargé d’Affaires to the United States Mission to the International Civil Aviation Organization shall pursue improvements to airport security, including if practicable, introducing a resolution to raise minimum standards for airport security.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5C68BE2D2EC746D189F53268FCE260AC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the United States Ambassador or the Chargé d’Affaires to the United States Mission to the International Civil Aviation Organization shall report to the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, the Committee on Foreign Relations, and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate on the implementation of subsection (a).</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date display="yes">September 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc><action-date>September 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc>The Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name> and <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to
			 be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill>


