<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H05A44BFD52634ACAB0FBEF93A42AA447" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 823 IH: Expand American Educational Opportunity Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 823</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170202">February 2, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000197">Ms. Pelosi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000015">Mr. Neal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001286">Mrs. Bustos</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001251">Mr. Butterfield</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001038">Mr. Crowley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001063">Mr. Cuellar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000620">Mr. Delaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000293">Ms. Esty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001038">Mr. Higgins of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000379">Mr. Kennedy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000380">Mr. Kildee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000263">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000565">Mr. Loebsack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001227">Mr. Brady of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000523">Mr. Price of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000602">Miss Rice of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000486">Ms. Roybal-Allard</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001168">Mr. Sarbanes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001150">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000874">Mr. Hoyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001064">Mr. Heck</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001170">Ms. Shea-Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001050">Ms. Hanabusa</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to extend and modify the American Opportunity Tax
			 Credit, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H7806A4BA9DED48D6ADA2105007546305" style="OLC">
 <section id="HD1A2F60EC55A45DDA351D9AE8B1ECCAA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Expand American Educational Opportunity Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H35BECBDE84D744529B6ACACAEF0F01F2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Extension and modification of american opportunity tax credit</header> <subsection id="HEDC4848691B0483F895A2A40D06B022A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/25A">Section 25A</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H4BF03420C32E47D19AF6865438D28FB6" style="OLC">
					<section id="HDCB106EC7C7547878329963DA01A78FD"><enum>25A.</enum><header>American opportunity tax credit</header>
 <subsection id="HB914C95B78234E09879F7BC486BA75C5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Allowance of credit</header><text>In the case of an individual who is an eligible student for any taxable year, there shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by this chapter for such taxable year the amount determined under subsection (b) with respect to such individual.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H462B4E6FF8334559BC37A7D576C24629"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amount of credit</header>
 <paragraph id="H3AB0FA7214774D4AAB6FCE71A1AE04FA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Student enrolled at least <fraction>½</fraction> time</header><text>In the case of an eligible student who is carrying at least <fraction>½</fraction> the normal full-time workload for the course of study the student is pursuing, the amount determined under this subsection with respect to such individual is the sum of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC97BB75EB5E24785BDF970F751D52023"><enum>(A)</enum><text>100 percent of so much of the qualified tuition and related expenses paid by the taxpayer during the taxable year (for education furnished to the eligible student during any academic period beginning in such taxable year) as does not exceed $2,000, plus</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF0C98486BF6A4F138DBDF91D2355423C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>25 percent of such expenses so paid as exceeds $2,000 but does not exceed $4,000.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEBF42545F31B4D47B5C6550672577597"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other students</header><text>In the case of an eligible student not described in paragraph (1), the amount determined under this subsection with respect to such individual is 25 percent of so much of the qualified tuition and related expenses paid by the taxpayer during the taxable year (for education furnished to the eligible student during any academic period beginning in such taxable year) as does not exceed $10,000.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDD986EBABE5E4036AE98DA421F458BB9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation based on modified adjusted gross income</header>
 <paragraph id="H9A2C06730B9848DBBF25D9CBC2F8DA8F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amount which would (but for this paragraph) be taken into account under this section for the taxable year shall be reduced (but not below zero) by the amount determined under paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7BD979E9191945E2960078BD7944938D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amount of reduction</header><text>The amount determined under this paragraph is the amount which bears the same ratio to the amount which would be so taken into account as—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0456469348A94C91987C8B8D948015B1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the excess of—</text> <clause id="H93DA8DF5A31D4398A07D3CA84E4DF414"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the taxpayer’s modified adjusted gross income for such taxable year, over</text>
 </clause><clause id="H41963620BEF24281A93A686273DB9B2E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>$80,000 ($160,000 in the case of a joint return), bears to</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2909C5CCA5A245CC98AF7880278B1C0C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$10,000 ($20,000 in the case of a joint return).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HADD74E2262384646A6805786DF85F582"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Modified adjusted gross income</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>modified adjusted gross income</term> means the adjusted gross income of the taxpayer for the taxable year increased by any amount excluded from gross income under section 911, 931, or 933.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4318DD48A0D34876B067A07F52E2E7CC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Other limitations and special rules</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text> <paragraph id="H2818A3E4A5B6401FA6CD429587A277B3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Lifetime dollar limitation</header><text>In the case of qualified tuition and related expenses with respect to any eligible student, the aggregate amount of the credits allowed in the taxable year and any prior taxable year for such eligible student (whether beginning before or after <short-title>Expand American Educational Opportunity Act of 2017</short-title>) shall not exceed $15,000, determined without regard to whether—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCF9B936C36CD470282845CED7888FC44"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such credits are claimed on the return of tax filed by the eligible student or by another taxpayer, or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6935EA1DCBE74C3198155CD9E191215C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such expenses are treated as paid by the eligible student or by another taxpayer.</text> </subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">If, in any taxable year, the aggregate amount of such credits equals or exceeds $15,000, the amount allowed as a credit under subsection (a) in any subsequent taxable year with respect to such student shall be zero.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H833F5D76BAD544139EF9B3D9C3E97AEB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Identification requirements</header> <subparagraph id="HC781418792FB43CA90D390DDD66F41DD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Students</header> <clause id="HFF83F6AB99F14A4CB59C9C47C786F2C9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No credit shall be allowed under this section to a taxpayer with respect to the qualified tuition and related expenses of an eligible student unless the taxpayer includes the name and taxpayer identification number of such eligible student on the return of tax for the taxable year.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1473F7CDEA0B476F9B6DD8997A2E2E27"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Issuance</header><text>The requirements of clause (i) shall not be treated as met unless the individual’s taxpayer identification number was issued on or before the due date for filing the return of tax for the taxable year.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB65B1F907E7C484FA7E65FD856922C35"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Taxpayer</header><text>No credit shall be allowed under this section if the identifying number of the taxpayer was issued after the due date for filing the return for the taxable year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD085C45AD7B420DB7653D67322C0A71"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Institution</header><text>No credit shall be allowed under this section unless the taxpayer includes the employer identification number of any institution to which qualified tuition and related expenses were paid with respect to the individual.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2A806107FF2434D9AF9E822AF4B7CC7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Adjustment for certain scholarships, etc</header>
 <subparagraph id="HE7AB08183AD144DCB5BA937B6454C8EB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amount of qualified tuition and related expenses otherwise taken into account under this section with respect to an individual for an academic period shall be reduced (before the application of subsections (b) and (c)) by the sum of any amounts paid for the benefit of such individual which are allocable to such period as—</text>
 <clause id="HA54EF774607F4306858ECAD5307AB9AB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a qualified scholarship which is excludable from gross income under section 117,</text> </clause><clause id="H78285158292849289C34CEC2797A0319"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an educational assistance allowance under chapter 30, 31, 32, 34, or 35 of title 38, United States Code, or under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/1606">chapter 1606</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAF5EC320C1DA404AB7890805C6C2E00B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a payment (other than a gift, bequest, devise, or inheritance within the meaning of section 102(a)) for such individual’s educational expenses, or attributable to such individual’s enrollment at an eligible educational institution, which is excludable from gross income under any law of the United States.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C5CBF5F05FA4F49AC3B6EEE6D5987A3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Coordination with pell grants not used for qualified tuition and related expenses</header><text>Any amount determined with respect to an individual under subparagraph (A) which is attributable to a Federal Pell Grant under section 401 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 shall be reduced (but not below zero) by the amount of the expenses (other than qualified tuition and related expenses) which are taken into account in determining the cost of attendance (as defined in section 472 of the Higher Education Act of 1965, as in effect on the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Expand American Educational Opportunity Act of 2017</short-title>) of such individual at an eligible educational institution for the academic period for which the credit under this section is being determined.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF4C6DA304AA4ACB94E163DC93820F82"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Treatment of expenses paid by dependent</header><text>If a deduction under section 151 with respect to an individual is allowed to another taxpayer for a taxable year beginning in the calendar year in which such individual’s taxable year begins—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5C06B4D60BD04BE987DA4A589C190C50"><enum>(A)</enum><text>no credit shall be allowed under this section to such individual for such individual’s taxable year, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5B42C6A96AA4ABA8A96E9BB2D9159BD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>qualified tuition and related expenses paid by such individual during such individual’s taxable year shall be treated for purposes of this section as paid by such other taxpayer.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A2F533B50774FA3A39B73642DF58360"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Treatment of certain prepayments</header><text>If qualified tuition and related expenses are paid by the taxpayer during a taxable year for an academic period which begins during the first 3 months following such taxable year, such academic period shall be treated for purposes of this section as beginning during such taxable year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA46DE5BA867242259BF9092C38729A9A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Denial of double benefit</header><text>No credit shall be allowed under this section for any expense for which a deduction is allowed under any other provision of this chapter.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1A803443F5C441F7989529573E8D5FCE"><enum>(7)</enum><header>No credit for married individuals filing separate returns</header><text>If the taxpayer is a married individual (within the meaning of section 7703), this section shall apply only if the taxpayer and the taxpayer’s spouse file a joint return for the taxable year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H377FFE2968904EEC837B0BF9ABC1EDD9"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Nonresident aliens</header><text>If the taxpayer is a nonresident alien individual for any portion of the taxable year, this section shall apply only if such individual is treated as a resident alien of the United States for purposes of this chapter by reason of an election under subsection (g) or (h) of section 6013.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7CFF39B2EF064DB38377D714760B2F85"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Election not To have section apply</header><text>A taxpayer may elect not to have this section apply with respect to the qualified tuition and related expenses of an individual for any taxable year.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H94D0313E38CD48DC85EA00B6ECB5180B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text> <paragraph id="HB2418427784149C6AAE6762A048AF821"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible student</header><text>The term <term>eligible student</term> means, with respect to any taxable year, an individual who—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCE46B91021C848ACAF9A837791F69399"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is enrolled for at least one academic period which begins during such taxable year at an eligible educational institution, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H968D8899711C4BE3B8924DDDDEB59B54"><enum>(B)</enum><text>meets the requirements of section 484(a)(1) of the Higher Education Act of 1965, as in effect on the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Expand American Educational Opportunity Act of 2017</short-title>.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H123B078340FD4C10BE8B9FC0310D66A5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified tuition and related expenses</header>
 <subparagraph id="HFB9052CC4B034107B30105194016B891"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>qualified tuition and related expenses</term> means tuition, fees, and course materials required for the enrollment or attendance of—</text> <clause id="HF3568906A2EA4E2E914D1F1DC42E694A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the taxpayer,</text>
 </clause><clause id="H244BC585F2E94890977C2E6851BFFFBA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the taxpayer’s spouse, or</text> </clause><clause id="H07246F14F0374CAFAAF74AE03FC41962"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any dependent of the taxpayer with respect to whom the taxpayer is allowed a deduction under section 151,</text>
									</clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">at an eligible educational institution for courses of instruction of such individual at such
 institution.</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0E7C0E410C1428980FDEB6A58B05946"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception for education involving sports, etc</header><text>Such term does not include expenses with respect to any course or other education involving sports, games, or hobbies, unless such course or other education is part of the individual’s degree program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H24A91E3FC7014861AF3A28A9D448E811"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exception for nonacademic fees</header><text>Such term does not include student activity fees, athletic fees, insurance expenses, or other expenses unrelated to an individual’s academic course of instruction.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1FB3BF4E485B4FFDB93AAC9C827A9D9B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible educational institution</header><text>The term <term>eligible educational institution</term> means an institution—</text> <subparagraph id="H64F382CD7A48411E917F0E76B2F1ACDE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>which is described in section 481 of the Higher Education Act of 1965, as in effect on the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Expand American Educational Opportunity Act of 2017</short-title>, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H133C61D8CC63451C9B3FADA62B58F6A7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>which is eligible to participate in a program under title IV of such Act.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0CC3D19DE7454346AB108BACEE9F795B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Portion of credit refundable</header><text>The lesser of—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF58866D88C9F4527A84809924665B478"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the credit allowed under this section for a taxable year (determined after application of subsections (c)(1) and (d) and without regard to this subsection and section 26(a)(2), as the case may be), or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6560EB63CFB94DEE8348E22ED1806ABC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$1,500,</text> </paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">shall be treated as a credit allowable under subpart C (and not allowed under this section). The preceding sentence shall not apply to any taxpayer for any taxable year if such taxpayer is a child to whom subsection (g) of section 1 applies for such taxable year.</continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="HF4B2A1B044304804B3849DE3A81A40DB"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Restrictions on taxpayers who improperly claimed credit in prior year</header> <paragraph id="H4B8874A66B1340EABF40A7652C073964"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Taxpayers making prior fraudulent or reckless claims</header> <subparagraph id="HBA38C17958F54E9C8328F49564812D0B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No credit shall be allowed under this section for any taxable year in the disallowance period.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H555ACB1E9DCD4A34B93AB947B6B50A49"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Disallowance period</header><text>For purposes of clause (i), the disallowance period is—</text> <clause id="H71B54A2741234DF8870A5779F7C2391A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the period of 10 taxable years after the most recent taxable year for which there was a final determination that the taxpayer’s claim of credit under this section was due to fraud, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5392E55DE9184D2A80DF06364D479DD3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the period of 2 taxable years after the most recent taxable year for which there was a final determination that the taxpayer’s claim of credit under this section was due to reckless or intentional disregard of rules and regulations (but not due to fraud).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5093B246FDCF49D9B227553D85DA909F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Taxpayers making improper prior claims</header><text>In the case of a taxpayer who is denied credit under this section for any taxable year as a result of the deficiency procedures under subchapter B of chapter 63, no credit shall be allowed under this section for any subsequent taxable year unless the taxpayer provides such information as the Secretary may require to demonstrate eligibility for such credit.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC04D0CEAE1C6412EAEA9EC57CB93D1A9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header><text>In the case of any taxable year beginning in a calendar year after 2018, each dollar amount in subsections (b) and (c)(2), and (d)(1) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA3D0E359758F4B20821B0BD8DC922A11"><enum>(1)</enum><text>such dollar amount, multiplied by</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H889AEFD3C9D94F83844A61E315B3D81B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for the calendar year in which the taxable year begins, determined by substituting <quote>calendar year 2017</quote> for <quote>calendar year 1992</quote> in subparagraph (B) thereof.</text>
							</paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">In the case of subsections (b) and (d)(1), any increase determined under the preceding sentence
			 shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $50. In the case of subsection
			 (c)(2), any increase determined under the preceding sentence shall be
 rounded to the nearest multiple of $500.</continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="HFE09F409062B470F9CD4FA5ED89BED74"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may prescribe such regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out this section, including regulations providing for a recapture of the credit allowed under this section in cases where there is a refund in a subsequent taxable year of any amount which was taken into account in determining the amount of such credit.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H3053C0FE0EA94019A4EAD82FC54420C9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Retention of limitation</header>
 <paragraph id="HC3A589D06204400DA80501E6B48E73E9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subparagraph (D) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/25A">section 25A(b)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as in effect before the enactment of the <short-title>Expand American Educational Opportunity Act of 2017</short-title> hereby transferred to section 25A of such Code, as amended by subsection (a), and is inserted as a new subsection (d)(9) of section 25A, as so amended.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC35B0FE939D94969BDC59E2FE7DAF93E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Paragraph (9) of section 25A(d) of such Code, as transferred and inserted by paragraph (1), is amended by striking <quote>The Hope Scholarship Credit under subsection (a)(1)</quote> and inserting <quote>The credit under subsection (a)</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD32D9F91AECC42D484EC8B5E2C94CD70"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="HBFD19A6F945343B491DC5766C0FA0367"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Subparagraph (B) of section 72(t)(7) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>25A(g)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>25A(d)(3)</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HACCCC3C411E74DF093F410AA149BA5D0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Paragraph (2) of section 221(d) of such Code is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEC0E9D9891C845D48BD53EF697F518E1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>25A(g)(2)</quote> in subparagraph (B) and inserting <quote>25A(d)(3)</quote>, and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7DEE731C04C8458AADB34A91868CCE2A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>25A(f)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>25A(f)(3)</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF79256A3BE5B41FCAFB84963EEAD3444"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Paragraph (3) of section 221(d) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>25A(b)(3)</quote> and inserting <quote>25A(f)(1) (but only with respect to a student who is carrying at least <fraction>½</fraction> the normal full-time workload for the course of study the student is pursuing)</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H923752A5771341998AF3C1BD470425B0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Clause (v) of section 529(c)(3)(B) of such Code is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HF3031B4AFB20463890F5F9EDADF65DDD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>25A(g)(2)</quote> in subclause (I) and inserting <quote>25A(d)(3)</quote>, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE37EAE693150461FADA0986EC3381ED7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>HOPE AND LIFETIME LEARNING CREDITS</quote> in the heading and inserting <quote>AMERICAN OPPORTUNITY CREDIT</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H39A33B0BA8C847A3A86E64F54BA22EE5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Clause (i) of section 529(e)(3)(B) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>25A(b)(3)</quote> and inserting <quote>25A(f)(1) (but only with respect to a student who is carrying at least <fraction>½</fraction> the normal full-time workload for the course of study the student is pursuing)</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3294A5EDB9A04F34961EAAD8EF7BF93E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Subparagraph (C) of section 530(d)(2) of such Code is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HFB64E68F1E1F4EA1B0B62D8DE537886A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>25A(g)(2)</quote> in clause (i)(I) and inserting <quote>25A(d)(3)</quote>, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD44FAD5406D493CB9C27B75410380D5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>HOPE AND LIFETIME LEARNING CREDITS</quote> in the heading and inserting <quote>AMERICAN OPPORTUNITY CREDIT</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1EED6608C8814A538EFAE9D36BF88DE7"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Clause (iii) of section 530(d)(4)(B) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>25A(g)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>25A(d)(3)</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDD97CA8C041549F2BE260C616F144EC1"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Section 1400O of such Code is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H0249C06D95424158A055421898D1FB2A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>25A(f)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>25A(f)(3)</quote>,</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3AA9A365CDB420D9F5B11CB0F939565"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(as in effect on the date of the enactment of this section)</quote> after <quote>25A(b)(1)</quote> in paragraph (2), and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H434BBD463B4B4760AD84EC22C6EFB352"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(as in effect on the date of the enactment of this section)</quote> after <quote>25A(c)(1)</quote> in paragraph (3).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB58CDFD0A5DE48E3A5B71271C9D28D7D"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Subsection (e) of section 6050S of such Code is amended by striking <quote>subsection (g)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (d)(3)</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDACF1161C6934D2C95F79B4A83551CC8"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Subparagraph (A) of section 6211(b)(4) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>subsection (i)(6)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (g)</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBD99768483404F23B951D86840A92102"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Section 6213(g)(2) of such Code is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H7D29128B371E4C4D999EE0B1D504AD0D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (J), by striking <quote>25A(g)(1)</quote> and inserting <quote>25A(d)(2)</quote>, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD750BB677F1494284CC9C4D13A598C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (Q), by striking <quote>25A(i)(8)(B)</quote> and inserting <quote>25A(h)(2)</quote> and by striking <quote>25A(i)</quote> and inserting <quote>25A</quote> .</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H08B9C88EBA5549E4885B64B28EEF574B"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Subsection (g) of section 6695(g) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>25A(a)(1)</quote> and inserting <quote>25A(a)</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0B7C23B2049147408D96D6B61D9AB7DF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The item relating to section 25A in the table of sections for subpart A of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H6C5CBF09C2B24584BE474AF83859A604" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 25A. American Opportunity Tax Credit.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD4D75703327A4E4B842A6950CCCDC30A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2017.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H27BFB56FE9BD48039B0BCE2D553AC534"><enum>3.</enum><header>Expansion of pell grant exclusion from gross income</header> <subsection id="H0AE0FBE1A14044FDBA7425325672B0BB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Paragraph (1) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/117">section 117(b)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>received by an individual</quote> and all that follows and inserting</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HDFBE2401AE614266BBC6426B42FBC5FF" style="OLC">
 <text>received by an individual—</text><paragraph id="H65B405A7C5014453A9A1333CA14BE423"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as a scholarship or fellowship grant to the extent the individual establishes that, in accordance with the conditions of the grant, such amount was used for qualified tuition and related expenses, or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA8A58D5C8C464A72B85901A8ADA95A4A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>as a Federal Pell Grant under section 401 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (as in effect on the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Expand American Educational Opportunity Act of 2017</short-title>).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCAA68D0778B8427AB91262352CDA0143"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2016.</text> </subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

