<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H45EC5DFBA3FB4F4C84B1D3FF8E83AF15" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 857 IH: California Off-Road Recreation and Conservation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 857</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170203">February 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001094">Mr. Cook</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for conservation and enhanced recreation activities in the California Desert
			 Conservation Area, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HD977AC1194E14E09AF46CBD146420369" style="OLC">
		<section id="H5FC3385170B84AB683037F57C5AE1C57" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="H053BF4BCBCB2460EAE6A2D41D48595AB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>California Off-Road Recreation and Conservation Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H48C9A97EC0F4483A9CDB034E2DE8D8AB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents of this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
					<toc-entry idref="H5FC3385170B84AB683037F57C5AE1C57" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HC097C24D94CF4795B52B7E081EBD281D" level="section">Sec. 2. California Off-Road Recreation and Conservation.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H48143A7020B94EE3AB8B567D83675CDD" level="section">Sec. 3. Visitor center.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H1F71AE4BD89E47B6B7C4CA77A18A2210" level="section">Sec. 4. California State school land.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HF3FEE66C33174F43AA93F780D05F0351" level="section">Sec. 5. Designation of wild and scenic rivers.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HF7D835243BC647C5A29F7094C4D886A2" level="section">Sec. 6. Conforming amendments.</toc-entry>
				</toc>
 </subsection></section><section id="HC097C24D94CF4795B52B7E081EBD281D"><enum>2.</enum><header>California Off-Road Recreation and Conservation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Public Law 103–433 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/410aaa">16 U.S.C. 410aaa</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HEC5F59A4DAC543DFB5DAB83EB5E8C12C" style="OLC"> <title id="H6093F967164B4E59B1CA2C674C0BE28E"><enum>XIII</enum><header>WILDERNESS</header> <section id="H00BB99D8352349D6AED746DB55FF7A8F"><enum>1301.</enum><header>Designation of wilderness areas</header> <subsection id="H57B910A68B5C45E396437C77D90541BF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation of wilderness areas To be administered by the bureau of land management</header><text>In accordance with the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</external-xref> et seq.) and sections 601 and 603 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1781">43 U.S.C. 1781</external-xref>, 1782), the following land in the State is designated as wilderness areas and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System:</text>
 <paragraph id="HABB0555749B241B18DDA2935B5468ACA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Avawatz mountains wilderness</header><text>Certain land in the Conservation Area administered by the Director of the Bureau of Land Management, comprising approximately 91,800 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Avawatz Mountains Proposed Wilderness</quote> and dated June 30, 2015, to be known as the <quote>Avawatz Mountains Wilderness</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H12CB953B20FF43E1A68B68268FF6A016"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Golden valley wilderness</header><text>Certain land in the Conservation Area administered by the Director of the Bureau of Land Management, comprising approximately 1,250 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Golden Valley Proposed Wilderness Additions</quote> and dated June 22, 2015, which shall be considered to be part of the <quote>Golden Valley Wilderness</quote>.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H387620C9BBEC44309244222D6B663772"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Great falls basin wilderness</header>
 <subparagraph id="HC8464CCED59348A187F9EDCB4152A1FB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Certain land in the Conservation Area administered by the Director of the Bureau of Land Management, comprising approximately 7,870 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Great Falls Basin Proposed Wilderness</quote> and dated April 29, 2015, to be known as the <quote>Great Falls Basin Wilderness</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CF922244717425F895A35B6B7358534"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>Designation of the wilderness under subparagraph (A) shall not establish a Class I Airshed under the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7401">42 U.S.C. 7401</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B3CA831EE46432B8A6CB788199983C2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Kingston range wilderness</header><text>Certain land in the Conservation Area administered by the Bureau of Land Management, comprising approximately 53,320 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Kingston Range Proposed Wilderness Additions</quote> and dated February 18, 2015, which shall be considered to be a part of as the <quote>Kingston Range Wilderness</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB1D9F13F58FB4E509F7327C9CD80445C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Soda mountains wilderness</header><text>Certain land in the Conservation Area, administered by the Bureau of Land Management, comprising approximately 79,990 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Soda Mountains Proposed Wilderness</quote> and dated February 18, 2015, to be known as the <quote>Soda Mountains Wilderness</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H69E4954041CC4FF1958E22827C745F63"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designation of wilderness areas To be administered by the national park service</header><text>In accordance with the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</external-xref> et seq.) and sections 601 and 603 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1781">43 U.S.C. 1781</external-xref>, 1782), the following land in the State is designated as wilderness areas and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System:</text>
 <paragraph id="HFEFDB067B391457B86F7D23A463ABFB2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Death valley national park wilderness additions-north eureka valley</header><text>Certain land in the Conservation Area administered by the Director of the National Park Service, comprising approximately 11,496 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Death Valley National Park Proposed Wilderness Area-North Eureka Valley</quote>, numbered 143/100,082C, and dated October 7, 2014, which shall be considered to be a part of the Death Valley National Park Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF2C1CE3390714E8293BDADBBE674CFB1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Death valley national park wilderness additions-ibex</header><text>Certain land in the Conservation Area administered by the Director of the National Park Service, comprising approximately 23,650 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Death Valley National Park Proposed Wilderness Area-Ibex</quote>, numbered 143/100,081C, and dated October 7, 2014, which shall be considered to be a part of the Death Valley National Park Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H922F7C7BE7434F5C80D0763C64EEBC3F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Death valley national park wilderness additions-panamint valley</header><text>Certain land in the Conservation Area administered by the Director of the National Park Service, comprising approximately 4,807 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Death Valley National Park Proposed Wilderness Area-Panamint Valley</quote>, numbered 143/100,083C, and dated October 7, 2014, which shall be considered to be a part of the Death Valley National Park Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H06ADEE0F13D24A6D94DAE5A69C59EA78"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Death valley national park wilderness additions-warm springs</header><text>Certain land in the Conservation Area administered by the Director of the National Park Service, comprising approximately 10,485 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Death Valley National Park Proposed Wilderness Area-Warm Spring Canyon/Galena Canyon</quote>, numbered 143/100,084C, and dated October 7, 2014, which shall be considered to be a part of the Death Valley National Park Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H16DF3AAF27324FC48F12E913EEC2E3B4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Death valley national park wilderness additions-axe head</header><text>Certain land in the Conservation Area administered by the Director of the National Park Service, comprising approximately 8,638 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Death Valley National Park Proposed Wilderness Area-Axe Head</quote>, numbered 143/100,085C, and dated October 7, 2014, which shall be considered to be a part of the Death Valley National Park Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDF0584A6267348F98C08CFA5589B0E23"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Death valley national park wilderness additions-bowling alley</header><text>Certain land in the Conservation Area administered by the Director of the Bureau of Land Management, comprising approximately 28,923 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Death Valley National Park Proposed Wilderness Area-Bowling Alley</quote>, numbered 143/128,606, and dated May 14, 2015, which shall be considered to be a part of the Death Valley National Park Wilderness.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H03855DB1527643359DD1B7846BB47A34"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Designation of wilderness area To be administered by the forest service</header>
 <paragraph id="H23044577167C4677BCD52690A85BC8BF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In accordance with the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</external-xref> et seq.), the land in the State described in paragraph (2) is designated as a wilderness area and as a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEF63F9F123194FCF95C6255B8F463344"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Description of land</header><text>The land referred to in paragraph (1) is certain land in the San Bernardino National Forest, comprising approximately 7,141 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>San Gorgonio Proposed Wilderness Expansion,</quote> dated November 2, 2016, which shall considered to be a part of the San Gorgonio Wilderness.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H1EDAEF28790C44DAA2CA038B68C45970"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Fire management and related activities</header>
 <subparagraph id="H88AAE3EF94B74131909F3D7CC1829C7A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may carry out such activities in the wilderness area designated by paragraph (1) as are necessary for the control of fire, insects, and disease, in accordance with section 4(d)(1) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(1)</external-xref>) and House Report 98–40 of the 98th Congress.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H07E527466AAD455C8701281997700BD7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Funding priorities</header><text>Nothing in this subsection limits the provision of any funding for fire or fuel management in the wilderness area designated by paragraph (1).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE003D829AC764E71AE340661A0B70271"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Revision and development of local fire management plans</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this title, the Secretary shall amend the local fire management plans that apply to the wilderness area designated by paragraph (1).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H205A68CB8D12427A86648EAEDCBA8ECF"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>In accordance with subparagraph (A) and other applicable Federal law, to ensure a timely and efficient response to fire emergencies in the wilderness area designated by paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</text>
 <clause id="H6A7CD9C762B04C418C16715C10B81D35"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this title, establish agency approval procedures (including appropriate delegations of authority to the Forest Supervisor, District Manager, or other agency officials) for responding to fire emergencies in the wilderness area designated by paragraph (1); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H06337A9A9A8A45F8AF19E0E36740C952"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>enter into agreements with appropriate State or local firefighting agencies relating to that wilderness area.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB8720BBF9670497888FE38F7172791C8"><enum>1302.</enum><header>Management</header>
						<subsection id="H6CF00A8168B042278A0EE8FBDDCDAF94"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Adjacent management</header>
 <paragraph id="H182DA9CD8685442CB997BF8F8D79ECE1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in this title creates any protective perimeter or buffer zone around the wilderness areas designated by section 1301.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H79BBF98218D74B5D96E9ED8125666807"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Activities outside wilderness areas</header>
 <subparagraph id="HD8FBF7EA5A3E43939E71EA21A4012E78"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The fact that an activity (including military activities) or use on land outside a wilderness area designated by section 1301 can be seen or heard within the wilderness area shall not preclude or restrict the activity or use outside the boundary of the wilderness area.</text>
								</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEAA8D3C964C74A5381D90165E251BD34"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effect on nonwilderness activities</header>
 <clause id="HCADD3B3525C54CEA9C20E3F60D66206A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In any permitting proceeding (including a review under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.)) conducted with respect to a project described in clause (ii) that is formally initiated through a notice in the Federal Register before December 31, 2013, the consideration of any visual, noise, or other impacts of the project on a wilderness area designated by section 1301 shall be conducted based on the status of the area before designation as wilderness.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4CFCA37325CD4AE7BE7A2A74F8ED3CDF"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Description of projects</header><text>A project referred to in clause (i) is a renewable energy project or associated energy transport facility project—</text>
 <subclause id="HEF25D1254A5246098EA5F7BC984D8A71"><enum>(I)</enum><text>for which the Bureau of Land Management has received a right-of-way use application on or before the date of enactment of this title; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H453F8D2ECF4A4EDDB63DD07BE66B7F1A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>that is located outside the boundary of a wilderness area designated by section 1301.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6DD6B23D91A94154A875B2F9359DBDFC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>No additional regulation</header><text>Nothing in this title requires additional regulation of activities on land outside the boundary of the wilderness areas.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE2BE87B9871A4F74B64703ADA1624CD1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Effect on military operations</header><text>Nothing in this title alters any authority of the Secretary of Defense to conduct any military operations at desert installations, facilities, and ranges of the State that are authorized under any other provision of law.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="HDD60CC5797E241488C30E544A5118D12"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Effect on utility facilities and rights-of-way</header>
 <subparagraph id="HBAB5859EAB614DA88167D01D4C2C6F25"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), nothing in this title terminates or precludes the renewal or reauthorization of any valid existing right-of-way or customary operation, maintenance, repair, upgrading, or replacement activities in a right-of-way, issued, granted, or permitted to the Southern California Edison Company or predecessors, successors, or assigns of the Southern California Edison Company that is located on land included in the San Gorgonio Wilderness Area or the Sand to Snow National Monument.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B1E3FD5C7624EFC8A0D8F6F4363596C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The activities described in subparagraph (A) shall be conducted in a manner that minimizes the impact of the activities resources of the San Gorgonio Wilderness Area or the Sand to Snow National Monument.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8BBA50CEF7E4CD3BB3BEA35E22451BE"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Applicable law</header><text>In accordance with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.), any approval required for an increase in the voltage of the Coachella distribution circuit shall require consideration of alternative alignments, including alignments adjacent to State Route 62.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9C896F1DFBD443D0875C907B8806E33D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Maps; legal descriptions</header>
 <paragraph id="HD17B13D66E0547BF9929C48D965E51EF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this title, the Secretary shall file a map and legal description of each wilderness area and wilderness addition designated by section 1301 with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H12F018E6610D43B782D2F225B9342972"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H250EEFA7F72446BEA94148B28FE7E6A8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E961F7097FF4B78816DF8F05CF881D0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Force of law</header><text>A map and legal description filed under paragraph (1) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this title, except that the Secretary may correct errors in the maps and legal descriptions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3261A90B39AE429BBCD1C8928EBF1165"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>Each map and legal description filed under paragraph (1) shall be filed and made available for public inspection in the appropriate office of the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H149798C909F04952AD1DB8336AE29152"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the land designated as wilderness or as a wilderness addition by section 1301 shall be administered by the Secretary in accordance with this Act and the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</external-xref> et seq.), except that any reference in that Act to the effective date shall be considered to be a reference to the date of enactment of this title.</text>
						</subsection></section><section id="H525BC5DE77134D27851352809042B1E3"><enum>1303.</enum><header>Release of wilderness study areas</header>
 <subsection id="H8BFA9F8972E04097835AB6EAA9DE3F04"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Finding</header><text>Congress finds that, for purposes of section 603 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1782">43 U.S.C. 1782</external-xref>), any portion of a wilderness study area described in subsection (b) that is not designated as a wilderness area or wilderness addition by section 1301 or any other Act enacted before the date of enactment of this title has been adequately studied for wilderness.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H961E78A2CF0B45B38C14AA9D85E3BA90"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Description of study areas</header><text>The study areas referred to in subsection (a) are—</text> <paragraph id="HB82E229BCACA4658AFBBF90D0B53E9D0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Cady Mountains Wilderness Study Area;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA3598A705D324126BA9FED2ADCBE9CF1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Kingston Range Wilderness Study Area;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H63EB9C4A24B24722B9D0CF812BBB7831"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Avawatz Mountain Wilderness Study Area;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE404F25061B447A7B3517479C022D866"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Death Valley National Park Boundary and Wilderness 17 Wilderness Study Area;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE6E02EACEDF747898F8AA10F320FA828"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Great Falls Basin Wilderness Study Area; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF5574C2381A64209AB965E4C0D46E95E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the Soda Mountains Wilderness Study Area.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1CC3E51262BC47BC85929271B193C4D2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Release</header><text>Any portion of a wilderness study area described in subsection (b) that is not designated as a wilderness area or wilderness addition by section 1301 is no longer subject to section 603(c) of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1782">43 U.S.C. 1782(c)</external-xref>).</text>
						</subsection></section><section id="H6B882C46C38F40F1AFB4883260C283AD"><enum>1304.</enum><header>Treatment of cherry-Stemmed roads</header>
 <subsection id="HC38AA50127EB4742B12F1A4DC07E9A07"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of cherry-Stemmed road</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>cherry-stemmed road</quote> means a road or trail that is excluded from a wilderness area or wilderness addition designated by section 202 by a non-wilderness corridor having designated wilderness on both sides, as generally depicted on the maps described in such section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA04C1BDEC2DE46CEB2716123A6B34D94"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on closure or travel restrictions on cherry-Stemmed roads</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall not—</text> <paragraph id="H0927991DE43343AF94810B718B5FE254"><enum>(1)</enum><text>close any cherry-stemmed road that is open to the public as of the date of the enactment of this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8DA3ADCC8C6B4B0D9C0ED4887B283187"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prohibit motorized access on a cherry-stemmed road that is open to the public for motorized access as of the date of the enactment of this Act; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1CB02D7A74384EA6BC0F2E15637D93E7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>prohibit mechanized access on a cherry-stemmed road that is open to the public for mechanized access as of the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAC9667B020614C97A1B5039B60013970"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Resource protection or public safety exceptions</header><text>Subsection (b) shall not apply to a cherry-stemmed road if the Secretary concerned determines that a closure or traffic restriction of the cherry-stemmed road is necessary for purposes of significant resource protection or public safety.</text>
						</subsection></section></title><title id="HB012E4EEC75847218A83FD6B9BBDA196"><enum>XIV</enum><header>NATIONAL PARK SYSTEM ADDITIONS</header>
					<section id="HD5A516980160478587434CFCF2ED0462"><enum>1401.</enum><header>Death valley national park boundary revision</header>
 <subsection id="HE201705DD5CC4C1899CC25D80298B129"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The boundary of Death Valley National Park is adjusted to include—</text> <paragraph id="HE434394126FA4BF4832CC289EA50F0DE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the approximately 28,923 acres of Bureau of Land Management land in Inyo County, California, abutting the southern end of the Death Valley National Park that lies between Death Valley National Park to the north and Ft. Irwin Military Reservation to the south and which runs approximately 34 miles from west to east, as depicted on the map entitled <quote>Death Valley National Park Proposed Boundary Addition-Bowling Alley</quote>, numbered 143/128,605, and dated May 14, 2015; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAECEB7D1CB9C467186AB9E642DAB29A9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the approximately 6,369 acres of Bureau of Land Management land in Inyo County, California, located in the northeast area of Death Valley National Park that is within, and surrounded by, land under the jurisdiction of the Director of the National Park Service, as depicted on the map entitled <quote>Death Valley National Park Proposed Boundary Addition-Crater</quote>, numbered 143/100,079C, and dated October 7, 2014.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE801599AD8B14F7AB55241C6C92EB81C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability of map</header><text>The maps described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA48A9BE98C714A348A68E151191FE6DB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior (referred to in this title as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall—</text> <paragraph id="H5C53A00D01364528BA44A1E937AD0D18"><enum>(1)</enum><text>administer any land added to Death Valley National Park under subsection (a)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6D95F35E3C4F442399628C1249DB834A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as part of Death Valley National Park; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50358EC40E834EE38452C56BFDB4032A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in accordance with applicable laws (including regulations); and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC10B44ABB2C4BD291C94F50EE3A8E2A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, enter into a memorandum of understanding with Inyo County, California, to permit operationally feasible, ongoing access and use (including, but not limited to, material storage as well as excavation) to gravel pits in existence as of that date along Saline Valley Road within Death Valley National Park for road maintenance and repairs in accordance with applicable laws (including regulations).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3F40318837AD4E5BA64A3E2A756A0543"><enum>1402.</enum><header>Mojave national preserve</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The boundary of the Mojave National Preserve is adjusted to include the 25 acres of Bureau of Land Management land in Baker, California, as depicted on the map entitled <quote>Mojave National Preserve Proposed Boundary Addition</quote>, numbered 170/100,199, and dated August 2009.</text>
					</section><section id="HB2039D585320406CA4C5C583542CEFD3"><enum>1403.</enum><header>Joshua tree national park boundary revision</header>
 <subsection id="HBD7EC91947B1446FBCD494F6FA6F5D43"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The boundary of the Joshua Tree National Park is adjusted to include—</text> <paragraph id="HA2C5C0DA90E142728DFADE96FFE7BA8C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the 2,879 acres of land managed by Director of the Bureau of Land Management that are contiguous at several different places to the northern boundaries of Joshua Tree National Park in the northwest section of the Park, as depicted on the map entitled <quote>Joshua Tree National Park Proposed Boundary Additions</quote>, numbered 156/100,077, and dated August 2009; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFCD8B8EBA315446B8986E2736D6AF77E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the 1,639 acres of land to be acquired from the Mojave Desert Land Trust that are contiguous at several different places to the northern boundaries of Joshua Tree National Park in the northwest section of the Park, as depicted on the map entitled <quote>Mojave Desert Land Trust National Park Service Additions</quote>, numbered 156/126,376, and dated September 2014.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6295FE7A32204E54921C6D3FB8A8DB50"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability of maps</header><text>The map described in subsection (a) and the map depicting the 25 acres described in subsection (c)(2) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H410E1F0E565A4DF1874B45102B242FBE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administration</header>
 <paragraph id="H10D6E04D569048A5B5F0BBFFA0B6B4E3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall administer any land added to the Joshua Tree National Park under subsection (a) and the additional land described in paragraph (2)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H46896A81C0CF45D0A0DE739D96917F0D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as part of Joshua Tree National Park; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23F215603E414EC586DA9C1AEACB1BF8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in accordance with applicable laws (including regulations).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCAF2E587A6924EC8860EAF4B18BA20F4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Description of additional land</header><text>The additional land referred to in paragraph (1) is the 25 acres of land—</text> <subparagraph id="H75627EE997DC453481D849811AFF8B9C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>depicted on the map entitled <quote>Joshua Tree National Park Boundary Adjustment Map</quote>, numbered 156/80,049, and dated April 1, 2003;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C713548DA014B12AA475DCCF64FC97D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>added to Joshua Tree National Park by the notice of the Department of the Interior of August 28, 2003 (68 Fed. Reg. 51799); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BA91D97EBFA420F8F47A25CB23C6942"><enum>(C)</enum><text>more particularly described as lots 26, 27, 28, 33, and 34 in sec. 34, T. 1 N., R. 8 E., San Bernardino Meridian.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5F48725F357E4EFEA304DED2DD55E935"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Southern california edison company energy transport facilities and rights-of-Way</header>
 <paragraph id="HA766CBFFD2ED482E9994960DC492352D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in this title terminates any valid right-of-way for the customary operation, maintenance, upgrade, repair, relocation within an existing right-of-way, replacement, or other authorized energy transport facility activities in a right-of-way issued, granted, or permitted to the Southern California Edison Company or the predecessors, successors, or assigns of the Southern California Edison Company that is located on land described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a), including, at a minimum, the use of mechanized vehicles, helicopters, or other aerial devices.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H58D83EBB79784A05B174DCBB27E6C167"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Upgrades and replacements</header><text>Nothing in this title prohibits the upgrading or replacement of—</text> <subparagraph id="H43ABC2AAF8C34E3EB0D57621ADA34882"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Southern California Edison Company energy transport facilities, including the energy transport facilities referred to as the Jellystone, Burnt Mountain, Whitehorn, Allegra, and Utah distribution circuits rights-of-way; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H455E776E5AC342DEB6B470DF9EB2A881"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an energy transport facility in rights-of-way issued, granted, or permitted by the Secretary adjacent to Southern California Edison Joshua Tree Utility Facilities.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H08F50D89F5A74CA2BDF3DE0852AC08C5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Publication of plans</header><text>Not later than the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of this title or the issuance of a new energy transport facility right-of-way within the Joshua Tree National Park, whichever is earlier, the Secretary, in consultation with the Southern California Edison Company, shall publish plans for regular and emergency access by the Southern California Edison Company to the rights-of-way of the Southern California Edison Company within Joshua Tree National Park.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="H8154AF23E4C046BAAF23FEA172DF20B7"><enum>XV</enum><header>NATIONAL OFF-HIGHWAY VEHICLE RECREATION AREAS</header>
					<section id="HD9D92D4D04444836A2615B410A8DA53A"><enum>1501.</enum><header>Designation of national off-highway vehicle recreation areas</header>
 <subsection id="HB558036286F54AC3A29315B54FE797B1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In accordance with the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.) and resource management plans developed under this title and subject to valid rights, the following land within the Conservation Area in San Bernardino County, California, is designated as National Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Areas:</text>
 <paragraph id="H922E84C7389445488A06B3D475533B31"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Dumont dunes national off-highway vehicle recreation area</header><text>Certain Bureau of Land Management land in the Conservation Area, comprising approximately 7,630 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Dumont Dunes Proposed National OHV Recreation Area</quote> and dated June 29, 2015, which shall be known as the <quote>Dumont Dunes National Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6C9D6E6DB57440F59CB861EAF53D6666"><enum>(2)</enum><header>El mirage national off-highway vehicle recreation area</header><text>Certain Bureau of Land Management land in the Conservation Area, comprising approximately 14,930 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>El Mirage Proposed National OHV Recreation Area</quote> and dated January 4, 2017, which shall be known as the <quote>El Mirage National Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAECE52DAFC0E4C24BAF8CA7D94B1C431"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rasor national off-highway vehicle recreation area</header><text>Certain Bureau of Land Management land in the Conservation Area, comprising approximately 23,910 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Rasor Proposed National OHV Recreation Area</quote> and dated February 15, 2015, which shall be known as the <quote>Rasor National Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE7B3DA038E0248C68FF2BD5CA0D022EB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Spangler hills national off-highway vehicle recreation area</header><text>Certain Bureau of Land Management land in the Conservation Area, comprising approximately 56,140 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Spangler Hills Proposed National OHV Recreation Area</quote> and dated January 4, 2017, which shall be known as the <quote>Spangler Hills National Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H96E71C0FCD75423B8CDF0155998AC690"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Stoddard valley national off-highway vehicle recreation area</header><text>Certain Bureau of Land Management land in the Conservation Area, comprising approximately 40,110 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Stoddard Valley Proposed National OHV Recreation Area</quote> and dated February 18, 2015, which shall be known as the <quote>Stoddard Valley National Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area</quote>.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFAF4718DBF7D4FADB86D5B53EA60C56E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Redesignation and expansion of johnson valley national off-Highway vehicle recreation area</header>
 <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H03A4E14B1B574D248E8881C5F2F4714C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Redesignation</header><text>The Johnson Valley Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area designated by section 2945 of the Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014 (division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/66">Public Law 113–66</external-xref>; 127 Stat. 1038)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFCF04D9F14094AC9AB79CCF1F1381884"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is hereby redesignated as the Johnson Valley National Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67DECDA11418474CB7F795773B76813C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is expanded to include all of the land, approximately 11,300 acres, depicted as the <quote>Proposed Johnson Valley National Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area Additions</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Johnson Valley National Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area</quote> and dated November 30, 2016.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7B1BAA5CC8B437F99BAB36D61849F96"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Relation to authorized navy use</header><text>The redesignation of the Johnson Valley Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area as the Johnson Valley National Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area does not alter or interfere with the rights and obligations of the Navy regarding the use of portions of the Recreation Area as provided in subtitle C of title XXIX of the Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014 (division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/66">Public Law 113–66</external-xref>; 127 Stat. 1034).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H180496782B104141AD40E27DA183F3FD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>References</header><text>Any reference in any law, regulation, document, record, map, or other paper of the United States to the Johnson Valley Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area is deemed to be a reference to the Johnson Valley National Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB58B5B7845034583821E176152398770"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purpose of the national off-highway vehicle recreation areas designated under subsections (a) and (b) is to preserve and enhance the recreational opportunities within the Conservation Area (including opportunities for off-highway vehicle recreation), while conserving the wildlife and other natural resource values of the Conservation Area.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="HC7CADA97EB1043FCB54122884CB50EE0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Maps and descriptions</header>
 <paragraph id="HE5321479B4A549FE87D5C488ADAED288"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Preparation and submission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this title, the Secretary shall file a map and legal description of each national off-highway vehicle recreation area designated or expanded by subsections (a) or (b) with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4033AD6F50364515ABEA8807D43FE9FA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B1EAA913F754A178325A887754E8CE0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H014FEBFD59194876BD406CFA73A9D0C7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Legal effect</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The map and legal descriptions of the national off-highway vehicle recreation areas filed under paragraph (1) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this title, except that the Secretary may correct errors in the map and legal descriptions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA4421F6DB142481886D328ECBF544B37"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>Each map and legal description filed under paragraph (1) shall be filed and made available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Bureau of Land Management.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1728007DAD484FCB9EE663A41DB9C57F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of the land</header>
							<paragraph id="H16682660F9024903A1D05ED996550489"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Recreational activities</header>
 <subparagraph id="HFFA50B183ECA4905A86B7A9CF972B4ED"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall continue to authorize, maintain, and enhance the recreational uses of the national off-highway vehicle recreation areas designated or expanded by subsections (a) and (b), including off-highway recreation, hiking, camping, hunting, mountain biking, sightseeing, rockhounding, and horseback riding, as long as the recreational use is consistent with this section and any other applicable law.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H46C15287469E44078C28806E764A6F2C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Off-highway vehicle and off-highway recreation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent consistent with applicable Federal law (including regulations) and this section, any authorized recreation activities and use designations in effect on the date of enactment of this title and applicable to the national off-highway vehicle recreation areas designated or expanded by subsections (a) and (b) shall continue, including casual off-highway vehicular use, racing, competitive events, rock crawling, training, and other forms of off-highway recreation.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E8E5FCA715F4C3DA42C14BC710F0A5F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Wildlife guzzlers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Wildlife guzzlers shall be allowed in the national off-highway vehicle recreation areas designated by subsection (a) in accordance with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD0D4FBB7EDB04FC9B8E20CBEFEEC7FAF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>applicable Bureau of Land Management guidelines; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HADF8E50231C94B5980AE5EC1217AA313"><enum>(B)</enum><text>State law.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7BD97A4636A340F6B3F8656D49C0AB4D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibited uses</header>
 <subparagraph id="H26C34E02D1B94B50925AB42A471DF02A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Commercial development (including development of energy facilities, but excluding energy transport facilities, rights-of-way, and related telecommunication facilities) shall be prohibited in the national off-highway vehicle recreation areas designated by subsections (a) and (b) if the Secretary determines that the development is incompatible with the purpose of this title.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H54E263C625DF4F06807167273179F6AB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception for temporary permitted vendors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (A) does not prohibit a commercial vendor from establishing, pursuant to a temporary permit, a site in the national off-highway vehicle recreation areas for the purpose of providing accessories and other support for off-highway vehicles and vehicles used for accessing the area.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAA206789C6D8499DB69F010C51FD5348"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Administration</header>
 <paragraph id="H9284F663F1A845E284A6C849165CE4C6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall administer the national off-highway vehicle recreation areas designated by subsections (a) and (b) in accordance with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H406ADD903B6743B38496EEC29CDEFB24"><enum>(A)</enum><text>this title;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC34707F763D74F9584C6DFC74828EB36"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA54E3D27136642609D82F942F4E95398"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other applicable laws (including regulations).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H520A402010F94D6E93596C947AED8B52"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Management plan</header> <subparagraph id="H3D9E3F9858584626ABE1A0C4720F7FE4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable, but not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this title, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <clause id="H8B857C96BCF54186B8AA422839B98D11"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">amend existing resource management plans applicable to the land designated as national off-highway vehicle recreation areas under subsection (a); or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3DD54DC733B14C68882571738A72235B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop new management plans for each national off-highway vehicle recreation area designated under that subsection.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB50D2900684413CB0D80033333AC939"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>All new or amended plans under subparagraph (A) shall be designed to preserve and enhance safe off-highway vehicle and other recreational opportunities within the applicable recreation area consistent with—</text>
 <clause id="H113B1D471700409E97C93818F1EF0543"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the purpose described in subsection (c); and</text> </clause><clause id="HD9C0CAE7F2134DAC80DFC7EF0F07852C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any applicable laws (including regulations).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5176488B0DD1480698896E2EEEC71113"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Interim plans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pending completion of a new management plan under subparagraph (A), the existing resource management plans shall govern the use of the applicable national off-highway vehicle recreation area.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF6F5F3B162D7454A98E5B0C30C044A22"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Study</header>
 <paragraph id="H5D16083037624C74BB8A35A4D8CC22CE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable, but not later than 2 years, after the date of enactment of this title, the Secretary shall complete a study to identify Bureau of Land Management land within the Conservation Area that is suitable for addition to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5DE25200507741B0BA66A6CA292619DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the national off-highway vehicle recreation areas designated by subsection (a) and (b); or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72949BCD077947E095ABF64776A121A7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Johnson Valley National Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area designated by section 2945 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/66">Public Law 113–66</external-xref>; 127 Stat. 1038).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFEAD1F2585CB4ACF812C3CDBF44C54CB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Study areas</header><text>The study required under paragraph (1) shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="H306F1FBB66864CA5A817808BC1B3DFEC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>certain Bureau of Land Management land in the Conservation Area, comprising approximately 41,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Spangler Hills Proposed National OHV Recreation Area</quote> and dated January 4, 2017; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55E5CE4967CF403BA28EA632BCB270F3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>certain Bureau of Land Management land in the Conservation Area, comprising approximately 680 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>El Mirage Proposed National OHV Recreation Area</quote> and dated January 21, 2017.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5476EEAFD05E4986BA205ED5941AABDA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>certain Bureau of Land Management land in the Conservation Area, comprising approximately 10,300 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Johnson Valley National Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area</quote> and dated November 30, 2016.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H66F8BDED002F4FA796594F8A4423C794"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In preparing the study under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H2DF0F077155E4BC6823CE8873553C280"><enum>(A)</enum><text>seek input from stakeholders, including—</text>
 <clause id="H1CCC5AC174A9427A991EDF6C658CCA85"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the State, including—</text> <subclause id="HFB4D7AE7053742FE88C13F65056B6EC8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the California Public Utilities Commission; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H4C764A401FCA496A969619E19FC4F890"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the California Energy Commission;</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HF05598D59AFA4ADB93FA8F460307B4E2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>San Bernardino County, California;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H30E97D39878C49D18CB1FC18BE406CA2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the public;</text> </clause><clause id="HDB3E5576FB5B450EB014A94C0F3837EE"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>recreational user groups;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H33966A7E6D6149549BB8AB3C8813E70D"><enum>(v)</enum><text>conservation organizations;</text> </clause><clause id="H8927E16F09F248D7854C96D55BEA7A80"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the Southern California Edison Company;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB11CBED7B671492596D5EF7E1F8E4814"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the Pacific Gas and Electric Company; and</text> </clause><clause id="HB70372535A3A49E0AB99BA8390BC1DFA"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>other Federal agencies, including the Department of Defense;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H99AAD6E6A28D45A7857AD46BEDF4C466"><enum>(B)</enum><text>explore the feasibility of—</text> <clause id="H40802015B73B4D349B22164904EE44D9"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expanding the southern boundary of the national off-highway vehicle recreation area described in subsection (a)(3) to include previously disturbed land; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0ED23A5931B34C889ADB9B69650CB2D6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishing a right of way for OHV use in the area identified in (g)(2), to the extent necessary to connect the non-contiguous areas of the Johnson Valley National Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21BA1C8C34D84219AF5378AB146BC0C5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identify and exclude from consideration any land that—</text> <clause id="H1B000151D39E4E18B77113B4393BF5D2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is managed for conservation purposes;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H67E0398B35EE4EC0AA07F8BAF03D5E1D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is identified as critical habitat for a listed species;</text> </clause><clause id="H5A0C27ADE0EC4DEF8FC680359B0C5E0D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>may be suitable for renewable energy development; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE0930BFC969041DCAE9E0585564AD2BC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>may be necessary for energy transmission; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD21A075AB87E45D3BA32323A7A87809F"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not recommend or approve expansion of national off-highway vehicle recreation areas within the Conservation Area that collectively would exceed the total acres administratively designated for off-highway recreation within the Conservation Area as of the day before the date of enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/66">Public Law 113–66</external-xref>; 127 Stat. 672).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7619BF4297014FC698ED3072F89E704A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Applicable law</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall consider the information and recommendations of the study completed under paragraph (1) to determine the impacts of expanding national off-highway vehicle recreation areas designated by subsection (a) on the Conservation Area, in accordance with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD87AF2096FFF4440BBDB93FD8E7E1213"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6A0D6A74B7B4B15A027283F2D42C19E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531</external-xref> et seq.);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3B27328F8544519A61228C0822F95EF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>applicable regulations and plans, including the Desert Renewable Energy Conservation Plan Land Use Plan Amendment; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB1BD63FF4B9C4147AA1DEF998BBDF188"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other applicable law.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H688F8DAFAB074077B970B18CCC69FAC5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Submission to congress</header><text>On completion of the study under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall submit the study to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0AA36A8318114F3E8984BD57798136A0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA1358D1800D45F7863032B45988EC5D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3752C3B0421A49D4B91B377EBEE0884E"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Authorization for expansion</header>
 <subparagraph id="H8A92C98F20A34445BE72956F234A46DE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On completion of the study under paragraph (1) and in accordance with all applicable laws (including regulations), the Secretary shall authorize the expansion of the national off-highway vehicle recreation areas recommended under the study.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBFFB59B06B9E4488A1FEF82E8DB11738"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Management</header><text>Any land within the expanded areas under subparagraph (A) shall be managed in accordance with this section.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA1DC45E9BC4B4C4F9EB042C704E529C9"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Southern california edison company utility facilities and rights-of-Way</header>
 <paragraph id="H7226656D0BB2417CAF4689B608F735D0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Effect of title</header><text>Nothing in this title—</text> <subparagraph id="HEFCC607DFE3D418C9706D871698F86F9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>terminates any validly issued right-of-way for the customary operation, maintenance, upgrade, repair, relocation within an existing right-of-way, replacement, or other authorized energy transport facility activities (including the use of any mechanized vehicle, helicopter, and other aerial device) in a right-of-way issued, granted, or permitted to Southern California Edison Company (including any predecessor or successor in interest or assign) that is located on land included in—</text>
 <clause id="H5908935602DF44CEAA8C20FB420A246C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the El Mirage National Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area;</text> </clause><clause id="HF68B84ED65314B9491F701E56F0EED86"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Spangler Hills National Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF4479EDE587A42DB87EEE0F3AD96BD29"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Stoddard Valley National Off Highway Vehicle Recreation Area;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8CE7548019BD458EBFF1AFE0CCA23A32"><enum>(B)</enum><text>affects the application, siting, route selection, right-of-way acquisition, or construction of the Coolwater-Lugo transmission project, as may be approved by the California Public Utilities Commission and the Bureau of Land Management; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE915749BF4DE4007B83A449B20926B1C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>prohibits the upgrading or replacement of any Southern California Edison Company—</text> <clause id="HAEBAF768BE03439FBAAE2D84F956EF26"><enum>(i)</enum><text>utility facility, including such a utility facility known on the date of enactment of this title as—</text>
 <subclause id="HD70CE566EC064C5983A6067A70A6F4AE"><enum>(I)</enum><text><quote>Gale-PS 512 transmission lines or rights-of-way</quote>; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HA26EFCE4797945F5AE5A9F4032A8BCC7"><enum>(II)</enum><text><quote>Patio, Jack Ranch, and Kenworth distribution circuits or rights-of-way</quote>; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H0932FB5CBFE54D3DA89C09562A94076C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>energy transport facility in a right-of-way issued, granted, or permitted by the Secretary adjacent to a utility facility referred to in clause (i).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F7CBD278C704E23AF599DF77C3CC89B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Plans for access</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Southern California Edison Company, shall publish plans for regular and emergency access by the Southern California Edison Company to the rights-of-way of the Company by the date that is 1 year after the later of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7B86F8476BF34EB9ADA5481A4E5736DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the date of enactment of this title; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10080FBD18F5483F9C719BDD2D203421"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date of issuance of a new energy transport facility right-of-way within—</text>
 <clause id="HC22A47B7BB2147BB86F400CEBDB4F04F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the El Mirage National Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area;</text> </clause><clause id="HCA27207D604E4174A6FCC1F47C50887B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Spangler Hills National Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF2D945D1CF204B08ABFDEC4A604907E0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Stoddard Valley National Off Highway Vehicle Recreation Area.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB8CBC28CCF0C440EB5E3F3CB9BA249A4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Pacific gas and electric company utility facilities and rights-of-Way</header> <paragraph id="HE8EEA8893A5A4B1A954F29F2E93170C0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Effect of title</header><text>Nothing in this title—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8BA06FE22A5A482CA5BA450468361C45"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">terminates any validly issued right-of-way for the customary operation, maintenance, upgrade, repair, relocation within an existing right-of-way, replacement, or other authorized activity (including the use of any mechanized vehicle, helicopter, and other aerial device) in a right-of-way issued, granted, or permitted to Pacific Gas and Electric Company (including any predecessor or successor in interest or assign) that is located on land included in the Spangler Hills National Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D439EB63B9B4EB4B47453D39D9330AD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prohibits the upgrading or replacement of any—</text> <clause id="H43BB466ECDC7453A9419958F60BA5BFD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>utility facilities of the Pacific Gas and Electric Company, including those utility facilities known on the date of enactment of this title as—</text>
 <subclause id="H145A5D37C4FA40A3B67FD726C7480A9E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Gas Transmission Line 311 or rights-of-way; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H59C31DF816604C9C9E5509A8FDFBA2B2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Gas Transmission Line 372 or rights-of-way; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HE6F2647EE28D44A095643ED290BC9751"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>utility facilities of the Pacific Gas and Electric Company in rights-of-way issued, granted, or permitted by the Secretary adjacent to a utility facility referred to in clause (i).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F09986D2CD94CB8A770AE889EFD2ABA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Plans for access</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this title or the issuance of a new utility facility right-of-way within the Spangler Hills National Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area, whichever is later, the Secretary, in consultation with the Pacific Gas and Electric Company, shall publish plans for regular and emergency access by the Pacific Gas and Electric Company to the rights-of-way of the Pacific Gas and Electric Company.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="H9460987B080F4E9B9C0A228441C22B08"><enum>XVI</enum><header>ALABAMA HILLS NATIONAL SCENIC AREA</header>
 <section id="H57692D45A0E94A9298799E2CB0E7C1C0"><enum>1601.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text> <paragraph id="HE67CDBA5330E4B278CC80884321AFFF4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Management plan</header><text>The term <quote>management plan</quote> means the management plan for the National Scenic Area developed under section 1603(a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4A179A2B72B444CD923B695B6DF2943C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Map</header><text>The term <quote>Map</quote> means the map titled <quote>Proposed Alabama Hills National Scenic Area</quote>, dated September 8, 2014.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9D1F9FF332814B92A2C2A675D37B8CCC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Motorized vehicles</header><text>The term <quote>motorized vehicles</quote> means motorized or mechanized vehicles and includes, when used by utilities, mechanized equipment, helicopters, and other aerial devices necessary to maintain electrical or communications infrastructure.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H87671D616D194DA78BF97B94C7BDD046"><enum>(4)</enum><header>National scenic area</header><text>The term <quote>National Scenic Area</quote> means the Alabama Hills National Scenic Area established by section 1602(a).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDA3C2D7A7E00491EA32F8450AB78ACD1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1709951D471F4F22A0B33E79D3AF50C1"><enum>(6)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> means the State of California.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H18E43DB6A4E24E23BA7ECF29F2C502DC"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Tribe</header><text>The term <quote>Tribe</quote> means the Lone Pine Paiute-Shoshone.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDC2EFC17A2A64ECE9E2BC627F12EF0E0"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Utility facility</header><text>The term <quote>utility facility</quote> means any and all existing and future water system facilities including aqueducts, streams, ditches, and canals; water facilities including, but not limited to, flow measuring stations, gauges, gates, values, piping, conduits, fencing, and electrical power and communications devices and systems; and any and all existing and future electric generation facilities, electric storage facilities, overhead and/or underground electrical supply systems and communication systems consisting of electric substations, electric lines, poles and towers made of various materials, <quote>H</quote> frame structures, guy wires and anchors, crossarms, wires, underground conduits, cables, vaults, manholes, handholes, above-ground enclosures, markers and concrete pads and other fixtures, appliances and communication circuits, and other fixtures, appliances and appurtenances connected therewith necessary or convenient for the construction, operation, regulation, control, grounding and maintenance of electric generation, storage, lines and communication circuits, for the purpose of transmitting intelligence and generating, storing, distributing, regulating and controlling electric energy to be used for light, heat, power, communication, and other purposes.</text>
						</paragraph></section><section id="HB48AF45CEC684BF192BAA4CC644F285A"><enum>1602.</enum><header>Alabama hills national scenic area, california</header>
 <subsection id="HB0D3C670D4BF43F79434A598B44F0EBC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Subject to valid, existing rights, there is established in Inyo County, California, the Alabama Hills National Scenic Area. The National Scenic Area shall be comprised of the approximately 18,610 acres generally depicted on the Map as <quote>National Scenic Area</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H97A57F449C194F658DF99B61DA0BF558"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the National Scenic Area is to conserve, protect, and enhance for the benefit, use, and enjoyment of present and future generations the nationally significant scenic, cultural, geological, educational, biological, historical, recreational, cinematographic, and scientific resources of the National Scenic Area managed consistent with section 302(a) of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1732">43 U.S.C. 1732(a)</external-xref>).</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H34F61BA3B4064A73980986D24DA47AD2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Map; legal descriptions</header>
 <paragraph id="HDADFF2159A664E7A8A1CF48A54A938A3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall file a map and a legal description of the National Scenic Area with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF12D28A7FA5F4E7AB15EFC54567D7798"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8BD6A3488D724CEA807308F5FF15BB4D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4E4886A8ACA4999AAFADA8FB11DDA61"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Force of law</header><text>The map and legal descriptions filed under paragraph (1) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act, except that the Secretary may correct any clerical and typographical errors in the map and legal descriptions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1535C52EE369498B9E26BA5CB4BDEBFC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>Each map and legal description filed under paragraph (1) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Forest Service and Bureau of Land Management.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC27F18EE7DFB4B79A0FFC1B044905DC7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The Secretary shall manage the National Scenic Area—</text> <paragraph id="HBA04F6B9D39647BD9F36E3A8143E215B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as a component of the National Landscape Conservation System;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0F483553DE834B5FBEF56F4BEF19DFAA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>so as not to impact the future continuing operations and maintenance of any activities associated with valid, existing rights, including water rights;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3B166FA63EB1439C92D8BC99DB587B2B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in a manner that conserves, protects, and enhances the resources and values of the National Scenic Area described in subsection (b); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8882380A537D4A9791803DF06228FF96"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in accordance with—</text> <subparagraph id="H04A278C4711F483F94746AEECBEC8D13"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H309E53880F3C44B1904141D98F1299E7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>this Act; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38CEA908739C47F3A505CAC752EE1DC6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other applicable laws.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H31063B012CD94BA7A3B4A2694E60D68D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Management</header>
 <paragraph id="H23ED28DB15B34F26AC92613CD436B5C8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall allow only such uses of the National Scenic Area as the Secretary determines would support the purposes of the National Scenic Area as described in subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1D5B4604194E460E8F1E7433B1B0006E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recreational activities</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this Act or other applicable law, or as the Secretary determines to be necessary for public health and safety, the Secretary shall allow existing recreational uses of the National Scenic Area to continue, including hiking, mountain biking, rock climbing, sightseeing, horseback riding, hunting, fishing, and appropriate authorized motorized vehicle use.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3851055A2A9C4C568CEF95773BEEBCE8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Motorized vehicles</header><text>Except as specified within this Act and/or in cases in which motorized vehicles are needed for administrative purposes, or to respond to an emergency, the use of motorized vehicles in the National Scenic Area shall be permitted only on—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7FFA490B56F64A359666B56E4E74FB39"><enum>(A)</enum><text>roads and trails designated by the Director of the Bureau of Land Management for use of motorized vehicles as part of a management plan sustaining a semi-primitive motorized experience; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC029CE5568F44CC0AAF643E5284783FF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>on county-maintained roads in accordance with applicable State and county laws.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9A52DD38855241838542A57B0B8942A9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>No buffer zones</header> <paragraph id="HCEF93DE61353466B9F298C8949DCC72A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in this Act creates a protective perimeter or buffer zone around the National Scenic Area.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD7E69B1772824759AECE6577B2EB4370"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Activities outside national scenic area</header><text>The fact that an activity or use on land outside the National Scenic Area can be seen or heard within the National Scenic Area shall not preclude the activity or use outside the boundaries of the National Scenic Area.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H141E1AAA1A4D49FAA10807BD09199793"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Access</header><text>The Secretary shall continue to provide private landowners adequate access to inholdings in the National Scenic Area.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB19FB9708E3242AD9D428823C63ECDF1"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Filming</header><text>Nothing in this Act prohibits filming (including commercial film production, student filming, and still photography) within the National Scenic Area—</text>
 <paragraph id="H37EB7EE72A1746C5AF1F9E63738223D6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>subject to—</text> <subparagraph id="HC00DD25A70DF447AA5617B7CE50915A2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such reasonable regulations, policies, and practices as the Secretary considers to be necessary; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC41F79C92E8E46F191DF7AA07E613D87"><enum>(B)</enum><text>applicable law; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D2F5C86EDF74B559A38CEF65031E73E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in a manner consistent with the purposes described in subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF38DE33222F2443A80E17D5E3F5015A4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Fish and wildlife</header><text>Nothing in this Act affects the jurisdiction or responsibilities of the State with respect to fish and wildlife.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBB7104630BA84213AF2C6B21598C097A"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Livestock</header><text>The grazing of livestock in the National Scenic Area, including grazing under the Alabama Hills allotment and the George Creek allotment, as established before the date of enactment of this Act, shall be permitted to continue—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB72FA0214D6E4A699332A11541BDCEFB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>subject to—</text> <subparagraph id="H7AD1C2ECA54B4C2CA76E27FB460B1AE4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such reasonable regulations, policies, and practices as the Secretary considers to be necessary; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H007C5446CAE94C9C83D99529E83B2E7E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>applicable law; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BAB47145E544B2B93ACA167FEF6E1B3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in a manner consistent with the purposes described in subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H759305782CEC4A28A1736FFB90E6C036"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Overflights</header><text>Nothing in this Act restricts or precludes flights over the National Scenic Area or overflights that can be seen or heard within the National Scenic Area, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDC449EE0DEE44A3183DCF07E0574FFF2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>transportation, sightseeing and filming flights, general aviation planes, helicopters, hang-gliders, and balloonists, for commercial or recreational purposes;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H94B55839FCF2459D8A162691189B7666"><enum>(2)</enum><text>low-level overflights of military aircraft;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H34FE20FDA7F64082AA36ACD2CB116162"><enum>(3)</enum><text>flight testing and evaluation;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H87203126A2014D2DA49000F46C364E3F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the designation or creation of new units of special use airspace, or the establishment of military flight training routes, over the National Scenic Area; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H00C493ADF9EB4E288E5BEAA6E6A10050"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the use, including take-off and landing, of helicopters and other aerial devices within valid rights-of-way to construct or maintain energy transport facilities.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H48A4F9FA47A4414F993BD944F85E288A"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Subject to this Act’s provisions and valid rights in existence on the date of enactment of this Act, including rights established by prior withdrawals, the Federal land within the National Scenic Area is withdrawn from all forms of—</text>
 <paragraph id="HEE7F7EFABB8D406EAAA826C8DC3E18B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H472B9D71FE994DD59B0EA1706CF55225"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDAD4072D9B044DB4BB5E7DB38BBA2327"><enum>(3)</enum><text>disposition under all laws pertaining to mineral and geothermal leasing or mineral materials.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAA45536133CC4D0EA7133661C351B5A6"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Wildland fire operations</header><text>Nothing in this Act prohibits the Secretary, in cooperation with other Federal, State, and local agencies, as appropriate, from conducting wildland fire operations in the National Scenic Area, consistent with the purposes described in subsection (b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEAD886AB904C469DA4DFD60E86A00505"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Grants; cooperative agreements</header><text>The Secretary may make grants to, or enter into cooperative agreements with, State, tribal, and local governmental entities and private entities to conduct research, interpretation, or public education or to carry out any other initiative relating to the restoration, conservation, or management of the National Scenic Area.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2DACC96F66214A05896A99871A78F5AC"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Air and water quality</header><text>Nothing in this Act modifies any standard governing air or water quality outside of the boundaries of the National Scenic Area.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="HF4A6FF030A00460AB2B9AE8388178946"><enum>(p)</enum><header>Utility facilities and rights of way</header>
 <paragraph id="HEE87FC2D66F142C7A60D6BD8416DF9E9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Nothing in this Act shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HAA44029940354699819E2C7B8E607B77"><enum>(A)</enum><text>affect the existence, use, operation, maintenance (including but not limited to vegetation control), repair, construction, reconfiguration, expansion, inspection, renewal, reconstruction, alteration, addition, relocation, improvement, funding, removal, or replacement of utility facilities or appurtenant rights of way within or adjacent to the National Scenic Area;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6631267BD4CD4CFE9574A5DC163BF8AD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>affect necessary or efficient access to utility facilities or rights of way within or adjacent to the National Scenic Area subject to subsection (e); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85F5FFB9D13B4954B9260603A0045D4B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>preclude the Secretary from authorizing the establishment of new utility facility rights of way (including instream sites, routes, and areas) within the National Scenic Area in a manner that minimizes harm to the purpose of the National Scenic Area as described in subsection (b)—</text>
 <clause id="HD6C64929821D41AF8598B7C66B039446"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.) and any other applicable law;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H58B3E40500D14F15A838CA3029F4457E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary determines to be appropriate; and</text> </clause><clause id="H5AF2D9A76E014ACE82A1E8A75E40AF62"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>are determined, by the Secretary, to be the only technical or feasible location, following consideration of alternatives within existing rights of way or outside of the National Scenic Area.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF93E9BEBB53416BA18E285B8EFD573B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Management plan</header><text>Consistent with this Act, the Management Plan shall establish plans for maintenance of public utility and other rights of way within the National Scenic Area.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2386048D279D4C3EB268148C203CC56B"><enum>1603.</enum><header>Management plan</header>
 <subsection id="H7A7E88A3377A4FBD8C0B532F07FE701F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, in accordance with subsection (b), the Secretary shall develop a comprehensive plan for the long-term management of the National Scenic Area.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF3343E7B2491496D844396F95356BF23"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In developing the management plan, the Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="HC9432EE72DF540F2A24E0C999F704A17"><enum>(1)</enum><text>consult with appropriate State, tribal, and local governmental entities, including Inyo County and the Tribe; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE8DA12BD334D49E0B67C9FCFDD2A963B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>seek input from—</text> <subparagraph id="HA0EDCB40DC3548ACB1EB1C4F817EAF5A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>investor-owned utilities, including Southern California Edison Company;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A152E4E9FED4D558CDC6F007D3C5844"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Alabama Hills Stewardship Group;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF2DD9C104554B8DA5318E7B647183E9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>members of the public; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6341A6D0E5624D5390A7F14A8A2CD06A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Los Angeles Department of Water and Power.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3B203E56E3BB445697D2C62535B686C7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Incorporation of management plan</header><text>In developing the management plan, in accordance with this section, the Secretary shall allow, in perpetuity, casual-use mining limited to the use of hand tools, metal detectors, hand-fed dry washers, vacuum cleaners, gold pans, small sluices, and similar items.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD64BB9002C6E4009AE95362AA1405442"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Interim management</header><text>Pending completion of the management plan, the Secretary shall manage the National Scenic Area in accordance with section 3.</text>
						</subsection></section><section id="H16A1F181C5B9476998C638BDF5FACB2A"><enum>1604.</enum><header>Land taken into trust for lone pine paiute-shoshone reservation</header>
 <subsection id="HD9FEC5292962498DB718BA411B09651D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Trust land</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall take the approximately 132 acres of Federal land depicted on the Map as <quote>Lone Pine Paiute-Shoshone Reservation Addition</quote> into trust for the benefit of the Tribe, subject to the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HDE839B32F33B43B3912BFA7254DC3DF7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Conditions</header><text>The land shall be subject to all easements, covenants, conditions, restrictions, withdrawals, and other matters of record on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBAE5D36D5E4543F2A7F0CE328BED7193"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The Federal lands over which the right-of-way for the Los Angeles Aqueduct is located, generally described as the 250-foot-wide right-of-way granted to the City of Los Angeles pursuant to the Act of June 30, 1906 (Chap. 3926), shall not be taken into trust for the Tribe.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA2CF0C46266F43908D6FD54F1EC89A32"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reservation land</header><text>The land taken into trust pursuant to subsection (a) shall be considered part of the reservation of the Tribe.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1ABB3185833244D38EDFF1E73EF09D01"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Gaming prohibition</header><text>Gaming under the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2701">25 U.S.C. 2701</external-xref> et seq.) shall not be allowed on the land taken into trust pursuant to subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H26EFDA1E68D443FEB189B4C3A5EC14B5"><enum>1605.</enum><header>Transfer of administrative jurisdiction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Administrative jurisdiction of the approximately 56 acres of Federal land depicted on the Map as <quote>USFS Transfer to BLM</quote> is hereby transferred from the Forest Service under the Secretary of Agriculture to the Bureau of Land Management under the Secretary.</text>
 </section><section id="H9643CA4E5FC84D748167AA6F2DF15FD3"><enum>1606.</enum><header>Protection of services and recreational opportunities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to limit commercial services for existing and historic recreation uses as authorized by the Bureau of Land Management’s permit process. Valid, existing, commercial permits to exercise guided recreational opportunities for the public may continue as authorized on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
					</section></title><title id="H70FE0BF62DC043D59C533376B2BA2731"><enum>XVII</enum><header>MISCELLANEOUS</header>
 <section id="H5961AFE5A88B4D5BA9D4C75DBD32A764"><enum>1701.</enum><header>Military activities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this title—</text> <paragraph id="H93C7006163B946B09F299BC821E9CFEF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>restricts or precludes Department of Defense motorized access by land or air—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H45CF5EF73B3C4FF3ADF4BF4D9CA94D2C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to respond to an emergency within a wilderness area designated by this Act; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7FA78E37964E44B6B9EFF2220B75D601"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to control access to the emergency site;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H57A707023AE44C8789D1391786FAA007"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prevents nonmechanized military training activities previously conducted on wilderness areas designated by this title that are consistent with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF6EE317C63DD4E40B78D1598CD36A7BB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</external-xref> et seq.); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C489CC94B5643F6B868FDB8E955BCC7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>all applicable laws (including regulations);</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F2997AD022E4E9B8ACA942C72F95626"><enum>(3)</enum><text>restricts or precludes low-level overflights of military aircraft over the areas designated as wilderness, national monuments, special management areas, or recreation areas by this Act, including military overflights that can be seen or heard within the designated areas;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD8FF1FF7D89A49C0B871E823F989844D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>restricts or precludes flight testing and evaluation in the areas described in paragraph (3); or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC475229E9B84A5BA8BE54BABF578C17"><enum>(5)</enum><text>restricts or precludes the designation or creation of new units of special use airspace, or the establishment of military flight training routes, over the areas described in paragraph (3).</text>
						</paragraph></section><section id="H43C7299C3BCD4DEBA85F962CCE3F43C0"><enum>1702.</enum><header>Prohibited uses of acquired, donated, and conservation land</header>
 <subsection id="H97AA3B76FF894B2E874BA3E5FF22C7E4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H8E5EEC21B38D44618DC4E1069B3C1BC4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Acquired land</header><text>The term <quote>acquired land</quote> means any land acquired within the Conservation Area using amounts from the land and water conservation fund established under section 200302 of title 54, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9ACE6D0C30224F45946E43E09CD9BB9D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conservation land</header><text>The term <quote>conservation land</quote> means any land within the Conservation Area that is designated to satisfy the conditions of a Federal habitat conservation plan, general conservation plan, or State natural communities conservation plan, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD496B7654E36489AA8736EACB7344561"><enum>(A)</enum><text>national conservation land established pursuant to section 2002(b)(2)(D) of the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/7202">16 U.S.C. 7202(b)(2)(D)</external-xref>); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78C800A1311C409B92B24AA153812861"><enum>(B)</enum><text>areas of critical environmental concern established pursuant to section 202(c)(3) of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1712">43 U.S.C. 1712(c)(3)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC82B04C97C074AB3887D901121279F4F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Donated land</header><text>The term <quote>donated land</quote> means any private land donated to the United States for conservation purposes in the Conservation Area.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H22A90F27124746F39796ED2A1A535278"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Donor</header><text>The term <quote>donor</quote> means an individual or entity that donates private land within the Conservation Area to the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE5095C69CD70462FA1A5BFF5BC31BFBF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3CE759F1F4414AABABFE4278806D6854"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibitions</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (c), the Secretary shall not authorize the use of acquired land, conservation land, or donated land within the Conservation Area for any activities contrary to the conservation purposes for which the land was acquired, designated, or donated, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="H1681780784E54B7DB30C4ED21E10D1F8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>disposal;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6E499F4E670143D39BC18B3E98E2F5EA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>rights-of-way;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDBFCA6EA106145D5A7091E333C5D070B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>leases;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H27AEA624810F4654A4018D93B879F3C6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>livestock grazing;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H26EE787576EA41279B661F9113AE1DBE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>infrastructure development, except as provided in subsection (c);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7184D092014C4760BE8F734EC0766629"><enum>(6)</enum><text>mineral entry; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAB6DF682E7E74617A3F382F1DD186B8B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>off-highway vehicle use, except on—</text> <subparagraph id="H44A4202487F94174BF5C366444736E81"><enum>(A)</enum><text>designated routes;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCFC6BA5143E94FEF94D2898CF757E634"><enum>(B)</enum><text>off-highway vehicle areas designated by law; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31812858008A4A21B581677FDE6DCAEB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>administratively designated open areas.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H00C5771AFBAE464B8AD2C2C290AB9135"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exceptions</header>
 <paragraph id="H46783C23F73C4BE98B3673E9C6B3A9B1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization by secretary</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), the Secretary may authorize limited exceptions to prohibited uses of acquired land or donated land in the Conservation Area if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBAB841A072B34F3DAA46DD795F56CA92"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a right-of-way application for a renewable energy development project or associated energy transport facility on acquired land or donated land was submitted to the Bureau of Land Management on or before December 1, 2009; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE98FD4DB74242A09F91AD874DEE540E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>after the completion and consideration of an analysis under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.), the Secretary has determined that proposed use is in the public interest.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8315627E5AB1431794907F9CF9908AF6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conditions</header>
 <subparagraph id="HF2630A327FC44D46B9AD90EC7AA4F164"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Secretary grants an exception to the prohibition under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall require the permittee to donate private land of comparable value located within the Conservation Area to the United States to mitigate the use.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC564CE16E67E4982B1A2AE2FA899CB06"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Approval</header><text>The private land to be donated under subparagraph (A) shall be approved by the Secretary after—</text> <clause id="HF5C27359958D4F0D9319CED154B2DF95"><enum>(i)</enum><text>consultation, to the maximum extent practicable, with the donor of the private land proposed for nonconservation uses; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDD778A56F2D244FDB211FECBE642DC81"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an opportunity for public comment regarding the donation.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8D088F0F809449C5B8B5DB1230BCA5BC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Existing agreements</header><text>Nothing in this section affects permitted or prohibited uses of donated land or acquired land in the Conservation Area established in any easements, deed restrictions, memoranda of understanding, or other agreements in existence on the date of enactment of this title.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1CBE5FCDBCB042338EA237B0AD8F056E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Deed restrictions</header><text>Effective beginning on the date of enactment of this title, within the Conservation Area, the Secretary may—</text>
 <paragraph id="H241736C6733E4DA18CEAC71BED13B115"><enum>(1)</enum><text>accept deed restrictions requested by landowners for land donated to, or otherwise acquired by, the United States; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H487E25FF60B64A928B050DF07D1BD63E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consistent with existing rights, create deed restrictions, easements, or other third-party rights relating to any public land determined by the Secretary to be necessary—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H684536C3860442C9A93B60BB71301CDA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to fulfill the mitigation requirements resulting from the development of renewable resources; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF825FA6E6ED4E5AB9C17F93C02AB7B2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to satisfy the conditions of—</text>
 <clause id="H4D766C4FB8594EA08B4D7865BC6CD499"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a habitat conservation plan or general conservation plan established pursuant to section 10 of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1539">16 U.S.C. 1539</external-xref>); or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7BD7B683229D43B5A22A88B55B51172A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a natural communities conservation plan approved by the State.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2BC3BB941E594123BD1B4107E619EDD2"><enum>1703.</enum><header>Tribal uses and interests</header> <subsection id="H67424B00FCBF431E8CFC248333806904"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Access</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure access to areas designated under this Act by members of Indian tribes for traditional cultural and religious purposes, consistent with applicable law, including <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/341">Public Law 95–341</external-xref> (commonly known as the <quote>American Indian Religious Freedom Act</quote>) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1996">42 U.S.C. 1996</external-xref>).</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H67EAA740B62D4968BE6C951F25C9707D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Temporary closure</header>
 <paragraph id="H6B264EDB8EBD4FF3A8266D21FD4213DA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In accordance with applicable law, including <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/341">Public Law 95–341</external-xref> (commonly known as the <quote>American Indian Religious Freedom Act</quote>) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1996">42 U.S.C. 1996</external-xref>), and subject to paragraph (2), the Secretary, on request of an Indian tribe or Indian religious community, shall temporarily close to general public use any portion of an area designated as a national monument, special management area, wild and scenic river, area of critical environmental concern, or National Park System unit under this Act (referred to in this subsection as a <quote>designated area</quote>) to protect the privacy of traditional cultural and religious activities in the designated area by members of the Indian tribe or Indian religious community.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HABEAC2B5602B4982944A67491B38E975"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>In closing a portion of a designated area under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall limit the closure to the smallest practicable area for the minimum period necessary for the traditional cultural and religious activities.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H06C41D29D9894019A8DDAC55BC7A02FD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Tribal cultural resources management plan</header>
 <paragraph id="HE5511D24302548FF856C904A8A16555A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this title, the Secretary of the Interior shall develop and implement a tribal cultural resources management plan to identify, protect, and conserve cultural resources of Indian tribes associated with the Xam Kwatchan Trail network extending from Avikwaame (Spirit Mountain, Nevada) to Avikwlal (Pilot Knob, California).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H305F49D1B08446779766D516327BC217"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Secretary shall consult on the development and implementation of the tribal cultural resources management plan under paragraph (1) with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE5D942EDC5CD4B1B9BAFBDDA95EB2BF9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each of—</text> <clause id="H0CFB2E1FC2EA4DE9BF2F5D823E88EC4F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Chemehuevi Indian Tribe;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFDF35DF0219E4C0E9AA97EFA4758AA09"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Hualapai Tribal Nation;</text> </clause><clause id="HDC4EFBA9E7914651BC0200585331BFC2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Fort Mojave Indian Tribe;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8B617BA51EBF430AB92BE00303D08C6A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Colorado River Indian Tribes;</text> </clause><clause id="H3C51A63469A64ADB914C63103CD13EBA"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the Quechan Indian Tribe; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9D8ED4A39A4346E59DEBC8B47CA78367"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the Cocopah Indian Tribe; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CBE4B6CBAB24055B88AD99DF80C0D5E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC1599B04375459FBB6029E8D31E276A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Resource protection</header><text>The tribal cultural resources management plan developed under paragraph (1) shall be—</text> <subparagraph id="H1F29711846744355919DE65E2BEF95C1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>based on a completed tribal cultural resources survey; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36E8628FC8DD44A3B807E37C012CC031"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include procedures for identifying, protecting, and preserving petroglyphs, ancient trails, intaglios, sleeping circles, artifacts, and other resources of cultural, archaeological, or historical significance in accordance with all applicable laws and policies, including—</text>
 <clause id="H15D994CDCC0842209981ACFB9B01DCDE"><enum>(i)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/54/2003">chapter 2003</external-xref> of title 54, United States Code;</text> </clause><clause id="H5174F0C1CCA64166BEE28C75631D64D3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Public Law 95–341 (commonly known as the <quote>American Indian Religious Freedom Act</quote>) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1996">42 U.S.C. 1996</external-xref>);</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBC08340FAD824510AEC83F58B12564F6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Archaeological Resources Protection Act of 1979 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/470aa">16 U.S.C. 470aa</external-xref> et seq.);</text> </clause><clause id="H1D8461A141D64D609758E4B423AEFF7C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Native American Graves Protection and Repatriation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/3001">25 U.S.C. 3001</external-xref> et seq.); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB3533B299A1B4E5DB5DBB4461DDAC37A"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Public Law 103–141 (commonly known as the <quote>Religious Freedom Restoration Act of 1993</quote>) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000bb">42 U.S.C. 2000bb</external-xref> et seq.).</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3B0402D0F23E4933A445286F31A779DE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, all Federal land within the area administratively withdrawn and known as the <quote>Indian Pass Withdrawal Area</quote> is permanently withdrawn from—</text>
 <paragraph id="H3F03A087E50D400F9C6DD4A1909FC00F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all forms of entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H597DE61A0AA0441EB30FEC1BE17D6660"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC47A90D762F848BBAE552B95C716D7CB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>right-of-way leasing and disposition under all laws relating to minerals or solar, wind, or geothermal energy.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H89233E0DF489461FB932BA96474D3C3C"><enum>1704.</enum><header>Release of federal reversionary land interests</header>
 <subsection id="H363FFF0A437747BB875799FA4453AE4B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H69431A0D5ED24F3DBFDAAAC968A82559"><enum>(1)</enum><header>1932 act</header><text>The <quote>1932 Act</quote> means the Act of June 18, 1932 (47 Stat. 324, chapter 270).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0469BAB76EAD4FBF8618025663EA5F9E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>District</header><text>The <quote>District</quote> means the Metropolitan Water District of Southern California.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H558F2AE5F2644571BDE2810578BA7A2F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Release</header><text>Subject to valid existing claims perfected prior to the effective date of the 1932 Act and the reservation of minerals set forth in the 1932 Act, the Secretary shall release, convey, or otherwise quitclaim to the District, in a form recordable in local county records, and subject to the approval of the District, after consultation and without monetary consideration, all right, title, and remaining interest of the United States in and to the land that was conveyed to the District pursuant to the 1932 Act or any other law authorizing conveyance subject to restrictions or reversionary interests retained by the United States, on request by the District.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7288681D1DE94A74A119AABAB2342066"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header><text>A conveyance authorized by subsection (b) shall be subject to the following terms and conditions:</text> <paragraph id="HA35EA8A091C04910A24F1C352FDBF46B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The District shall cover, or reimburse the Secretary for, the costs incurred by the Secretary to make the conveyance, including title searches, surveys, deed preparation, attorneys’ fees, and similar expenses.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8BEF5DD38D564C299B601291FC6BE3BC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>By accepting the conveyances, the District agrees to indemnify and hold harmless the United States with regard to any boundary dispute relating to any parcel conveyed under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H48143A7020B94EE3AB8B567D83675CDD"><enum>3.</enum><header>Visitor center</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title IV of the California Desert Protection Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/410aaa-21">16 U.S.C. 410aaa–21</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="H0A32EA3305B04B49B1F9A12B2A414813" style="OLC">
				<section id="H3EA567BEE1014BCDB5E15F716ED62AE1"><enum>408.</enum><header>Visitor center</header>
 <subsection id="HF3A50623CC4541BA853112B842D69FB0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may acquire not more than 5 acres of land and interests in land, and improvements on the land and interests, outside the boundaries of Joshua Tree National Park, in the unincorporated village of Joshua Tree, for the purpose of operating a visitor center.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7CD1D0392E7B4AFCBF4DDD25874B1757"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Boundary</header><text>The Secretary shall modify the boundary of the park to include the land acquired under this section as a noncontiguous parcel.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7B4C5E3D97FA4B009400DA760CBA141F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>Land and facilities acquired under this section—</text> <paragraph id="H19827851D44D426B8D04A9EDDF32FF3F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may include the property owned (as of the date of enactment of this section) by the Joshua Tree National Park Association and commonly referred to as the <quote>Joshua Tree National Park Visitor Center</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCD66EB26AF5F4DD4805CC672626033E1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall be administered by the Secretary as part of the park; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H98C8462406ED438DB0182E16747E624F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>may be acquired only with the consent of the owner, by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, or exchange.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H1F71AE4BD89E47B6B7C4CA77A18A2210"><enum>4.</enum><header>California State school land</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 707 of the California Desert Protection Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/410aaa-77">16 U.S.C. 410aaa–77</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H3FFE8ED06C6E4878B482AB0240379521"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H97DAE3C8156140A18599EDA8579FE41F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the first sentence—</text> <clause id="HEE1D1CB5E9474761BB5EF09F791B5A62"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Upon request of the California State Lands Commission (hereinafter in this section referred to as the <quote>Commission</quote>), the Secretary shall enter into negotiations for an agreement</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
						<quoted-block id="H55EF392C890B4215B1622F74AC3268AD" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H365AB6BB5028447E84D64344628A6479"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall negotiate in good faith to reach an agreement with the California State Lands Commission (referred to in this section as the Commission).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause><clause id="H64DC5ACCECD04FFD8D32E37003C6E240"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, national monuments,</quote> after <quote>more of the wilderness areas</quote>; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H51FA72F0655B4B3E9ECE32AD505D2A26"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the second sentence, by striking <quote>The Secretary shall negotiate in good faith to</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="HA9C1A25AA4F1465FB8D346B6ECDF2332" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H62049F61FB7B407C8B53B3161E4C7808"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agreement</header><text>To the maximum extent practicable, not later than 10 years after the date of enactment of this title, the Secretary shall</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC576BCC491D4DCA8BD2B1C86235F0E3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1), by inserting <quote>, national monuments,</quote> after <quote>wilderness areas</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H958AAB7655AC4493B2D06A7F15F97F72"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H0243BF14886E414EB3FE57EED1A314DC" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="HDBB803ECA24441648873E82E8CAF20D2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Special deposit fund account</header>
 <subparagraph id="HFFB3F783EEF9492DA470D768F971E5E3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Assembled land exchanges may be used to carry out this section through the sale of surplus Federal property and subsequent acquisitions of State school land.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C4262F85A7F44FAACBE390058C8040E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Receipts</header><text>Past and future receipts from the sale of property described in subsection (a), less any costs incurred related to the sale, shall be deposited in a Special Deposit Fund Account established in the Treasury.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1811C0C0788445008D735A7380C6D12F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Use</header><text>Funds accumulated in the Special Deposit Fund Account may be used by the Secretary, without an appropriation, to acquire State school lands or interest in the land consistent with this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HF3FEE66C33174F43AA93F780D05F0351"><enum>5.</enum><header>Designation of wild and scenic rivers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3(a) of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1274">16 U.S.C. 1274(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HA9DA5336BB0946A4AC5FCFA8248A0516"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (196), by striking subparagraph (A) and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H29E13DB063044E1A8172C74D217F72D7" style="OLC">
					<subparagraph id="H833BFC95DEA8470FB4008F8EC02F0B22"><enum>(A)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE478D7116CA14E8C88C3B53CED168552"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The approximately 1.4-mile segment of the Amargosa River in the State of California, from the private property boundary in sec. 19, T. 22 N., R. 7 E., to 100 feet downstream of Highway 178, to be administered by the Secretary of the Interior as a scenic river as an addition to the wild and scenic river segments of the Amargosa River on publication by the Secretary of a notice in the Federal Register that sufficient inholdings within the boundaries of the segments have been acquired as scenic easements or in fee title to establish a manageable addition to those segments.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB99F7628432D447FB0CC829D6DC54381" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The approximately 6.1-mile segment of the Amargosa River in the State of California, from 100 feet downstream of the State Highway 178 crossing to 100 feet upstream of the Tecopa Hot Springs Road crossing, to be administered by the Secretary of the Interior as a scenic river.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5E4B18A87D8C4F76A07B3A2862325D5A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HD29F37FBDD7E4E80BA093DBCE6628AF4" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HD2C6BDC9BCDD44EDB1B13E49423899AA"><enum>(213)</enum><header>Surprise canyon creek, california</header> <subparagraph id="HFB920CE7782B4FDE93D2A509BB0F369F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The following segments of Surprise Canyon Creek in the State of California, to be administered by the Secretary of the Interior:</text>
 <clause id="HC2F93C6CB75045FEBEE2F5EAFF85FBD7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The approximately 5.3 miles of Surprise Canyon Creek from the confluence of Frenchman’s Canyon and Water Canyon to 100 feet upstream of Chris Wicht Camp, as a wild river.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2577B5B6179F40D481E5037D38B6D685"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The approximately 1.8 miles of Surprise Canyon Creek from 100 feet upstream of Chris Wicht Camp to the southern boundary of sec. 14, T. 21 N., R. 44 E., as a recreational river.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H398AB5A14A804C2AA21D7005E2E84D3D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effect on historic mining structures</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph affects the historic mining structures associated with the former Panamint Mining District.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H11C0ACF0AC5B43F1B70896D8B3D09A32"><enum>(214)</enum><header>Deep creek, california</header>
 <subparagraph id="HE141F475221A47079C103F464F5E53C8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The following segments of Deep Creek in the State of California, to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture:</text>
 <clause id="HD14F26BB63594260B1E08C0B8E634C16"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The approximately 6.5-mile segment from 0.125 mile downstream of the Rainbow Dam site in sec. 33, T. 2 N., R. 2 W., to 0.25 miles upstream of the Road 3N34 crossing, as a wild river.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAAFFAA4ED60447D697ACEB082B62CEE1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The 0.5-mile segment from 0.25 mile upstream of the Road 3N34 crossing to 0.25 mile downstream of the Road 3N34 crossing, as a scenic river.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H91772F96B37E4C669CFC4B3622A11666"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The 2.5-mile segment from 0.25 miles downstream of the Road 3 N. 34 crossing to 0.25 miles upstream of the Trail 2W01 crossing, as a wild river.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEDD58F0F413B47308B5DFE2046E8977E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The 0.5-mile segment from 0.25 miles upstream of the Trail 2W01 crossing to 0.25 mile downstream of the Trail 2W01 crossing, as a scenic river.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD57BE9911C754076969B5312AB91150F"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The 10-mile segment from 0.25 miles downstream of the Trail 2W01 crossing to the upper limit of the Mojave dam flood zone in sec. 17, T. 3 N., R. 3 W., as a wild river.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H32839348786842E8A8D3AB9BF7D53AC6"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The 11-mile segment of Holcomb Creek from 100 yards downstream of the Road 3N12 crossing to .25 miles downstream of Holcomb Crossing, as a recreational river.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6026FD9FE7364E5FBF8682F883F08ED4"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>The 3.5-mile segment of the Holcomb Creek from 0.25 miles downstream of Holcomb Crossing to the Deep Creek confluence, as a wild river.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB9AAB46EBB8474C95832F0495CAD746"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effect on ski operations</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph affects—</text> <clause id="H219AD84CE83B4BD0B1749269DF520EFC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the operations of the Snow Valley Ski Resort; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H893AE1F6CA1A48DF8C1F75B3253FCEEE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the State regulation of water rights and water quality associated with the operation of the Snow Valley Ski Resort.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F311E19767746BA949E725FB3C4AE9A"><enum>(215)</enum><header>Whitewater river, california</header><text>The following segments of the Whitewater River in the State of California, to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior, acting jointly:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFA8E7B499DCF497FAD1B93081EA44FEF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The 5.8-mile segment of the North Fork Whitewater River from the source of the River near Mt. San Gorgonio to the confluence with the Middle Fork, as a wild river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F6B55AE3840485EA13AE8B83A87A61C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The 6.4-mile segment of the Middle Fork Whitewater River from the source of the River to the confluence with the South Fork, as a wild river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB946D7FBCDC48178969E32B1E88F36C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The 1-mile segment of the South Fork Whitewater River from the confluence of the River with the East Fork to the section line between sections 32 and 33, T. 1 S., R. 2 E., as a wild river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22CAB80F8FFB44BC9DDF4F8284E4726A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The 1-mile segment of the South Fork Whitewater River from the section line between sections 32 and 33, T. 1 S., R. 2 E., to the section line between sections 33 and 34, T. 1 S., R. 2 E., as a recreational river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C3C9D05C55B4D4680985AF0078BD096"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The 4.9-mile segment of the South Fork Whitewater River from the section line between sections 33 and 34, T. 1 S., R. 2 E., to the confluence with the Middle Fork, as a wild river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB562F686CDD34D17A9A37A0430A562D9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The 5.4-mile segment of the main stem of the Whitewater River from the confluence of the South and Middle Forks to the San Gorgonio Wilderness boundary, as a wild river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7210C7F42FF4284B2EB66A62925AD3E"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The 3.6-mile segment of the main stem of the Whitewater River from the San Gorgonio Wilderness boundary to .25 miles upstream of the southern boundary of section 35, T. 2 S., R. 3 E., as a recreational river.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HF7D835243BC647C5A29F7094C4D886A2"><enum>6.</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <subsection id="H11AF15127E864C4BBF1D299D627F3DB9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>Section 1 of the California Desert Protection Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/410aaa">16 U.S.C. 410aaa</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/103/433">Public Law 103–433</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>1 and 2, and titles I through IX</quote> and inserting <quote>1, 2, and 3, titles I through IX, and titles XIII through XVIII</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H40DED46C4F6F4EB49C50E54BE7D01B5C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>The California Desert Protection Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/103/433">Public Law 103–433</external-xref>; 108 Stat. 4481) is amended by inserting after section 2 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H9983D4F141F84362830C5B5DD88AC892" style="OLC">
 <section id="H2E8CB683A7774E6396782611D63833C0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In titles XIII through XVIII:</text> <paragraph id="H1F04E348F3604BBE9D62A5B2B2D34477"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Conservation area</header><text>The term <quote>Conservation Area</quote> means the California Desert Conservation Area.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H116E1CD172E6486CA660661C45E5E5C4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H1ACC5EA74AF0484E89DC2F474CFC5711"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of the Interior; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38F2D19C216E467CB7724659AEB7562D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC526F05073C449AFB38B108E7D3A6B50"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> means the State of California.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H880DA2AFA7384767BAB6846F28BC196A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administration of wilderness areas</header><text>Section 103 of the California Desert Protection Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/103/433">Public Law 103–433</external-xref>; 108 Stat. 4481) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H903F5D9EC2C84AFBA0405CA77024BDE3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking subsection (d) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H9BBF1AE686C24AAFBCEDBC7C7CFD304B" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H31E85135EB214A5A9DC42570E1087DCE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>No buffer zones</header> <paragraph id="H1054B328485445C58FB86F636F466C09"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Congress does not intend for the designation of wilderness areas by this Act—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H89E9E0CC876C46C5B1113A817F7E8659"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to require the additional regulation of land adjacent to the wilderness areas; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20338BDB12E442FE96C7F6DBA7770F7F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to lead to the creation of protective perimeters or buffer zones around the wilderness areas.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6EEE656CF66F409586ED683A42EB3A78"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nonwilderness activities</header><text>Any nonwilderness activities (including renewable energy projects, energy transmission or telecommunications projects, mining, camping, hunting, and military activities) in areas immediately adjacent to the boundary of a wilderness area designated by this Act shall not be restricted or precluded by this Act, regardless of any actual or perceived negative impacts of the nonwilderness activities on the wilderness area, including any potential indirect impacts of nonwilderness activities conducted outside the designated wilderness area on the viewshed, ambient noise level, or air quality of wilderness area.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H891330716F254FB585B46398BEB393CF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (f), by striking <quote>designated by this title and</quote> inserting <quote>, potential wilderness areas, special management areas, and national monuments designated by this title or titles XIII through XVIII</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBE625B4527D64D6994C7AA08F7F0E933"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (g), by inserting <quote>, a potential wilderness area, a special management areas, or national monument</quote> before <quote>by this Act</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEF731174F03B4C649E67CE36E473AC31"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Juniper Flats</header><text>Title VII of the California Desert Protection Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/103/433">Public Law 103–433</external-xref>; 108 Stat. 4497) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HB71E882631744EFBA2170A859912E3D7" style="OLC">
 <section id="H2CF788AF5E1F483B86409EEB3B5FBCC7"><enum>712.</enum><header>Juniper flats</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Development of renewable energy generation facilities (excluding rights-of-way or facilities for the transmission of energy and telecommunication facilities and infrastructure) is prohibited on the approximately 28,000 acres of Federal land generally depicted as <quote>BLM Land Withdrawn from Energy Development and Power Generation</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Juniper Flats</quote> and dated September 21, 2015.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H9E5E6EFE5DBB4944A2474C7D25A50137"><enum>(e)</enum><header>California military lands withdrawal and overflights act of 1994</header>
 <paragraph id="H33360361B8BA495E973244F7DCA75191"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Section 801(b)(2) of the California Military Lands Withdrawal and Overflights Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/410aaa-82">16 U.S.C. 410aaa–82</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/103/433">Public Law 103–433</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, special management areas, potential wilderness areas,</quote> before <quote>and wilderness areas</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H71E2B430F87D4FF7A997828510E68AB8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Overflights; special airspace</header><text>Section 802 of the California Military Lands Withdrawal and Overflights Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/410aaa-82">16 U.S.C. 410aaa–82</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H93396ACC1BD24A08A76506E510AA06AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by inserting <quote>or special management areas</quote> before <quote>designated by this Act</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D1C8C0A2E274BD7900F66A299836D57"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by inserting <quote>or special management areas</quote> before <quote>designated by this Act</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2F73A0C64BD4D9FB69801A726D4A11F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H6326EC1FC7EE400A9F86DCE5450A099A" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HA86CDB2A90114EA9A7DD6F441BF059A3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Department of defense facilities</header><text>Nothing in this Act alters any authority of the Secretary of Defense to conduct military operations at installations and ranges within the California Desert Conservation Area that are authorized under any other provision of law.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6922FD414CD54586B1A272BED4CD0DC5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Clarification regarding funding</header><text>No additional funds are authorized to carry out the requirements of this Act and the amendments made by this Act. Such requirements shall be carried out using amounts otherwise authorized.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


