<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2957EC35CD7E467386F0B66317305806" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2474 IH: Medical Product Review Harmonization Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2474</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170516">May 16, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000820">Mrs. Mimi Walters of California</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to provide an alternative standard for
			 substantial equivalence determinations for devices, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H46CF645BAC854044B27DCBE41548A3F3" style="OLC">
 <section id="H88D6EB26FDE748D69E98344ED145139D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medical Product Review Harmonization Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H790C4D62FDCA4F709C24C70049404EFF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Alternative substantial equivalence showing</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subsection 513(i)(1) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360c">21 U.S.C. 360c(i)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFA16205A3C3D45718BAAAC26DEE1DBAE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (B) through (F) as subparagraphs (C) through (G), respectively;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H89C48645CB434FB78999F9B9C11B68EA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (A) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H2C82F176759A48A4B74ADF24B1883C8A" style="OLC">
					<subparagraph id="H60160A2CEC46452185C5F2BCB6458754" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H47B3BCC9347E403DBC484EC60E96855E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As an alternative to clause (ii) of subparagraph (A), and for the purpose of determining substantial equivalence under subsection (f) and section 520(l), a person may submit information to the Secretary that demonstrates that a device conforms with national or international standards, standards established or recognized under section 514, or guidance documents developed by the Secretary to demonstrate that a device is as safe and effective as a legally marketed device, notwithstanding technological differences.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3C7376E505D64F779612BB663031560C" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Any person may propose to the Secretary, for purposes of clause (i), a national or international standard, a standard established or recognized under section 514, or a guidance document developed by the Secretary. Not later than 60 days after receipt of any such proposal, the Secretary shall provide to the person submitting the proposal a written determination—</text>
 <subclause id="HEBBC8509372B4551838FF4DC4DF23AA0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>accepting all, part, or none of the proposal for purposes of demonstrating substantial equivalence under this paragraph; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H3F74273B321940E58E1AC8D869489768"><enum>(II)</enum><text>stating the full rationale (including the scientific, technical, and regulatory basis) for the Secretary’s determination.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H144C076113CF405695E58A071A4D9515" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The Secretary shall—</text> <subclause id="H5BA5A97544824249A777431BB085DBC9"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">except as provided in subclause (II), comply with the requirements for public participation described in section 701(h)(1)(C) before first using a standard or guidance document for purposes of this subparagraph; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H15E2797524934299BFD4968C05F8AD9A"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of establishing or recognizing a standard, comply with the requirements described in section 514 for establishing or recognizing, as applicable, a performance standard.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HA957E57F207C4DF2B49ECEE6447B6B86" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A person submitting a notification under section 510(k) may rely on a standard or guidance document identified, established, or recognized by the Secretary in accordance with clause (iii) to resolve some or all of the differences that exist between a new device and its legally marketed predicate device to demonstrate substantial equivalence.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6885AD0751394E38AA232AE26C94C86F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (F) (as redesignated by paragraph (1)), by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H27179DE4D6BE457A8D2AC3EAF6982981" style="OLC"> <clause id="H5D0AF1CD818B43D0856438898454D824" indent="up3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The reliance on standards or guidance documents to demonstrate substantial equivalence as described in subparagraph (B) shall be optional and have no effect on the establishment of substantial equivalence pursuant to subparagraph (A) where such option is not exercised.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


