<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H352C3089E0F34AE1BF0A62664E0D7BBF" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3391 IH: Medical Marijuana Research Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3391</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170725">July 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000568">Mr. Griffith</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Controlled Substances Act to make marijuana accessible for use by qualified marijuana
			 researchers for medical purposes, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HCBB44397F05246D1AD224706E49DA6A2" style="OLC">
 <section id="H0CB01678A1374D74B9C117F67BEEC69A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medical Marijuana Research Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HD6A64228C3E34314AC9CAA711CE8BA32"><enum>2.</enum><header>Production and supply</header> <subsection id="HBC2A402072C54F23B9E849779AAB9A66"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6068E7A5DAF44881931823229E43B711"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">until the date on which the Secretary determines that manufacturers and distributors (other than the Federal Government) can ensure a sufficient supply of marijuana for qualified marijuana researchers intended for medical research, shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC92637346C9B4617A2C4E65C0DEB7499"><enum>(A)</enum><text>continue to produce marijuana through the National Institute on Drug Abuse (NIDA) Drug Supply Program; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF2DC7ADD8804F9CA21152D803CBD7F2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">offer for sale immature marijuana plants and the seeds of marijuana—</text> <clause id="H8172667313474304BA92AB75957D8335"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to all qualified marijuana researchers who submit a request for such plants or seeds to engage in research pursuant to the section 303(f)(3) of the Controlled Substances Act, as amended by section 3; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7F82F8EBC2774C37A8A2EC1892289050"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in quantities sufficient to produce an adequate supply of marijuana for such research; and</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H884B8CC6AD5C4945890BA9B248FF29CF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>beyond the date specified in paragraph (1), may, at the Secretary’s discretion, continue to so produce and supply marijuana.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HCF9E43A4C9404DEA8BA5E35A07AED5B5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement To verify registration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before supplying marijuana to any person through the National Institute on Drug Abuse Drug Supply Program, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H6AF579898098410D82277D25F7ED2708"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require the person to submit documentation demonstrating that the person is a qualified marijuana researcher seeking to conduct research pursuant to section 303(f)(3) of the Controlled Substances Act, as amended by section 3; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H03396019300B4D4081C03D09E78BBB71"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 30 days after receipt of such documentation, review such documentation and verify that the marijuana will be used for such research (and for no other purpose authorized pursuant to this Act).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB9EDF976851546B69EF3EF5813B15C06"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Guidelines on production</header><text>The Commissioner of Food and Drugs, in consultation with the Director of the National Institute on Drug Abuse, shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD1D83B54E6CD40108537C2810EB07759"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, issue guidelines on the production of marijuana by qualified marijuana researchers pursuant to subsection (a)(1)(B); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H91AF9C6DE1FA4057BCEDC30C9C46C9FC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourage researchers and manufacturers that are authorized to produce or manufacture marijuana pursuant to section 303 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/823">21 U.S.C. 823</external-xref>), as amended by this Act, to comply with such guidelines to the extent applicable.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEE9511EF98C74DF9AF6FD01DE8134458"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HAE611C91619B4EA3BF50A3E904B019FF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>immature marijuana plant</term> means a marijuana plant with no observable flowers or buds.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBA23259DDF0B494B932BB8FF1897CD19"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified medical marijuana researcher</term> means a researcher who is registered to conduct research with marijuana under section 303(f)(3) of the Controlled Substances Act, as amended by section 3.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC359E9A8130E4A93AC1FFF6865CA80A9" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Facilitating marijuana research</header>
 <subsection id="HDF4388B676A547D6B2E76E5E3E4C77BC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 303(f) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/823">21 U.S.C. 823(f)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HE8E6FACB296F4B49A371F8BFB5637913"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating paragraphs (1) through (5) as subparagraphs (A) through (E), respectively;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H33F49E94BC1A48E0B8ADB04F0293E41F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(f) The Attorney General</quote> and inserting <quote>(f)(1) The Attorney General</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD032C36798FB43E4962FCC8B00FBF996"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Registration applications</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEEBD96BC03AB4F9680A376338253804E" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H17AAA374321B4DFCA1B803DA609B4E0A" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Registration applications</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6C66E8B3C3B1476CA32ED3F7A61BE8B1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), as so designated, by striking <quote>schedule I</quote> each place that term appears and inserting <quote>schedule I, except marijuana,</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB91B71A61CFE4E1AAA6888076A58E3F4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Article 7</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBFBE048CB8F843A0BD994243F6F503C2" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HC8436AC10DAC4B68A79956EA20216F43" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Article 7</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2FB2A9C526684A10B2733FB0001E7307"><enum>(6)</enum><text>by inserting before paragraph (4), as so designated, the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H01467AECE8544D86BEE1A62C59DB45B6" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HA01122D31B54474494F7498BD94FB6F4" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H35F9B63E66E54AC9A30D7DA92E9B4413"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Attorney General shall register a practitioner to conduct research with marijuana if—</text>
 <clause id="HD0D4629AAEDB4EFAAB57274E392D2FFA" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the applicant is authorized to dispense, or conduct research with respect to, controlled substances in schedules II, III, IV, and V under the laws of the State in which the applicant practices;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEDC727905B794B55899C303C507A4E2F" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the applicant is only using marijuana manufactured by a person registered under subsection (k);</text> </clause><clause id="HCC9087F8DE244275B04750579369B3C4" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the applicant’s research protocol—</text>
 <subclause id="H5541A717F0F64F02AB810B283131D7ED"><enum>(I)</enum><text>has been reviewed and allowed by—</text> <item id="H0D775A5EAFF44282886304F9EE61E17A"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the Secretary under section 505(i) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355(i)</external-xref>); or</text>
 </item><item id="H1853BDBF28664370B6161ADCB535DD69"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the National Institutes of Health or another Federal agency that funds scientific research; or</text> </item></subclause><subclause id="H8815B1DBE3394F5DAD2EE852B26185BD"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the case of nonhuman research that is not federally funded, has been voluntarily submitted by the applicant to, and approved by, the National Institutes of Health; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H53D59152947D4EE1B01EEFF8EACDC28A" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the applicant has demonstrated that there are effective procedures in place to adequately safeguard against diversion of the marijuana from legitimate medical or scientific use, in accordance with subparagraph (E).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78E99C77C3F041CF8FFBF38DD83027DA" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Attorney General shall grant an application for registration under this paragraph unless the Attorney General determines that the issuance of the registration would be inconsistent with the public interest. In determining the public interest, the following factors shall be considered:</text>
 <clause id="HEBE445A503C14A428D5697655C955494"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The applicant’s experience in dispensing, or conducting research with respect to, controlled substances.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB1CB25B8C67B4DC08E2A9A8D6C87F7DC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The applicant’s conviction record under Federal or State laws relating to the manufacture, distribution, or dispensing of controlled substances.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCD08CCFC86CB407191A13D26F2B2C7C6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Compliance with applicable State or local laws relating to controlled substance misuse or diversion.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8D3FBDA318148CEABF182FEA5C448D8" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Medical Marijuana Research Act of 2017</short-title>, for purposes of subparagraph (A)(ii)(II), the National Institutes of Health shall establish a process that—</text>
 <clause id="H35F0FC455DC24009AE8CBAEBE50564D6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>allows a researcher to voluntarily submit the research protocol of the researcher for review and approval; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H682A9A4AAC8A41B3BB26ABA49D07E7B9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provides a researcher described in clause (i) with a decision not less than 30 days after the date on which the research protocol is submitted.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD3C051A43AF74A6693620ACF219DE204" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H3C6EDD538CB247C9BD5198E7DACB3BD0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Not later than 60 days after the date on which the Attorney General receives a complete application for registration under this paragraph, the Attorney General shall approve or deny the application.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAEDC0F859517495DAE4052DDA1E3507C" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>For purposes of clause (i), an application shall be deemed complete when the applicant has submitted documentation showing that the requirements under subparagraph (A) are satisfied.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HCA6B3216757141E9ABFA3458F48DD5C1" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a denial under clause (i), the Attorney General shall provide a written explanation of the basis for the denial and a description of any curative steps that may be taken for such request to be approved.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7558E9E8D1694027B13AE1AFFDD4AE20" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA73479B7243248D38ECADEDF55CF89C1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A researcher registered under this paragraph shall store marijuana to be used in research in a securely locked, substantially constructed cabinet.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8A75EDFF19574A2F85E1F4AF5E9AC21D" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Except as provided in clause (i), any security measures required by the Attorney General for practitioners conducting research with marijuana pursuant to a registration under this paragraph shall be consistent with the security measures for practitioners conducting research on other controlled substances in schedule II that have a similar risk of diversion and abuse.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA62B4BAA7504BE0AD20F40C4D1633CF" indent="up1"><enum>(F)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H435F38FEB46C47A181D37A9ED343F921"><enum>(i)</enum><text>If the Attorney General grants an application for registration under this paragraph, the applicant may amend or supplement the research protocol without reapplying if the applicant does not—</text>
 <subclause id="HF7935580FA2844258B2C185207455FA7" indent="up1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>change the type of drug, the source of the drug, or the conditions under which the drug is stored, tracked, or administered; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HBA779056AC324CB982F0593652EC535A" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>otherwise increase the risk of diversion.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HE004F48916E84FDDA28709CFA820E4F1" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>If an applicant amends or supplements the research protocol or initiates research on a new research protocol under clause (i), the applicant shall, in order to renew the registration under this paragraph, provide notice to the Attorney General of the amended or supplemented research protocol or any new research protocol in the applicant's renewal materials.</text>
								</clause><clause id="HC282774934EA44B7848DD019B90E4330" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA1E6A4571B3A4DC3AB88E2F93E84E749"><enum>(I)</enum><text>If an applicant amends or supplements a research protocol and the amendment or supplement involves a change to the type of drug, the source of the drug, or conditions under which the drug is stored, tracked, or administered or otherwise increases the risk of diversion, the applicant shall provide notice to the Attorney General not later than 30 days before proceeding on such amended or supplemental research or new research protocol, as the case may be.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H977C3054D1D64EA7897574EA8EA560C6" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>If the Attorney General does not object during the 30-day period following a notification under subclause (I), the applicant may proceed with the amended or supplemental research or new research protocol.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H88253A5E7B95426188046C683C055751" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The Attorney General may object to an amended or supplemental protocol or a new research protocol under clause (i) or (iii) only if additional security measures are needed to safeguard against diversion or abuse.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H39723AC65904449C97D866A4F82D449E" indent="up1"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If marijuana or a compound of marijuana is listed on a schedule other than schedule I, the provisions of paragraphs (1), (2), and (4) that apply to research with a controlled substance in the applicable schedule shall apply to research with marijuana or that compound, as applicable, in lieu of the provisions of subparagraphs (A) through (G) of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF7509912D4824BA6BBECDF4D2366B1D0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 102(16) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802(16)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>or <term>marijuana</term></quote> after <quote>The term <term>marihuana</term></quote>.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H414194E25F4245D9BAA7EBFC9C3C513E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Manufacture and distribution of marijuana for use in legitimate, medical research</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 303 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/823">21 U.S.C. 823</external-xref>), as amended by section 3, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H548DEAC5EC3B4881B0FCAFC8EA65E5E4" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="H82C15B8233564258A2361E7D2DB5F5DF"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Registration of persons To manufacture and distribute marijuana for use in legitimate, medical
			 research</header>
 <paragraph id="H975EB12CD9504C19BC6FE176691847B8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Registration of manufacturers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than the day that is 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Medical Marijuana Research Act of 2017</short-title>, the Attorney General shall register an applicant to manufacture marijuana to the extent the marijuana will be used exclusively by qualified marijuana researchers for research pursuant to subsection (f)(3), unless the Attorney General determines that the issuance of such registration is inconsistent with the public interest. In determining the public interest, the Attorney General shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H40DADEEDC0C1405499D00D0AAFA0FF0E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>take into consideration—</text> <clause id="HF6DE47632E5140669A66160DAF06CC9A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>maintenance of effective controls against diversion of marijuana and any controlled substance compounded therefrom into other than legitimate medical, scientific, or research channels;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAED498FE1DE74BA4A00E8DA38E83F81D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>compliance with applicable State and local laws relating to controlled substance misuse and diversion; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H50240E475A62473892B0586035B9F1C3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>prior conviction record of the applicant under Federal or State laws relating to the manufacture, distribution, or dispensing of such substances; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1070B9BFC2EF4116BA38D4014211415C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not take into consideration any factors other than the factors listed in subparagraph (A).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3BD58E2C382E410CA63FDD600FFC59AB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Registration of distributors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than the day that is 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Medical Marijuana Research Act of 2017</short-title>, the Attorney General shall register an applicant to distribute marijuana that is intended to be used exclusively by qualified medical marijuana researchers for research pursuant to subsection (f)(3), unless the Attorney General determines that the issuance of such registration is inconsistent with the public interest.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HABBD412D17FF45BAA554A9A23FAD2A3D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public interest</header><text>In determining the public interest under paragraph (2), the Attorney General shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H6CA62C8F5B6F4C1BB3DDE884D79D0955"><enum>(A)</enum><text>take into consideration—</text>
 <clause id="H78EEDD504E74466EA958572CBC73A17A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>maintenance of effective controls against diversion of marijuana and any controlled substance compounded therefrom into other than legitimate medical, scientific, or research channels;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE8CF1DF412E140D3B6171C3CEBEBAD09"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>compliance with applicable State and local law;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HDB029AFCDC784776B114BB8A487F845C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>prior conviction record of the applicant under Federal or State laws relating to the manufacture, distribution, or dispensing of such substances; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HA2D2BCA1C41A463DA583507EEB6FA0A0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>past experience in the distribution of controlled substances, and the existence in the establishment of effective controls against diversion; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7A9E480099C4D6D8715E28D1F422913"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not take into consideration any factors other than the factors listed in subparagraph (A).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H86CB45C830D24D8C9D0B956AA5E979C9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>No limit on number of manufacturers and distributors</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Attorney General shall not impose or implement any limit on the number of persons eligible to be registered to manufacture or distribute marijuana pursuant to paragraph (1) or (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H911570D07F754D3A9CC6F474E6B12C07"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Requirement to verify use for legitimate, medical research</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a condition on registration under this section to manufacture or distribute marijuana, the Attorney General shall require the registrant—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7D15931490074393A3033F31758F835F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to require any person to whom the marijuana will be supplied to submit documentation demonstrating that the marijuana will be used exclusively by qualified medical marijuana researchers for research pursuant to subsection (f)(3);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31C98B1AC3BF41948BB6ABFEEDED56C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of distribution, to complete, with respect to that distribution, the DEA Controlled substance order form (DEA 222) (or a successor form) and the DEA Certificate of Registration (DEA Form 223) (or a successor form) and to upload such forms to the system used by the Drug Enforcement Agency for such distribution;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEBB4CE5D34104F34999256258636643C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to include in the labeling of any marijuana so manufactured or distributed—</text> <clause id="H1BDA77667BF04D42AEE333729A964AAB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the following statement: <quote>This material is for medical and scientific research purposes only.</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1CB4C7A1A0EC4C1896DE8408F4324253"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the name of the requestor of the marijuana; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4098BC3B2EC94E138A816713357A4577"><enum>(D)</enum><text>not later than 30 days after receipt of such documentation, and before supplying the marijuana to such person, to review such documentation and verify that the marijuana will be so used.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H855FE753FA7642119C84E925A8B42E7D"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>Not later than 30 days after receipt of a request for registration under this subsection to manufacture or distribute marijuana, the Attorney General shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H16AB16EA6B8F4A9AB1D259072272F110"><enum>(A)</enum><text>grant or deny the request; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H072CF322D9E04C55B8E16244E999DE80"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a denial, provide a written explanation of the basis for the denial and a description of any curative steps that may be taken for such request to be approved.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H527253E3A4C649CE950D0C91BE311839"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Deemed approval</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Attorney General fails to grant or deny a request for registration under this subsection to manufacture or distribute marijuana within the 30-day period referred to in paragraph (5), such request is deemed approved.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3B7F532EE7B3483C829F7D305AB6ABD6"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>qualified medical marijuana researcher</term> means a researcher who is registered to conduct research with marijuana under subsection (f)(3).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H78DF7867BDF5492FBE7920E808118279" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5.</enum><header>Termination of interdisciplinary review process for non-NIH-funded researchers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services may not—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6686C47C53604A989FBEAA67DF1F4A42"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reinstate the Public Health Service interdisciplinary review process described in the guidance entitled <quote>Guidance on Procedures for the Provision of Marijuana for Medical Research</quote> (issued on May 21, 1999); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAE70FEA43A8543399EE1F53E91155015"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">create an additional review of scientific protocols that is only conducted for research on marijuana other than the review of research protocols performed at the request of a researcher conducting nonhuman research that is not federally funded, in accordance with section 303(f)(3)(A)(ii)(II) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/823">21 U.S.C. 823(f)(3)(A)(ii)(II)</external-xref>), as amended by section 3.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H5C0D0CD5AD4043B4BB6B89BF7556F627"><enum>6.</enum><header>Consideration of results of research</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Immediately upon the approval by the Food and Drug Administration of an application for a marijuana-based drug under section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355</external-xref>), and (irrespective of whether any such approval is granted) not later than the date that is 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4591C9FF99FF48AEAF81C0AD5326D10C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a review of existing medical and other research with respect to marijuana;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8E946EBDD48D4EE9A47175DB56AF40F2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit a report to the Congress on the results of such review; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H106727B091D942B1B6146EEED25DB692"><enum>(3)</enum><text>include in such report whether, taking into consideration the factors listed in section 201(c) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/811">21 U.S.C. 811(c)</external-xref>), as well as any potential for medical benefits, any gaps in research, and any impacts of Federal restrictions and policy on research, marijuana should be transferred to a schedule other than schedule I (if marijuana has not been so transferred already).</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H4BF7C52B9F244BA481D0AAACEAA1A811"><enum>7.</enum><header>No production quotas for marijuana grown for legitimate, scientific research</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 306 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/826">21 U.S.C. 826</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA1D116D31ECF47EFA4D1E38F3D2D1949" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H73127BB73ED94A2E8BB7CD141C1CAE02"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General may only establish a quota for production of marijuana that is manufactured and distributed in accordance with the Medical Marijuana Research Act of 2016 that meets the changing medical, scientific, and industrial needs for marijuana (as defined by the National Institute on Drug Abuse).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="HFCB1751D1C1C4BBFBC5DF2A4552D8F72"><enum>8.</enum><header>Article 28 of the Single Convention on Narcotic Drugs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Article 28 of the Single Convention on Narcotic Drugs shall not be construed to prohibit, or impose additional restrictions upon, research involving marijuana, or the manufacture, distribution, or dispensing of marijuana, that is conducted in accordance with the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/801">21 U.S.C. 801</external-xref> et seq.), this Act, and the amendments made by this Act.</text>
 </section><section commented="no" id="H4A51BAE13E764D829DDE1AA7F15ABC2B"><enum>9.</enum><header>No interference by Department of Justice</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Attorney General of the United States, and any officer or employee of the Department of Justice, shall not interfere with the production, distribution, and sale of marijuana in accordance with this Act and the amendments made by this Act.</text>
 </section><section id="H9282226CDC824524AE973DFB99CE5DE7"><enum>10.</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>marijuana</term> has the meaning given to the term <quote>marihuana</quote> in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>).</text> </section></legis-body></bill> 

