<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCD1F8096106F41F584CF1832403E74C6" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4433 IH: Securing Department of Homeland Security Firearms Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4433</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171116">November 16, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Under Secretary for Management of the
			 Department of Homeland Security to achieve security of sensitive assets
			 among the components of the Department of Homeland Security, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H8F37F8CB5779472CA6A8B26F0E476B7E" style="OLC">
 <section id="HFF11C2A8673E492CBD3B8D1D88357299" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Securing Department of Homeland Security Firearms Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Securing DHS Firearms Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H18E240B319874D1AA8B47A63604EEC76"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="H26F8394FE42B499CAE27D974CF24297A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Department</header><text>The term <term>Department</term> means the Department of Homeland Security.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7A2E68608F1541788A15CECDB2F84DE0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Under Secretary for Management</header><text>The term <term>Under Secretary for Management</term> means the Under Secretary for Management of the Department of Homeland Security.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H0032C46EBC464D438A133655277F80DC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Inclusion of securing firearms and other sensitive assets in responsibilities of Under Secretary
 for Management</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Paragraph (6) of section 701(a) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/341">6 U.S.C. 341(a)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>(including firearms and other sensitive assets)</quote> after <quote>equipment</quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="H4CA64635123943D7B487EBB93D032B88"><enum>4.</enum><header>Management directive</header>
			<subsection id="H3A4CF4EB1C56443A9EE75DA17D4141B3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Safeguarding firearms and sensitive assets directive</header>
 <paragraph id="H6CFB4E1471C34331916CDFC7647A2FC1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Under Secretary for Management shall disseminate a Department-wide directive for achieving adequate security over firearms and other sensitive assets across the Department.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H85EAE510E2B048BFA61CDB43033D83D2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The directive required under subsection (a) shall, at a minimum, include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H86D7770AADBC4C15B09BEFA052320D91"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Descriptions of what equipment, in addition to firearms, is classified as a sensitive asset for the purpose of carrying out this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE96F04CD0FA406AB498B8B50FF887A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Requirements for securing Department-issued firearms and other sensitive assets.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E2D0B83942A46BF977ED3869B88A6F5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A classification system for all categories of Department-issued badges and corresponding requirements for safeguarding such assets.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06A6D08BE322405CB854998D5145739F"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reporting requirements for lost firearms and other sensitive assets, including timelines for such reporting, to supervisors, local law enforcement, the Federal Bureau of Investigation’s National Crime Information Center, and Department headquarters.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1EF333E6998D4625A80C4B34D4D3C898"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Recordkeeping requirements for lost firearms and other sensitive assets in inventory systems, including a timeline for recording such losses.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H865A9DECE899438DBAAC6B36DFA34929"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Review and update of directive</header><text>Not later than one year after the issuance of the directive required under subsection (a) the Under Secretary for Management shall review and update, as necessary, such directive, including adding a requirement relating to recording in the inventory systems maintained by each component of the Department the acceptance or transfer of a firearm or other sensitive asset by such component.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6297722D6328452FB11454F073EE2B81"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Personal Property Asset Management Program Manual</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Together with the issuance of the directive pursuant to subsection (a), the Under Secretary for Management shall disseminate a revised version of the Personal Property Asset Management Program Manual that includes the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H6CADD4F904054AF6ACCBD34DEAC9E564"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Procedures to safeguard sensitive assets during on- and off-duty time, and utilization of safety locking devices and policies on the use of such assets, as applicable.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9FE2E141EDE44F95A57F48877A2A0E79"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Initial, recurrent, and remedial training on safeguarding such assets.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1102ED2CAA6542B4AAEA7EE1F6A77C7C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Examples, with detail, of how to record lost sensitive assets across components of the Department, and an enforcement mechanism to ensure supervisors maintain such records.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H19B1AB4676824E77A0960E6A7B0155C8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A requirement that the file maintained on a lost firearm or other sensitive asset contains both the corresponding police report and the Department report detailing the circumstances surrounding such loss, including information on adherence to safeguarding procedures.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H68485379E31D44BD99F93608425E58A0"><enum>5.</enum><header>Component responsibilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Department component heads shall—</text> <paragraph id="H2629F5DD426B4BEE87770D020F5EDDFC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>comply with Federal law, Federal regulations, executive branch guidance, and Department policy, including directives required by this Act, relating to the management and oversight of securing firearms and other sensitive assets;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4C8B4599C0944D8A8ADA4022084D09DD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>review the need for non-law enforcement badges;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H309891119081479F91C497FB9E1AE09B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>require component personnel to safeguard firearms and other sensitive assets in accordance with the directive issued by the Under Secretary for Management under section 4;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H625D6B85039C4A1C87B851229152AA3B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>require that component personnel adhere to the procedures and timelines for properly reporting to supervisors lost firearms and other sensitive assets;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H99EE4E5302514E359CE39B2DD4250B8F"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require that lost firearms and other sensitive assets are reported to local law enforcement, the Federal Bureau of Investigation’s National Crime Information Center, and Department headquarters in the timeframe established in such directive; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE66A0749C1E14E9D9FC8850D61E32756"><enum>(6)</enum><text>require that lost firearms and other sensitive assets are recorded in inventory systems in the timeframe established by such directive.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H2308CECB5963403688FB16C8339F6533"><enum>6.</enum><header>Inspector General review</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security shall, on an ongoing basis, review implementation of this Act and, not later than 180 days after issuance of the directive under section 4, submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a review of the progress and effectiveness of such directive, including an assessment of the adequacy of such directive, as well as the level of compliance among the components of the Department to achieve adequate security of sensitive assets across Department components.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


