<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H05E885892B3E487EB5B5D54C095256A1" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2311 IH: Express Appeals Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2311</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170503">May 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000170">Mr. O'Rourke</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001073">Mr. Hurd</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001184">Mr. Massie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000066">Mr. Young of Iowa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001106">Mr. Costello of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000565">Mr. Loebsack</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a pilot program to provide veterans the
			 option of using an alternative appeals process to more quickly determine
			 claims for disability compensation.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HB588374128BF434BAEC8CFB46B56E908" style="OLC">
 <section id="HEC0B7C480B1842BEB17102B4419C470B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Express Appeals Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H26B76554925F499295C1E2E6CE68B082" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pilot program on fully developed appeals</header> <subsection id="HE317388487E64DC78A4EEE90106A9D2A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall carry out a pilot program to provide the option of an alternative appeals process that shall more quickly determine such appeals in accordance with this section.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H01FCF7E844B44F31A1AAF99E9F08DD98"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Election</header>
 <paragraph id="HABAB314BBCB9457AB42AFCE03D7350DB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Filing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In accordance with paragraph (2), a claimant may elect to file a fully developed appeal under the pilot program under subsection (a) by filing with the Secretary the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2D9D34CD37DE491FBC81472FFF551070"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The notice of disagreement under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/71">chapter 71</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, along with the written election of the claimant to have the appeal determined under the pilot program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H242161DD66074ADDB002CDED3C61CF5E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>All evidence that the claimant believes is needed for the appeal as of the date of the filing.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF582618F1D2242B1A65E63BF25588726"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A statement of the argument in support of the claim, if any.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBBA7A06C7F794331B936F5171909DE49"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>A claimant shall make an election under paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H95FCDA8759184A508CDAE50B7FBF8A38"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the claimant has filed a traditional appeal with respect to the claim for disability compensation before the date on which the pilot program under subsection (a) commences, at any time during the traditional appeal process, notwithstanding paragraph (1)(A); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2592C0D556AF4333BEEC8781E4258654"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the claimant has not so filed a traditional appeal with respect to the claim for disability compensation before such date, as part of the notice of disagreement filed by the claimant in accordance with paragraph (1)(A).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H24A5D55DFBD4485595A1CDE156416D5F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Change of processing</header><text>If a claimant described in paragraph (2)(A) seeks to elect to make an election under paragraph (1) to change a traditional appeal to a fully developed appeal, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H8ABF77E2E81B45C58EDC70DDC9CE4183"><enum>(A)</enum><text>inform the claimant of whether, in light of such traditional appeal being processed, the claimant will achieve any time savings through such a fully developed appeal; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H885EBA8F86E74ADEBF8FF931EBDAF5D2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the claimant elects to file such fully developed appeal, process the fully developed appeal in accordance with this section to the extent practicable.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE8034A8CF3834014AB21841FC38248E9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reversion</header><text>At any time, a claimant who makes an election under paragraph (1) may elect to revert to the traditional appeals process without any penalty to the claimant other than the loss of the docket number associated with the fully developed appeal.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE49330B6F20D421BB6CE3CD4B8AA2EFA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Use of fully developed appeal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A claimant may only make an election under paragraph (1) with respect to a claim for disability compensation filed by the claimant that is not, with respect to a claim previously decided by fully developed appeal, a petition to reopen the claim or a separate claim for an increased rating for the claim.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H41D6738AF28247AC98CD1005CBE82FD5"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Outreach</header><text>In providing claimants with notices of the determination of a claim during the period in which the pilot program under subsection (a) is carried out, the Secretary shall provide to the claimant information regarding—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H6C0F3411F6C941F1B24DE56F6C5F724E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the pilot program;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD4D6177D57194BB3A1B9E3CB4A463B5D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how to make an election under paragraph (1);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H92A093687EB54D61848BA8C95EC7035C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>what documents the claimant must provide during the course of the appeals process; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5B3D2E010B57452AB7016C9C00DC00CB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the ability of the claimant to seek advice and education regarding such process from veterans service organizations and attorneys recognized under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/59">chapter 59</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9D23AD42D09243849F4B6DDD3151D415"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Treatment by Department and Board</header>
 <paragraph id="H964A9FF55B3B4F0E88D978A9DFF34EA2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the election of a claimant to file a fully developed appeal pursuant to subsection (b)(1), the Secretary shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5E5B0F5B6D0B4A6281E605930750A1CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not provide the claimant with a statement of the case nor require the claimant to file a substantive appeal; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0A9E69DCC4C4D05AAF2D678F8E0220C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>transfer jurisdiction over the fully developed appeal directly to the Board of Veterans’ Appeals.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC9BB10C6FE844A39AB770FB9B480E981"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Docket</header> <subparagraph id="H88DD1660717449F9B3B51FE7CF538D81"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Board of Veterans’ Appeals shall—</text>
 <clause id="H1C178E55F76544D1A3AA07643E6075D4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>maintain fully developed appeals on a separate docket than traditional appeals;</text> </clause><clause id="H108C6B73C8F34B7485BAFEA748B6B849"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>hear fully developed appeals in the order that the fully developed appeals are received on the fully developed appeal docket;</text>
 </clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9C8A368F364E481C96D921849C021AA9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>except as provided by subparagraph (B), decide not more than one fully developed appeal for each four traditional appeals decided; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3BE315AA421D44A3873E8F76BCE412B1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, decide each fully developed appeal by the date that is one year following the date on which the claimant files the notice of disagreement.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H32D3F44A4F8445699C3F1F34A1456955"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning one year after the date on which the pilot program under subsection (a) commences, the Board may adjust the number of traditional appeals decided for each fully developed appeal under subparagraph (A)(iii) if the Board determines that such adjustment is fair for both traditional appeals and fully developed appeals.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H0FBA3FC16D3746F1B6BC84D6E59D9962"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation on use of new evidence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A claimant may not submit to the Board of Veterans’ Appeals any new evidence relating to a fully developed appeal after filing such appeal unless the claimant reverts to the traditional appeals process pursuant to subsection (b)(4).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H36135317CC004A8680A52DD72C1821B3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Prohibition on remand to regional office</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Board of Veterans’ Appeals determines that a fully developed appeal requires Federal records, independent medical opinions, or new medical exams, the Board shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H47E7F199914B46F5B8FE1CA10258D307"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in accordance with paragraph (5), take such actions as may be necessary to develop such records, opinions, or exams;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H283614C0AF0744019DEBD6BB348292FC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">retain jurisdiction of the fully developed appeal without requiring a determination by the Veterans Benefits Administration based on such records, opinions, or exams;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDFD43E23779466B97A4ADEAED642734"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure the claimant receives a copy of such records, opinions, or exams; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9C3F4BB301E43DF9B67CF614AD76BDF"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide the claimant a period of 45 days after the receipt of such records, opinions, or exams to provide the Board any additional evidence.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD270ADE7D91405F904A90FD2DD06C28"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Development unit</header>
 <subparagraph id="H543BFF60C6AF46A8A3B3E80949218093"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board of Veterans’ Appeals shall establish an office to develop Federal records, independent medical opinions, and new medical exams pursuant to paragraph (4)(A) that the Board determines necessary to decide a fully developed appeal.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF143F1C7B7A4FF5991FEF6E552113C3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall—</text> <clause id="H2E9A663FE5684C24AC659C991BB2932B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>ensure that the Veterans Benefits Administration cooperates with the Board of Veterans’ Appeals in carrying out subparagraph (A); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAF86F236A7494DABB850A6526A5AEA4C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>transfer employees of the Appeals Management Center of the Veterans Benefits Administration to the office of the Board established under subparagraph (A) in a number that the Secretary determines sufficient to carry out such subparagraph.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H5B4A597F6A4F4CA49D7ABA3C401E87C3"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Hearings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 7107 of title 38, United States Code, the Board of Veterans’ Appeals may not provide hearings with respect to fully developed appeals. A claimant may request to hold a hearing pursuant to such section 7107 if the claimant reverts to the traditional appeals process pursuant to subsection (b)(4).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2482D675C93E42C49C239A9786AB946D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duration; application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall carry out the pilot program under subsection (a) for a five-year period beginning one year after the date of the enactment of this Act. This section shall apply only to fully developed appeals that are filed during such period.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB9A8CCD964D14495B37130E1526F3C0D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During each year in which the pilot program under subsection (a) is carried out, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report on the pilot program. The first such report shall be submitted by not later than 180 days after the date on which the pilot program commences. Each report shall include—</text>
 <paragraph id="H63020818D7E6415C8EB2DFFC7F5F6E69"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a recommendation for any changes to improve the pilot program; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H62843A460DCD44DE9E629DCFCDD87BCA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an assessment of the feasibility and advisability of expanding the pilot program.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD359A1A44C5B4BC895E9F57FB72FDEB1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H15204B0105B04972A5CF3E40522B772A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>claimant</term> has the meaning given that term in section 5100 of title 38, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H82F1CA892E4B4E0E8DBD07760DAFF29C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>compensation</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of title 38, United States Code.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H13FBA00375CF431AB8601440DFE80160"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>fully developed appeal</term> means an appeal of a claim for disability compensation that is—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBECCF281638149B48305690947BEB545"><enum>(A)</enum><text>filed by a claimant in accordance with subsection (b)(1); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B5F6CCE86FE4B158092DA346E168893"><enum>(B)</enum><text>considered in accordance with this section.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC56B5C9DEBA84D0299AC4300C4A8DFDC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>traditional appeal</term> means an appeal of a claim for disability compensation that is not a fully developed appeal.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

