<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB6D1B17457174E7389900485F401E4C1" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4532 IH: Shash Jáa National Monument and Indian Creek National Monument Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4532</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171204">December 4, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001114">Mr. Curtis</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001250">Mr. Bishop of Utah</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001192">Mr. Stewart</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000584">Mrs. Love</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To create the first Tribally managed national monument, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HE620A99C15614C009D25BF9E048BE7CD" style="OLC">
 <section id="HF65C86D86D0443B293976DED75971BF7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Shash Jáa National Monument and Indian Creek National Monument Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HD75F2804B41246C28D7C2B8ADEFFAFF3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
			<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
				<toc-entry idref="HF65C86D86D0443B293976DED75971BF7" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HD75F2804B41246C28D7C2B8ADEFFAFF3" level="section">Sec. 2. Table of contents.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HC6D42CB9E6984C2389BA8903770562E3" level="section">Sec. 3. Withdrawal.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H750CFA08C6A04D55BB9AF9FA868BEBEF" level="section">Sec. 4. Proclamation termination.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H59506AFBB3464937A499FD9EFA2DDB94" level="section">Sec. 5. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H5ACA67A518634826ADEF735DE33C1E5E" level="title">Title I—SHASH JÁA NATIONAL MONUMENT</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H1632B8F324B1450ABB50688175A0F6E7" level="section">Sec. 101. Establishment and purpose.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HF98954C74FFB4C098FA408384185E95D" level="section">Sec. 102. Map and legal description.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H1633F7CE3DAE4CE9829B66A9FBBB247B" level="section">Sec. 103. Administration of Shash Jáa National Monument.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H4D44FE801F164EBBBA1DF3EC3E617B17" level="section">Sec. 104. General provisions.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HDD99A22070FC4CB79AA44ED8BB58178B" level="section">Sec. 105. Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HCFB8468C9CEB44F59D6B933CC05772CB" level="section">Sec. 106. Bears Ears Commission.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H1F16B4FFE83C45ED9C558388CBF9B9B7" level="section">Sec. 107. Archaeological resources protection.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HBC02AF73E60042288517E67354BFB789" level="section">Sec. 108. Enhanced resource protection capabilities in the Shash Jáa National Monument.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H63995CE688C1441091734D615A645AA8" level="section">Sec. 109. Scientific research to further purpose of Shash Jáa National Monument.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H554760409C45447BB173A2D33DCECDAC" level="section">Sec. 110. Federal land manager adherence.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H429DD5B535C34644A83E73C23876B51B" level="title">Title II—INDIAN CREEK NATIONAL MONUMENT</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H1BD766AEDBEA40E6BB5564518784729C" level="section">Sec. 201. Establishment and purpose.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H345442CA630E4901BFD72C008BB02375" level="section">Sec. 202. Map and legal description.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HD08DB1F70ACA4507B45CA6A799486491" level="section">Sec. 203. Administration of Indian Creek National Monument.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H33CFD3C68B00482D888A68CBF026D89F" level="section">Sec. 204. General provisions.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HA4C5740BFAB74620ABA231F862094F93" level="section">Sec. 205. Indian Creek Management Council.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HF81491CC727F49B8BFF5CEEC3243020E" level="section">Sec. 206. Bears Ears Commission.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H49ED0014C0AD4A26A9DCAF1B64677B8A" level="section">Sec. 207. Archaeological resources protection.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H2514E8ABE2ED4380896B0F051914B4E0" level="section">Sec. 208. Enhanced resource protection capabilities in the Indian Creek National Monument.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H25C0785D250840FA9C48F0A489157CDB" level="section">Sec. 209. Scientific research to further purpose of Indian Creek National Monument.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HE8609484F44542E580136ADC1649F314" level="section">Sec. 210. Federal land manager adherence.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HC6A7D71F11B6434C94F0D98A4AC47BE8" level="title">Title III—UTAH PUBLIC SCHOOL TRUST LAND CERTAINTY </toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H6E0F895BB7714D6698ABC20FCC9F779A" level="section">Sec. 301. Definitions.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H8D118DD097BD4CB8A244DC189729B492" level="section">Sec. 302. Exchange of land to benefit the Utah Public School Trust.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H0301579E6912458CB9996162D352D9F6" level="section">Sec. 303. Equal value land exchanges and appraisals.</toc-entry>
			</toc>
 </section><section id="HC6D42CB9E6984C2389BA8903770562E3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subject to valid existing rights, all Federal land and interests in land within the exterior boundaries of the Bears Ears National Monument declared under Presidential Proclamation 9558, dated December 28, 2016, is withdrawn from—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF5665B94D9D54C41AE46792D1A0214E2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all forms of entry, appropriation, and disposal under the public land laws;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H292A96036F4E4E3195FDAED3C092439F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE4A02EA52B44D9C83B6E84EAF83B321"><enum>(3)</enum><text>operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H750CFA08C6A04D55BB9AF9FA868BEBEF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Proclamation termination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Presidential Proclamation 9558, dated December 28, 2016, and issued under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/54/3203">chapter 3203</external-xref> of title 54, United States Code, is hereby declared null and void.</text>
 </section><section id="H59506AFBB3464937A499FD9EFA2DDB94"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act $1,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2024.</text>
		</section><title id="H5ACA67A518634826ADEF735DE33C1E5E"><enum>I</enum><header>SHASH JÁA NATIONAL MONUMENT</header>
			<section id="H1632B8F324B1450ABB50688175A0F6E7"><enum>101.</enum><header>Establishment and purpose</header>
 <subsection id="H475289E5BA0849D1B5E8BD44FA9215BC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the valid existing rights, the Federal land comprising approximately 142,337 acres, identified as <quote>Shash Jáa National Unit</quote> and generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Bears Ears National Monument Boundary Modification</quote>, including Moon House Ruin and Doll House Ruin, is hereby established as the <quote>Shash Jáa National Monument</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE1A7AB838A684F3D9898B807D083AC84"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the Shash Jáa National Monument shall be to protect, conserve, and enhance the unique and nationally important historic, sacred, cultural, scientific, scenic, archaeological, natural, and educational resources of the Shash Jáa National Monument.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="HF98954C74FFB4C098FA408384185E95D"><enum>102.</enum><header>Map and legal description</header>
 <subsection id="H8D4938926D67485E80067544F2BBC453"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a map and legal description of the Shash Jáa National Monument established by section 101.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEF2161C6992347F88CA1FAA56E4D5D2A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Force and effect</header><text>The map and legal description submitted under this section shall have the same force and effect as if included in this title, except that the Secretary of the Interior and Secretary of Agriculture may make minor modifications of any clerical or typographical errors in the map or legal description provided these changes are first reported to the State of Utah, San Juan County, Utah, and the Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5C63710502D940EDBC0368B4869CCB3B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>A copy of the map and legal description shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate field offices of the Bureau of Indian Affairs, the Bureau of Land Management, and the Forest Service.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H1633F7CE3DAE4CE9829B66A9FBBB247B"><enum>103.</enum><header>Administration of Shash Jáa National Monument</header>
 <subsection id="HC94A8BEB9B954929A357ED90B4AC21B7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In accordance with this title, the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.), and other applicable laws and regulations, the Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council shall manage the Shash Jáa National Monument in a manner that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6DAD18A195784EEDB32102107CD8CCD4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>furthers the purpose of the Monument;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0DCB1991983A4A2E8A5BA3524D27E444"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages cooperative and innovative management practices between resource managers, private landowners, and the public; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEC9764C881D1427EAA50F7006E5F0627"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes and maintains historic Tribal uses, including hunting, gathering, wood cutting, and cultural and religious uses.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H81FE450302B94AD28FB90F4EE1AFA49F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Management plan</header>
 <paragraph id="H24B7CFD3C2AB45B0A58B5CBD48015DB8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Plan required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act, consistent with the purpose of the monument, the Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council shall develop a comprehensive plan for the long-term management of the Shash Jáa National Monument. The plan may be updated or amended by the Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council in response to changing circumstances or as determined by the Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF3858A4875F64FE1A93DEA035D74C2CF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In developing the management plan, the Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council shall consult with appropriate State and local entities, the Bears Ears Commission, affected Indian Tribes, and the public. In particular, the Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council shall solicit information and proposals as needed to integrate Native American traditional and historical knowledge and special expertise into the management plan of the Shash Jáa National Monument. Such information and proposals may include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC51856FF18954E25BE83DD41FFA9D7F1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>protections for and use of sacred sites;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCBF9E072D08249C8A962584E7FC8DDD9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>cultural and educational programming;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9172D215D0124942BD9F6213A713B3EC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identification of plants, animals, and special resources;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H877D74128459442FB60C94330BB83175"><enum>(D)</enum><text>identification of traditional uses, such as gathering firewood; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD0F30CB8D384B9EB6F342D73A600AE0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>historical and archaeological resources.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE5BAA24708B4F49B742ABE6373B8DC2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rejection of recommendations</header><text>If the Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council does not incorporate written recommendations submitted by State or local entities, the Bears Ears Commission, or affected Indian Tribes into the management plan, the Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council shall submit a written explanation, not less than 30 days before the effective date of the management plan, to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate, and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate outlining the reasons for rejecting the recommendations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE2204A59E6354228BFBA5B7C6544F76A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Relationship with Bears Ears Commission</header><text>In addition to the consultation under paragraph (2), the Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HA6AC1C5450FF4183AFB87755984612EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>carefully and fully consider integrating the traditional and historical knowledge and special expertise of the Bears Ears Commission into the management plan of the Shash Jáa National Monument; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBFB32C4CF9954B1A9E9D9EF17B94EDCB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less than 45 days before the effective date of the management plan for the Shash Jáa National Monument, provide the Bears Ears Commission with a written explanation regarding any written recommendations from the Bears Ears Commission that are not integrated into the management plan for the Shash Jáa National Monument.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H80C6DBA17C7849F39021AACD370BAB63"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Elements included</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The management plan developed under this subsection shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H2C1801E6463B4A9991753D3765B4A618"><enum>(A)</enum><text>allow only those uses of the Shash Jáa National Monument that are determined by the Council to be consistent with the purpose of the Monument;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2AB807F88F34E4DA6F7CD9DF4E7F89F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be consistent with the Native American Graves Protection and Repatriation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/3001">25 U.S.C. 3001</external-xref> et seq.), the American Indian Religious Freedom Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1996">42 U.S.C. 1996</external-xref> et seq.), Executive Order 13007, division A of subtitle III of title 54, United States Code (formerly the National Historic Preservation Act), and the Archaeological Resources Protection Act of 1979 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/470aa">16 U.S.C. 470aa</external-xref> et seq.) to protect and preserve and minimize disturbance to covered sites and properties, including human remains;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB927C6253684FD284817C5DCC8C69C5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>integrate Native knowledge (as defined in section 219.19 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations) to improve social, economic, and ecological sustainability in accordance with Forest Service regulations set forth in section 219 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations, or successor regulations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E3055846C6841D4BBE32D05AB19D4AA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>allow for the continued use and access (including by motorized vehicle) of the Shash Jáa National Monument—</text>
 <clause id="H66659919E35E4EFB90C929DD6C515138"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for traditional and cultural ceremonies;</text> </clause><clause id="H1E2D162A96D24633B4A47233A7A08C3D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>as a source of traditional plants and other materials for subsistence and other uses in accordance with Federal law; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD9F28101755E467FAFC48F4423EA271E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>for any other activities deemed appropriate, in consultation with the Shash Jáa Archaeological Resources Protection Unit;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEFAB4F0A7634457390C08FF76F487B62"><enum>(E)</enum><text>allow grazing where grazing was established before the date of the enactment of this Act—</text> <clause id="HEB050CC935DE4B259EE556A387AC438B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>subject to such reasonable regulations, policies, and practices as the Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council deems necessary;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H64323844B19445D88DF798172F6F43C3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>subject to all applicable laws; and</text> </clause><clause id="HC70BB9E000A544C2B62A6F0724BECEC2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>with adjustments only allowed in the numbers of livestock allowed as a result of revisions in the normal grazing and land management planning and policy setting process;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAAE8328A5E9E4E348C14EBE9606696E9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>allow commercial recreation activities within the Shash Jáa National Monument in accordance with this title and all other applicable laws and regulations; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22536AADD3694927BAD8E2D6872D7F08"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">allow wildland fire operations in the Shash Jáa National Monument consistent with the purpose of the Shash Jáa National Monument.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H109A39D155C0431EBAD8236BF56C421E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Donations</header><text>The Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council may accept, hold, administer, and use gifts, bequests, donations of funds or real property within the boundaries of the Shash Jáa National Monument, and devices (including labor and services) to further the purposes of the Shash Jáa National Monument and to administer the Monument. Donations accepted under this subsection shall be considered as a gift or bequest to or for the use of the United States.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H4D44FE801F164EBBBA1DF3EC3E617B17"><enum>104.</enum><header>General provisions</header>
 <subsection id="H8B1D59A1A2174EB98A7EC15CE50562E4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Withdrawals</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, all Federal land and interests in land that is acquired by the United States within the Shash Jáa National Monument after the date of the enactment of this Act, is withdrawn from—</text>
 <paragraph id="HEFC64BA395E84CFFABE4A1A143D219FA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all forms of entry, appropriation or disposal under the public land laws;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1B40B333916747639A5AB0FDD8EC2E41"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEC46517404894B48837F3DA77099917C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H80A785B141B04F0289080E0A830640EB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Land acquisition</header> <paragraph id="HB3BAC47B692F40CCAFF59812FAA21D66"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture, as appropriate, may acquire lands or interest in lands within the exterior boundaries of the Shash Jáa National Monument by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, exchange, or transfer from a Federal agency only with the concurrence of the Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF23E2643342F4669A8BE9ECBD458330F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No eminent domain or condemnation</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture may not use eminent domain or condemnation to acquire land or interest in land within the exterior boundary of the Shash Jáa National Monument.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H91C73D12A3C247B8960653B11C871E41"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Incorporation in national monument</header><text>Any land or interest in land located inside the exterior boundary of the Shash Jáa National Monument that is acquired by the United States after the date of the enactment of this Act shall be added to and administered as part of the Shash Jáa National Monument.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H452C45A5B23E403D853DE135FE2CB528"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exclusion of non-Federal land</header><text>The Shash Jáa National Monument includes only Federal land and interests in Federal land and does not include private property or other non-Federal land and interests in land. The management plan developed and implemented under this title shall not apply to private property or non-Federal land or interests in land.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H526F5A85F38941B49A9565E7BBEAB5E9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Water rights</header><text>Nothing in this title—</text> <paragraph id="H411B3818B072409FA6C4E3D2F7E094B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>affects the use or allocation, in existence on the date of the enactment of this Act, of any water, water right, or interest in water;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA25FB86D645F49248D4538D18DFE9678"><enum>(2)</enum><text>affects any vested absolute or decreed conditional water right in existence on the date of the enactment of this Act, including any water right held by the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDEA4556D14024078BD95BFA8FB14D9ED"><enum>(3)</enum><text>affects any claims or rights to water not yet asserted or finally determined;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8DC7D0C79CE84EABB053A7D3D4B43C1D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>affects any interstate water compact in existence on the date of the enactment of this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEAD9F52DC3D0484C80F5AAC5D5CA8E83"><enum>(5)</enum><text>authorizes or imposes any new reserved Federal water rights; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2EEAB30FF60A4E70A5175C60C99C7651"><enum>(6)</enum><text>relinquishes or reduces any water rights reserved or appropriated by the United States in the State of Utah on or before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H94910EA7651741AFB26CBB6DD59026FE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Fish and wildlife</header><text>Nothing in this title affects the jurisdiction of the State of Utah with respect to the management of fish and wildlife in the State.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB5F8263FCB3E4C858DABEDE6F1A1EBBC"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Emergency response</header><text>Nothing in this title alters the authority or responsibility of any party with respect to emergency response activities within the Shash Jáa National Monument, including wildfire response.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7887504D1B3E4ED787B2BF348EF805C5"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Overflights</header><text>Nothing in this title shall preclude overflights of military aircraft, the designation of special-use airspace, or the use or establishment of military flight training routes over the Shash Jáa National Monument.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1F75FF8A46814F2BAAD3B1A0A85A5FE6"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Tribal rights</header><text>Nothing in this title affects the rights of any federally recognized Indian Tribe or any treaty right.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="HDD99A22070FC4CB79AA44ED8BB58178B"><enum>105.</enum><header>Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council</header>
 <subsection id="HAD36CB3B02234D98938F47AE24439DF4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council shall—</text> <paragraph id="HE5166ED175C24A89A13412B314874C33"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop and implement the comprehensive management plan required by section 103; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H585F5E9AE1A6487FA0F5260B33D2CCB2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>regularly and meaningfully engage with the Bears Ears Commission regarding the management of the Shash Jáa National Monument.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4F588DD9812E49E0BB6CEEE41A964460"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council shall be composed of the following members appointed not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act by the President:</text>
 <paragraph id="HCC5324AB66C1404D84D877DE8AAB6AB1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>One individual from the Department of the Interior or the Department of Agriculture.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9A1DD7708BD443AFA78922B89B681260"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Six individuals, in consultation with the Congressional delegation from the State of Utah, who shall represent the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC674BC7BD2014CF68C49842A4E92CBDC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Three who are members of the Navajo Nation, one of whom must represent the Aneth Chapter of the Navajo Nation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2264618A4D2649A7A6C6D324E0C6693B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>One who is a member of the White Mesa Utes of the Ute Mountain Ute Tribe.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBDCCEC7422664F1F9F34F1CFCA158B5F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Two who are members of the San Juan County, Utah, Board of Commissioners.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3061DCABC61A4AC591B48CBD2317E808"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>Of the representatives appointed by the President under subsection (b)(2)—</text> <paragraph id="HC257A607D1D142E690B95F592D47153C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>none shall be employees of the Federal Government;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCFB046B0D5774863A62647E14D3BC3AE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>all shall be residents of the State of Utah.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H492A32A11C6C4E44A84EF9F85F8C6B0C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Terms</header><text>The President shall appoint the members of the Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council under subsection (b)(2) for a term of five years, except that the President shall designate staggered terms for the members initially appointed to the Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council. The President may not reappoint a member to more than three consecutive terms.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC6973C95109D471BBCC874FF7F14464C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>The President shall fill Presidentially appointed vacancies on the Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council as soon as practicable after the vacancy has occurred.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H515CF8E935A34623AD2E7CD8C63CF6E5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>Non-Federal members of the Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council shall serve without pay, except for reasonable travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at the rate authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of duties for the Council.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC43671831D7C4D018F33B924B4F2ADCD"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Chair</header><text>The members of the Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council shall select the chair of the Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council from one of the Presidentially appointed representatives under subsection (b)(2) for a term beginning on the date of selection, and ending in five years or until the member’s term of office expires, whichever occurs first.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="H699BFDF13C0249A5842A548C5E8EA5DF"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Annual Shash Jáa Tribal management council report</header>
 <paragraph id="HDD4040122E1146AFBA59C156273E7741"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Public report publication</header><text>Not later than September 30 of each year, the Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council shall post a public report on the Forest Service, Bureau of Land Management, and any Shash Jáa National Monument-affiliated websites maintained by the Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council. If the Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council cannot meet the September 30 deadline in any year, on September 30 the Chair of the Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council shall publicly post on the websites the reasons for such delay and the date on which the submission of the report is anticipated.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAD93F60D4AB94C9DAE2FB0C92F0DAB6E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="HC7192521053743A3B72B5BDAACA1D8AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the actions of the Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council to develop or implement the management plan for the Shash Jáa National Monument;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF33A433A1B74A4D9431A52E3BD150D0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the recommendations made by the State, local entities, the Bears Ears Commission, the Shash Jáa Archaeological Resources Protection Unit, affected Indian Tribes, and the public to the Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council during the preceding year and actions taken by the Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council as a result of the recommendations; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5594D1CB3F648218D56F539E448C479"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an accounting of the expenses of the Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H51EB12DAAB654538B32054A62E294818"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Staff assistance</header><text>The Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council may request administrative staff assistance from Federal employees under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="HEC5FA720678943B0A33A3364D0CF9371"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Meetings</header>
 <paragraph id="HAAA7EB2C95C44C8F95FC9F8B2E143382"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Frequency</header><text>The Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council shall meet at the call of the Chair or a majority of the members. Meetings shall be held no less than once each calendar year. A majority must be present to constitute a quorum to conducting an official meeting of the Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9586431349C9427A8B23E8E454453E8F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Announcement; open meetings</header><text>All meetings of the Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council shall be announced not less than one week in advance in publications of general circulation and shall be open to the public.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HCFB8468C9CEB44F59D6B933CC05772CB"><enum>106.</enum><header>Bears Ears Commission</header>
 <subsection id="H853360DEBC8048779AABC2F4A2B1F295"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established a Bears Ears Commission with the same membership, responsibilities, and duties as that established under Presidential Proclamation 9558, dated December 28, 2016.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5C447965E71E488E8B638A15A8EFD6EC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>In addition to the duties described in subsection (a), the Bears Ears Commission shall provide guidance and recommendations to the Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council and the Shash Jáa Archaeological Resources Protection Unit regarding the development and implementation of the management plan required under section 103(b).</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H1F16B4FFE83C45ED9C558388CBF9B9B7"><enum>107.</enum><header>Archaeological resources protection</header>
				<subsection id="H43D07916837647F3B796A2FBC82F48E7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Shash Jáa Archaeological Resources Protection Unit</header>
 <paragraph id="H53D964F1A0124D3ABEFC6ABFB462A479"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council shall establish and maintain a Shash Jáa Archaeological Resources Protection Unit to provide technical and other specific assistance to help protect, conserve, and enhance the unique and nationally important historic, sacred, cultural, scientific, scenic, archaeological, natural, and educational resources in the Shash Jáa National Monument.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H98DB4448807344F4BEFD83BBFD2AED55"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>Not later than 210 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council shall appoint 9 individuals to the Shash Jáa Archaeological Resources Protection Unit as follows:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0AC3F7E30FCE43528E59F2FB80DB639E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Five individuals with expertise in preserving Tribal relics, artifacts, or other sacred Tribal sites and objects.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D3AF2DE1BA54BF4A6030BACDB317EA6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>One individual with expertise in the preservation of archaeological resources in federally protected areas.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H059392384FC443B1AC9F70A609590ADC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>One individual with expertise in protecting scenic and natural resources.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC99F9D59A2CC4FFC9262F1CFB3EA1A9A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>One individual representing a scientific or educational institution in the State of Utah.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H88E8DA09E9C44DF6A91E12509A3EF7EE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>One individual with historic preservation expertise in the State of Utah.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H173B28CB8A8E4923940CD393A334709B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Shash Jáa Archaeological Resources Protection Unit shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5B4A87955C7A45EBAD538FDF1826C9E2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>advise the Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council on ways to protect, conserve, and enhance the unique and nationally important historic, sacred, cultural, scientific, scenic, archaeological, natural, and educational resources in the Shash Jáa National Monument;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H640DC72FCCD541A1B2EE3400C0C022C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommend educational materials and signage informing visitors of the unique and nationally important historic, sacred, cultural, scientific, scenic, archaeological, natural, and educational resources in the Shash Jáa National Monument;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD632E3FA38CA49D39740C202BB66F1E1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recommend educational materials or signage to prevent the destruction, degradation, vandalism, or looting of sites within the Shash Jáa National Monument; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA02E224FA5B044E3B0F1F46E8F1E1FDB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>not later than 60 days after its establishment under paragraph (2), submit to the Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council information regarding—</text>
 <clause id="H2ACEDBEAE2124D65ABAB1A571000D625"><enum>(i)</enum><text>sites located within the Shash Jáa National Monument at high risk of destruction, degradation, vandalism, or looting;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2D30503A44BC4A179DEAFF930D44FA91"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>specific actions to eliminate, prevent, or minimize destruction, degradation, vandalism, and looting within Shash Jáa National Monument; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4CF9430EA93B495CB79D74E15E261ED3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>suggestions for additional administrative or other actions to help eliminate, prevent, or minimize destruction, degradation, vandalism, or looting within Shash Jáa National Monument.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB1FDB8F7A3174943AF15BAD9A7B72322"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Terms</header>
 <subparagraph id="H9FFFB195E0CF440A9436C7ABF404941E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of the Shash Jáa Archaeological Resources Protection Unit shall serve a term of 5 years beginning on the date of appointment, except that the Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council shall designate staggered terms for the members initially appointed to Shash Jáa Archaeological Resources Protection Unit.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB00D17F654294FC4BD4BD4B41BAD6C24"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>The Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council shall make appointments to fill vacancies on the Shash Jáa Archaeological Resources Protection Unit as soon as practicable after the vacancy has occurred.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8BA15089ACA44123AE0A18C69ABA7BCB"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>Members of the Shash Jáa Archaeological Resources Protection Unit shall serve without pay, except for reasonable travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at the rate authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of duties for the Unit.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H852064DB2F4442EAB966FFB3797BC353"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Staff assistance</header><text>The Shash Jáa Archaeological Resources Protection Unit may request administrative staff assistance from Federal employees under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture or State employees under the jurisdiction of the State of Utah.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC342CAB85033478690BFDB6A07276EA8"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Shash Jáa Archaeological Resources Protection Unit shall meet at the call of the Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council or a majority of its members. Meetings shall be held not less than once per calendar year. A majority must be present to constitute a quorum for the purpose of conducting an official meeting of the Shash Jáa Archaeological Resources Protection Unit.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HBC02AF73E60042288517E67354BFB789"><enum>108.</enum><header>Enhanced resource protection capabilities in the Shash Jáa National Monument</header>
				<subsection id="HF34265D5DBEF418490D89EC85287A698"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Enhanced enforcement capability</header>
 <paragraph id="H4D3CE09894D045B6A66B6829620EA0CD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall assign not less than 10 law enforcement personnel to protect the unique and nationally important historic, sacred, cultural, scientific, scenic, archaeological, natural, and educational resources of Shash Jáa National Monument and its surrounding area, consistent with the management plan developed under section 103(b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H44F1D1B815AB4A299145E4E8F433A006"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Plan compliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall each ensure the law enforcement personnel perform the duties under paragraph (1) consistent with the management plan developed under section 103(b).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8B654BF60CF6421F86DD5CB16FED78B9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Memoranda of understanding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall each enter into memoranda of understanding or cooperative agreements with local, State, or Tribal law enforcement entities to perform the duties described in subsection (a)(1).</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H63995CE688C1441091734D615A645AA8"><enum>109.</enum><header>Scientific research to further purpose of Shash Jáa National Monument</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture may enter into memoranda of understanding or cooperative agreements with educational institutions or other entities with expertise in archaeological, historical, or natural science fields to conduct scientific research in the Shash Jáa National Monument to aid in the development or implementation of the management plan required in section 103(b).</text>
 </section><section id="H554760409C45447BB173A2D33DCECDAC"><enum>110.</enum><header>Federal land manager adherence</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Federal land managers employed by the Bureau of Land Management or the Forest Service and working in the Shash Jáa National Monument shall adhere to the management plan created by the Shash Jáa Tribal Management Council under section 103(b).</text>
			</section></title><title id="H429DD5B535C34644A83E73C23876B51B"><enum>II</enum><header>INDIAN CREEK NATIONAL MONUMENT</header>
			<section id="H1BD766AEDBEA40E6BB5564518784729C"><enum>201.</enum><header>Establishment and purpose</header>
 <subsection id="H79755468E6344059A524F57B17A20DFE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to valid existing rights, the Federal land comprising approximately 86,447 acres, identified as <quote>Indian Creek Unit</quote> and generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Bears Ears National Monument Boundary Modification</quote> is hereby established as the <quote>Indian Creek National Monument</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCFC5ABC2472A4F4593B831DBCB24B84A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purpose of the Indian Creek National Monument shall be to protect, conserve, and enhance the unique and nationally important recreational, historic, sacred, cultural, scientific, scenic, archaeological, natural, and educational resources of the Indian Creek National Monument.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H345442CA630E4901BFD72C008BB02375"><enum>202.</enum><header>Map and legal description</header>
 <subsection id="H912D3A3B15614869A002FA910C88EE14"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a map and legal description of the Indian Creek National Monument established by section 201.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6B5A06208CF647C9BD947B2F5634AD8F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Force and effect</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The map and legal description submitted under this section shall have the same force and effect as if included in this title, except that the Secretary of the Interior and Secretary of Agriculture may make minor modifications of any clerical or typographical errors in the map or legal description provided these changes are first reported to the State of Utah, San Juan County, Utah, and the Indian Creek Management Council.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1FB6EB56BB404EE4B2F04970D2E15864"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>A copy of the map and legal description shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate field offices of the Bureau of Indian Affairs, the Bureau of Land Management, and the Forest Service.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="HD08DB1F70ACA4507B45CA6A799486491"><enum>203.</enum><header>Administration of Indian Creek National Monument</header>
 <subsection id="HF5665B14E9B141EF95290F0C1F314CEA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In accordance with this title, the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.), and other applicable laws and regulations, the Indian Creek Management Council shall manage the Indian Creek National Monument in a manner that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB0724303652E4776A0A36FA1B192CC83"><enum>(1)</enum><text>furthers the purpose of the Monument;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H77C8425B5D5A4F0BA77E2445E17660C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages cooperative and innovative management practices between resource managers, private landowners, and the public; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAD523CE3E39D451F81E6DA1151BEC997"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes and maintains historic uses, including recreation, hunting, gathering, wood cutting, and cultural and religious uses.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H475E343DF7064A14A821FE8CF6572538"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Management plan</header>
 <paragraph id="HBE977625BC464B7F96F551048171C62A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Plan required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act, consistent with the purpose of the monument, the Indian Creek Management Council shall develop a comprehensive plan for the long-term management of the Indian Creek National Monument. The plan may be updated or amended by the Indian Creek Management Council in response to changing circumstances or as determined by the Indian Creek Management Council.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H152E93127C604F3093B075C23C0B38BD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In developing the management plan, the Indian Creek Management Council shall consult with appropriate State and local entities, the Bears Ears Commission, affected Indian Tribes, and the public. In particular, the Indian Creek Management Council shall solicit information and proposals as needed to integrate Native American traditional and historical knowledge and special expertise into the management plan of the Indian Creek National Monument. Such information and proposals may include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H67604F4E7EB744818D3235DB3EFFD1AA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>protections for and use of sacred sites;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8DE1B44D40614D199167A07A87AD43A4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>cultural and educational programming;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H47862FB5D27748EB8504E0EB9941CFF2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identification of plants, animals, and special resources;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92119FA28E4D40349A7AB5F19BF5EBC8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>identification of traditional uses, such as gathering firewood; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6855E1CA895A495087CD097AD78B0BF7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>historical and archaeological resources.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB397839D38F84A04A5DF012444A3ACD1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rejection of recommendations</header><text>If the Indian Creek Management Council does not incorporate written recommendations submitted by State or local entities, the Bears Ears Commission, or affected Indian Tribes into the management plan, the Indian Creek Management Council shall submit a written explanation, not less than 30 days before the effective date of the management plan, to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate, and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate outlining the reasons for rejecting the recommendations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF9FF169059DF49569C5D91C730994CC9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Relationship with Bears Ears Commission</header><text>In addition to the consultation under paragraph (2), the Indian Creek Management Council shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HBAED1F5F4B104E2FA6EC6086BD54BEC6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>carefully and fully consider integrating the traditional and historical knowledge and special expertise of the Bears Ears Commission into the management plan of the Indian Creek National Monument; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37624438412542718B09194922D2FCFA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less than 45 days before the effective date of the management plan for the Indian Creek National Monument, provide the Bears Ears Commission with a written explanation regarding any written recommendations from the Bears Ears Commission that are not integrated into the management plan for the Indian Creek National Monument.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF4E7405FAACF4F758CA0650397CC507F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Elements included</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The management plan developed under this subsection shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HDF6E0560A82243A2BFC5F2C361854952"><enum>(A)</enum><text>allow only those uses of the Indian Creek National Monument that are determined by the Council to be consistent with the purpose of the Monument;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H399E7FB0085F4ACA83B6CD9864BA46C7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be consistent with the Native American Graves Protection and Repatriation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/3001">25 U.S.C. 3001</external-xref> et seq.), the American Indian Religious Freedom Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1996">42 U.S.C. 1996</external-xref> et seq.), Executive Order 13007, division A of subtitle III of title 54, United States Code (formerly the National Historic Preservation Act), and the Archaeological Resources Protection Act of 1979 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/470aa">16 U.S.C. 470aa</external-xref> et seq.) to protect and preserve and minimize disturbance to covered sites and properties, including human remains;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5EF8888B9DF4D78B918C6489C3AADE0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>integrate Native knowledge (as defined in section 219.19 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations) to improve social, economic, and ecological sustainability in accordance with Forest Service regulations set forth in section 219 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations, or successor regulations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3CC30AECA9B049F591097681791A8A0B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>allow for the continued use and access (including by motorized vehicle) of the Indian Creek National Monument—</text>
 <clause id="H9DB79E57EC6344BCBA07E16AA1657E8A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for traditional and cultural ceremonies;</text> </clause><clause id="H0FFBDAC68D224A538126651DA9CAACF1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>as a source of traditional plants and other materials for subsistence and other uses in accordance with Federal law;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H39C5B6B8B9194844A62E31CCB24D5BD3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>for recreational access; and</text> </clause><clause id="H8CE13D8E4A9F4EE4B640AF7EE18A3192"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>for any other activities deemed appropriate, in consultation with the Indian Creek Archaeological Resources Protection Unit;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H821073777E2A4357B9EFE06261373508"><enum>(E)</enum><text>allow grazing where grazing was established before the date of the enactment of this Act—</text> <clause id="H6934681247BD4CA58622ACE18FFFA01C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>subject to such reasonable regulations, policies, and practices as the Indian Creek Management Council deems necessary;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H826B5710621B45EFA6EB5790EC1B4745"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>subject to all applicable laws; and</text> </clause><clause id="HDEBBAF1E9E6643CFAE3DF68EFA86F490"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>with adjustments only allowed in the numbers of livestock allowed as a result of revisions in the normal grazing and land management planning and policy setting process;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9CC696AF8FD04007B05AD6B66DC200CA"><enum>(F)</enum><text>allow commercial recreation activities within the Indian Creek National Monument in accordance with this title and all other applicable laws and regulations; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6C36707AA204F1B8BD3566973CE978A"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">allow wildland fire operations in the Indian Creek National Monument consistent with the purpose of the Indian Creek National Monument.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5762868A030246FABFEB4051A56AF078"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Donations</header><text>The Indian Creek Management Council may accept, hold, administer, and use gifts, bequests, donations of funds or real property within the boundaries of the Indian Creek National Monument, and devices (including labor and services) to further the purposes of the Indian Creek National Monument and to administer the Monument. Donations accepted under this subsection shall be considered as a gift or bequest to or for the use of the United States.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H33CFD3C68B00482D888A68CBF026D89F"><enum>204.</enum><header>General provisions</header>
 <subsection id="HF5FC08ECE4FF40E0B53DCD3AE7BA1E1D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Withdrawals</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, all Federal land and interests in land within the Indian Creek National Monument that is acquired by the United States within the Indian Creek National Monument after the date of the enactment of this Act, is withdrawn from—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF3F68697917341A1BAEBF7D0037C388F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all forms of entry, appropriation or disposal under the public land laws;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H32BB38D34545486EA1BCBD217311C839"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6FA3743CCEED4F47BA1A7705C9F8D325"><enum>(3)</enum><text>operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEDBF6535FA184A14ADC198686FDE64C6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Land acquisition</header> <paragraph id="HB2AD77F0CF734BBAA33FA2AC7B5FAA08"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture, as appropriate, may acquire lands or interest in lands within the exterior boundaries of the Indian Creek National Monument by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, exchange, or transfer from a Federal agency only with the concurrence of the Indian Creek Management Council.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H07D66D3D4D4F44BD874BECD457818744"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No eminent domain or condemnation</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture may not use eminent domain or condemnation to acquire land or interest in land within the exterior boundary of the Indian Creek National Monument.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H769CDD095BC94F92B8D4EB6D0B2CE80B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Incorporation in national monument</header><text>Any land or interest in land located inside the exterior boundary of the Indian Creek National Monument that is acquired by the United States after the date of the enactment of this Act shall be added to and administered as part of the Indian Creek National Monument.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7A4839EFD87C453982999859DB17407F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exclusion of non-Federal land</header><text>The Indian Creek National Monument includes only Federal land and interests in Federal land and does not include private property or other non-Federal land and interests in land. The management plan developed and implemented under this title shall not apply to private property or non-Federal land or interests in land.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB1F585211872452083EF573B058A971F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Water rights</header><text>Nothing in this title—</text> <paragraph id="HE8C23BF64BA444729BC22C2B97E976E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>affects the use or allocation, in existence on the date of the enactment of this Act, of any water, water right, or interest in water;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAF8DD77033AB40E495C92B6E6C340991"><enum>(2)</enum><text>affects any vested absolute or decreed conditional water right in existence on the date of the enactment of this Act, including any water right held by the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE66C53E37B394B6BBE936ED5ECF672C0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>affects any claims or rights to water not yet asserted or finally determined;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H96B1F31C740B471AA9105DCC89CF3BBE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>affects any interstate water compact in existence on the date of the enactment of this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBA9CB938563C491D94FA1F0396E256BA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>authorizes or imposes any new reserved Federal water rights; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF8B64D494BFA4DAFACB5E4EF17F5CED2"><enum>(6)</enum><text>relinquishes or reduces any water rights reserved or appropriated by the United States in the State of Utah on or before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H09B5FC460AE44C479B77FDBE642298BF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Fish and wildlife</header><text>Nothing in this title affects the jurisdiction of the State of Utah with respect to the management of fish and wildlife in the State.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE6E123F0386D44C095D4E6D1C51EDF6C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Emergency response</header><text>Nothing in this title alters the authority or responsibility of any party with respect to emergency response activities within the Indian Creek National Monument, including wildfire response.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H078C5D5039C74A0194104674C783ED98"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Overflights</header><text>Nothing in this title shall preclude overflights of military aircraft, the designation of special-use airspace, or the use or establishment of military flight training routes over the Indian Creek National Monument.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB6E2CB272474414F8BEC6A83F9A33D9A"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Tribal rights</header><text>Nothing in this title affects the rights of any federally recognized Indian Tribe or any treaty right.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="HA4C5740BFAB74620ABA231F862094F93"><enum>205.</enum><header>Indian Creek Management Council</header>
 <subsection id="HE245DC7BABA349F8ABD81C8FB80D44D8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Indian Creek Management Council shall—</text> <paragraph id="H86352DD3F0114F3987875974F6181965"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop and implement the comprehensive management plan required by section 203; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8AB6AECAD6F44F19A7938C26C2804264"><enum>(2)</enum><text>regularly and meaningfully engage with the Bears Ears Commission regarding the management of the Indian Creek National Monument.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD8363647843D4B14B03F5489845DE178"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Indian Creek Management Council shall be composed of the following members appointed not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act by the President:</text>
 <paragraph id="H6247FFAEEDFD42F987B28E53BD949F2A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>One individual from the Department of the Interior or the Department of Agriculture.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H30E4D1BC2A244F22A2D526EFC9F34EAA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Four individuals, in consultation with the Congressional delegation from the State of Utah, who shall represent the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCCC4B71B04B3415291B675BDF15F961B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Two who are members of the San Juan County, Utah, Board of Commissioners.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H262CDE2D18DC4206A4C7D206CEAC36D2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">One who is a representative of the executive branch of the State of Utah with relevant expertise in the purposes of the Indian Creek National Monument.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF04A421E1C3D49769C11A294507C0EDF"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">One who is a member of a federally recognized Indian Tribe in the State of Utah.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4B4F19455A3341A59003D8B96B030551"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>Of the representatives appointed by the President under subsection (b)(2)—</text>
 <paragraph id="HEFB5555DCCA947249571420EF38C71A4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>none shall be employees of the Federal Government;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8D3859175FD3422D9365D4195544B5BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>all shall be residents of the State of Utah.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2FC0531C9A17481BA62E3DC9D4487A89"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Terms</header><text>The President shall appoint the members of the Indian Creek Management Council under subsection (b)(2) for a term of five years, except that the President shall designate staggered terms for the members initially appointed to the Indian Creek Management Council. The President may not reappoint a member to more than three consecutive terms.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H461BD68FC80042F18C96DEBE5FAB7982"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>The President shall fill Presidentially appointed vacancies on the Indian Creek Management Council as soon as practicable after the vacancy has occurred.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0E947878F12D48FE87A5BEA2DA805FCC"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>Non-Federal members of the Indian Creek Management Council shall serve without pay, except for reasonable travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at the rate authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of duties for the Council.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4DC5888BFAC44B5D9EC36FA553DB2A6D"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Chair</header><text>The members of the Indian Creek Management Council shall select the chair of the Indian Creek Management Council from one of the Presidentially appointed representatives under subsection (b)(2) for a term beginning on the date of selection, and ending in five years or until the member’s term of office expires, whichever occurs first.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="H0F86E1DBC48F49A5BC4B97DF0D310DD5"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Annual Indian Creek Management council report</header>
 <paragraph id="HF77E14588DF84B199E415431CD305B2D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Public report publication</header><text>Not later than September 30 of each year, the Indian Creek Management Council shall post a public report on the Forest Service, Bureau of Land Management, and any Indian Creek National Monument-affiliated websites maintained by the Indian Creek Management Council. If the Indian Creek Management Council cannot meet the September 30 deadline in any year, on September 30 the Chair of the Indian Creek Management Council shall publicly post on the websites the reasons for such delay and the date on which the submission of the report is anticipated.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB78680D68F8840DA9F853A4C4CF2A0EE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="H86D7533EA1594207975B07CBE3D3C57D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the actions of the Indian Creek Management Council to develop or implement the management plan for the Indian Creek National Monument;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A91491077ED44A58BAFFB0AD1CF1CDC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the recommendations made by the State, local entities, the Bears Ears Commission, the Indian Creek Archaeological Resources Protection Unit, affected Indian Tribes, and the public to the Indian Creek Management Council during the preceding year and actions taken by the Indian Creek Management Council as a result of the recommendations; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H781769BAC8BB4A92828F6EA40BB5D301"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an accounting of the expenses of the Indian Creek Management Council.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H34567EE83908478993F2C726561BEB27"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Staff assistance</header><text>The Indian Creek Management Council may request administrative staff assistance from Federal employees under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="HB543490AF6E94DF49BACD62D80153AD9"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Meetings</header>
 <paragraph id="H9AAD9F3BF5EA423EADF7A8F477656F76"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Frequency</header><text>The Indian Creek Management Council shall meet at the call of the Chair or a majority of the members. Meetings shall be held no less than once each calendar year. A majority must be present to constitute a quorum to conducting an official meeting of the Indian Creek Management Council.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H03EB0119D23A42E09F5A0598968DEEC3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Announcement; open meetings</header><text>All meetings of the Indian Creek Management Council shall be announced not less than one week in advance in publications of general circulation and shall be open to the public.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF81491CC727F49B8BFF5CEEC3243020E"><enum>206.</enum><header>Bears Ears Commission</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In addition to its duties under title I, the Bears Ears Commission established under section 106 shall advise the Indian Creek Management Council as provided in this title.</text>
			</section><section id="H49ED0014C0AD4A26A9DCAF1B64677B8A"><enum>207.</enum><header>Archaeological resources protection</header>
				<subsection id="HA2C51ACF74BD4E7CBE1A981497C36261"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Indian Creek Archaeological Resources Protection Unit</header>
 <paragraph id="HD2E09C1B09C241D5805226A402828705"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Indian Creek Management Council shall establish and maintain a Indian Creek Archaeological Resources Protection Unit (which may be the same Unit as authorized under section 107) to provide technical and other specific assistance to help protect, conserve, and enhance the unique and nationally important historic, sacred, cultural, scientific, scenic, archaeological, natural, and educational resources in the Indian Creek National Monument.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H927EE14A156C4510BAFBDDFEC04285E4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>Not later than 210 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Indian Creek Management Council shall appoint 9 individuals to the Indian Creek Archaeological Resources Protection Unit as follows:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6B53F7640C9A4FBB9FFDD75C47052080"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Five individuals with expertise in preserving Tribal relics, artifacts, or other sacred Tribal sites and objects.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCBB5D3FB7D00423AA7968513C850B6B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>One individual with expertise in the preservation of archaeological resources in federally protected areas.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBECE7714B38C4E1A9B502AB82018488C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>One individual with expertise in protecting scenic and natural resources.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE3E4D8034F404F8E87C67993749F133F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>One individual representing a scientific or educational institution in the State of Utah.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H91E15C5F33EE44A9AD0E0AF1B9BF6B3B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>One individual with historic preservation expertise in the State of Utah.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H51BC42836CC64182BB7D3ADB61310134"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Indian Creek Archaeological Resources Protection Unit shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA7E2619E12F74B29AEF052E44A0D9F2F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>advise the Indian Creek Management Council on ways to protect, conserve, and enhance the unique and nationally important recreational, historic, sacred, cultural, scientific, scenic, archaeological, natural, and educational resources in the Indian Creek National Monument;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1CFFECC5C9904E58AE59045E10DC180F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommend educational materials and signage informing visitors of the unique and nationally important recreational, historic, sacred, cultural, scientific, scenic, archaeological, natural, and educational resources in the Indian Creek National Monument;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8D70D888511493F8D462F0225EB4AE0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recommend educational materials or signage to prevent the destruction, degradation, vandalism, or looting of sites within the Indian Creek National Monument; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA2E97318C954129B101EA931041BF14"><enum>(D)</enum><text>not later than 60 days after its establishment under paragraph (2), submit to the Indian Creek Management Council information regarding—</text>
 <clause id="HC41EA7C05F6F4756B483F8C107E7BFFB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>sites located within the Indian Creek National Monument at high risk of destruction, degradation, vandalism, or looting;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF005BFB9CEC14CA18DB5AB5B81B7D4AB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>specific actions to eliminate, prevent, or minimize destruction, degradation, vandalism, and looting within Indian Creek National Monument; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA721F38524824453A9D91A415CE125E8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>suggestions for additional administrative or other actions to help eliminate, prevent, or minimize destruction, degradation, vandalism, or looting within Indian Creek National Monument.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H08BC5AAE42304BB58210AE19486D5455"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Terms</header>
 <subparagraph id="H3E9E44B02A0D45FBA4439839DDE8245F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of the Indian Creek Archaeological Resources Protection Unit shall serve a term of 5 years beginning on the date of appointment, except that the Indian Creek Management Council shall designate staggered terms for the members initially appointed to Indian Creek Archaeological Resources Protection Unit.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD15CFBC720A64F26B3857A2B6BCAF4C2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>The Indian Creek Management Council shall make appointments to fill vacancies on the Indian Creek Archaeological Resources Protection Unit as soon as practicable after the vacancy has occurred.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H265324AD1BA843109B329B78E44F7550"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>Members of the Indian Creek Archaeological Resources Protection Unit shall serve without pay, except for reasonable travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at the rate authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of duties for the Unit.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E592415E2DE4591B980B2013C817D03"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Staff assistance</header><text>The Indian Creek Archaeological Resources Protection Unit may request administrative staff assistance from Federal employees under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture or State employees under the jurisdiction of the State of Utah.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H455A31B4EFAA401EBE1B26B0FEA4E1B9"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Indian Creek Archaeological Resources Protection Unit shall meet at the call of the Indian Creek Management Council or a majority of its members. Meetings shall be held not less than once per calendar year. A majority must be present to constitute a quorum for the purpose of conducting an official meeting of the Indian Creek Archaeological Resources Protection Unit.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2514E8ABE2ED4380896B0F051914B4E0"><enum>208.</enum><header>Enhanced resource protection capabilities in the Indian Creek National Monument</header>
				<subsection id="H8B81BEDF568542FEB6BF4743EE40F1B7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Enhanced enforcement capability</header>
 <paragraph id="HD326AE78511641BC8E3D89170955B515"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall assign not less than 10 law enforcement personnel to protect the unique and nationally important recreational, historic, sacred, cultural, scientific, scenic, archaeological, natural, and educational resources of Indian Creek National Monument and its surrounding area, consistent with the management plan developed under section 203(b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3D7CE13EFF1447A183B8CB51854DF613"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Plan compliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall each ensure the law enforcement personnel perform the duties under paragraph (1) consistent with the management plan developed under section 203(b).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H79E9AD9F6674450993E3903B422A277B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Memoranda of understanding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall each enter into memoranda of understanding or cooperative agreements with local or State law enforcement entities to perform the duties described in subsection (a)(1).</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H25C0785D250840FA9C48F0A489157CDB"><enum>209.</enum><header>Scientific research to further purpose of Indian Creek National Monument</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture may enter into memoranda of understanding or cooperative agreements with educational institutions or other entities with expertise in archaeological, historical, or natural science fields to conduct scientific research in the Indian Creek National Monument to aid in the development or implementation of the management plan required in section 203(b).</text>
 </section><section id="HE8609484F44542E580136ADC1649F314"><enum>210.</enum><header>Federal land manager adherence</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Federal land managers employed by the Bureau of Land Management or the Forest Service and working in the Indian Creek National Monument shall adhere to the management plan created by the Indian Creek Management Council under section 203(b).</text>
			</section></title><title id="HC6A7D71F11B6434C94F0D98A4AC47BE8"><enum>III</enum><header>UTAH PUBLIC SCHOOL TRUST LAND CERTAINTY </header>
 <section id="H6E0F895BB7714D6698ABC20FCC9F779A"><enum>301.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text> <paragraph id="H7C13C21E8E444FA1802A3394AA8D51F5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal land</header><text>The term <term>Federal land</term> means the lands identified on the Map as <quote>Federal Land Proposed to Transfer to SITLA</quote> administered by the Bureau of Land Management.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H133BED18A4824A62B14F4D1D27C71175"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Map</header><text>The term <term>Map</term> means the map prepared by the Bureau of Land Management entitled <quote>State and Federal Land Exchange Map</quote> dated _____.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7640FCC7C0F34DA7927974E961819275"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Non-Federal land</header><text>The term <term>non-Federal land</term> means the lands identified on the Map as <quote>State Trust Land Proposed for Transfer to United States</quote> in San Juan County, Utah, as generally depicted on the Map.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5E52CF0C2EFA486ABF9074B439BCE5B1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Permitted existing uses</header><text>The term <term>permitted existing uses</term> means any use authorized under the applicable Bureau of Land Management Resource Management Plan.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA5A0FF85A84041E8A1D33B9EB4B6A298"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0B20C4401E1745879CE47FC2A62AFCBC"><enum>(6)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of Utah, acting as trustee under the Utah State School and Institutional Trust Lands Management Act (Utah Code Ann. 53C–1–101 et seq.) through the Utah School and Institutional Trust Lands Administration.</text>
				</paragraph></section><section id="H8D118DD097BD4CB8A244DC189729B492"><enum>302.</enum><header>Exchange of land to benefit the Utah Public School Trust</header>
 <subsection id="HDEE74BA41B69464BB564C8E22DF77979"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the State offers to convey to the Secretary all right, title, and interest of the State in and to all or part of the non-Federal land, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H15A3B380F6C14C9C95090B2A13441ADB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>accept the offer; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5B0EBBEC274D4E9B9DAD16731B8B9D04"><enum>(2)</enum><text>on receipt of all right, title, and interest in and to the non-Federal land, convey to the State (or a designee) all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to all or part of the Federal land on an equal value basis.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H13D8B400E84D403ABC5FCC725E8C1175"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicable law</header>
 <paragraph id="H65ECAD93E53C40688305006ED39BD95B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The land exchange shall be subject to section 206 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1716">43 U.S.C. 1716</external-xref>) and other applicable law.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H238502DF63884F61A4767D8240E0BBBD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Land use planning</header><text>The Secretary shall not be required to undertake any additional land use planning under section 202 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1712">43 U.S.C. 1712</external-xref>) before the conveyance of the Federal land under this title.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3F25D6265B5E4F538F88862E24224953"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Joint selection required</header><text>The Secretary and State shall jointly select which parcels of Federal land to exchange under subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCB647D75C90E4D80BE4BFD98B8B23AB9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Valid existing rights</header><text>The exchange authorized under subsection (a) shall be subject to valid existing rights and permitted existing uses.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H662D329852AB47D29CDBE7C9FBD66203"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Title approval</header><text>Title to the Federal land and non-Federal land to be exchanged under this title shall be in a format acceptable to the Secretary and the State.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC299F0BA557543D08EEFB0E53C407BF3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Consultation with Tribes</header><text>The Secretary shall consult with any federally recognized Indian Tribe in the vicinity of the Federal land and the non-Federal land to be exchanged under this title before the completion of the land exchange.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H58954C2B54794DBF8C2973FF18D610EB"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Map and legal descriptions</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall finalize a map and legal descriptions of all land to be conveyed under this Act. The Secretary may correct any minor errors in the map or in the legal descriptions. The map and legal descriptions shall be on file and available for public inspection in appropriate field offices of the Bureau of Land Management.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8F83CC36AE6A4FE69A29FB8324999AEC"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Costs of conveyance</header><text>Except as provided in section 303(a)(5), as a condition of conveyance, any costs related to the exchanges shall be allocated in accordance with section 206(f)(2)(B) of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1716">43 U.S.C. 1716(f)(2)(B)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF50A1586EE674E40B90F8DB87A2AA19D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights and permitted existing uses, at the completion of each exchange of Federal land and non-Federal land under this title the non-Federal land shall be—</text>
 <paragraph id="HBC88AD6DE298437B81212DB64D943DE9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">added to the Shash Jáa National Monument or the Indian Creek National Monument, as appropriate, if located within the exterior boundary of the Shash Jáa National Monument or the Indian Creek National Monument; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H45643E9A3D4241AB883CC2F63A1547F4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>administered in accordance with—</text> <subparagraph id="HC8C8009B47D14A479064DB4B39150EF0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>this Act;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC3D23AF6BB145209280DC2B69320BB1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82FE005A810F41F59C81289CB5E39A04"><enum>(C)</enum><text>other applicable laws and regulations.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H757DB3210679454F89D76842FF5FA69F"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>The land exchange under this title shall be completed as expeditiously as possible.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H0301579E6912458CB9996162D352D9F6"><enum>303.</enum><header>Equal value land exchanges and appraisals</header> <subsection id="HB6539995108B4C7A94E135B88E10A673"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Appraisals</header> <paragraph id="H11F59C5CCDE4448A809BA029637F0B96"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The values of the lands to be exchanged under this title shall be determined by appraisals conducted by one or more independent and qualified appraisers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC3745D19FD91422A9ACEBA38CCBF6245"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State appraiser</header><text>The Secretary and the State may agree to use an independent and qualified appraiser retained by the State, with the consent of the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9F79E6D13DF0491E854B7A786D305810"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applicable law</header><text>The appraisals shall be conducted in accordance with nationally recognized appraisal standards, including, as appropriate, the Uniform Appraisal Standards for Federal Land Acquisitions and the Uniform Standards of Professional Appraisal Practice.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H449979CBEC884485ADDFE1B1C45FC26E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Approval</header><text>An appraisal conducted under this title shall be submitted to the Secretary and the State for approval.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H13FFC34FE8A349B3BC9DF9A9C68C56FF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Cost of appraisal</header><text>The cost of an appraisal conducted under this title shall be paid in equal shares by the Secretary and the State. If the State retains an appraiser under paragraph (2), the Secretary shall reimburse the State 50 percent of the costs incurred by the State.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H821968038F464252845185E1DE1F711D"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Minerals</header>
 <subparagraph id="HE47DFBE6A39F4177969BB7A3C70CD76C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Mineral reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The appraisals required under paragraph (1) may take into account mineral and technical reports provided by the Secretary and the State in the evaluation of minerals in the Federal land and non-Federal land.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD793E0B21ED24D8D9290417EA6F1C71B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Mining claims</header><text>Federal land that is encumbered by a mining or millsite claim located under sections 2318 through 2352 of the Revised Statues (commonly known as the <quote>Mining Law of 1872</quote>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/21">30 U.S.C. 21</external-xref> et seq.) shall be appraised in accordance with standard appraisal practices, including, as appropriate, the Uniform Appraisal Standards for Federal Land Acquisition.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE6ACEC0A7D7443CA613F595A67660A6"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>An appraisal conducted under paragraph (1) shall remain valid for 3 years after the date on which the appraisal is approved by the Secretary and the State.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD2AD07A494A54E39BB3937A71593764E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Equalization</header>
 <paragraph id="H083590074F3C4EA5883CF4379B87331B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Surplus of Federal land</header><text>If the final appraised value of the Federal land exceeds the final appraised value of the non-Federal land to be exchanged under this title, the value of the Federal land and non-Federal land shall be equalized—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCF07FB6A29AB4B648A6D8F0180141139"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by conveying additional non-Federal land in the State to the Secretary, subject to the approval of the Secretary; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9B75A51C9EA4E2B9D2D81E4303B4A54"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by using a combination of the methods described in paragraphs (2) and (3).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B2DC7C560404DBCBF86F2A3C22E0AEE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Surplus of non-Federal land</header><text>If the final appraised value of the non-Federal land exceeds the final appraised value of the Federal land to be exchanged under this title, the value of the Federal land and non-Federal land shall be equalized by the State adjusting the acreage of the non-Federal land to be conveyed</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3E8507B893834F9E8D4B1CCAA7102BD1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Amount of payment</header><text>Notwithstanding section 206(b) of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1716">43 U.S.C. 1716(b)</external-xref>), the Secretary may accept a payment under paragraph (1) in excess of 25 percent of the value of the Federal land conveyed.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section></title></legis-body></bill>


