<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H3C7652A70A5B48489F204D6CA9A479B7" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3777 IH: Juab County Conveyance Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3777</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170914">September 14, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000584">Mrs. Love</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to convey certain National Forest System land containing the
			 Nephi Work Center in Juab County, Utah, to Juab County.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H58C82791EB4C48C592109DF9D8412859" style="OLC">
 <section id="H2305FE7E4EE94D8BAC36CBB2216F80CC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Juab County Conveyance Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H35DE62D10D2C48099EEFFC9C294E9713"><enum>2.</enum><header>Land conveyance, Nephi Work Center, Juab County, Utah</header> <subsection id="H0B6B158ED7A148A3B83032EBC802429E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Conveyance required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to valid existing rights, if Juab County, Utah, submits a written request to the Secretary of Agriculture not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall convey, without consideration and by quitclaim deed, to the County all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the parcel of National Forest System land, including improvements thereon, described in subsection (b).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HBDCF5963594D4011825D50C964C14596"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Description of land</header>
 <paragraph id="H64E12C7FBF7946A297F582BDD61BD8CB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The parcel of National Forest System land and improvements to be conveyed under subsection (a) is the Nephi Work Center at 740 South Main Street, Nephi, Utah, which consists of approximately 2.61 acres within Nephi Plat B Block of the Nephi Townsite Survey as Parcels #XA545-1-1-1-1, #XA545-1-2-1, and #XA00-0545-2, and is identified on the map entitled <quote>Nephi Plat B</quote> and dated May 6, 1981.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3D561E521C4C48FCB0A184FFAF755E48"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability of map</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The map referred to in paragraph (1) shall be kept on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate office of the Forest Service. The Secretary may correct minor errors in the map.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3A3AE1014ABB4050963BA756EDE9C21F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Survey</header><text>The exact acreage and legal description of the National Forest System land to be conveyed under subsection (a) shall be determined by a survey satisfactory to the Secretary.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB800D97BECB04661A87B3128F0B57AA1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Costs of conveyance</header><text>As a condition for the conveyance under subsection (a), the County shall pay the reasonable costs incurred by the Secretary for—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8169943BD947471FA75E078DF2D26BA8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the survey required by subsection (c); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF141786460B345A092297CFD2E3034AE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any environmental or administrative analysis required by law related to the conveyance.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA55E40A661174E80BD69C062ACAF3FF2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Additional terms and conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The conveyance under subsection (a) is subject to any other terms and conditions as the Secretary considers appropriate to protect the interests of the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE03106054A2D4FAE8156928D45374906"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Time for completion of conveyance</header><text>The Secretary shall complete the conveyance under subsection (a) not later than one year after the date on which the County submits the written request described in such subsection.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


