<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HFC722C7D23F34F36A4217C7A779558D6" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4590 IH: To provide an exception to certain mandatory minimum sentence requirements for a person employed outside the United States by a Federal agency, who uses, carries, or possesses the firearm during and in relation to a crime of violence committed while on-duty with a firearm required to be carried while on-duty.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4590</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171207">December 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B000755">Mr. Brady of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001053">Mr. Cole</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000815">Mr. Wenstrup</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide an exception to certain mandatory minimum sentence requirements for a person employed
			 outside the United States by a Federal agency, who uses, carries, or
			 possesses the firearm during and in relation to a crime of violence
			 committed while on-duty with a firearm required to be carried while
			 on-duty.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HB1A5917FC7D641DF8E766FD3C82E4314" style="OLC">
		<section id="H79124947A78340C58B287ED830B5FA58" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Exception to certain mandatory minimum sentencing requirements for person employed outside the
			 United States by a Federal agency, who uses, carries, or possesses a
			 firearm during and in relation to a crime of violence committed while
 on-duty with a firearm required to be carried while on-duty</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3261 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEB3C6CEA4F624D0FA0EC9CC01F9471DD" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H5E6C7AD156464540830283CF90FA936B"><enum>(e)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, if the offense is a violation of section 924(c)(1) of this title, the minimum sentencing requirements of section 924(c)(1)(A) of this title shall not apply if—</text>
 <paragraph id="H1D37F038EDE040E1B28F209349FA8993"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the person committed a crime of violence during and in relation to the offense;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDBD8DD7B174F4A18894B9F69AB1677BC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an agency of the United States required the person to carry a firearm while on-duty; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB9FD0032DA8349C5956A4CA1F9CAE4F5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>at the time the person used, carried, or possessed the firearm, the person was employed outside the United States by the agency, and was on-duty.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


