<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1A72DF488FE44962BF9EBEE54FE53C91" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3887 IH: Safeguarding Addresses From Emerging at Home Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3887</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170928">September 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001195">Mr. Smith of Missouri</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001191">Ms. Sinema</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001053">Mrs. Hartzler</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000379">Mr. Kennedy</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require Federal agencies and Federal courts to comply with address confidentiality programs, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HDD344E5EC5DD478383234521D54FA7BA" style="OLC">
 <section id="HF950AAFDEF014131A5FCFFC761B8DAEA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safeguarding Addresses From Emerging at Home Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SAFE at Home Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H7014D37B165D4549884CD03D391AD846"><enum>2.</enum><header>Federal agency and Federal court compliance with State address confidentiality programs</header> <subsection id="H6043FF69768A4927BED2FC963888EE76"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each Federal agency and Federal court shall accept, for any purpose for which an individual is required to provide an address to the agency or court, an address designated to that individual pursuant to an address confidentiality program.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA657F905F1D642E79C39E9B89160D15C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exemption from liability</header><text>An individual who provides to a Federal agency or Federal court an address which is designated to that individual pursuant to an address confidentiality program shall not be subject to any Federal regulatory, civil, or criminal penalties for providing such address in lieu of the individual’s actual physical address.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H991AB141446D4461A15B3F5637DF21EF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Compliance with address confidentiality program procedures and exemption from FOIA</header><text>In the case of a Federal agency or Federal court seeking to acquire the actual physical address of an individual described in subsection (a), the agency or court shall comply with any applicable procedures of the address confidentiality program for acquiring such address. Upon acquiring such an address, the address shall be considered confidential, and shall not be subject to any request pursuant to section 552 of title 5, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Freedom of Information Act</quote>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7157757A9D1E43BC97FFAFE2C243879A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HB66E4DCACB214EED9A90B3A4ADE49669"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>address confidentiality program</term> means a program implemented by a State which provides a designated address to an eligible individual for use in lieu of the individual’s actual physical address.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCEA7C0B58A88449187D42BA049127459"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>actual physical address</term> may include the address of the individual’s residence, school, and place of employment.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1B0D8EA9A09B42F5AA4C51BA913FF357"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible individual</term> means an individual who is determined, pursuant to an address confidentiality program—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA452D1570CCA4E3C876F503E453841D1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to be at risk to be a victim of domestic violence, rape, sexual assault, human trafficking, stalking, or who otherwise fears for their safety; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9838BF15E3E44C0BB05F055914E7FB1D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to reside in the same household as an individual described in subparagraph (A).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

