<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H5D98BA40CD4541C0B0BA53F87A83877B" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3635 IH: Local Coverage Determination Clarification Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-08-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3635</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20170801">August 1, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000290">Ms. Jenkins of Kansas</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act in order to improve the process whereby medicare
			 administrative contractors issue local coverage determinations under the
			 Medicare program, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H7D0CB203AF3240198F9BCF9C9AD6F698" style="OLC">
 <section id="H332EC3BF4CE2478B846AB107A4BFE36D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Local Coverage Determination Clarification Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H670BD05E76F946E6AFDD8423AA7F80B3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improvements in the Medicare local coverage determination (LCD) process for specified LCDs</header> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD5B84620BC434F4081A8261418752801"><enum>(a)</enum><header>LCD development process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1862(l)(5)(D) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395y">42 U.S.C. 1395y(l)(5)(D)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5D2D95FFEC49496F8078D2E22C2671CF" style="OLC">
					<subparagraph id="HE7C06535DBE645BEA7DF919511F730D5"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Process for issuing specified local coverage determinations</header>
 <clause id="HA21DAAF64DA44051B589461435DF6235"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a specified local coverage determination (as defined in clause (iv)) within an area by a fiscal intermediary or carrier that has entered into a contract with the Secretary under section 1874A, such intermediary or carrier must take the following actions with respect to such determination before such determination may take effect:</text>
 <subclause id="HFB6BA80960ED477F9E07E11C79C740C7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Publish on the public Internet website of the intermediary or carrier a proposed version of the specified local coverage determination (in this subparagraph referred to as a <quote>draft determination</quote>), a written rationale for the draft determination, and a description of all evidence relied upon and considered by the intermediary or carrier in the development of the draft determination.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H226F66F73582485A87F75EAA88F24530"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date on which the intermediary or carrier publishes the draft determination in accordance with subclause (I), convene one or more open, public meetings to review the draft determination, receive comments with respect to the draft determination, and secure the advice of an expert panel (such as a carrier advisory committee described in chapter 13 of the Medicare Program Integrity Manual in effect on August 31, 2015) with respect to the draft determination. The intermediary or carrier shall make available means for the public to attend such meetings remotely, such as via teleconference.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H3A6336E27DAC41AB902626F751D83D1F"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to each meeting convened pursuant to subclause (II), post on the public Internet website of the intermediary or carrier, not later than 14 days after such meeting is convened, a record of the meeting minutes for such meeting.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HAE7D664F59CA48C2AF2AFF17127BC7B9"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Provide a period for submission of written public comment on such draft determination that begins on the date on which all records required to be posted with respect to such draft determination under subclause (III) are so posted and that is not fewer than 30 days in duration.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HDC033095E86743968E7B86138695611B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Finalizing a specified local coverage determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A fiscal intermediary or carrier that has entered into a contract with the Secretary under section 1874A shall, with respect to a specified local coverage determination, post on the public Internet website of the fiscal intermediary or carrier the following information before the specified local coverage determination (in this subparagraph referred to as the <quote>final determination</quote>) takes effect—</text>
 <subclause id="H6E103EE2303E43B5B0DC48B18FAFBFCF"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a response to the issues raised at meetings convened pursuant to clause (i)(II) with respect to the draft determination;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H54FE34854B6B4C86A6813F8FBD49F972"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the rationale for the final determination;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HF91D2BEE4D2D44E0BA19A8549BFC3326"><enum>(III)</enum><text>in the case that the intermediary or carrier considered qualifying evidence in the development of the determination that was not described in the written notice provided pursuant to clause (i)(I), a description of such qualifying evidence; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H7E64B4AE6F78473292B7F739681E985D"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an effective date for the final determination that is not less than 30 days after the date on which such determination is so posted.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H03EAE017EEEB437A97644A23CB1B241C"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Limitation on determinations across jurisdictions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any plan under section 1862(l)(5)(A), in the case of a contract with a fiscal intermediary or carrier under section 1874A, such intermediary or carrier may not finalize a specified local coverage determination pursuant to clause (ii) with respect to a geographic area that applies, or has the effect of applying, outside such area. In the case that such an intermediary or carrier wishes to adopt, with respect to a specific geographic area a specified local coverage determination developed for a different geographic area, such intermediary or carrier may not so adopt such determination unless, prior to so adopting such determination, such intermediary or carrier independently evaluates and considers the qualifying evidence supporting the determination as applicable to such specific geographic area and makes a local coverage determination for such area in accordance with this subparagraph.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H755005BFCF3844269E3254D24D79E051"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Specified local coverage determination defined</header><text>For purposes of this subparagraph, the term <term>specified local coverage determination</term> means, with respect to a geographic area—</text> <subclause id="H80FD9EE7E9264E139BB9BE6ECDF5D522"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a new local coverage determination (regardless of whether such determination made by a fiscal intermediary or carrier that has entered into a contract with the Secretary under section 1874A and is based upon a specified local coverage determination that previously has been made with respect to another geographic area, or by another such intermediary or carrier);</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H781638DF5FE74DE59A772146342304C8"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a revised local coverage determination for such geographic area that restricts one or more existing coverage criteria for such area (such as by adding non-covered indications to an existing local coverage determination or by deleting previously covered ICD–9 or ICD–10 codes);</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA858A93A92EB4518A0717A11758BE4B8"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a revised local coverage determination that makes a substantive revision to one or more existing local coverage determinations; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA7BD6C3B913046EE93DF2BE97915E4F3"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>any other local coverage determination specified by the Secretary pursuant to regulations.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HEBE048013F9840F9B4CDE48E290779F4"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Qualifying evidence defined</header><text>For purposes of this subparagraph, the term <term>qualifying evidence</term> means either of the following:</text>
 <subclause commented="no" id="HACE07D7CF0A74CE9A66389E44D6DE291"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Scientific evidence published in peer-reviewed medical literature, such as randomized clinical trials or other studies.</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HB7EE85D2D1A146B493C7E0CAE498476A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>A general consensus of the applicable medical community (such as a consensus evinced through a recognized standard of practice in such medical community) that is supported by information provided by a recognized medical authority, such as a professional medical society.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H37196C991D8341358C2F1AB5A27BE743"><enum>(b)</enum><header>LCD reconsideration process</header><text>Section 1869(f) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ff">42 U.S.C. 1395ff(f)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HEAE5E888536340A8B0F895EC2142546D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2)(A), by inserting <quote>(other than the reconsideration process described in paragraphs (8) and (9))</quote> after <quote>local coverage determination</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H13911E82F8BA40D39FF7978DF2A8B16A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (5), by inserting <quote>(other than under the reconsideration process described in paragraphs (8) and (9))</quote> after <quote>local coverage determination</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2F3EBD6EF053405EA4F0499C37A5D35C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (8) as paragraph (13); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD3CA5782178A419D97C4702CBEEC9405"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (7) the following new paragraphs:</text> <quoted-block id="H87C84C125FCD4EC6955E7182FB23301D" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H3D73D26DE8CE4147B9B85084E0AED6C1"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Carrier or fiscal intermediary reconsideration process for specified local coverage determinations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the filing of a request by an interested party with respect to a specified local coverage determination by a fiscal intermediary or carrier that has entered into a contract with the Secretary under section 1874A, the intermediary or carrier shall reconsider such determination in accordance with the following process:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC10525EFD0C74FFE977F066C8E739DE9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Not later than 30 days after such a request is filed with the fiscal intermediary or carrier by the interested party with respect to such determination, the intermediary or carrier shall—</text>
 <clause id="H85D9584ACDAD4E75BE629CE89D616B71"><enum>(i)</enum><text>determine whether the request is an applicable request; and</text> </clause><clause id="HA4648D609DCD4D04AFE358ACE4FC8464"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case that the request is not an applicable request, inform the interested party of the reasons why such request is not an applicable request.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3FE4F34577E64985B6B718322EFB7144"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In the case that the intermediary or carrier determines under subparagraph (A) that the request described in such subparagraph is an applicable request, the intermediary or carrier shall, not later than 90 days after the date on which the request was filed with the intermediary or carrier, take the actions described in subparagraphs (C), (D), and (E) with respect to the determination.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58D67D61503F4E80A5A18019B0F228E1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The action described in this subparagraph is the action of specifying whether any of the following statements is applicable to the determination:</text>
 <clause id="HDEB86DD26E8945DCB76BAEA348FC4EBD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The determination did not apply, or inaccurately applied, qualifying evidence relevant to such determination.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H46CE0AD6CE5D4512AB2BFBEA0C6DEEF4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The determination used language that exceeded the scope of the intended purpose of the determination.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H64396F0732814B1AA7DF26952B367FDA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The determination was incorrect in its determination of whether such item or service is reasonable and necessary for the diagnosis or treatment of illness or injury under section 1862(a)(1)(A).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2EC0DF75AE884D13BD687ECC84E9251A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The determination failed to describe, with respect to such an item or service, the clinical conditions to be used for purposes of determining whether such item or service is reasonable and necessary for the diagnosis or treatment of illness or injury under section 1862(a)(1)(A).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3EDAF7C97FF44460A947491922B5BD8C"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The determination does not apply with respect to items or services to which it was intended to apply.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4FCDCAAFE92E465EB9C6849A088E093A"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The determination is erroneous for another reason that the intermediary or carrier identifies.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE89A428C9F3D4813913A9377ACA7F56B"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The action described in this subparagraph, with respect to the determination, is the action of taking, based on the specification under subparagraph (C) of whether any of the statements in such subparagraph applied to such determination, one or more of the following actions:</text>
 <clause id="HE6B4521DD62945A6895D3CBA181CA358"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Making no change in the determination.</text> </clause><clause id="H850041CC535E465EAC2F7EB3D2CAB79A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Rescinding a part of the determination (including, as applicable, the entire determination).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H501F6D2B0B01479F81E3A00CC9128FC3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Modifying the determination to restrict the coverage provided under this title for an item or service that is subject to the determination.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEA3965860B294F77B814A8BB0A92F635"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Modifying the determination to expand the coverage provided under this title for an item or service that is subject to the determination.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H59641907BE0A4A0D899CFA0D650DA316"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The action described in this subparagraph is the action of making publicly available a written description of the action taken under subparagraph (D) with respect to the determination.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDBF14116F5BA43208862E0965A7B5AC1"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Agency evaluation of reconsideration decision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case that an interested party that filed an applicable request under paragraph (8) with respect to a specified local coverage determination files with the Secretary, on a date that is not later than 120 days after the date on which an intermediary or carrier takes an action described under paragraph (8)(D) with respect to such determination, an appeal with respect to such decision in such form and manner as the Secretary may require, the Secretary shall, not later than 30 days after such appeal is filed—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7F8D0ED2DD39432896B00548E35C643C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specify which, if any, of the statements in subparagraph (C) of paragraph (8) is applicable to the determination; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H513ED9792ABC43D59A9FBA78D8AC1317"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">based on such specification, take one of the actions described in subparagraph (D) of such paragraph with respect to the determination.</text>
 </subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">The Secretary shall apply subparagraph (A) as though the reference to <quote>the intermediary or carrier</quote> in clause (vi) of paragraph (8)(D) were a reference to the Secretary.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C32870958D144C09670DE1F427A6F9F"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in paragraph (8) or (9) may be construed as affecting the right of an aggrieved party to file a complaint under paragraph (2)(A) and receive a determination in accordance with the provisions of such paragraph.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFA9478E63D4F4ABE989A563B7CBD6941"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Definitions applicable to paragraphs (8) and (9)</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of paragraphs (8) and (9):</text> <subparagraph id="HFC43D62FA3754A6CB84A0F6A59E0ED40"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>applicable request</term> means a request that is submitted in fiscal year 2018 or a subsequent fiscal year, that is solely with respect to a specified local coverage determination, and that includes a description of the rationale for such request and any evidence supporting such request. For purposes of the preceding sentence, the Secretary may not require, as a condition of treating a request with respect to such a determination as an applicable request, that the request contain qualifying evidence that was not considered in the development of such determination.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66EC1116D9064583B0C7BF1F21DAB408"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>interested party</term> means, with respect to a specified local coverage determination within an area by a fiscal intermediary or carrier that has entered into a contract with the Secretary under section 1874A—</text>
 <clause id="H9336692CF051452690BAF88CB80BAE5A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a provider of services or supplier that, in such area, furnishes, provides, or supplies items or services that are subject to such determination; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6376C8F328334DEC801662C4B46C54BC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an organization that represents such a provider of services or supplier.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFAA9579A9654728AAEF07A707ED0AEF"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualifying evidence</term> has the meaning given such term by clause (v) of section 1862(l)(5)(D).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H65962E009E824EA3908C6C5399A5AC58"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>specified local coverage determination</term> has the meaning given such term by clause (iv) of such section.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H31895D3BA0C24248A004C28D350B043C"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Appointment of Ombudsman</header> <subparagraph id="HC287586AAFB64816988C57CE3A9FCEAC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, within the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, appoint a Medicare Reviews and Appeals Ombudsman (referred to in this paragraph as the <quote>Ombudsman</quote>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6EC60542A626488FA0CF5179B4CAE670"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Ombudsman shall, with respect to specified local coverage determinations, carry out the following duties:</text>
 <clause id="H25064EC13B134D0BADF25DC1A71E5D51"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Provide interested parties (as defined in paragraph (11)(B)) with administrative and technical assistance in filing requests under paragraph (8) and appeals under paragraph (9).</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBE2509FECE774AC4AC90F051E205FB35"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Make publicly available in a uniform, consistent, and easily understood format the following information for each 12-month period:</text>
 <subclause id="HF13A2DA34667419EB3C731652B7D0E35"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The number of requests filed with fiscal intermediaries and carriers under paragraph (8), and of appeals filed with the Secretary under paragraph (9), during such period.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HF1966068182C45729A75CC1FA704F4A9"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to such requests during such period, the number of times that intermediaries and carriers took, with respect to the actions described subparagraph (A)(iv) of such paragraph, each such action.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H94FAF2E8645445C3B355BA5E3FFA536E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>With respect to such appeals during such period, the number of times that the Secretary took each such action.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD44BFBD71CCC41578490BF84CA3C76F1"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the numbers made available under subclauses (I), (II), and (III), the number of each such number that is attributable to—</text>
 <item id="HFB76E40678184C48A472C32E539CB92E"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>each fiscal intermediary or carrier; and</text> </item><item id="HEF35765A5F80422286DB3F4F7643D0B2"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each interested party (as defined in paragraph (11)(B)).</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H6608EDBB6C1745F19E76A0E1E516BD18"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Measures of the responsiveness of fiscal intermediaries and carriers with respect to requests filed with such intermediaries and carriers under paragraph (8).</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HE276D9F2987C4DEE8D50634369AFA7D4"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>Recommendations to the Secretary with respect to ways to improve—</text> <item commented="no" id="HD8B4889DCACF49B3B42FAD6778F9FCD4"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the efficacy and efficiency of the process described in paragraph (8); and</text>
 </item><item commented="no" id="H48C76DEB86254E289F0294955FFFDEA8"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>communication with individuals entitled to benefits under part A or enrolled under part B, providers of services, and suppliers regarding such process.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H430919C4569B44E5B34D85F101B1DC68"><enum>3.</enum><header>Promulgation of regulations; application date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall promulgate regulations to carry out paragraph (5)(D) of section 1862(l) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395y">42 U.S.C. 1395y(l)</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (a), and paragraphs (8) and (9) of section 1869(f) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ff">42 U.S.C. 1395ff(f)</external-xref>), as inserted by subsection (b), in such a manner as to ensure that the processes described in such paragraphs are fully implemented by October 1, 2017.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


