<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF1C2C8F66C4946E0BE3F4C4EF1EEC0E7" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 358 IH: To amend chapter 44 of title 18, United States Code, to more comprehensively address the interstate transportation of firearms or ammunition.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 358</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170106">January 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000568">Mr. Griffith</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000601">Mr. Palazzo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001274">Mr. Brooks of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000292">Mr. Johnson of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001192">Mr. Stewart</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001189">Mr. Messer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000374">Mr. Abraham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000470">Mr. Tipton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000460">Mr. Farenthold</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Z000017">Mr. Zeldin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000563">Mr. Gibbs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000614">Mr. Duffy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000576">Mr. Long</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000168">Mr. Olson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000290">Ms. Jenkins of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001036">Mr. Hensarling</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000174">Mr. Sam Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young of Alaska</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001071">Mr. Jody B. Hice of Georgia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000582">Mr. Roe of Tennessee</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/44">chapter 44</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, to more comprehensively address the interstate
			 transportation of firearms or ammunition.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H726E4324A1AC4AF9882FD0D0F499C5FD" style="OLC">
		<section id="HA62FFAE1BBC1451CBDCA8E27C239110D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Interstate transportation of firearms or ammunition</header>
 <subsection id="HD3A0F3AA49AD4B8ABC4E2E192F78E9C1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 926A of title 18, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H51013FDE197942E2A5095EB519B74A75" style="USC"> <section id="HB418FCAFF5A84D6581AF4068D5966739"><enum>926A.</enum><header>Interstate transportation of firearms or ammunition</header> <subsection id="H824887144156475CACF2EB5E55C635D3"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any provision of any law, rule, or regulation of a State or any political subdivision thereof:</text>
 <paragraph id="HD290BB270269491ABFE74BEC390813B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A person who is not prohibited by this chapter from possessing, transporting, shipping, or receiving a firearm or ammunition shall be entitled to transport a firearm for any lawful purpose from any place where the person may lawfully possess, carry, or transport the firearm to any other such place if, during the transportation, the firearm is unloaded, and—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBE635E61005F49F99999002344EC9B3F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the transportation is by motor vehicle, the firearm is not directly accessible from the passenger compartment of the vehicle, and, if the vehicle is without a compartment separate from the passenger compartment, the firearm is in a locked container other than the glove compartment or console, or is secured by a secure gun storage or safety device; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F3B03623B7A4847B47AFF9D262FCF60"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the transportation is by other means, the firearm is in a locked container or secured by a secure gun storage or safety device.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB93B296041E247BBAB0766F7ACDB8B2C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person who is not prohibited by this chapter from possessing, transporting, shipping, or receiving a firearm or ammunition shall be entitled to transport ammunition, or any detachable magazine or feeding device for ammunition, for any lawful purpose from any place where the person may lawfully possess, carry, or transport the ammunition, magazine, or feeding device to any other such place if, during the transportation, the ammunition, magazine, or feeding device is not loaded into a firearm, and—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD0EAA372E8F04B61A131EE998A7E4515"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the transportation is by motor vehicle, the ammunition, magazine, or feeding device is not directly accessible from the passenger compartment of the vehicle, and, if the vehicle is without a compartment separate from the passenger compartment, the ammunition, magazine, or feeding device is in a locked container other than the glove compartment or console; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H893BA893B853456BBA35911907194E33"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the transportation is by other means, the ammunition, magazine, or feeding device is in a locked container.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H141A126D882949DE94D9D945A1DACD0B"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In subsection (a), the term <term>transport</term> includes staying in temporary lodging overnight, stopping for food, fuel, vehicle maintenance, an emergency, medical treatment, and any other activity incidental to the transport, but does not include transportation—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2130783423574D55B084534D370FE111"><enum>(1)</enum><text>with the intent to commit a crime punishable by imprisonment for a term exceeding one year that involves the use or threatened use of force against another; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA29EDEDCB16B40FA98294A7F3D6611E4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with knowledge, or reasonable cause to believe, that such a crime is to be committed in the course of, or arising from, the transportation.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H207F3D14CEAB4927BD033E9B1EDBBA57"><enum>(c)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H5BBE91D164A14F498A4A233B3C80EDD6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A person who is transporting a firearm, ammunition, magazine, or feeding device may not be arrested or otherwise detained for violation of any law or any rule or regulation of a State or any political subdivision thereof related solely to the possession, transportation, or carrying of firearms, ammunition, magazine, or feeding device unless there is probable cause to believe that the person is doing so in a manner not provided for in subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA7D184B4017D46C1BBB03DC5C38809A0" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When a person asserts this section as a defense in a criminal proceeding, the prosecution shall bear the burden of proving, beyond a reasonable doubt, that the conduct of the person did not satisfy the conditions set forth in subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDD5979B4A89A43E481A150888F2F9AEB" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>When a person successfully asserts this section as a defense in a criminal proceeding, the court shall award the prevailing defendant a reasonable attorney’s fee.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA84010BA73024E4CBD85B2E9A171A98B"><enum>(d)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H2EAD5D20F78543BAA568D68CCA176AFD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person who is deprived of any right, privilege, or immunity secured by this section, section 926B or 926C, under color of any statute, ordinance, regulation, custom, or usage of any State or any political subdivision thereof, may bring an action in any appropriate court against any other person, including a State or political subdivision thereof, who causes the person to be subject to the deprivation, for damages and other appropriate relief.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H653036BF4F094620A967AA07CD288278" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The court shall award a plaintiff prevailing in an action brought under paragraph (1) damages and such other relief as the court deems appropriate, including a reasonable attorney's fee.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF633D6F957874E089082DDD75787292B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for such chapter is amended in the item relating to section 926A by striking <quote>firearms</quote> and inserting <quote>firearms or ammunition</quote>.</text> </subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

