<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC6D5A42A80E74DC782EB2C344B245DC6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><form><distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 970</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170207">February 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 41, United States Code, to require the submission of data relating to diversity by certain contractors, to amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to require the submission of such data by issuers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4652D2B35F5445CA9FF578FD50F7DFDF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H198F841D8BE943358174CA917F084359" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Improving Corporate Governance Through Diversity Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H2A2E40FEA2C942F483DA6917FCD8A5E2" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Submission of data relating to diversity by certain contractors</header> <subsection id="HA73743475BB14969AA739A459C736260"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chapter 47 of subtitle I of title 41, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H6DDE556D700444AFA907DE8E49422C91" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H056BB493BC454A8AA83E24848A72239D"><enum>4713.</enum><header>Submission of data relating to diversity by certain contractors.</header> 
<subsection id="HCE133B07FCB54B9C870DD5E1F867B063"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Submission of data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of the award of a contract in an amount of $5,000,000 or more to a covered contractor, the head of an executive agency shall require the contractor to submit, not later than 60 days after the award of the contract, the following:</text> <paragraph id="H7F0ADF8149234BDF9E238C3DA5F75CF6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Data on the racial, ethnic, and gender composition of the board of directors and the C-level executives of the covered contractor.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDF454F3F7A5A4514847BE9F66D5FB935"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Data on the affiliation of any member of the board of directors or any C-level executive to a historically underrepresented group, including veterans of the Armed Forces and individuals with disabilities.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HF0A171F479E14E4FA89DAF36B708114A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any plan or strategy that exists on the date of the submission of data under this subsection to improve the diversity of the board of directors or the C-level executives of the covered contractor.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEF1BED893847452984726D691F69A00C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reports</header> 
<paragraph id="H2F480DD4860E4952B423E9303127A1F1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Quarterly report to General Services Administration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After the end of a calendar quarter, each executive agency shall submit to the Administrator of General Services a report that includes the data submitted by contractors under subsection (a) during the quarter covered.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H608073E2D40742D19FE4BF7B822F9DBA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual report to Congress and Offices of Minority and Women Inclusion</header> <subparagraph id="H5AEA6E57C45549BDAC32E91878F6532D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than February 14 of each calendar year, the Administrator of General Services shall submit to Congress and each Office of Minority and Women Inclusion established under section 342 of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5452">12 U.S.C. 5452</external-xref>) an annual report that—</text> 
<clause id="H71FF180919F84F9FA3B9483BB897522E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes the data submitted to the Administrator under paragraph (1) during the preceding calendar year and the data submitted under section 13(s) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934;</text></clause> <clause id="HB0B5AA93E6EB44B6B54B0D39BD1F603F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">uses the data described in clause (i), as well as information from other reliable sources, to analyze the diversity of the board of directors and the C-level executives of each entity submitting data in comparison to the industry peers of such entity, including any trends and progress related to such diversity; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HCCC5392B812846E2B774C54F349EE88C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>based on the analysis conducted under clause (ii), lists each entity submitting data that is significantly lagging behind the industry peers of such entity with respect to the diversity of the board of directors and the C-level executives.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5287A605F0E644EDBA07F8C2B63B4499"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Administrator of General Services shall make publicly available each annual report submitted under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9131C58700D5485FB48B15D34CAF2B8E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public comment</header><text>After the end of the four-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this section, and every four years thereafter, the Administrator of General Services shall review the implementation of the requirements of this section and provide an opportunity for public comment on such review.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H53821E24C64C4B4098A446A0A6CEE85F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HE80BE8710CA64918A2E7CB1C6B2730AC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered contractor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered contractor</quote> means a for-profit business with annual gross receipts in excess of $1,000,000,000 during the year preceding the submission of a bid or proposal for a contract described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3C1D68A8311D47E8A65F04541E3BECE5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>C-level executive</header><text>The term <quote>C-level executive</quote> means the most senior executive officer, information officer, technology officer, financial officer, compliance officer, or security officer of a covered contractor.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H44F52C18BDF143D8AAD22827CBD51502"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 47 of such title is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 4712 the following new item:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H015E4F838E3B463284371E25C412EDDE" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">4713. Submission of data relating to diversity by certain contractors.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="H536A6C94EE8D4251AC17F75D72AC6830" commented="no"><enum>3.</enum><header>Submission of data relating to diversity by issuers</header> <subsection id="H9A148E981CD74D3B9C8BEEBFFE55F73F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 13 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78m">15 U.S.C. 78m</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HCC74D9F7113C48F39F296DE32821BC44" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H8DAB68947B984485BB22F3CFACDE33F3" commented="no"><enum>(s)</enum><header>Submission of data relating to diversity</header> 
<paragraph id="H795440C6B1244A5B97915391305AF02F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Submission of data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each issuer required to file an annual report under subsection (a) shall disclose in that report, the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HAAEFFA699F6D4B0ABCEBA1A06EDC2C82" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Data on the racial, ethnic, and gender composition of the board of directors and the C-level executives of the issuer.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF6E142500B5E4E4D8EC2F8A65588D341" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Data on the affiliation of any member of the board of directors or any C-level executive of the issuer to a historically underrepresented group, including veterans of the Armed Forces and individuals with disabilities.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H425ED94BB734499DA536CA07CD789295" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any plan or strategy that exists on the date of the submission of data under this paragraph to improve the diversity of the board of directors or the C-level executives of the issuer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0E8C517BDCD44CAEA5A47CD85C68F140" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>C-level executive defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>C-level executive</quote> means the most senior executive officer, information officer, technology officer, financial officer, compliance officer, or security officer of an issuer.</text> </paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HB8E21767089946488D64B557FC0FDBFB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Corporate governance regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Securities and Exchange Commission shall revise paragraph (v) of section 229.407(c)(2) of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, to require that when the description described in such paragraph is presented in a proxy or information statement relating to the election of directors, the qualities and skills described in such paragraph, along with the nominee’s gender, race, ethnicity, and affiliation with a historically underrepresented group should be presented in a chart or matrix form. </text> </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

