<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB98744C4C15446AB8A78CC669008EE65" key="H" public-private="public"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2602 IH: Secure our Skies Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2602</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20170523">May 23, 2017</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend title 49, United States Code, to include training for certain employees of air carriers to combat human trafficking, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H8610DF980BF04C7BBC915BB620CC4C15" style="OLC"> 
<section commented="no" id="H8A136ACEAB1749039A45758164D7CFB3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Secure our Skies Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="HA97FD298CF03415C8EEE464EA35F3945"><enum>2.</enum><header>Training to combat human trafficking for certain employees of air carriers</header> <subsection id="H80A02B7309044A8BB27707D079F5F86D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/417">chapter 417</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HC18B6A846043435989F1FE866B862947" style="USC"> 
<section id="HBEADB891831E4AF5A4306487A958761C"><enum>41725.</enum><header>Training to combat human trafficking</header> 
<subsection id="H315B0709DAD14B7F902B3EB99BE9BD9D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each air carrier providing passenger air transportation shall provide flight attendants, pilots, and dispatchers who are employees or contractors of the air carrier with training to combat human trafficking in the course of carrying out their duties as employees or contractors of the air carrier.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HEF1AA2F47E3D4BD295AEB7F79946B335"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements of training</header><text>The training an air carrier is required to provide under subsection (a) to flight attendants, pilots, and dispatchers shall include training with respect to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDE5FBDE84366443EA15937B400CF7699"><enum>(1)</enum><text>common indicators of human trafficking; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H31262CB5906C49FD9122677D98D83421"><enum>(2)</enum><text>best practices for reporting suspected trafficking to law enforcement officers.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6B59C4C534D643529DC34A409CAFD5E2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Training module</header><text>To assist in training flight attendants, pilots, and dispatchers to identify and report human trafficking, the Department of Homeland Security and the Department of Transportation shall provide information to air carriers, including the Blue Campaign training module, and permit air carriers to use such information, in whole or in part, in complying with subsection (a).</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H1267F0ECEF1A47AEAF1088BF24CDA35B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Human trafficking defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>human trafficking</quote> means one or more severe forms of trafficking in persons (as defined in section 103 of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7102">22 U.S.C. 7102</external-xref>)).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H3D858100F21647E4A90E42F313ED03E1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The analysis for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/417">chapter 417</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/41724">section 41724</external-xref> the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HCA8C2764A3E640DC9BEBD8C13DBE0F2B" style="OLC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">41725. Training to combat human trafficking.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection> <subsection id="H3C716D8A275F4AC8BD766CC833AD91E8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report that includes—</text> 
<paragraph id="HFF3DA3EC4ADB44B18F9BEAC4B67EF599"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the status of air carrier compliance with section 41725(a) and the dissemination and use of information described in subsection (c) of that section; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H11A66750DEDC4182B09860CD832C0B7C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommendations for improving the identification and reporting of human trafficking by air carrier personnel while protecting the civil liberties of passengers.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H24E7877CC81E4C2589C6D7041898951B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Immunity for reporting human trafficking</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 44941(a) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>or terrorism, as defined by section 3077 of title 18, United States Code,</quote> and inserting <quote>human trafficking (as defined by section 41725), or terrorism (as defined by section 3077 of title 18, United States Code)</quote>.</text> </section> </legis-body> </bill> 

