<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H63474BE8488D4737AD0912EE51725CA3" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4664 IH: Repeal Insurance Plans of the Multi-State Program Act of 2017 </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4664</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171215">December 15, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001187">Mr. Meadows</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Appropriations</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To repeal the multi-State plan program.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HC17CE14955814FD295B0B8562DB34944" style="OLC">
 <section id="HEA029A44ED9047E9B2AF35450464FD12" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Repeal Insurance Plans of the Multi-State Program Act of 2017 </short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>RIP MSP Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H966B7C7614714018BCB90CDD8B0DE440"><enum>2.</enum><header>Repeal of Multi-State Plan program</header> <subsection id="H81083018591449148B20B5A8DC90E832"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the terms <term>multi-State plan issuer</term> and <term>MSP issuer</term> mean a health insurance issuer or group of health insurance issuers that has a contract with the Office of Personnel Management to offer multi-State plan options pursuant to section 1334 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5C8AFA5A6EA64AA08FA8729AFFEC35FE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program Repeal</header><text>Effective October 1, 2018, section 1334 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref>) shall have no force or effect.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H85A91040F6794346AF93BABD0693C9E1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Required reporting</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall provide the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives a briefing concerning the efforts of the Office of Personnel Management (referred to in this section as <quote>OPM</quote>) to wind down the multi-State program under section 1334 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act. Such briefing shall contain such information as may be required, including information regarding—</text>
 <paragraph id="H920406A24A9541159D7166CB1FE13869"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the methods of communication OPM and an MSP issuer will use to notify current enrollees that the multi-State plan will not be offered during the next open season, including a timeline of the planned communications;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H591748C6D7C24BC39041B93ADB68E9BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of how the Director of OPM will work with the Secretary of Health and Human Services to ensure that no plans previously offered pursuant to such section 1334 are offered on State or Federal Exchanges; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB9F1B235DA6C4FE480EC24486A3817F1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a timeline detailing how OPM will close down the information technology portal that MSP issuers utilize.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H56EC426604094C75B5287C47D7643BE2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rescission of Unused Funds</header><text>Of the amounts made available to OPM for the purposes of staffing and administering the program under section 1334 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, the unobligated balance is rescinded, effective October 1, 2018.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB32191CD6B22405CB0328D55CA6D054E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="H5EF6AE7063044204ACDC7F514B23FD77"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Director of the Office of Personnel Management should assign employees of the Office whose duties on the date of enactment relate to carrying out section 1334 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref>) to duties relating to processing appeals brought by individuals or employers pursuant to such section 1334; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB21A3D183EA84058B1C6312B73A06F4D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">no additional amounts should be appropriated for salaries and expenses relating to processing such appeals.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


