<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD6D2F323B443433E84347B8279FF381C" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2090 IH: Election Integrity Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2090</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170412">April 12, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001189">Mr. Messer</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to require voters in elections for Federal office to
			 provide photo identification as a condition of casting a ballot in such
			 elections, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HB1326B2902DC466A9719FF13EA00F375" style="OLC">
 <section id="HD94614723ED84B188308C5E8322DA7EC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Election Integrity Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H60F07C0A2BC149B49ACE16C874016D4F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requiring Voters to Provide Photo Identification</header> <subsection id="HA2B8A322F72B4332A6E428E196A3D05B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement To Provide Photo Identification as Condition of Casting Ballot</header> <paragraph id="H1579D684FE2F4880A9A4297EEF56D224"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title III of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/15481">52 U.S.C. 15481</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by inserting after section 303 the following new section:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA9FE2F2C14734D62AF45D2C6C21AD0EA" style="OLC">
						<section id="HBF846ADC0DF34AA2B29DC5347F2EBBEB"><enum>303A.</enum><header>Photo identification requirements</header>
							<subsection id="HFEEA384C17FD4519AA44A5D95EF65766"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Provision of identification required as condition of casting ballot</header>
								<paragraph id="H4668B55074E4416EB27BF96A6C76AB2C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Individuals voting in person</header>
 <subparagraph id="HD5FB06FC635041AB9B6FE6DF0637072F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Requirement to provide identification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law and except as provided in subparagraph (B), the appropriate State or local election official may not provide a ballot for an election for Federal office to an individual who desires to vote in person unless the individual presents to the official a valid photo identification.</text>
									</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6B022A63FA84743B0DD16518CECFE83"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Availability of provisional ballot</header>
 <clause id="H587B3FF002994551BBCC282A7FF460C6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an individual does not present the identification required under subparagraph (A), the individual shall be permitted to cast a provisional ballot with respect to the election under section 302(a), except that the appropriate State or local election official may not make a determination under section 302(a)(4) that the individual is eligible under State law to vote in the election unless, not later than 10 days after casting the provisional ballot, the individual presents to the official—</text>
 <subclause id="HBB59D2F591554DFF805AF7E165743B21"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the identification required under subparagraph (A); or</text> </subclause><subclause id="HA070971C0FE04A3C882D373B81730728"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an affidavit attesting that the individual does not possess the identification required under subparagraph (A) because the individual has a religious objection to being photographed.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H8246713F67D741029BB9E9AC352A2EED"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>No effect on other provisional balloting rules</header><text>Nothing in clause (i) may be construed to apply to the casting of a provisional ballot pursuant to section 302(a) or any State law for reasons other than the failure to present the identification required under subparagraph (A).</text>
										</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1583F526E206445596C62EA2F39FEBD1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Individuals voting other than in person</header>
 <subparagraph id="HD30F20A06DBE4F34AF493FA515407E6C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law and except as provided in subparagraph (B), the appropriate State or local election official may not accept any ballot for an election for Federal office provided by an individual who votes other than in person unless the individual submits with the ballot a copy of a valid photo identification.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1A118B0CA8840DC99C2EB9C8B154C7D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception for overseas military voters</header><text>Subparagraph (A) does not apply with respect to a ballot provided by an absent uniformed services voter who, by reason of active duty or service, is absent from the United States on the date of the election involved. In this subparagraph, the term <term>absent uniformed services voter</term> has the meaning given such term in section 107(1) of the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20310">52 U.S.C. 20310(1)</external-xref>), other than an individual described in section 107(1)(C) of such Act.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF04796E43C454E9389F5AAC636B11570"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Provision of identifications without charge to individuals unable To pay costs of obtaining
 identification</header><text>If an individual presents a State or local election official with an affidavit attesting that the individual is unable to pay the costs associated with obtaining a valid photo identification under this section, the official shall provide the individual with a valid photo identification under this subsection without charge to the individual.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0D3DEA3ED6234CE68688FC23137DA222"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Valid photo identifications described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, a <quote>valid photo identification</quote> means, with respect to an individual who seeks to vote in a State, any of the following:</text> <paragraph id="HDCE41E1469A74B07BB4E0F8DA0A91515"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A valid State-issued motor vehicle driver’s license that includes a photo of the individual and an expiration date.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA3E4C63D50D8404A86D3BF082415D364"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A valid State-issued identification card that includes a photo of the individual and an expiration date.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF1806C537CB94E28932FD4B0DE6CB4EC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A valid United States passport for the individual.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H52D5692B9C6E4F8BA4C54909402E4F25"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A valid military identification for the individual.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9CE2DCEA3D854745AB7113EA9962BB70"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Any other form of government-issued identification that the State may specify as a valid photo identification for purposes of this subsection.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2007965E32324E82A35743DF6BBEED75"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notification of identification requirement to applicants for voter registration</header>
 <paragraph id="H7342EE71554344F7B0EBD93DEE005353"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each State shall ensure that, at the time an individual applies to register to vote in elections for Federal office in the State, the appropriate State or local election official notifies the individual of the photo identification requirements of this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7B4631D41FE946A1B25A74F26934EDD9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rule for individuals applying to register to vote online</header><text>Each State shall ensure that, in the case of an individual who applies to register to vote in elections for Federal office in the State online, the online voter registration system notifies the individual of the photo identification requirements of this section before the individual completes the online registration process.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H669C3C1E31CD4AA79393EBE79D1B662C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Treatment of States with photo identification requirements in effect as of date of enactment</header><text>If, as of the date of the enactment of this section, a State has in effect a law requiring an individual to provide a photo identification as a condition of casting a ballot in elections for Federal office held in the State and the law remains in effect on and after the effective date of this section, the State shall be considered to meet the requirements of this section if—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB4217D938CBD4BA495F1F34265DAF328"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the State submits a request to the Attorney General and provides such information as the Attorney General may consider necessary to determine that the State has in effect such a law and that the law remains in effect; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8E2F53D7B1A244E088FECAB0CB7BC176"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Attorney General approves the request.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDF1A587E03A14A32A7E9D6B85D05134F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall apply with respect to elections for Federal office held in 2020 or any succeeding year.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H29A7C9CAFFCD438C80B43B728A8C90F8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents of such Act is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 303 the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5AF6D7996A5C400EB38B5FAABC09EDF1" style="OLC">
						<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
							<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 303A. Photo identification requirements.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB559F54889FD4181B4B8CF8DC31D96ED"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment relating to voluntary guidance by Election Assistance Commission</header><text>Section 311(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21101">52 U.S.C. 21101(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H610DE65027394D04840C7D3A1AE5ACEA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (2);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB0AB2FEAF19D47D8A5A58A7A4E67519A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of paragraph (3) and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4B50574601904B5CA0DDF2F58F6B40A0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB2B1A619AFC54C51A857743BB03CC489" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H251A905FE9BF45D09D78B1F4AC50FA61"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of the recommendations with respect to section 303A, October 1, 2018.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA953F595EEA349D8878F4950EEBB77C6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendment relating to enforcement</header><text>Section 401 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21111">52 U.S.C. 21111</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>and 303</quote> and inserting <quote>303, and 303A</quote>.</text>
			</subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6E9E283883FD421FB71C8350995C1F19"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conforming amendments relating to repeal of existing photo identification requirements for certain
			 voters</header>
 <paragraph id="H06D3C369F35C4CB5BA2334DA9A01301A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 303 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15483">42 U.S.C. 15483</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H8F83585354AD4ABFAC18EDAF822413C5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section">and requirements for voters who register by mail</header-in-text></quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBFC417FA63F845D6B6B12F029D7E5596"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the heading of subsection (b), by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection">for Voters Who Register by Mail</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection">for Mail-In Registration Forms</header-in-text></quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H470612E32DD14A129C752BAB5EB4114A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking paragraphs (1) through (3) and redesignating paragraphs (4) and (5) as paragraphs (1) and (2), respectively; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC511E89D1C0A4A879398E30F21726800"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by striking <quote>subsections (a)(5)(A)(i)(II) and (b)(3)(B)(i)(II)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (a)(5)(A)(i)(II)</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2E78952FA7CD49D7841C07C8FCBED6C7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical Amendment</header><text>The table of contents of such Act is amended by amending the item relating to section 303 to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE40A59ECBB8643EDAD3F7B1492E861F3" style="OLC">
						<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
							<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 303. Computerized statewide voter registration list requirements.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7C621A1699ED48518166A0B8C9C6B455"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective Date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section and the amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to elections for Federal office held in 2020 or any succeeding year.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


