<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H298D52F4CACF4818AC9990D1C0F3ED6D" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2493 IH: Conflicts from Political Fundraising Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2493</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170517">May 17, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001168">Mr. Sarbanes</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 to require individuals nominated or appointed to
			 Senate-confirmed positions or to positions of a confidential or
			 policymaking character to disclose certain types of contributions made or
			 solicited by, or on behalf of, the individuals.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H9FC97D5D638449C6AE6D9D5DB8A823A4" style="OLC">
 <section id="H0254768132B34E65B8B6A5A903C0DE4B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Conflicts from Political Fundraising Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H5D2C0DB342984EB5B0427E209D685971" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HB011C6B0E65A465D970CA614A75B2FF9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Public confidence in the Federal Government is based on the expectation that officers and employees will discharge their duties impartially, and avoid either actual conflicts of interest or the appearance thereof.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H59916A1B04D84FA69ACE4E999B9FECB3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The risk of an actual conflict of interest, or the appearance thereof, arises when a nominee or appointee to a Senate-confirmed position or an individual in a position of a confidential or policymaking character has previously donated to, solicited for, or received funds from a political action committee or entity organized under section 501(c)(4) or <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(6)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8F16C5B74BC94DE29B5A78B1F831F7E1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Since the 2010 decision by the Supreme Court of the United States in Citizens United v. Federal Election Commission, spending by corporations subject to Federal laws and regulations has increased dramatically.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC194D37F814744D899DC0CF697285E05"><enum>(4)</enum><text>While some corporate political spending is done publicly, contributions to entities organized under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(4)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 need not be disclosed, making this spending effectively anonymous. The risk of an actual conflict of interest, or the appearance thereof, arises whether political spending is public or anonymous.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H487CBD1E15774487ADCD7D983BA8D54C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Current financial disclosure requirements do not require filers to report funds they have donated to, solicited for, or received from political action committees or entities organized under section 501(c)(4) or <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(6)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H01C2EE555CB94E94A84F763AFB6EC8B8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Apparent or actual conflicts of interest are best ameliorated through public disclosure of this activity to the Office of Government Ethics so the apparent or actual conflicts can be addressed in ethics agreements negotiated between the filer and the agency in which the filer will serve.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HC32ECDE2E8D641A1A89274EF4D2208F2" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Disclosure of certain types of contributions</header>
 <subsection id="H3E11D14DBB1F4360AF82CCA3CA896AA7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Section 109 of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H061A2CA631954CDAA2A5CC5E9687D15E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (2) through (19) as paragraphs (5) through (22), respectively; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H51BF88798C3A4480A8057947F523C7F5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (1) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBC5E6B33612243BFB3CD932BB576C881" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HEAC1BE696E5D4F54A680188FE7EBA644"><enum>(2)</enum><text><term>covered contribution</term> means a payment, advance, forbearance, rendering, or deposit of money, or any thing of value—</text>
							<subparagraph id="H47D4F4C52D564C80916CFD9620F7A7E1"><enum>(A)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H61038D1CB06C43969166FAB6C3CF8B5D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that—</text> <subclause id="HC29077D49B8A4E33A8748C688C544284" indent="up1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is—</text>
 <item id="H9316669B9E5345CCA81F4365C71EDEE0"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>made by or on behalf of a covered individual; or</text> </item><item id="H125FDB953F014383B2EC26C7EE143A43"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>solicited in writing by or on behalf of a covered individual; and</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H736979851AF540DBA32FE11354C803FE" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is made—</text> <item id="H510B89A3AB714EF680EB9391890B5E01"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>to a political organization, as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/527">section 527</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; or</text>
 </item><item id="H44EBDC6AA8E446CB8E9EA5703E2DC976"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>to an organization—</text> <subitem id="HABD78C69DA0A4E0496E5BA9791D3F4E5"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>that is described in paragraph (4) or (6) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from tax under section 501(a) of such Code; and</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="HFD4463C381C2491D96129C5DF2DD9F93"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>that promotes or opposes changes in Federal laws or regulations that are (or would be) administered by the agency in which the covered individual has been nominated for appointment to a covered position or is serving in a covered position; or</text>
 </subitem></item></subclause></clause><clause id="H3E1AE9AC6D20451AAA01714FC0F18CE0" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that is—</text> <subclause id="H189850ED5D214A9D8E626386F6285DDB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>solicited in writing by or on behalf of a covered individual; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H1E5D9361989D4EF9A612FBC78C3CE780"><enum>(II)</enum><text>made—</text> <item id="H9EA17817369043DC8DEF09E48CCC6DC1"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>by an individual or entity the activities of which are subject to Federal laws or regulations that are (or would be) administered by the agency in which the covered individual has been nominated for appointment to a covered position or is serving in a covered position; and</text>
 </item><item id="HBEF6F195F5CB4739B6318FA303C3D0F5"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>to—</text> <subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H43DFA4A2A1BF49C7B190D512E7EFED26"><enum>(AA)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a political organization, as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/527">section 527</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; or</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="HDC386036D9E4437B965E29B86FADE813"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>an organization that is described in paragraph (4) or (6) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from tax under section 501(a) of such Code; and</text>
 </subitem></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF9759D832FE24E2EA958D29941D8DC7E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that is made to an organization described in item (aa) or (bb) of clause (i)(II) or clause (ii)(II)(bb) of subparagraph (A) for which the total amount of such payments, advances, forbearances, renderings, or deposits of money, or any thing of value, during the calendar year in which it is made is not less than the contribution limitation in effect under section 315(a)(1)(A) of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30116">52 U.S.C. 30116(a)(1)(A)</external-xref>) for elections occurring during such calendar year;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2AC29948D4E2435BBDEE3E09472FE160"><enum>(3)</enum><text><term>covered individual</term> means an individual who has been nominated or appointed to a covered position; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD0F39B20174C4659B0F8090DBFA0B9F5"><enum>(4)</enum><text><term>covered position</term>—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9DB9FE7893644968A28524F296D04B97"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means—</text> <clause id="HD71489D40EE349E3B14DCF5FA4C2558F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a position described under sections 5312 through 5316 of title 5, United States Code;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H52FFA23F55EB4E529AA43389F356792E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a position placed in level IV or V of the Executive Schedule under section 5317 of title 5, United States Code;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2AB5D711839C49CEBF735F992E63A799"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a position as a limited term appointee, limited emergency appointee, or noncareer appointee in the Senior Executive Service, as defined under paragraphs (5), (6), and (7), respectively, of section 3132(a) of title 5, United States Code; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE715C83143A346E7A0F1EB8A70EF42C4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a position in the executive branch of the Government of a confidential or policy-determining character under schedule C of subpart C of part 213 of title 5 of the Code of Federal Regulations; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD5B9EC133DB64C5D80463F4A621DF85E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include a position if the individual serving in the position has been excluded from the application of section 101(f)(5);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDFAB40F2895640969E2BA636995B5513"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Disclosure requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H52CB72685D97455989F1A6AEAFF4670E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 101—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4B0378356F8241CE9F45E78A3C4FFB47"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <clause id="HAA36CA0E28B548A2B51DF9C3102DE338"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(1)</quote> before <quote>Within</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3B1AF5E7E46C4EE682B0AF5477C54A87"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>unless</quote> and inserting <quote>and, if the individual is assuming a covered position, the information described in section 102(j), except that, subject to paragraph (2), the individual shall not be required to file a report if</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0E9F3BE19D7941918AAA5D457FD59202"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF160237C42344B77A04D66A87BAEE892" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H20330B283B6D4FD3BBCDF90AEB1B5E31" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>If an individual has left a position described in subsection (f) that is not a covered position and, within 30 days, assumes a position that is a covered position, the individual shall, within 30 days of assuming the covered position, file a report containing the information described in section 102(j)(2)(A).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0735ACAE0A7434D9E321E86F3FE41CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1), in the first sentence, by inserting <quote>and the information required by section 102(j)</quote> after <quote>described in section 102(b)</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF08ED874DE624AC487245F2F59BD827B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (d), by inserting <quote>and, if the individual is serving in a covered position, the information required by section 102(j)(2)(A)</quote> after <quote>described in section 102(a)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H88DDF3CDB40C434095383F552E22339D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subsection (e), by inserting <quote>and, if the individual was serving in a covered position, the information required by section 102(j)(2)(A)</quote> after <quote>described in section 102(a)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H06F75F71245442DAA7B239E899F5D2B1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 102—</text> <subparagraph id="HC9DFD86C147B476ABF1A87F622D58AC2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (g), by striking <quote>Political campaign funds</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in subsection (j), political campaign funds</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81DC8B2B7E8C4C1F8AD9CE265859192B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0904AAD2CA7F4886927FE830199CC2A2" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H5145AC42B68B49F2BF81A42F39F66F6A"><enum>(j)</enum> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA4B6287413BD4697B577ED3972882B9A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In this subsection—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA1D6FE7A677D4991A317E4B744EFBC51" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>applicable period</term> means—</text> <clause id="HE424FB117BDB4930B882ACC194DAE4E3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with respect to a report filed pursuant to subsection (a) or (b) of section 101, the year of filing and the 4 calendar years preceding the year of the filing; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9C98B8A34F1749AE8C906060A7817AC1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect to a report filed pursuant to subsection (d) or (e) of section 101, the preceding calendar year; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3EBBAC997C2F41D4B8743EC92C0477F0" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <term>covered gift</term> means a gift that—</text> <clause id="H0D44923EB74641188E7641C71E4D3728"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is made to a covered individual, the spouse of a covered individual, or the dependent child of a covered individual;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB29C8C5D3B8645C19C22D024B7590CB9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is made by an entity described in item (aa) or (bb) of section 109(2)(A)(i)(II); and</text> </clause><clause id="H523BFA722A8D44528094D6A53B35FBC8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>would have been required to be reported under subsection (a)(2) if the covered individual had been required to file a report under section 101(d) with respect to the calendar year during which the gift was made.</text>
										</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD98B565D403F482DB85F32DAB0DB1EA0" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H82C28BB86EF243F4B1DE7B2D10423878"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A report filed pursuant to subsection (a), (b), (d), or (e) of section 101 by a covered individual shall include, for each covered contribution made by or on behalf of, or that was solicited in writing by or on behalf of, the covered individual during the applicable period—</text>
 <clause id="HA1501B3E3F374054A5AE935B3A922465" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the date on which the covered contribution was made;</text> </clause><clause id="H6A3A00FD94FE44E9AB2C8564EB0A52B6" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if applicable, the date or dates on which the covered contribution was solicited;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H01C04E5691084B0986561EC02361499B" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the value of the covered contribution;</text> </clause><clause id="H41F2A809A4424587A63F00EECE6E6035" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the name of the person making the covered contribution; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H76117E69C7274A7DAFBB9260AB9EA663" indent="up1"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the name of the person receiving the covered contribution.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2BE15BF9317747B39221F2FC5E8742EF" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum> <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HEDBF1E66806C4BBDAB772A3EE5B09A83"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Subject to clause (ii), a covered contribution made by or on behalf of, or that was solicited in writing by or on behalf of, a covered individual shall constitute a conflict of interest, or an appearance thereof, with respect to the official duties of the covered individual.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB784C7837D1B48558AA1278CEE34788E" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Director of the Office of Government Ethics may exempt a covered contribution from the application of clause (i) if the Director determines the circumstances of the solicitation and making of the covered contribution do not present a risk of a conflict of interest and the exemption of the covered contribution would not affect adversely the integrity of the Government or the public's confidence in the integrity of the Government.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0DD75BA2487415B946DC62779D82E83" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A report filed pursuant to subsection (a) or (b) of section 101 by a covered individual shall include the information described in subsection (a)(2) with respect to each covered gift received during the applicable period.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE322061FB4A34AD7ADD0EF757E545CA4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Provision of reports and ethics agreements to Congress</header><text>Section 105 of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H767F49C8BC3E4905B3B2DADBFCF0099B" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HE18656F070514C4097493F47AF90D7D3"><enum>(e)</enum><text>Not later than 30 days after receiving a written request from the Chairman or Ranking Member of a committee or subcommittee of either House of Congress with jurisdiction of the agency in which a covered individual has been nominated for appointment to a covered position or is serving in a covered position, the Director of the Office of Government Ethics shall provide to the Chairman or Ranking Member, respectively, each report filed under this title by the covered individual and any ethics agreement entered into between the agency and the covered individual.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDD2675BB7A7643438D6AB5EC9D366172"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rules on ethics agreements</header><text>The Director of the Office of Government Ethics shall promptly issue rules regarding how an agency in the executive branch shall address information required to be disclosed under the amendments made by this Act in drafting ethics agreements between the agency and individuals appointed to positions in the agency.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H148E5266467C465A95CC43121ACE613A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="HB8D83EC46B3B45EEAEB239C4A3F5C597"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HEBB722226CBF45D8A94EC0B57D4E46DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in section 101(f)—</text>
 <clause id="HA99122B333854D3E9B429FD07B42BB29"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (9), by striking <quote>section 109(12)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 109(15)</quote>;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6F5E9E651475441CB7BE3B91D9424F26"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (10), by striking <quote>section 109(13)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 109(16)</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8FBDA1F81FBF4F2AB1ACFC3A95A6D5E3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (11), by striking <quote>section 109(10)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 109(13)</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H99A98CE64CAB4FFF983D2417E8F08F59"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (12), by striking <quote>section 109(8)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 109(11)</quote>;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H21FDC44A60324B7BBA1E323B24BB90E1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 103(l)—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H69630C68D0CD42C0BDEBF23C93A0DE6B"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (9), by striking <quote>section 109(12)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 109(15)</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H194EA45F6D7B44709E594AA9A9B1A91E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (10), by striking <quote>section 109(13)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 109(16)</quote>; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H92FBD8557EAC4287A3315F15EBC1C008"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in section 105(b)(3)(A), by striking <quote>section 109(8) or 109(10)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 109(11) or 109(13)</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2437C5905EFB448AA8AD1F36104DAADD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 3(4)(D) of the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1602">2 U.S.C. 1602(4)(D)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 109(13)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 109(16)</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAEFE5601E74F4C96890463BE929B7AB5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Section 21A of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78u-1">15 U.S.C. 78u–1</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBB2347A9050941E49900907FC57F3A93"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (g)(2)(B)(ii), by striking <quote>section 109(11) of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc-appendix" parsable-cite="usc-appendix/5/109">5 U.S.C. App. 109(11)</external-xref>))</quote> and inserting <quote>section 109 of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.))</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1976A5B46D4E41C88DC9B3574B910D93"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (h)(2)—</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA755BAF709BD419A8A996F0120DBB502"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>section 109(8) of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc-appendix" parsable-cite="usc-appendix/5/109">5 U.S.C. App. 109(8)</external-xref>)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 109 of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD20909DFEE68422FB943298C47301DF5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>section 109(10) of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc-appendix" parsable-cite="usc-appendix/5/109">5 U.S.C. App. 109(10)</external-xref>)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 109 of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote>.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4C695154BA0F4AFB806FD04AEEB7E4A4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Section 499(j)(2) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290b">42 U.S.C. 290b(j)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 109(16) of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978</quote> and inserting <quote>section 109 of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

