<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H8663999BA06E4FD0B4267A412745CABF" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1414 IH: Justice for Victims of Fraud Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1414</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170307">March 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Maxine Waters of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001050">Ms. Hanabusa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001185">Mr. Sean Patrick Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Truth in Lending Act and the Electronic Fund Transfer Act to provide justice to
			 victims of fraud.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H663D1D8599EC4E678FFE59FD4FC800DC" style="OLC">
 <section id="HA112CE44E8BC419D971DBAB7877F3ABD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Justice for Victims of Fraud Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H9D72D9A1C40D41C6BE0DDD90CEE9D40C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H2DE58DA3DE524EA6A5ACC03ADB682135"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection found that Wells Fargo management implemented sales incentives, including an incentive-compensation program, in part to increase the number of banking products and services that its employees sold to its customers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4DEAE508BC2144FEACA1962E09A34A77"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection found that Wells Fargo employees engaged in improper sales practices to satisfy sales goals under Wells Fargo’s incentive compensation program, including opening as many as 1,534,280 checking accounts and 565,443 credit card accounts using consumers’ information without their knowledge or consent between May 2011 and July 2015.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC3FD84014F79447EB0C6874F2F34196A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Wells Fargo successfully claimed in Jabbari v. Wells Fargo that customers had signed away their rights to hold Wells Fargo accountable in court for claims of fraud because those customers were bound to a forced arbitration clause for their legitimate accounts.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDCEC513077D341DB904383AB7E77EEBF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>After Wells Fargo publicly entered a settlement with Federal regulators for the opening of thousands of unauthorized customer accounts, Wells Fargo claimed in Mitchell et al. v. Wells Fargo et al. that customers’ fraud claims must continue to be forced into arbitration.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB3872925837748F89EEFAE9FFF09B107"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Several courts have determined that despite claims of fraud over unauthorized accounts opened without customer knowledge or consent, those customers are still bound by contracts forcing those claims into arbitration based on the courts’ interpretation of the Federal Arbitration Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1506231B8D9647A2B336FFC6A928D307"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Federal Arbitration Act (now codified as <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/9/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of title 9, United States Code) was intended to apply to disputes between commercial entities of generally similar sophistication and bargaining power, but a series of decisions by the Supreme Court of the United States have interpreted the Federal Arbitration Act as applicable to claims of fraud.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9C61C482F0A348AD825DD8C6A73DF3A1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Consumers have no meaningful choice whether to submit their claims to arbitration and are typically unaware that they have given up their rights to file claims in court.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H44C43835EB0F45B486C18195D017FBA1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Arbitration of consumer disputes related to credit card accounts</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Chapter 2 of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1631">15 U.S.C. 1631</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following (and the table of contents for such chapter is conformed accordingly):</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8C2481D4204143B3A1D5E0C116111F65" style="USC">
				<section id="HAE1566ADAB5745D79B11A483D5B01C48"><enum>140B.</enum><header>Validity and enforceability</header>
 <subsection id="H63A330D854DC4817ACC3A629F9DF6F08"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="HA2013EC34CF84A67A117F6B3A0C500AE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>covered dispute</term> means a dispute that is not subject to a final judgment by a court; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA5021B5593074C52BC4087F36F8998A7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>predispute arbitration agreement</term> means any agreement between a person and a consumer providing for arbitration of any future dispute between the parties.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H20760AE83DC74F0DAF240A5E7D38CF99"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Validity and enforceability</header><text>No pre­dis­pute arbitration agreement shall be valid or enforceable in a covered dispute that is related to a credit card that was not issued in response to a request or application for that credit card account.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAF18E43B2DE94F94819F1EBA87329A63"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The applicability of this section to a predispute arbitration agreement shall be determined by a State or Federal court of competent jurisdiction.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H0EE50127846C40DDA09A69964227CFD5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Arbitration of consumer disputes related to covered accounts</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Electronic Fund Transfer Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1693">15 U.S.C. 1693</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by inserting after section 920 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1693o-2">15 U.S.C. 1693o–2</external-xref>) the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFA0D82305A914133AA57C7F5AAD3F794" style="OLC">
				<section id="H99663BEAAE4E4E2EA4C0751F41C7AEBF"><enum>920A.</enum><header>Validity and enforceability</header>
 <subsection id="H8C59FDD42EDC49F89450B08A9F5F1890"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="H58515A8F044945E394AFCCF9F147FAFD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>covered account</term>—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H49F313BE046B4C6EA655337BF705DA61"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a demand deposit, savings deposit, or other asset account (other than an occasional or incidental credit balance in an open end credit plan as defined in section 103(i)), as described in regulations of the Bureau, established primarily for personal, family, or household purposes, including demand accounts, time accounts, negotiable order of withdrawal accounts, and share draft accounts; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H130284AB2A0449EF8CFD9A0DE0270CE2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include an account held by a financial institution pursuant to a bona fide trust agreement;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F33F2926E844777A13EB2D80BA155CC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>covered dispute</term> means a dispute that is not subject to a final judgment by a court; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBB90B49C09234D7BB016848C9432DDF4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>predispute arbitration agreement</term> means any agreement between a financial institution and a consumer providing for arbitration of any future dispute between the parties.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE5003066746947A2A9219D3527EDEF2A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Validity and enforceability</header><text>No pre­dis­pute arbitration agreement shall be valid or enforceable in a covered dispute that is related to a covered account that was not issued in response to a request or application for that covered account.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H842DBB1464204DC8B00C7ACF0DDFED6B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The applicability of this section to a predispute arbitration agreement shall be determined by a State or Federal court of competent jurisdiction.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H8ECB776D2BA54EDAA1506C2E8EEBDB28"><enum>5.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in the amendments made by this Act shall be construed—</text> <paragraph id="H45C36935CFBE4733965DB66B0266E1A2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to authorize the imposition of a requirement to submit a dispute to arbitration; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H46102E777F84407E8E63A6FDC938CBE7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to restrict any court from ruling that a requirement to submit a dispute to arbitration is invalid or unenforceable.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


