<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H5C4E9E3096E7412A88082EBFADE47784" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2872 : Promoting Hydropower Development at Existing Nonpowered Dams Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2872</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date date="20171213">December 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc> Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Power Act to promote hydropower development at existing nonpowered dams, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H5DBAB5C2FB7C4222A136738BF7677216" style="OLC">
 <section id="HDBAFC54142694A2F949A3DE8D0EE0B06" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Promoting Hydropower Development at Existing Nonpowered Dams Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H8FE33B3F80FB46908E0D27F126DF3630"><enum>2.</enum><header>Promoting hydropower development at existing nonpowered dams</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part I of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/792">16 U.S.C. 792</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="HF65103A600B644F8891276EE3448BA69">
				<section id="H15973A1B2FF04AD9B4D2B2500B7F04C2"><enum>34.</enum><header>Promoting hydropower development at existing nonpowered dams</header>
					<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDFBDA9D0123D4B30B13CC1F08EDDA32F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Expedited licensing process for non-Federal hydropower projects at existing nonpowered dams</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HE44944C247A148449FA1D54725F930BB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As provided in this section, the Commission may issue and amend licenses and preliminary permits, as appropriate, for any facility the Commission determines is a qualifying facility.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H399072BA0FD7419B92DCDA751AE6DA5E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Commission shall issue a rule establishing an expedited process for issuing and amending licenses and preliminary permits for qualifying facilities under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H083C468077FC455FB74D0827B9E8548D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Interagency Task Force</header><text>In establishing the expedited process under this section, the Commission shall convene an interagency task force, with appropriate Federal and State agencies and Indian tribes represented, to coordinate the regulatory processes associated with the authorizations required to construct and operate a qualifying facility.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3BB08B0971CD4DC5B1D5260494822BA5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Length of Process</header><text>The Commission shall ensure that the expedited process under this section will result in a final decision on an application for a license by not later than 2 years after receipt of a completed application for the license.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBAB90C6618B047BB9537761CFF69661D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Dam safety</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HD4A9CC7052014D86BC31BCA0338E5ECB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text>Before issuing any license for a qualifying facility, the Commission shall assess the safety of existing non-Federal dams and other non-Federal structures related to the qualifying facility (including possible consequences associated with failure of such structures).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H29C480BCBD1F4EE6953959E1542C4986"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In issuing any license for a qualifying facility, the Commission shall ensure that the Commission’s dam safety requirements apply to such qualifying facility, and the associated qualifying nonpowered dam, over the term of such license.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5F16C73D7F584D25BDB9AC1259943B9A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Interagency communications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Interagency cooperation in the preparation of environmental documents under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.) with respect to an application for a license for a qualifying facility under this section, and interagency communications relating to licensing process coordination pursuant to this section, shall not—</text>
 <paragraph id="H73F12A52FF374E35B910F049DA0926E5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be considered to be ex parte communications under Commission rules; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H325B2E8D34D84D5788BBAD88CB0FC55A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>preclude an agency from participating in a licensing proceeding under this part.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9B47218F4F0C4F6083734EAD3B958A88"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Identification of nonpowered dams for hydropower development</header>
 <paragraph id="H49005E7F11FF4C9CABC51BC6C4CB43A9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 12 months after the date of enactment of this section, the Commission, with the Secretary of the Army, the Secretary of the Interior, and the Secretary of Agriculture, shall jointly develop a list of existing nonpowered Federal dams that the Commission and the Secretaries agree have the greatest potential for non-Federal hydropower development.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC2FA349CEC144552A523096ABEA1EB16"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In developing the list under paragraph (1), the Commission and the Secretaries may consider the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF4FC389A529B409CAF555238B326DA00"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The compatibility of hydropower generation with existing purposes of the dam.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CF803E5EC5D4AB195FFA01672D209B2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The proximity of the dam to existing transmission resources.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H622FF9ED2AEC4751A70F63D6A9D5F0D0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The existence of studies to characterize environmental, cultural, and historic resources relating to the dam.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84EFC3CCECAA43B0A5901F55047111AB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The effects of hydropower development on release or flow operations of the dam.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC63EB0231856482186C5D048B3F5E01B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>The Commission shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC17BF1D2FB9B44DB9ADC1AD790E395C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide the list developed under paragraph (1) to—</text> <clause id="H9235B7F93DA648DEA7E8203DA505BA4F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Commerce, the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and the Committee on Natural Resources, of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2390D0B8E5354C4BA238DE447FC89BD1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Committee on Environment and Public Works, and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, of the Senate; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1ADB73D262954D2FB1C9271EC0862D49"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make such list available to the public.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H731E76F8ABD94B7BB5B8E7A979C44722"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HAE5ABE610F1B4C768B5AE612D82844B2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Qualifying criteria</header><text>The term <term>qualifying criteria</term> means, with respect to a facility—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HA23251D72F0644629D251CE09146726A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as of the date of enactment of this section, the facility is not licensed under, or exempted from the license requirements contained in, this part;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD2ABFABB868B46FB806083EE0F2A3276"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the facility will be associated with a qualifying nonpowered dam;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9BEE7AEB9F484A0B8735BA6BB3E0561F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the facility will be constructed, operated, and maintained for the generation of electric power;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8F0E8F3B8809420DB89A4158031C6A54"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the facility will use for such generation any withdrawals, diversions, releases, or flows from the associated qualifying nonpowered dam, including its associated impoundment or other infrastructure; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H23278BB8A5C54E31AEA7FECD59A332C0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the operation of the facility will not result in any material change to the storage, release, or flow operations of the associated qualifying nonpowered dam.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H37865ED5818E4D32BA32B13AA0564B27"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualifying facility</header><text>The term <term>qualifying facility</term> means a facility that is determined under this section to meet the qualifying criteria.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4FBEC23995DC4C65B3797F823425D314"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualifying nonpowered dam</header><text>The term <term>qualifying nonpowered dam</term> means any dam, dike, embankment, or other barrier—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0E4EAA89D01D49D1AACBB3D4EF3C4C55"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the construction of which was completed on or before the date of enactment of this section;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H86A8EE0706134CA888A4727A56E1D195"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that is or was operated for the control, release, or distribution of water for agricultural, municipal, navigational, industrial, commercial, environmental, recreational, aesthetic, drinking water, or flood control purposes; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H868F07299B24401CA9AF0A1DD9F6A1C7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that, as of the date of enactment of this section, is not generating electricity with hydropower generating works that are licensed under, or exempted from the license requirements contained in, this part.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section commented="no" id="H09B9E5869CAA4270BE5DB8F17BFC7B66"><enum>3.</enum><header>Obligation for payment of annual charges</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 10(e) of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/803">16 U.S.C. 803(e)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0DF3EF4094B54D228D20AEF46DF55AF8" style="OLC">
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H4ED441FE704848FB832F516E8C1D7618" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any obligation of a licensee for payment of annual charges under this subsection shall commence when the construction of the applicable facility commences.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body>
	<attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20171212">Passed the House of Representatives December 12, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill>


