<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE52886450162445D99835B46CA076980" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3828 IH: Patsy T. Mink Gender Equity in Education Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3828</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170925">September 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001166">Mr. McNerney</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To support educational entities in fully implementing title IX and reducing and preventing sex
			 discrimination in all areas of education.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H3EFF3A641E994C95992A1144C685A3F1" style="OLC">
 <section id="H46A899EF57424D54978C4F9ACDFD67A3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Patsy T. Mink Gender Equity in Education Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H8085B50BCCBB4AE384A0FC61AE2EDB4C" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header> <subsection id="HBE10CF7142DA4F58AD5C9C80C3D0BAFE"><enum></enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HB76C3A53A75C45EE949F819B3CE14665"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681</external-xref> et seq.) (in this Act referred to as <quote>title IX</quote>) and the implementing regulations of title IX prohibit sex discrimination in federally funded education programs and activities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEDB00E5B2F594ACB9DC06076BE47DFA4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Although title IX ensures equal opportunities to participate in athletics, female participation rates, especially for girls of color, lag far behind male participation rates. The National Women’s Law Center reports that only 64 percent of Black girls, 64 percent of Hispanic girls, and 53 percent of Asian-American girls play sports, compared to 76 percent of Caucasian girls. Female student athletes have been found to have higher levels of self-esteem and to be more likely to graduate from high school than female students who do not play sports. Although the availability of athletic scholarships facilitates access to higher education, many schools fail to award proportional athletic financial aid to females, which can affect the long-term employment outcomes and economic security of women.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC6C4C92F8794EEE907C85A1E4474EBD"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Although title IX ensures gender equity in career and technical education, women are severely underrepresented in nontraditional fields. The American Association of University Women reports that females make up more than 70 percent of students enrolled in classes that prepare students for low-paying and historically female jobs, such as caregivers and cosmetologists and only 20 percent of students enrolled in classes that prepare students for high-paying and historically male jobs, such as energy technicians and electricians.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0A96F98D1D2846099B43559E3CBFC870"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Although title IX ensures gender equity in the fields of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (in this section referred to as <quote>STEM</quote>) education, women are disproportionately lost at nearly every stage of the STEM pipeline. The National Student Clearinghouse reports that the percentage of women earning STEM degrees has decreased over the past decade, with women earning 19 percent of engineering bachelor's degrees, 18 percent of computing bachelor's degrees, 42 percent of mathematics bachelor's degrees, and 39 percent of physical science bachelor’s degrees. In 2013, women of color earned only 6 percent of computing bachelor's degrees and 3 percent of engineering bachelor’s degrees.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF3F18A412847495983F43396CA2C1BD8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Although title IX prohibits sex discrimination in employment in federally funded education programs, women comprise only 37.5 percent of tenured faculty and 22 percent of university presidents, and female representation in STEM drops at every faculty and leadership level. The National Science Foundation reports that women hold only 25 percent of all tenured and tenure-track positions and 17 percent of full professor positions in STEM fields, Black and Hispanic women together hold only 4.4 percent of all tenured and tenure-track positions and 1.5 percent of full professor positions in STEM fields, and Asian-American women hold only 6.1 percent of all tenured and tenure-track positions and 1.9 percent of full professor positions in STEM fields.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3F85200367B5455683A0CC5058A55C00"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Although title IX protects against sexual and sex-based harassment and violence, more than 50 percent of girls in grades 7 through 12 experience sexual harassment each year and approximately 10 percent of high school students experience dating violence each year. A 2013 study by the Gay Lesbian Straight Education Network reports that 55 percent of lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender youth report feeling unsafe at school because of their sexual orientation and 38 percent report feeling unsafe because of their gender expression. Research has shown that students who experience harassment at school are more likely to experience depression and anxiety, to engage in unhealthy and antisocial behaviors, and to have more unexcused absences from school.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF4CF6E270AAD4632867937DBF2B948FD"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Although title IX guarantees access to medical leave, the availability of accommodations for pregnancy-related conditions, and the availability of enrollment in school-related activities for pregnant and parenting students, numerous studies have found that pregnancy and parenting are the leading reasons that females drop out of high school. A 2012 report from the National Women's Law Center shows that only 51 percent of teenage mothers earn a high school diploma by the age of 22, compared with 89 percent of women who do not have a child during their teenage years, limiting continuing opportunities for education and employment.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD30FF34960DC406EA6E563271889282F"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Although title IX protects against discrimination based on stereotypes of actual or perceived sex, gender, gender identity, or sexual orientation, many people carry implicit or unconscious biases that can unintentionally influence attitudes, beliefs, behaviors, and decisionmaking processes. Research has shown that unconscious biases can impact classroom environments, teaching methods, student evaluations, disciplinary practices, and career and counseling guidance, particularly for students who are pursuing nontraditional fields.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H162612A9C1F24E618B1B58B338CADFC1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H4A58FC1CF7414451B5B845E82D01460D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>ESEA definitions</header><text>The terms <term>elementary school</term>, <term>institution of higher education</term>, <term>local educational agency</term>, <term>secondary school</term>, and <term>State educational agency</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4FBC0992E7D94235BE37610F0EB3877B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compound discrimination</header><text>The term <term>compound discrimination</term> means discrimination based on sex, and one or more other characteristic, including race, ethnicity, national origin, disability status, religion, or age.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF092264F700A4444BEDBA26F548E21EE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <quote>Director</quote> means the Director of the Officer for Gender Equity established under section 5(a).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD25CAF6460FC45E6820D8A9859EB875C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Educational entity</header><text>The term <term>educational entity</term> means any of the following entities that receive Federal funds:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H02F0E470014F4A4D8E517760165B4AE9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A State educational agency.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6F8267391E44C6EA9DFD5245DDA8C71"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A local educational agency.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A5C6B6677A0412DBFA36AED2908039C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An institution of higher education.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCB8F187A6334D558BFFE97ADDAAF49F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An elementary school or secondary school.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE6F77FDABA184CF287A9256AFC073FAD"><enum>(5)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H123B587561BC4C838F6027CE2339C661"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Sex discrimination</header><text>The term <term>sex discrimination</term> means bias, discrimination, harassment, or violence based on:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD125ED0A3F504ACABBAB776326404AC8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Actual or perceived sex, sexual orientation, gender, or gender identity.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3762082902D84EC18E1EAA73EBBB5487"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Pregnancy, childbirth, or a related medical condition.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H128B9E951E70411D8F50CB8F343F2DCF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A stereotype associated with any characteristic described in subparagraph (A) or (B).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H530F8D20FCE04D04BD86AA8662C21D38"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Title ix coordinator</header><text>The term <term>title IX coordinator</term> means a responsible employee, as described in section 106.8(a) of title 34, Code of Federal Regulations, designated to coordinate efforts under title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H1CF43530D17D4151A148626B5CB4B778"><enum>4.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are to—</text> <paragraph id="H6A6B680430644025AB316B017CF6DE8E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promote gender equity in education in the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF7920DFD098B46918737895A28C6FF39"><enum>(2)</enum><text>support educational entities so that such entities have the support to fully implement title IX;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD0BB6B59239F4A7E93700FC33D7F8B22"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide title IX coordinators with training, technical assistance, and support to fully carry out their roles and responsibilities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD45E2DEBB81C41A18B8A8133061D8C59"><enum>(4)</enum><text>increase general awareness about the rights and obligations of individuals and entities under title IX;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBA41E32114EB4A05A718276B2627D0A6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>identify, implement, and disseminate best practices for reducing and preventing sex discrimination in all areas of education;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD5527EFAAED447288D44C54723ECB4B6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>promote educational environments that are safe and free of sexual and sex-based bullying, harassment, and violence; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4E2B5BB2720B49048AA9DE2551677DE3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>promote equity in education for students who face compound discrimination.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="HE7596AFF0FBB48FEA2AFEA37F62F557D"><enum>5.</enum><header>Establishment of an Office for Gender Equity</header> <subsection id="HDD0D48E6A0564668814735523BD8A8C8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish an Office for Gender Equity. The Director of the Office for Gender Equity shall be the Special Assistant for Gender Equity, as authorized under section 202(b)(3) of the Department of Education Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/3412">20 U.S.C. 3412(b)(3)</external-xref>). The Director of the Office for Gender Equity shall report directly to the Secretary.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFDDA7706DD0847188C27B7E90BDC6293"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Office for Gender Equity shall be responsible for the following:</text> <paragraph id="HB604551888FA4D06A208E13C11575BDC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Supporting educational entities in the full implementation of title IX.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H53AC422751DC4CCC8AE66F5B8A99AAB3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Providing title IX coordinators with training, technical assistance, and support to fully carry out their roles and responsibilities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAEABCB78E9BB4BBFA7AD1C07F5BCE01B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Providing grants to implement programs and activities that are focused on reducing and preventing sex discrimination in all areas of education.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFA75A70B079E426B9FCF0D10DA1D296C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Identifying and disseminating best practices for reducing and preventing sex discrimination in all areas of education.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H48240DB232B441B8A50161884F6BD6DB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Maintaining an Office of Gender Equity resource center website to disseminate best practices in achieving gender equity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFF3B4CB9C3B64F7181B7B802E661E516"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Performing any other activity consistent with achieving the purposes of this Act.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFE641ABA065744A8B8607E42B2C430A2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>To carry out the purposes of this Act, the Secretary shall coordinate with other relevant Federal offices and agencies, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="H88C956D7CEC84DC68F51ECE138595D7B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Office for Civil Rights of the Department of Education;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0EEE231E45C04EE9AFCD5BD7A2FF158F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Institute of Education Sciences;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCF0DDAED87384E3190451ABECD01529F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the White House Council on Women and Girls;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA6BEF68EE5F741F5921E6A7C6BCA70BC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Women's Bureau of the Department of Labor;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H08A1C1CE3D59448A9118B3550F2B24EC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Office on Women's Health of the Department of Health and Human Services;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H90A396C13B3F4DECB399006B2155B27F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the Civil Rights Division of the Department of Justice;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD22E265E76A74AC6B8AAB001B871C40B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the Office on Violence Against Women of the Department of Justice;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4F056B80E03B4732BE28C66ABA94AEE9"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H28F760E2EF36444E98A73CF0398947EE"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the Office of Safe and Healthy Students of the Department of Education; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H456C7C18BD1747298CDA1E4B52BC1762"><enum>(10)</enum><text>other entities determined relevant for carrying out the purposes of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3E27CC8E5E3E4F07A1AF51D47121101E"><enum>6.</enum><header>Support for title ix coordinators</header>
 <subsection id="H2D75532EDA6744E2A2664BFDA2955C75"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director shall provide coordination, training, technical assistance, and support for title IX coordinators to ensure that educational entities are able to fully implement title IX and reduce and prevent sex discrimination in all areas of education.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H7CE257B7CC844EF29429B56C63723D87"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Title IX coordinator training</header>
 <paragraph id="H901F874ECDD8490893829A36A818CA54"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not less than once a year, the Director shall conduct a training for all title IX coordinators. The training may be conducted in partnership with a national organization with relevant expertise, and may be completed online or in person.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H620BC16495384DEBBB05844E94A09F35"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents of training</header><text>The training described in paragraph (1) shall include the following information:</text> <subparagraph id="H9D9226D91C2A40E39C507FE93E4EA35C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The role and responsibility of title IX coordinators.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6EE442728E72407FB495FE8255C262E6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Best practices for increasing awareness about rights and obligations under title IX.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5E17E1C6F404FCB9BED59E82D0BB632"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Best practices for investigating and responding to claims of violations of title IX.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F298A9C2029419AB67A823251A2BD80"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Best practices for identifying and preventing implicit and explicit sex discrimination in all areas of education, including—</text>
 <clause id="H3A4A106871464A15BA391DA3FABA94B7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>recruitment and admissions;</text> </clause><clause id="H91A67399561B495E939ADF5B6FC5309C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>teaching practices, textbooks, and curricula;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5792F400BCE94317A41C318CA1BE9866"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>campus safety and security;</text> </clause><clause id="H0B98FB81034D4444918620F1B768C527"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>financial assistance;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1CD9BF7DB92249F78F587BD92D310E2B"><enum>(v)</enum><text>access to facilities, resources, and housing;</text> </clause><clause id="H24926F1124B34547BB960C12CCCCC87D"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>access to course offerings;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H868DC61505254BAB8B288B70B404F714"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>student health services and insurance benefits;</text> </clause><clause id="H737BD773497E41F39CE3B3046E324C11"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>counseling and career guidance;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H55A6CE8C0BB3479C8AF398E201F81FDE"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>athletics;</text> </clause><clause id="H7537CBC59DB0439FBA0DB0DF55462C33"><enum>(x)</enum><text>discipline policies;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7AD2034AD0784B3C859D1CD3FBFDED19"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>employment; and</text> </clause><clause id="HE56F14BA8E6F4D9C9F007E7D05A4DA97"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>other areas that the Director determines are relevant for such purposes.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD65DAB037A34E6CA6ADF37FBDA9873F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application of Training</header>
 <subparagraph id="H805E11E3C2C44D1C896CF4DC4DAC4B70"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In General</header><text>The Director shall take steps to ensure that the trainings described in paragraph (1)—</text> <clause id="H997C45713BA646A99E2691F27A66D36B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are adapted, as necessary, to address issues of sex discrimination at all levels of education;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H50B6F74CB437480083226D89B27D8EF8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are updated with the latest evidence-based best practices; and</text> </clause><clause id="H2BC1A419F40E4FA2BAE2533BB468BF5A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>address recent trends in sex discrimination.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FAACC2C5C8648D8B46F06F63FE24428"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Attention to compound discrimination</header><text>The Director shall take steps to ensure that such trainings include attention to students who face compound discrimination.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4397766710794ACB94520FF4C6B6F356"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>The Director shall—</text> <clause id="HDBF36D237A2E412FB023D597A5FB4B2C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>develop and conduct pre- and post-training evaluations to assess the effectiveness of such trainings in improving the knowledge of the roles and responsibilities of title IX coordinators; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD6B5DA81C289425796E5B8EEF36C2D78"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>use such evaluations to update the title IX coordinator trainings annually.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC0AB34F26EA24AEDA0C9D294F959640B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Handbook for conducting title IX compliance self-Evaluations</header><text>The Director shall develop a handbook for conducting self-evaluations of compliance with title IX in all areas of education, as described in subsection (b)(2)(D).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB3453CD475FC4F678AA0C87BD4789031"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Assessment of title IX coordinator support</header><text>The Director shall collect relevant data and statistics on all title IX coordinators, including salary information, budgets, and primary roles, in order to make recommendations for improving title IX coordinator support.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8E96D2B4653344C2B89D8557EE0E83FB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Dissemination</header><text>The Director shall ensure that the workplace contact information of all title IX coordinators and any training materials or information developed under this section are made available on the Office of Gender Equity resource center website, described in section 5(b)(5).</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H01717869A7DA443D904D118CE65DE224"><enum>7.</enum><header>Support for local implementation</header>
			<subsection id="HBDF73AE1A0DC49DFA647442A38563700"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header>
 <paragraph id="H53E8E5485AFD4B13AA66ACD8D9B26E65"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director, is authorized to award grants to educational entities to support such educational entities in fully implementing title IX and reducing and preventing sex discrimination in all areas of education.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H13952E8ED32D45C2ABD719A8BAD026F8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible Entity</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>eligible entity</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HEAB1CAE6AE5B45AABA6616B006D2C7B4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State educational agency;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A7A0C120FCA4CE6B9245BD50944507A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a local educational agency;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C8555F8725746AA84EC18D6A5F7FB64"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an institution of higher education;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H714FF6B426C54A539F58F6C39185D9DF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an elementary school or secondary school; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6BD87D029F70462790EBEEC5574A093B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a partnership consisting of—</text>
 <clause id="H239EAF02505A410780D7BF180E82F9C3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an entity described in subparagraphs (A) through (D); and</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF1A2180977384E29B141D4433F586E21"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a national organization with relevant expertise, or another entity that the Secretary determines has relevant expertise.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6BF28C9094154FBBA6AC54E07EE6DA66"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An eligible entity receiving a grant shall use such funds to carry out programs and activities designed to fully implement title IX and prevent and reduce sex discrimination, including programs and activities that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE18FAEB940A74C279ADA3730CE8C25F0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>increase awareness of and counteract sex stereotypes, biases, and discrimination;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7112E679E4784F8A9C53E401899C08F4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include trainings for students, teachers, faculty, and all personnel to learn about best practices for reducing and preventing sex discrimination in all areas of education;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H694FCDF4252349478A6B0E7740AF5338"><enum>(3)</enum><text>increase access to campus resources, facilities, and course offerings;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5B7D31C56B0F430B80DBD8C6E8594732"><enum>(4)</enum><text>support title IX coordinators in performing outreach, advocacy, and education about title IX and reducing and preventing sex discrimination;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H76303DD0220945219BDA326FCFDBF42F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>are aimed at identifying patterns or systemic problems in compliance with title IX;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC613CF66721C4D55A364CA96DCA0920E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>strengthen prevention education and awareness programs regarding sexual and sex-based harassment and violence;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H91D96E1F46BE46D6BD436D4ED500727A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>conduct and analyze campus climate and victimization surveys;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H929532F0480948BE8900AB5C75F06C28"><enum>(8)</enum><text>include institutional assessment activities to identify areas and causes of gender inequities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H67F88D57939A49ECB11604089CEDD283"><enum>(9)</enum><text>make efforts to improve progress on gender equity indicators as described in subsection (c)(2)(A); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE2098B6D218E4C89B83D5DE966A47A15"><enum>(10)</enum><text>make efforts to improve accuracy in measurement, data collection, and reporting of gender equity indicators as described in subsection (c)(2)(A).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H17AB08AB14464165A7F7D7C9D15DAB89"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applications</header>
 <paragraph id="HBD41ACAEB88A49169F2674F88B1827B4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity desiring a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may reasonably require.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9016457163DA49E5B3441CF08F608314"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents of application</header><text>Each application submitted by an eligible entity under this section shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H7483D8698AF24ABE9644AC4838208A50"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of locally defined and documented gender equity needs and priorities, which may include any of the following indicators:</text>
 <clause id="H17E2EE8456F64138BF9754D780BC5900"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Academic indicators, including performance on State assessments, enrollment, admission, attrition, time to completion, and graduation rates.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1F33ED0A5E9B47F0A222DBCF113EDE9A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Civil rights data, including statistics on bullying, harassment, violence, discipline and expulsion.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFFC6D2B377CF4673BC8CDFE474C0242D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Campus climate and victimization data.</text> </clause><clause id="H8D353D6D6F204B0BAE98FE5F34473C42"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Employment data.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCE7D74FC17A44181B40697CFBE0E58EA"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Attendance and absenteeism data.</text> </clause><clause id="H9CC68DA3FD894694B7D25117BF9B6015"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Evidence of burden on title IX coordinators, including coordinator to student ratio and competing responsibilities.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3BA327E99B3B42BCAE7DAC9C6D8EFC87"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Other documentation of need that the Secretary determines is relevant.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF2EB2F9AED4468EB723A5D78A7B146D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of the evidence that will serve as the basis for the activities that the eligible entity proposes to carry out using grant funds under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF0338443CAE45FD8682E1A65A90BC4F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A description of the activities that the eligible entity proposes to carry out using grant funds under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3FFBFC77268E4460808F10F30A69E53D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A description of how the proposed activities will be adapted, as necessary, to meet the needs of students who face compound discrimination.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3946E103E1F14FB9A31794759642628F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A description of how the proposed activities will help the educational entity fully implement title IX.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22DB6C968B8A4C9D96D214944FDD3A32"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A description of a plan for how the proposed activities under this section will continue with local support following completion of the grant period and termination of Federal funding.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB39712701D0346B5B574110A9508D607"><enum>(G)</enum><text>A description of how the proposed activities are a significant component of a comprehensive plan for gender equity in education and full implementation of title IX.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H96C1313CE984400C9434EB185D3E4E05"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed as prohibiting persons of any sex or gender from participating in any of the programs or activities funded under this section.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H688CE7E1A2EC43DAAA8C2BBF43B90E5F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Award Basis</header>
 <paragraph id="H5052C3C7F8C24D8185ACDC0C83F060E2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Merit review</header><text>Grants shall be awarded under this section on a competitive basis.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1ADCCD778E5142F5B5395BD2F2749A39"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priorities</header> <subparagraph id="HBF3C75DD4FFE494EB380AA213D610B7B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In General</header><text>The Secretary shall establish criteria for determining which eligible entities shall have priority in receiving a grant under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB1E7F5755CA4484EBAF5C336AC0B9FEF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Level of priority</header><text>The criteria described in subparagraph (A) may include a consideration of the extent to which the application demonstrates that the eligible entity—</text>
 <clause id="HFE2C407AE7204C8DBE2C1E6FE7C1A1A8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has demonstrated a high need for gender equity assistance based on indicators described in subsection (c)(2)(A) and a high commitment to addressing these issues;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD6CE30438E79425E85E3FD461658D50A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>will address the needs of students who face compound discrimination;</text> </clause><clause id="HB67A31056CA0455B8757EECF72EB6222"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>has not previously received assistance under this section;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCB161D43E03E4E2FA99C5AC3252493A5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>will address relevant issues of national significance through solutions that can be replicated;</text> </clause><clause id="HDA17C34AE1F646ADB20E2EC7E4A4B285"><enum>(v)</enum><text>will implement an institutional change strategy with a long-term impact that will continue to be a central activity of the eligible entity upon termination of the grant; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H97DDE5A2A2C144A38DE17CC4093B7636"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>will serve a high percentage of low-income students.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB5A20793EFC4BD9973E4304D70ED20C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text>To the extent practicable, the Secretary shall ensure that grants awarded under this section, for each fiscal year, address—</text>
 <clause id="H070F78AD40F3433E945175863B99594B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>all levels of education, including—</text> <subclause id="H70F1DDC3115647708514350DB2468C55"><enum>(I)</enum><text>elementary and secondary education;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H2FEDD9BAF0F24A91A31880B53DDFD49E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>undergraduate and graduate education;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HB104BC50D0E74D57ADA51854E58CA3BE"><enum>(III)</enum><text>postdoctoral education and research;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H2EE98EEBCACF4E3199AA22C1B913DE1D"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>career and technical education; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H722355729F8E4254AFC30382D7575578"><enum>(V)</enum><text>adult education;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H4493D26837894DCFA10BB37CEA294C30"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>all regions of the United States; and</text> </clause><clause id="H6EDD6397AD094B388E5EA100629698FC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>urban, rural, and suburban educational entities.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF441DFF4445E46389EA3A0DCC5242C86"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Evaluation and dissemination</header>
				<paragraph id="H1258D192458B40DD84A7D21F37DBA8A2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Evaluation</header>
 <subparagraph id="H60E97C55CECC4F638BED9564159ACD0F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In General</header><text>Each eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall conduct an assessment about the extent to which the eligible entity made progress on the indicators under subsection (c)(2)(A).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38890B4AFCFD40A5B3B882BC4E938C8B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text>An eligible entity may work in partnership with the Institute of Education Sciences to conduct such assessment.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H165C0C7CE7234FE6A2F4AE5937C9290D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Use by secretary</header><text>Not later than 1 year after receiving the grant award, the eligible entity shall submit a report to the Secretary containing the results of such assessment. The Secretary shall use those reports in order to build the knowledge base on promising models for preventing and reducing sex discrimination across all areas and levels of education.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H028BBA853DFA4855BB420A168888A110"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Dissemination</header><text>The Secretary shall coordinate with the Director of the Institute of Education Sciences and other relevant Federal offices and agencies to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HADF7A0AB6FE5468BBBF5E69AA347E357"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure that the results of the activities carried out under this section are made readily available on the Office for Gender Equity resource center website; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35B87F40F87044A587738711C601312A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>widely disseminate the results described in subparagraph (A) to relevant Federal offices, and agencies, educational entities and the general public.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H936A47964DD445B881316E048BAB0D90"><enum>8.</enum><header>Research and development</header>
 <subsection id="H7EA452BE9F6C4805BD77D248B0653202"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall coordinate with the Director of the Institute of Education Sciences and other relevant Federal offices and agencies and entities to investigate, identify, and disseminate best practices to fully implement title IX and reduce and prevent sex discrimination in all areas of education, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="H645240EABB814ECD911222DC54190F7D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the reduction and prevention of sex stereotyping, bias, and discrimination in curricula, textbooks, software, and other educational materials;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCF65FE052BFC4460BE21DA52EBBF40B6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the development of policies and programs to—</text> <subparagraph id="HA165FA0C440B442C8A9570C91A8664E1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>address and prevent sexual and sex-based harassment and violence; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3EA674569DE142EA8D467DF6CB21C549"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that campuses are free from threats to the safety of students, teachers, faculty, and personnel;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB4AC996F8B949F9803EEF8170B4363D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the development and evaluation of—</text> <subparagraph id="H986228FED8FA49ADAF0CECC6A4AA9D1A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>counseling and career guidance training; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E45A263233440E6B09F77F9BA343FF4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>programs to reduce and prevent sex stereotyping, bias, and discrimination;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5AF15D5729234BBFA4E35D3F6B7ED185"><enum>(4)</enum><text>best practices for mitigating implicit bias in teaching, discipline, and all areas of education;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H53AD3567434547A082F638E65241313B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>best practices for addressing the needs of students who face compound discrimination; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H403CD71B3AE54704B8B843918AA8E3EA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>other activities that the Secretary determines are consistent with the purposes of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD162DF5BB05245A9934811CE63A68311"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Dissemination</header><text>The best practices described under subsection (a) shall be published on the Office for Gender Equity resource center website, as described in section 5(b)(5), and the What Works Clearinghouse website of the Institute of Education Sciences.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H710CF114C19C4D149757B725DA35DDBE"><enum>9.</enum><header>Report; dissemination</header>
 <subsection id="HCCF7A025733642A6A38E89505F80A942"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act and every 2 years thereafter, the Secretary shall publish a report on the steps the Department of Education has taken to—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD37F21EE83A148C1941881925019F540"><enum>(1)</enum><text>support educational entities in fully implementing title IX and reducing and preventing sex discrimination;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H05DD12F3821E42EA987412962E8C15D5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide coordination, training, and resources for title IX coordinators to fully carry out their roles and responsibilities; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAFE3348BCCB8418BAA924CF71719CF4E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>promote equity in education for students who face compound discrimination.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA4FCB3BA860E469F95F749158754D63C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Dissemination</header><text>The Secretary shall coordinate with the Director of the Institute of Education Sciences and the heads of relevant Federal agencies to ensure that the results of trainings, activities, evaluations, and research developments under this Act are made readily available on the Office for Gender Equity resource center website and disseminated widely to other relevant Federal agencies and offices, educational entities, and the general public.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H58D1622DCBA446B8898A7F6FABB79A1D"><enum>10.</enum><header>Rule of Construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed—</text> <paragraph id="H314B24F9515D458B80FA6C72EFECA617"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as modifying any provision of title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681</external-xref> et seq.); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H05BCB7DC74354910926A9EB07353019D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>as affecting the enforcement of such title by the Department of Education, the Department of Justice, or any other Federal agency.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H05D9AD74161E4B7EBCE530C2CA8A1EBB"><enum>11.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <subsection id="H2160EF29DE4240758454AAD70FE0382A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act $80,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H23FF4B7C052F454F9789CE6249E1EF8B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use</header><text>From amounts made available to carry out this Act for each fiscal year, the Secretary shall use not less than $70,000,000 of such amounts to award grants under section 7.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


