<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H23011008AF0043CA9F0E91486D07FF50" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4230 IH: Comprehensive Listing of Evidence for Assessments of Regulations Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4230</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171102">November 2, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001187">Mr. Meadows</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001193">Mr. MacArthur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000190">Mr. Norman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000065">Mr. Yoho</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000289">Mr. Jordan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001297">Mr. Buck</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the timely publication of any research source code and data used by a Federal agency in
			 assessing the costs and benefits of new regulations, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H56A543D4B58A40AB9D990C6E2D846469" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE2D0B443C1394ABF9DBDB72C715E0AC9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Comprehensive Listing of Evidence for Assessments of Regulations Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CLEAR Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HBEF79351DE1A46508BEC07A90D067F2E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requirement to publish research source code and data</header> <subsection id="H7DA7529ECA4447B28F6788FCFF965D19"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At any time during a rulemaking process that an assessment of any new regulation is completed, including the costs and benefits of such regulation, and not later than the issuance of such rule, the head of each agency, to enable entities outside the Federal Government to replicate the assessment, shall publish the following related to such assessment:</text>
 <paragraph id="H9864A70C70C146C0B15D13F575CD338E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any research source code and data used by that agency, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H07D44BA3F7DD4D11A422BECE30874A3F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any program used for any model, including intermediate and final;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E4C7362682F4BE0BB83135E1C2F47E3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any source code, data, and other materials used for any estimate or assumption used as a component in the overall model; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4BAD94EACB0435AB40D8C7091B6F859"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each data preparation routine, including cleaning, statistical matching, replacement of missing data with substituted values, and other data steps used in turning raw data into the data set used and the assessment.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F74FE86780C499BB9E353D273C3435D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any unprocessed data that is not prohibited from disclosure by statute.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7D4E6A21FF60401D9453AAD17719FE0B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With regard to any unprocessed data that is prohibited from disclosure by statute—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7463EC3495614F64B3A735139C770096"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a complete list of all data variables for such data; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB79602E057DF43ABB66CE8883EE0A3B5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">descriptive statistics for all data variables for such data (including averages, standard deviations, number of observations, and correlations to other variables), in lieu of but analogous to the original data, to allow the research source code and data to function as intended.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H09B73F39E29D4963898DD0D0763022CF"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any supplemental documentation, including that which documents—</text> <subparagraph id="H529A79B694A549DEA85806414C4FD7EB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>changes to the methodology and changes between versions of software implementation code; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7416946BC1C64D46A88B2B241E48DA28"><enum>(B)</enum><text>instructions that are sufficient to allow an individual outside of the Federal Government or not employed by the agency to run the model on their own.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H6817A61F30ED43B183E855D7C6EF38DE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Issuance to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the result of an assessment described in subsection (a) is requested privately and is issued to a Member of Congress or to a committee, such source code, data, and other materials shall be released to the private recipient, who may then choose to release the information publicly.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H90593492C896486E916332F0B5C8DB3D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Agency defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given that term in section 551 of title 5, United States Code.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H827DEACE105E4D438BB663B220A35ED9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act shall take effect 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


