<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB56EEFCDE9EA4E6A8104E522BC4A17C4" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4354 IH: Missed Opportunities in Science and Engineering Research Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4354</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171109">November 9, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000287">Mr. Lewis of Georgia</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require reporting by the National Science Foundation on requests for funding research that were
			 not granted and had the greatest potential for promoting scientific
			 progress and advancing national health, prosperity, and welfare, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H165F641AD66E47F48163E2F1FFE0CE08" style="OLC">
 <section id="H55298A2D56104CA0B93FB885A05DD2E9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Missed Opportunities in Science and Engineering Research Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H3B7853065FC34F7F97D948C936F7AFF7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Annual reporting by National Science Foundation on missed opportunities</header> <subsection id="H412BD31ACEDE4E40B6B2E571569EE121"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than March 30 of each fiscal year starting with fiscal year 2017 through fiscal year 2021, the Director of the National Science Foundation (in this section, referred to as the <quote>Director</quote>) shall submit to Congress a report on the fiscal health of the National Science Foundation research enterprise and the volume of worthy but unfunded grant proposals submitted to the National Science Foundation in the preceding fiscal year. Such report shall identify—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD947343B7ED84540972C056CEFED83A9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the success rate of grant applications reviewed during such fiscal year;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H48C3846B12D844D29FDCE6B907077215"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the top two grant applications reviewed during such fiscal year that were not selected for funding; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDC69CB3B42CE4069ADBAEB17052A54DD"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the success rate described in paragraph (1) is less than 32 percent, the top applications for grants that were not selected for funding but would have been so selected if the Foundation had achieved a success rate of 32 percent or greater for the fiscal year.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEADF0964D41747E3A096898AC76BFD02"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Trade secrets and confidential information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section does not authorize the Secretary to disclose any information that is a trade secret or confidential information subject to section 552(b)(4) of title 5, United States Code, or section 1905 of title 18, United States Code.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2AA6D72DE4E1414E9895D5E20A25A08B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H63F35BA5BB974C9EB174661B65165602"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Success rate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>success rate</quote> means the percentage of grant applications reviewed by the Director that received funding.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE7D316CFE50748BEB40EB33BA42EE6D6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Top</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>top</quote>, with respect to a grant application, means that such application has been determined by the Director to have greater potential than any other grant applications submitted to the Director for—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAA1B8CAD864E4BC6996A01E19B7C4624"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promoting any field of fundamental science or engineering;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A907E8D269A444D8480F61478772CB9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advancing the national health, prosperity, and welfare; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H105944FF4B9E4480B18FFC0D134006FC"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">securing the national defense.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

