<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H3343CBC75A6140FC8276E591B0E9B254" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 306 EH: Energy Efficient Government Technology Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 306</legis-num>
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 to promote energy efficiency via information and computing technologies, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form> 
<legis-body id="HAD8F56AD69B241028850D2A964F1C146" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD949A3BCE71849D98F1C759030083A96" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Energy Efficient Government Technology Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="HA52A6214CA0B4AE29E7564FD656463F4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Energy-efficient and energy-saving information technologies</header> <subsection id="HBE792833B0F94EA89C3E766B8704173E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle C of title V of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/140">Public Law 110–140</external-xref>; 121 Stat. 1661) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HACB499BA38C341FC908524684370A40B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H28783220D89842369C5FEBBF9F2E4998"><enum>530.</enum><header>Energy-efficient and energy-saving information technologies</header> 
<subsection id="HBBB6DFAB54E34FC3BF97D9189F7E44AC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HDDFE165B3A174D6DA2275543C9A761C2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9FB78B30E2304DBC8764803FAC17C0A7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information technology</header><text>The term <term>information technology</term> has the meaning given that term in section 11101 of title 40, United States Code.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCCE558CD1C154A80A5CA88DED0CE59D2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Development of implementation strategy</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, each Federal agency shall coordinate with the Director, the Secretary, and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to develop an implementation strategy (that includes best practices and measurement and verification techniques) for the maintenance, purchase, and use by the Federal agency of energy-efficient and energy-saving information technologies, taking into consideration the performance goals established under subsection (d).</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="HCA4B9828E1924640A5004D9CAE9D32FF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>In developing an implementation strategy under subsection (b), each Federal agency shall consider—</text> <paragraph id="H963BE7ADADDC45B18FEE999D911E04F4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>advanced metering infrastructure;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD159E244D2664D4DA4CD33B07C18D741"><enum>(2)</enum><text>energy-efficient data center strategies and methods of increasing asset and infrastructure utilization;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H5D3487A7C8344C1683190852FD1370BF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>advanced power management tools;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC6B5C0C5C36A4F6EB106542F5F2DA4C9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>building information modeling, including building energy management;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H86E3A8D3E6A645CBA0D7761A0773392B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>secure telework and travel substitution tools; and</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H96FEC7AC412045388051829984A36FF6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>mechanisms to ensure that the agency realizes the energy cost savings brought about through increased efficiency and utilization.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H01BB55A57AB14C6D8897D63B6A9E70F1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Performance goals</header> <paragraph id="H22C54977457847D18417FE94D88AD81A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Director, in consultation with the Secretary, shall establish performance goals for evaluating the efforts of Federal agencies in improving the maintenance, purchase, and use of energy-efficient and energy-saving information technology.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9982B7DA9149498DA6EBDB8980AC1153"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Best practices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chief Information Officers Council established under section 3603 of title 44, United States Code, shall recommend best practices for the attainment of the performance goals, which shall include Federal agency consideration of, to the extent applicable by law, the use of—</text> <subparagraph id="HD036A8C3ABC14FC5B2366BB95CC02835"><enum>(A)</enum><text>energy savings performance contracting; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H30560176DFA045E89391548CB705B60A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>utility energy services contracting.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H884FEC1D772C4E64A053D8BABF9D4B93"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports</header> <paragraph id="HDF20EEAFB25C41A6853992D5D79253A7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency reports</header><text>Each Federal agency shall include in the report of the agency under section 527 a description of the efforts and results of the agency under this section.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB783D7530190497EA9C2A68F80E7A6E1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>OMB government efficiency reports and scorecards</header><text>Effective beginning not later than October 1, 2017, the Director shall include in the annual report and scorecard of the Director required under section 528 a description of the efforts and results of Federal agencies under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection> <subsection id="H2BBACC4B07A949B6AE7351B5213286D3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>The table of contents for the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 is amended by adding after the item relating to section 529 the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H523FA7AC87BF4048841913E2103194A7" style="OLC"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 530. Energy-efficient and energy-saving information technologies.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection></section>
<section id="H1ECCA49D22E54F34A41FAB418CE81B6F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Energy efficient data centers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 453 of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17112">42 U.S.C. 17112</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HA1A6194A96164E8CBAC39C173046CB02"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDBBC40182B6B44D694248D609C3EA588"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(D)(iv), by striking <quote>determined by the organization</quote> and inserting <quote>proposed by the stakeholders</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H74F9AD245D3C4FB99B5E60B449C0CAE2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (3); and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF68E9F95C1124458A897437EB3EFD4BC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subsections (c) through (g) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H817233EEBD5241C8814D4F47E7BE1D31" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H0DB9B3A03918489EA05F9625D229D42F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Stakeholder involvement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary and the Administrator shall carry out subsection (b) in collaboration with information technology industry and other key stakeholders, with the goal of producing results that accurately reflect the most relevant and useful information. In such collaboration, the Secretary and the Administrator shall pay particular attention to organizations that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H15925BE8BD02446B8B06FFA18FE1E9DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>have members with expertise in energy efficiency and in the development, operation, and functionality of data centers, information technology equipment, and software, such as representatives of hardware manufacturers, data center operators, and facility managers;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HAFA853EF9E754A609A56C739D5F2B8EB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>obtain and address input from Department of Energy National Laboratories or any college, university, research institution, industry association, company, or public interest group with applicable expertise;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H77B46ED24D7444B2ABBC72A0E1D4BC6B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>follow—</text> <subparagraph id="HAEE3DEB9C2B04CEB89C6C8F476860875"><enum>(A)</enum><text>commonly accepted procedures for the development of specifications; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H653AD07526614E3C97E5AA693279749C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>accredited standards development processes; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H04DDBEB38508403D9CA8D80D0458ED79"><enum>(4)</enum><text>have a mission to promote energy efficiency for data centers and information technology.</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HD403EE0482A748DAAE30C5071DFC592E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Measurements and Specifications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary and the Administrator shall consider and assess the adequacy of the specifications, measurements, best practices, and benchmarks described in subsection (b) for use by the Federal Energy Management Program, the Energy Star Program, and other efficiency programs of the Department of Energy or the Environmental Protection Agency.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H3B5199AA45F340E29C16C146062FF3D2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Secretary, in collaboration with the Administrator, shall, not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of the Energy Efficient Government Technology Act, make available to the public an update to the Report to Congress on Server and Data Center Energy Efficiency published on August 2, 2007, under section 1 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/431">Public Law 109–431</external-xref> (120 Stat. 2920), that provides—</text> 
<paragraph id="H591FEE64DB8E4D3596CA6F3CB1F3ACDF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a comparison and gap analysis of the estimates and projections contained in the original report with new data regarding the period from 2008 through 2015;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HCEF5C6485B234918A80E7496F4A6B962"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis considering the impact of information technologies, including virtualization and cloud computing, in the public and private sectors;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC19588FD72094D909AC51D3507D73871"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an evaluation of the impact of the combination of cloud platforms, mobile devices, social media, and big data on data center energy usage;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H2133E02FCE6B44BF937FF6DD2E0B54DB"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an evaluation of water usage in data centers and recommendations for reductions in such water usage; and</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDCFA10FED731429CB07B527E85677ADB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>updated projections and recommendations for best practices through fiscal year 2020.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA1E9F76204A54FBB8397C9512A0B6880"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Data center energy practitioner program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in collaboration with key stakeholders and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, shall maintain a data center energy practitioner program that leads to the certification of energy practitioners qualified to evaluate the energy usage and efficiency opportunities in Federal data centers. Each Federal agency shall consider having the data centers of the agency evaluated every 4 years, in accordance with section 543(f) of the National Energy Conservation Policy Act, by energy practitioners certified pursuant to such program.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="HAC902A67EBEE4F12991B7ABD8E0E4C2C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Open data initiative</header><text>The Secretary, in collaboration with key stakeholders and the Office of Management and Budget, shall establish an open data initiative for Federal data center energy usage data, with the purpose of making such data available and accessible in a manner that encourages further data center innovation, optimization, and consolidation. In establishing the initiative, the Secretary shall consider the use of the online Data Center Maturity Model.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HD017C2314449403EADA091C82F88D27A"><enum>(h)</enum><header>International specifications and metrics</header><text>The Secretary, in collaboration with key stakeholders, shall actively participate in efforts to harmonize global specifications and metrics for data center energy and water efficiency.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H36F3F297F74D4635B0DB8F8875A03BB3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Data center utilization metric</header><text>The Secretary, in collaboration with key stakeholders, shall facilitate in the development of an efficiency metric that measures the energy efficiency of a data center (including equipment and facilities).</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H6F867267E38943B8B3932D71836CFA7C"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Protection of proprietary information</header><text>The Secretary and the Administrator shall not disclose any proprietary information or trade secrets provided by any individual or company for the purposes of carrying out this section or the programs and initiatives established under this section.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></section>
</legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20170110" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives January 10, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement>
</bill> 


