<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H817F42FC00D449578FBFF7CB41CF08D9" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4276 IH: Safeguarding Election Infrastructure Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4276</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171107">November 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to require voting systems used in elections for Federal
			 office to produce a voter-verified, auditable paper record of the votes
			 cast in such elections, to require State election officials to audit the
			 results of such elections prior to certifying the results, to provide
			 grants to States to improve voting system security, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HE55056F3E3F342D79E3460C6F1C65BF0" style="OLC">
 <section id="H75B95D372F674A0896BA7CB6B5C705C1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safeguarding Election Infrastructure Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HE2F9C669798B4768AFEC447E624E10E6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requiring use of voting systems capable of producing voter-verified, auditable paper record in elections for Federal office</header> <subsection id="H5947C2008C8A4DB3AD6F793535C2C19F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Moratorium on acquisition of certain direct recording electronic voting systems and certain other voting systems</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 301 of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21081">52 U.S.C. 21081</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC8AE157C1E0F48108A7470EF704B6170"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (c) and (d) as subsections (d) and (e); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCC71112E0DC646A883F406364E37A113"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following new subsection:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H56555A78A83A4A358BA7B08CFA0EE1DD" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="H1EB155853FFD41A1A422DE447D4C57E5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Moratorium on acquisition of certain direct recording electronic voting systems and certain other
 voting systems</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date of the enactment of the Safeguarding Election Infrastructure Act of 2017, no State or jurisdiction may purchase or otherwise acquire for use in an election for Federal office a direct recording electronic voting system or other electronic voting system that does not produce a voter-verified paper record as required by section 301(a)(2) (as amended by such Act).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H418969C48E6445CC90F3AD2AB7BD8C0F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Paper ballot and manual counting requirements</header>
 <paragraph id="HDED2CE3BAED447EEA3AF1E8682B1EEEF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 301(a)(2) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21081">52 U.S.C. 21081(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="H7D8005EA538E479CA856414B6F363C47"> <paragraph id="H47456A9ED84E4C489CA8ABBA381D547A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Paper ballot requirement</header> <subparagraph id="H37D03F15AF5D40278C6FF9F9A0C4221C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Voter-verified paper ballots</header> <clause id="H8CB019C8FAB34816B43D5C5AB3836694"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Paper ballot requirement</header> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H4400183892A345C29FFCF829F5DAD4D6"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The voting system shall require the use of an individual, durable, voter-verified, paper ballot of the voter’s vote that shall be marked and made available for inspection and verification by the voter before the voter’s vote is cast and counted, and which shall be counted by hand or read by an optical character recognition device or other counting device. For purposes of this subclause, the term <term>individual, durable, voter-verified, paper ballot</term> means a paper ballot marked by the voter by hand or a paper ballot marked through the use of a nontabulating ballot marking device or system, so long as the voter shall have the option to mark his or her ballot by hand (or, in the case of an individual with a disability, by such alternative method as the election official shall establish that provides an equivalent opportunity, including with privacy and independence, as for other voters).</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HEDDEF675C5654E3E8FED749A15FB6568" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The voting system shall provide the voter with an opportunity to correct any error on the paper ballot before the permanent voter-verified paper ballot is preserved in accordance with clause (ii).</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H4094E66CB3E542CEA722E3EAE7A5A3A1" indent="up1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>The voting system shall not preserve the voter-verified paper ballots in any manner that makes it possible, at any time after the ballot has been cast, to associate a voter with the record of the voter’s vote without the voter’s consent.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HD7F131F840DB47E6872F2D0F40E42824"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Preservation as official record</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The individual, durable, voter-verified, paper ballot used in accordance with clause (i) shall constitute the official ballot and shall be preserved and used as the official ballot for purposes of any recount or audit conducted with respect to any election for Federal office in which the voting system is used.</text>
								</clause><clause id="HC7B0954831D74BCBA50782ABA270E87A"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Manual counting requirements for recounts and audits</header>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0DCFAF33A6454247A17E4058CA233925"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Each paper ballot used pursuant to clause (i) shall be suitable for a manual audit, and shall be counted by hand in any recount or audit conducted with respect to any election for Federal office.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H8C8096FE888446839D188DCB0797D978" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the event of any inconsistencies or irregularities between any electronic vote tallies and the vote tallies determined by counting by hand the individual, durable, voter-verified, paper ballots used pursuant to clause (i), and subject to subparagraph (B), the individual, durable, voter-verified, paper ballots shall be the true and correct record of the votes cast.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H44BA152D3AE84F45AB61E7AEE78732A6"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Application to all ballots</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements of this subparagraph shall apply to all ballots cast in elections for Federal office, including ballots cast by absent uniformed services voters and overseas voters under the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act and other absentee voters.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA824A6E181C8456DB6B447D7C37D727F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Special rule for treatment of disputes when paper ballots have been shown to be compromised</header>
 <clause id="H94854FDEB0094EC5986261560364614C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the event that—</text> <subclause id="H587DD043FA1347A88A08C17CC85C9C84"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">there is any inconsistency between any electronic vote tallies and the vote tallies determined by counting by hand the individual, durable, voter-verified, paper ballots used pursuant to subparagraph (A)(i) with respect to any election for Federal office; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H2E691F92916041DF94BBBED82E8D8182"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">it is demonstrated by clear and convincing evidence (as determined in accordance with the applicable standards in the jurisdiction involved) in any recount, audit, or contest of the result of the election that the paper ballots have been compromised (by damage or mischief or otherwise) and that a sufficient number of the ballots have been so compromised that the result of the election could be changed,</text>
									</subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">the determination of the appropriate remedy with respect to the election shall be made in
			 accordance with applicable State law, except that the electronic tally
			 shall not be used as the exclusive basis for determining the official
 certified result.</continuation-text></clause><clause id="H360CF85209EF428897160E0570724E8B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Rule for consideration of ballots associated with each voting machine</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of clause (i), only the paper ballots deemed compromised, if any, shall be considered in the calculation of whether or not the result of the election could be changed due to the compromised paper ballots.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE70F187A4AEA471198BEF6BFEE88691B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment clarifying applicability of alternative language accessibility</header><text>Section 301(a)(4) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21081">52 U.S.C. 21081(a)(4)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>(including the paper ballots required to be used under paragraph (2))</quote> after <quote>voting system</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H016D2A179A3F485C8FDDB174A5C1882B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Other conforming amendments</header><text>Section 301(a)(1) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21081">52 U.S.C. 21081(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H83645772039E47A6B59A037A1CAED127"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)(i), by striking <quote>counted</quote> and inserting <quote>counted, in accordance with paragraphs (2) and (3)</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAAAB9CC541AD4C35B8A0B763225BFA4A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)(ii), by striking <quote>counted</quote> and inserting <quote>counted, in accordance with paragraphs (2) and (3)</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H48080828B7B64FD1A6168DB3FD3BCA55"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)(iii), by striking <quote>counted</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>counted, in accordance with paragraphs (2) and (3)</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC455934CF5C4ECCBB69552BEE0D7D91"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)(ii), by striking <quote>counted</quote> and inserting <quote>counted, in accordance with paragraphs (2) and (3)</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4117BE7B6DDA49AAA2D0C5696069BAFA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Section 301(d) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21081">52 U.S.C. 21081(d)</external-xref>) is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting the following: <quote>, or, in the case of the requirements of this section which are first imposed on a State or jurisdiction pursuant to the amendments made by section 2 of the Safeguarding Election Infrastructure Act of 2017, with respect to voting systems used for elections held on or after the expiration of the 1-year period which begins on the date of the enactment of such Act</quote>.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HD10AA8C4DE0A4AF7813F90E9D9E9539B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Mandatory manual audits of results of Federal elections</header>
 <subsection id="H828CC7082D404556BF51236F17974B26"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requiring audits of results</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title III of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21081">52 U.S.C. 21081</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following new subtitle:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H712C6CDDDB1D495C8E72AC811E91A2DC" style="OLC">
					<subtitle id="HA0BF495504CB4C00A9894C42FACAFC47"><enum>C</enum><header>Mandatory manual audits</header>
						<section id="H7321D1DDE4A7484FAC05C265B463C658"><enum>321.</enum><header>Requiring audits of results of elections</header>
							<subsection id="H7CD8701480394BD39B82458FE16E66C3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requiring Audits</header>
 <paragraph id="HE0C92E0388E74DF1B61AB6F40F6F10E4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In accordance with this subtitle, each State shall administer, without advance notice to the precincts or alternative audit units selected, audits of the results of all elections for Federal office held in the State (and, at the option of the State or jurisdiction involved, of elections for State and local office held at the same time as such election) consisting of random hand counts of the voter-verified paper ballots required to be used and preserved pursuant to section 301(a)(2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H02ADCD6611EE45BBBAF96B53550D1688"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for certain elections</header><text>A State shall not be required to administer an audit of the results of an election for Federal office under this subtitle if the winning candidate in the election—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H22AD425B671F440E8C7C60C3784847D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>had no opposition on the ballot; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE434D85549AC467392DFF2667A561CCC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>received 59 percent or more of the total number of votes cast in the election, as determined on the basis of the final unofficial vote count.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H06D4438971F04E4195F00CB458D94F5C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Determination of Entity Conducting Audits; Application of GAO Independence Standards</header><text>The State shall administer audits under this subtitle through an entity selected for such purpose by the State in accordance with such criteria as the State considers appropriate consistent with the requirements of this subtitle, except that the entity must meet the general standards established by the Comptroller General and as set forth in the Comptroller General’s Government Auditing Standards to ensure the independence (including, except as provided under section 323(b), the organizational independence) of entities performing financial audits, attestation engagements, and performance audits.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0892FFF949244474A244EEBE0683072D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>References to Election Auditor</header><text>In this subtitle, the term <term>Election Auditor</term> means, with respect to a State, the entity selected by the State under subsection (b).</text> </subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFEE69981D51349B3811DDFCE1E386273" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>322.</enum><header>Number of ballots counted under audit</header> <subsection id="H82EEC8BAA6674FEEB1A36E8FC87644D1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (b), the number of voter-verified paper ballots which will be subject to a hand count administered by the Election Auditor of a State under this subtitle with respect to an election shall be determined as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="H6DAD86D74E644505B42B1E05D7BC2E0E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the event that the unofficial count as described in section 323(a)(1) reveals that the margin of victory between the two candidates receiving the largest number of votes in the election is less than 1 percent of the total votes cast in that election, the hand counts of the voter-verified paper ballots shall occur in at least 10 percent of all precincts or equivalent locations (or alternative audit units used in accordance with the method provided for under subsection (b)) in the congressional district involved (in the case of an election for the House of Representatives) or the State (in the case of any other election for Federal office).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H36355C1124C24C62B3D851977883058F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the event that the unofficial count as described in section 323(a)(1) reveals that the margin of victory between the two candidates receiving the largest number of votes in the election is greater than or equal to 1 percent but less than 2 percent of the total votes cast in that election, the hand counts of the voter-verified paper ballots shall occur in at least 5 percent of all precincts or equivalent locations (or alternative audit units used in accordance with the method provided for under subsection (b)) in the congressional district involved (in the case of an election for the House of Representatives) or the State (in the case of any other election for Federal office).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB091A4CD123D4B9E95C7A9F297BD2350"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the event that the unofficial count as described in section 323(a)(1) reveals that the margin of victory between the two candidates receiving the largest number of votes in the election is equal to or greater than 2 percent of the total votes cast in that election, the hand counts of the voter-verified paper ballots shall occur in at least 3 percent of all precincts or equivalent locations (or alternative audit units used in accordance with the method provided for under subsection (b)) in the congressional district involved (in the case of an election for the House of Representatives) or the State (in the case of any other election for Federal office).</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDCA68293B19D469E99F650D863ED9726"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of Alternative Mechanism</header>
 <paragraph id="H6282D26239194D2F9496FC6E0B9DDC84"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Permitting use of alternative mechanism</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (a), a State may adopt and apply an alternative mechanism to determine the number of voter-verified paper ballots which will be subject to the hand counts required under this subtitle with respect to an election, so long as the alternative mechanism uses the voter-verified paper ballots to conduct the audit and the National Institute of Standards and Technology determines that the alternative mechanism is in accordance with the principles set forth in paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF5C6E08A85F345EEB69D58281C247C98"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Principles for approval</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In approving an alternative mechanism under paragraph (1), the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall ensure that the audit procedure will have the property that for each election—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD573A86CA43E4AC2BD4AF52D421723E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the alternative mechanism will be at least as statistically effective in ensuring the accuracy of the election results as the procedures under this subtitle; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H010EAAF793A840C0A989AF8D5118476D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the alternative mechanism will achieve at least a 95 percent confidence interval (as determined in accordance with criteria set forth by the National Institute of Standards and Technology) with respect to the outcome of the election.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H665749E9D853447997F7A83125D63929"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Deadline for response; reasons for denial</header><text>The Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall make a determination regarding a State’s request to approve an alternative mechanism under paragraph (1) not later than 30 days after receiving the State’s request. If the Director rejects such a request, the Director shall provide the State with the reasons for the rejection in writing.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB55D72E529D440F19DD904ECBA16C153" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>323.</enum><header>Process for administering audits</header>
 <subsection id="HC0437B3DAE4546B98059C355355FF0B8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text>The Election Auditor of a State shall administer an audit under this section of the results of an election in accordance with the following procedures:</text>
 <paragraph id="H2552781DE82C44219D7FDAE2F1038449"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Within 24 hours after the State announces the final unofficial vote count (as defined by the State) in each precinct in the State, the Election Auditor shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB4B3AC9BBE594466BB2486C7D63DA12B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determine and then announce publicly the precincts or equivalent locations (or alternative audit units used in accordance with the method provided under section 322(b)) in the State in which it will administer the audits; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2371DDA22D604BC7A856DC405327FA30"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to votes cast at the precinct or equivalent location on or before the date of the election (other than provisional ballots described in paragraph (2)), begin to administer the hand count of the votes on the voter-verified paper ballots required to be used and preserved under section 301(a)(2)(A) and the comparison of the count of the votes on those ballots with the final unofficial count of such votes as announced by the State.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E6D0465A6FA4FE496091474F3EF13E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to votes cast other than at the precinct on the date of the election (other than votes cast by provisional ballot on the date of the election which are certified and counted by the State on or after the date of the election), including votes cast by absent uniformed services voters and overseas voters under the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act, the Election Auditor shall administer the hand count of the votes on the applicable voter-verified paper ballots required to be produced and preserved under section 301(a)(2)(A) and the comparison of the count of the votes on those ballots with the final unofficial count of such votes as announced by the State.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H524BC73AD56349C787B0FFDAB9DACDF2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of personnel</header><text>In administering the audits, the Election Auditor may utilize the services of the personnel of the State or jurisdiction, including election administration personnel and poll workers, without regard to whether or not the personnel have professional auditing experience.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE5A60282FB8842BFA7C619C70FCF09EE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Location</header><text>The Election Auditor shall administer an audit of an election—</text> <paragraph id="H100942E017954F23A7502A4E612D1C2C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>at the location where the ballots cast in the election are stored and counted after the date of the election or such other appropriate and secure location agreed upon by the Election Auditor and the individual that is responsible under State law for the custody of the ballots; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H110415FB17F4491686B07B03BFFDFFAA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the presence of the personnel who under State law are responsible for the custody of the ballots.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H87264B259A854B04B5F708DFBED98C85"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Special rule in case of delay in reporting absentee vote count</header><text>In the case of a State in which the final count of absentee and provisional votes is not announced until after the date of the election, the Election Auditor shall initiate the process described in subsection (a) for administering the audit not later than 24 hours after the State announces the final unofficial vote count for the votes cast at the precinct or equivalent location on or before the date of the election, and shall initiate the administration of the audit of the absentee and provisional votes pursuant to subsection (a)(2) not later than 24 hours after the State announces the final unofficial count of such votes.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="H918A3979CA21413BB888B15B23DDA152"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Additional Audits if Cause Shown</header>
 <paragraph id="H90F6FF17AD9C49CA9A7759B4A6947905"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Election Auditor finds that any of the hand counts administered under this section do not match the final unofficial tally of the results of an election, the Election Auditor shall administer hand counts under this section of such additional precincts (or alternative audit units) as the Election Auditor considers appropriate to resolve any concerns resulting from the audit and ensure the accuracy of the election results.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H37898A2E93D94C7C9D0B50DAA0D1CC71"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Establishment and publication of procedures governing additional audits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than June 1, 2020, each State shall establish and publish procedures for carrying out the additional audits under this subsection, including the means by which the State shall resolve any concerns resulting from the audit with finality and ensure the accuracy of the election results.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6514E2D47857406181B84ADF19EB7CC4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Public Observation of Audits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each audit conducted under this section shall be conducted in a manner that allows public observation of the entire process.</text>
							</subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA48E4400CA604CC28C4E812CE2D7B666" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>324.</enum><header>Selection of precincts</header>
 <subsection id="H5341D0B6531E4D6096B25AC401F1CBF4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (c), the selection of the precincts or alternative audit units in the State in which the Election Auditor of the State shall administer the hand counts under this subtitle shall be made by the Election Auditor on a random basis, in accordance with procedures adopted by the National Institute of Standards and Technology, except that at least one precinct shall be selected at random in each county, with additional precincts selected by the Election Auditor at the Auditor’s discretion.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0473A25C87B6479EA18CEC4270A60CC2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Public Selection</header><text>The random selection of precincts under subsection (a) shall be conducted in public, at a time and place announced in advance.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFD70D7B8223B4727AAF139AEFAE355F4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Mandatory Selection of Precincts Established Specifically for Absentee Ballots</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a State does not sort absentee ballots by precinct and include those ballots in the hand count with respect to that precinct, the State shall create absentee ballot precincts or audit units which are of similar size to the average precinct or audit unit in the jurisdiction being audited, and shall include those absentee precincts or audit units among the precincts in the State in which the Election Auditor shall administer the hand counts under this subtitle.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H300DBC6832654102916930AC018B8997"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Deadline for Adoption of Procedures by Commission</header><text>The National Institute of Standards and Technology shall adopt the procedures described in subsection (a) not later than October 1, 2019, and shall publish them in the Federal Register upon adoption.</text>
							</subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6ABB7258467E439187D297F9BEC9BEDA" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>325.</enum><header>Publication of results</header>
 <subsection id="HD2D9D2D59EC4412EA6176BC121F9B790"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Submission to Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As soon as practicable after the completion of an audit under this subtitle, the Election Auditor of a State shall submit to the Commission the results of the audit, and shall include in the submission a comparison of the results of the election in the precinct as determined by the Election Auditor under the audit and the final unofficial vote count in the precinct as announced by the State and all undervotes, overvotes, blank ballots, and spoiled, voided, or cancelled ballots, as well as a list of any discrepancies discovered between the initial, subsequent, and final hand counts administered by the Election Auditor and such final unofficial vote count and any explanation for such discrepancies, broken down by the categories of votes described in paragraphs (1)(B) and (2) of section 323(a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9286A8A4D6514B848AE812A1D9F442CD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Publication by Commission</header><text>Immediately after receiving the submission of the results of an audit from the Election Auditor of a State under subsection (a), the Commission shall publicly announce and publish the information contained in the submission.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="HFBC4118B84D54DC0856129F6A6F3800B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Delay in certification of results by State</header>
 <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H12675214246B48CD8C195F34442C8EC3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibiting certification until completion of audits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No State may certify the results of any election which is subject to an audit under this subtitle prior to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H92CDF4C07BE94BF68BD04D2B201F4771"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the completion of the audit (and, if required, any additional audit conducted under section 323(e)(1)) and the announcement and submission of the results of each such audit to the Commission for publication of the information required under this section; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C5F1248983048BFA6D57B014A1634D2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the completion of any procedure established by the State pursuant to section 323(e)(2) to resolve discrepancies and ensure the accuracy of results.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H535B0B0589504EC08A336C6851093293"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadline for completion of audits of Presidential elections</header><text>In the case of an election for electors for President and Vice President which is subject to an audit under this subtitle, the State shall complete the audits and announce and submit the results to the Commission for publication of the information required under this section in time for the State to certify the results of the election and provide for the final determination of any controversy or contest concerning the appointment of such electors prior to the deadline described in section 6 of title 3, United States Code.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8C005F4C571B467DBB699029D17549B0" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>326.</enum><header>Payments to States</header>
 <subsection id="HDAE374E31B944A97BEDB06D1C739C394"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Payments for Costs of Conducting Audits</header><text>In accordance with the requirements and procedures of this section, the Commission shall make a payment to a State to cover the costs incurred by the State in carrying out this subtitle with respect to the elections that are the subject of the audits conducted under this subtitle.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="HF6F5CADA3CDC4E3ABD63DBB34BA6648B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certification of Compliance and Anticipated Costs</header>
 <paragraph id="H4FB812FC39A945D49FDB056AD34523B6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Certification required</header><text>In order to receive a payment under this section, a State shall submit to the Commission, in such form as the Commission may require, a statement containing—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H63C6576328094EBD9A187FCDCA5C7ECD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a certification that the State will conduct the audits required under this subtitle in accordance with all of the requirements of this subtitle;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05C35D25A27447AF8C0DAB54CA126498"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a notice of the reasonable costs incurred or the reasonable costs anticipated to be incurred by the State in carrying out this subtitle with respect to the elections involved; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50533A1FCBEE4FFD82BF0645527803E8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such other information and assurances as the Commission may require.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB335818D22334AB5BD210A7AC9D9CFFE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amount of payment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of a payment made to a State under this section shall be equal to the reasonable costs incurred or the reasonable costs anticipated to be incurred by the State in carrying out this subtitle with respect to the elections involved, as set forth in the statement submitted under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4A31A603723045BDAAB14FA67CF3C78B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Timing of notice</header><text>The State may not submit a notice under paragraph (1) until candidates have been selected to appear on the ballot for all of the elections for Federal office which will be the subject of the audits involved.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7E9FEFE1B78A4AFFA17191983E5D6663"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Timing of Payments</header><text>The Commission shall make the payment required under this section to a State not later than 30 days after receiving the notice submitted by the State under subsection (b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3175DA3ED0CA4B298D6E7C11E8E5260D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Recoupment of Overpayments</header><text>No payment may be made to a State under this section unless the State agrees to repay to the Commission (for deposit in the general fund of the Treasury) the excess (if any) of—</text>
 <paragraph id="H3EE0D9AE241F434D9940FED4F9923D0C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the amount of the payment received by the State under this section with respect to the elections involved; over</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H23549F9D7CA4436388D3DE5F7A66B388"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the actual costs incurred by the State in carrying out this subtitle with respect to the elections involved.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H018758EF1F504DE9A9060186B29E5731"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header>
 <paragraph id="H7776F4B71A794073BD0E95ED2D64C2A9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Commission for fiscal year 2020 and each succeeding fiscal year $45,000,000 for payments under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H63511E00DB204084AB48DAE5342CA250"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Continuing availability of amounts appropriated</header><text>Any amount appropriated for a fiscal year pursuant to the authorization under paragraph (1) shall remain available until expended.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H30BFB9B2CF974DE98DC44863668C4A12" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>327.</enum><header>Exception for elections subject to recount under State law prior to certification</header>
 <subsection id="HA05E281B52C44862970AA40D99FA8046"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This subtitle does not apply to any election for which a recount under State law will commence prior to the certification of the results of the election, including but not limited to a recount required automatically because of the margin of victory between the 2 candidates receiving the largest number of votes in the election, but only if each of the following applies to the recount:</text>
 <paragraph id="H2B608C1E9D4E4BE7855BD3026F84BFE5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The recount commences prior to the determination and announcement by the Election Auditor under section 323(a)(1) of the precincts in the State in which it will administer the audits under this subtitle.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H61B78C6265074910A73A959F9AB5D714"><enum>(2)</enum><text>If the recount would apply to fewer than 100 percent of the ballots cast in the election—</text> <subparagraph id="HB8FDFF3EE12241E3B47ECCD0E30BCEFA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of ballots counted will be at least as many as would be counted if an audit were conducted with respect to the election in accordance with this subtitle; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E0D53579ACA4BB29B71BB2ED0DD90BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the selection of the precincts in which the recount will be conducted will be made in accordance with the random selection procedures applicable under section 324.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB65B7C294FC44882804AE54F1B0F0DC1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The recount for the election meets the requirements of section 323(f) (relating to public observation).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HED081D24EAED4103933DA7EC124E2BCE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The State meets the requirements of section 325 (relating to the publication of results and the delay in the certification of results) with respect to the recount.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7A7AD7FA295C4757B689DA3C46FAFFA3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clarification of Effect on Other Requirements</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to waive the application of any other provision of this Act to any election (including the requirement set forth in section 301(a)(2) that the voter-verified paper ballots serve as the vote of record and shall be counted by hand in all audits and recounts, including audits and recounts described in this subtitle).</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H6C9C67AB1F7442FE93675BA9D40BC757"><enum>328.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This subtitle shall apply with respect to the regularly scheduled general elections for Federal office held in November 2020 and each succeeding election for Federal office.</text>
						</section></subtitle><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H84D5E6BB01E14EB6A52B455A4C690013"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability of enforcement under Help America Vote Act of 2002</header><text>Section 401 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21111">52 U.S.C. 21111</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>sections 301, 302, and 303</quote> and inserting <quote>title III</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H08EEAD5588214FEFB5A677107B42E64F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents of such Act is amended by adding at the end of the items relating to title III the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2EC0869A9539493689182360890F284B" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="subtitle">Subtitle C—Mandatory Manual Audits</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 321. Requiring audits of results of elections.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 322. Number of ballots counted under audit.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 323. Process for administering audits.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 324. Selection of precincts.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 325. Publication of results.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 326. Payments to States.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 327. Exception for elections subject to recount under State law prior to certification.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 328. Effective date.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H125102BF816745B39DCFBABA0F39FE2A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Incentives to States to improve voting system security</header>
 <subsection id="H6D495E18E883452DA96D9CE32D1F59EA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants from Election Assistance Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle D of title II of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21001">52 U.S.C. 21001</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following new part:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF9FB0C345C624D938F6A9CE0222B0B21" style="OLC">
					<part id="H1683022ABE1C456CA6CDD797EC004B6C"><enum>7</enum><header>Payments for Improving Voting System Security</header>
						<section id="HF996CD7A6ABD48C6BB6D21C74D7ADCC4"><enum>297.</enum><header>Incentives for States to improve voting system security</header>
							<subsection id="HEFA25622946D4F498F6A17338E378D49"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header>
 <paragraph id="H89E18D4662124A5181056EE1503C31D6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From the amounts made available under section 297E for a fiscal year and not reserved under section (b) of such section, the Commission shall award grants on a competitive basis to States in accordance with section 297B.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8E1C92F681204A2C8E644B80A1E3CFE3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Number of grants</header><text>A State may not receive more than 1 grant under this part for a fiscal year.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HA3E915F43B514D7E836BCBF5D01815BD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State that receives a grant under this part shall use the funds provided by the grant to carry out the State's grant implementation plan described in section 297A(b).</text>
							</subsection></section><section id="H0813EE345CD64EFDB5FBBC30606E5AE7"><enum>297A.</enum><header>Criteria for awarding grants</header>
 <subsection id="H10AC38FA1BBF4A1DA644CBB3F3732676"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>Each State that desires to receive a grant under this part shall submit an application to the Commission at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Commission may reasonably require. At a minimum, each such application shall include each of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HF2882DC627FF4E298662EE9110D92273"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The grant implementation plan described in subsection (b).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H61C9795FA9CC4A7AAB086BE3C754275A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Evidence of established conditions of innovation and reform in providing voting system security and the State’s proposed plan for implementing additional conditions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H78C065430A294B55AB2F8177577157AE"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Evidence of collaboration between relevant stakeholders in developing the grant implementation plan described in subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA4AC4DCC44E4494A970AD3F72961C262"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Annual performance measures and targets for the activities carried out with the grant.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCC7C5D63135D4CE091A6E9B80B57909C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A description of the State’s plan to conduct a rigorous evaluation of the effectiveness of the activities carried out with the grant.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2B17C5DAA5DD43CD97CCC85E16748F1B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grant implementation plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The grant implementation plan described in this subsection is a plan developed by the State for using funds provided by the grant to carry out some or all of the following, and to otherwise meet the requirements of section 301 which are first imposed on a State or jurisdiction pursuant to the amendments made by section 2 of the Safeguarding Election Infrastructure Act of 2017, during the grant implementation period:</text>
 <paragraph id="H4F46E64BF008430296A83D82E4123AFA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providing voting machines that are less than 10 years old as of the date on which the State submits its application for the grant under subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF7ADF84AE8E447B6BFE764FCA9DE0691"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Updating voting equipment to provide a verifiable paper trail at polling stations.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEB24C7745ADA492FB1089020720FE5F4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Implementing strong chain of custody procedures for the physical security of voting equipment and paper records at all stages of the process.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H45E69DCDD12544408040BC1971DB8E43"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Conducting pre-election testing on every voting machine and ensuring paper ballots are available wherever electronic machines are used.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0227DB5F04EF4960830F2A264B71E4E6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Keeping offline backups of voter registration lists.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H33268958A98C4B6FAE7869C2DE4949D3"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providing a secure voter registration database that logs requests submitted to the database.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H84C1F578465048918D531CB09609B1A1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Publishing and enforcing a policy detailing use limitations and security safeguards to protect voters’ personal information in the voter registration process.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8FFC0E8B98A2454BA6FBDB966D92ABA5"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Providing secure processes and procedures for reporting vote tallies.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5B6D20D64CA34363A2ED1BCE43D049AB"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providing a secure platform for disseminating vote totals.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H90C1EA5AE9D94B8FBCA82022AB17041D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant implementation period defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this part, the <quote>grant implementation period</quote> with respect to a grant is the 4-year period which begins on the first day of the fiscal year for which the grant is awarded.</text>
							</subsection></section><section id="H3B009E18551A40CE99E559DD0FDFAC1D"><enum>297B.</enum><header>Criteria for evaluating applications</header>
 <subsection id="HF1CC85AB0B0A48B1A398816E1F77FAA9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Award basis</header><text>The Commission shall award grants to States under this part on a competitive basis, based on the quality of the State’s application submitted under section 297A, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="HBDCE42FF7D8A4008BCE2C8DA8C9C9BC5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the quality and likelihood of success of the State’s grant implementation plan described in section 297A(b), including the State’s capacity to implement the plan and evidence of collaboration as described in paragraph (3) of section 297A(a);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6DE7251BF6324E47814E473340D04530"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the State’s record of, and commitment to, establishing conditions for innovation and reform, as described in paragraph (2) of section 297A(a); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H867AB685639F47B7B007E4A60A7983B9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the State’s evaluation plan as described in paragraph (5) of section 297A(a).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H851333577D2C41558EEA432006D8B203"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Special rule for States receiving grants in previous fiscal years</header><text>In the case of a State that received a grant under this part in a previous fiscal year, the Commission may not award a grant under this part to the State for any subsequent fiscal year unless the State demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Commission that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H03B39C91D1FF4FD6916873919DC74750"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the State made sufficient progress in carrying out the grant implementation plan for that previous fiscal year at a rate that will enable the State to fully implement the plan prior to the end of the grant implementation period for that plan; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H62245C8E9E9A42EA955336F49F4B64E7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the State made sufficient progress in meeting the performance measures and targets for the programs and activities funded by the grant (as established by the State under section 297C) to enable the State to fully meet such measures and targets prior to the end of the grant implementation period for that plan.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H77AA058D08FA467CB137B97149994681"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Explanation</header><text>The Commission shall publish an explanation of how the application review process under this subsection will ensure an equitable and objective evaluation based on the criteria described in subsection (a) and the special rule described in subsection (b).</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H78AAF3859AE746B4A2A02BFBC232A74A"><enum>297C.</enum><header>Establishment of performance measures and targets</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Each State receiving a grant under this part shall establish performance measures and targets approved by the Commission for the programs and activities carried out with the funds provided by the grant.</text>
						</section><section id="H09D176C0DEF14D12AC2AB7B6E9E7EEE5"><enum>297D.</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Each State receiving a grant under this part shall submit to the Commission, at such time and in such manner as the Commission may require, an annual report including—</text>
 <paragraph id="H88998E977DDE4A50BA11A4CD35435595"><enum>(1)</enum><text>data on the State’s progress in achieving the targets for the performance measures established under section 297C;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBBA84D7C11094283BEB9E1F7F81C23BE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of the challenges the State has faced in implementing the programs and activities funded by the grant and how it has addressed or plans to address those challenges; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE6AA27802A9D4392B17CBBE5DEA61CD0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>findings from the evaluation plan for the grant.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H2644486210134B6884F749272AEAEA78"><enum>297E.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header> <subsection id="H20F79705E3F54BF49407A6DC1CC97C26"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header> <paragraph id="H04E8B96D762E41FCA3DE7F436B9D6FF1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2018 and each succeeding fiscal year to carry out this part.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD69D745E848E4B55B98101D63C751708"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No continuing availability of funds</header><text>Any amount appropriated for a fiscal year pursuant to the authorization under paragraph (1) shall not remain available for any subsequent fiscal year.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF7C7681A0BFB467191CF11B7CA519F46"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reservation of funds</header><text>From the amount made available to carry out this part for a fiscal year, the Commission may reserve not more than 10 percent of such amount to carry out activities related to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H79A375863DFC481F80D5DCD30FFEFDA1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>technical assistance; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE8BD371767C447859E5B418ADE5C7954"><enum>(2)</enum><text>outreach and dissemination.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H32A9A8DA50564D9EAC1150FB2EE60A25"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents of such Act is amended by adding at the end of the items relating to subtitle D of title II the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H64056892D12C4BDA8AE40724772A9241" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry idref="H1683022ABE1C456CA6CDD797EC004B6C" level="part">Part 7—Payments for Improving Voting System Security</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry idref="HF996CD7A6ABD48C6BB6D21C74D7ADCC4" level="section">Sec. 297. Incentives for States to improve voting system security.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry idref="H0813EE345CD64EFDB5FBBC30606E5AE7" level="section">Sec. 297A. Criteria for awarding grants.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry idref="H3B009E18551A40CE99E559DD0FDFAC1D" level="section">Sec. 297B. Criteria for evaluating applications.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry idref="H78AAF3859AE746B4A2A02BFBC232A74A" level="section">Sec. 297C. Establishment of performance measures and targets.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry idref="H09D176C0DEF14D12AC2AB7B6E9E7EEE5" level="section">Sec. 297D. Reporting requirements.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry idref="H2644486210134B6884F749272AEAEA78" level="section">Sec. 297E. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="HED38249AF4014743BBDBD309FA9C2227"><enum>5.</enum><header>Duties of Secretary of Homeland Security</header>
			<subsection id="H85886282B84C4F9B80BC518A2908500B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Notification of breaches of voting system security or related investigations</header>
 <paragraph id="HF479DBF9160A4334A80C6E3B3F27953F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requiring notification to Congress and State election officials</header><text>If the Secretary of Homeland Security makes a determination that the security of any voting system or any voter registration database that has been used or will be used in an election for Federal office has been breached, or if the Secretary is conducting an investigation regarding whether or not the security of such a system or database has been breached, the Secretary shall submit a report on the determination or investigation to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, and the chief State election official of the State in which the system is used or will be used.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2088985586B54528AA204152BB2B709F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>The Secretary shall submit the report required under paragraph (1) not later than 30 days after making the determination involved or initiating the investigation involved (as the case may be).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H92F57F5BA2914321BC726E975356B524"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sharing information with State election officials</header><text>At the request of a State, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall collaborate with the chief State election official of the State to help prevent and respond to threats to the security of the voting systems and databases described in subsection (a), including assisting such official with obtaining the appropriate level of security clearance necessary to receive information regarding such threats.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1DC3AD1B6795436FABF2F80BF033E17A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection—</text> <paragraph id="H999F360ACBE940A8801193AD5A4F5168"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the <quote>chief State election official</quote> of a State is the individual designated by the State under section 10 of the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20509">52 U.S.C. 20509</external-xref>) to be responsible for coordination of the State’s responsibilities under such Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAD7E37D400FF488681546E25BA68BA50"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>voting system</term> has the meaning given such term under section 301(b) of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21081">52 U.S.C. 21081(b)</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


