<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H0DEF515F9F4A43B6AE95F47EAA59F98D" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2664 : Enhancing Detection of Human Trafficking Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2664</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date date="20170713">July 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Labor to train certain Department of Labor personnel how to effectively
			 detect and assist law enforcement in preventing human trafficking during
			 the course of their primary roles and responsibilities, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H9C76C228DD734C13B8D01ADCEED7879F" style="OLC">
 <section id="HD6B86467036540F18D4511F05E01E8B9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Enhancing Detection of Human Trafficking Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HFC43F522164E4D378A9825ADCCC39C76"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definition of human trafficking</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act the term <quote>human trafficking</quote> means an act or practice described in paragraph (9) or (10) of section 103 of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7102">22 U.S.C. 7102</external-xref>).</text>
		</section><section id="HC6EB61C36DD541278A193A96310920AD"><enum>3.</enum><header>Training for Department personnel to identify human trafficking</header>
 <subsection id="H3DE6759EE67A484085B0E798BE019C1E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Labor shall implement a program to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H85DC4C5DA39F4644BBFFFA42B9CA9B51"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">train and periodically retrain relevant personnel across the Department of Labor that the Secretary considers appropriate, how to effectively detect and assist law enforcement in preventing human trafficking during the course of their primary roles and responsibilities; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H797E47C2ABAC4516B2696E455D69784D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure that such personnel regularly receive current information on matters related to the detection of human trafficking, including information that becomes available outside of the Department’s initial or periodic retraining schedule, to the extent relevant to their official duties and consistent with applicable information and privacy laws.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB3407B6FC3B745A8B128B6416E52CAED"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Training described</header><text>The training referred to in subsection (a) may be conducted through in-class or virtual learning capabilities, and shall include—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA618E0684FF044A4817FBC1CF7970537"><enum>(1)</enum><text>methods for identifying suspected victims of human trafficking and, where appropriate, perpetrators of human trafficking;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCF2B4A062C0645DCA5038B9DFC4DE291"><enum>(2)</enum><text>training that is most appropriate for a particular location or environment in which the personnel receiving such training perform their official duties;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA6075813AB45465B8B999BD87F44C285"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other topics determined by the Secretary to be appropriate reflecting current trends and best practices for personnel in their particular location or professional environment;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD37C03E6D66B494097ABE199E0500A4A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a clear course of action for referring potential cases of human trafficking to the Department of Justice and other appropriate authorities; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFCB5FFDDD08E43BCA205B98D73CE9310"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a post-training evaluation for personnel receiving the training.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H083DB07F8CC94E68A7D3C7DEA461C1F2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and each year thereafter, the Secretary of Labor shall report to the appropriate congressional committees on the training provided to the personnel referred to in section 3(a), including—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9E0BB79BE6D5493BB4F4F459F334280D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an evaluation of such training and the overall effectiveness of the program required by this Act;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1B23B70212314977A900A1187F9FD242"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of cases referred by Department of Labor personnel in which human trafficking was suspected and the metrics used by the Department to accurately measure and track its response to instances of suspected human trafficking; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1540BA4B1E5342EEB2A5C89259CF05F0"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of Department of Labor employees who have completed such training as required by this Act.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
	<attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20170712">Passed the House of Representatives July 12, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill>


