<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H59D5ECDA69F84E46956F448B27F8A25B" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 878 IH: Right to Try Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>115th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 878</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20170206">February 6, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001096">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001189">Mr. Messer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000606">Mr. Pittenger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001192">Mr. Stewart</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000567">Mr. Lance</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000168">Mr. Olson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001197">Ms. McSally</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000065">Mr. Yoho</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000409">Mr. Rohrabacher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000587">Mr. Lewis of Minnesota</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001283">Mr. Bridenstine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000552">Mr. Gohmert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001299">Mr. Banks of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001199">Mr. Smucker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001290">Mr. Brat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000244">Mr. Sensenbrenner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001183">Mr. Schweikert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001179">Mr. Marino</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000592">Mr. Rokita</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To authorize the use of unapproved medical products by patients diagnosed with a terminal illness
			 in accordance with State law, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H6ADFEF7A1A9845FFBB0DC3397DB443AE" style="OLC">
		<section id="H70CA8620FAA340AA8B426DE9518AAC95" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Right to Try Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idB95F3C2BC6CA470F86B200A9A65EDF73" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Use of unapproved medical products by patients diagnosed with a terminal illness</header> <subsection id="idBB1B940856BD469E8C2E8CBB95837A9C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/301">21 U.S.C. 301</external-xref> et seq.), the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/801">21 U.S.C. 801</external-xref> et seq.), and any other provision of Federal law, the Federal Government shall not take any action to prohibit or restrict—</text><paragraph id="idA19218070F3545B988A68776DBD4ACD8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the production, manufacture, distribution, prescribing, or dispensing of an experimental drug, biological product, or device that—</text><subparagraph id="id0C9F203375AB4CDCB7E8E0684D5F5660"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is intended to treat a patient who has been diagnosed with a terminal illness; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC33757B1AAB84EF086A9BA9AD371F4E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is authorized by, and in accordance with, State law; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id905CD437B502461DB5DC2584976E5D17"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the possession or use of an experimental drug, biological product, or device—</text><subparagraph id="id4A34DE9156584155BF9B5504CDD9657C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that is described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE3366E6C1857455B99CAB6B8148AF4AD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for which the patient has received a certification from a physician, who is in good standing with the physician’s certifying organization or board, that the patient has exhausted, or otherwise does not meet qualifying criteria to receive, any other available treatment options.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id50395E78AD874AB1B973E0AEDAAD25CD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No liability or use of outcomes</header><paragraph id="id34EEBECB863E4769B24519B059A69246"><enum>(1)</enum><header>No liability</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no liability shall lie against a producer, manufacturer, distributor, prescriber, dispenser, possessor, or user of an experimental drug, biological product, or device for the production, manufacture, distribution, prescribing, dispensing, possession, or use of an experimental drug, biological product, or device that is in compliance, with subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idDE2BD368D2E64E2F93CCEB8B7A06C0B7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No use of outcomes</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the outcome of any production, manufacture, distribution, prescribing, dispensing, possession, or use of an experimental drug, biological product, or device that was done in compliance with subsection (a) shall not be used by a Federal agency reviewing the experimental drug, biological product, or device to delay or otherwise adversely impact review or approval of such experimental drug, biological product, or device.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idD1D820790FA4489F9CC13041BE0E7824"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id87BC758DC4194F74A996502BC68F89A6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Biological product</header><text>The term <term>biological product</term> has the meaning given to such term in section 351 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id726AD7AE944647F38A157379378BF4F4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Device; drug</header><text>The terms <term>device</term> and <term>drug</term> have the meanings given to such terms in section 201 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/321">21 U.S.C. 321</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id52F7682A239D43D090688772E942BDD4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Experimental drug, biological product, or device</header><text>The term <term>experimental drug, biological product, or device</term> that—</text><subparagraph id="id0CE2C5D1FD774D60971BF9A67C49D474"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has successfully completed a phase 1 clinical investigation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3A925B68A25843679BE12622A6C36276"><enum>(B)</enum><text>remains under investigation in a clinical trial approved by the Food and Drug Administration; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id20A9042F9D2C40B29798F8F39B640DB4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is not approved, licensed, or cleared for commercial distribution under section 505, 510(k), or 515 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355</external-xref>, 360(k), 360(e)) or section 351 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8F9D9E0CE99D4CB994BCF4F4F5B4FCC3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Phase 1 clinical investigation</header><text>The term <term>phase 1 clinical investigation</term> means a phase 1 clinical investigation, as described in section 312.21 of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id44662B20869C42288031B33ECEAF622C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Terminal illness</header><text>The term <term>terminal illness</term> has the meaning given to such term in the State law specified in subsection (a)(1)(B).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body> </bill> 

