<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H44B1CBEBCA18422A84812B23DEF4821D" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4078 IH: Expanding America’s Workforce Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4078</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171019">October 19, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001048">Mr. Hunter</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish various programs to ease the burden on undereducated and financially deficient workers
			 seeking to further their education.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H7B73656E917F44F593FC4099D709BAF5" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE9613E3FBC7A45A5B0D256CEB008A4C3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Expanding America’s Workforce Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HF70A8F0154E041B38F72868BA4A82689"><enum>2.</enum><header>Review of gainful employment measurement</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Education shall prepare and submit to Congress, a report on the accuracy of the manner in which gainful employment is measured under the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref> et seq.) for different geographic regions and courses of study.</text>
 </section><section id="HDA78A83D569E4149A29C657CB2878AD3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Short-term Workforce Federal Pell Grants</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 401 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a">20 U.S.C. 1070a</external-xref>) is amended by inserting at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="H108B9B7AF7624774B5688B7D25A4BD3F" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="HE3AD051820F9494B864122F973824831"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Short-Term Workforce Pell Grants</header>
 <paragraph id="HDA50528C6CA9453D9DF921AF71C90A62"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For award years beginning on or after July 1, 2020, the Secretary shall carry out a program under which the Secretary shall award Federal Pell Grants to eligible students for short-term workforce programs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9630DB5C77CD49BC906113A07ADF5678"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header><text>A Federal Pell Grant awarded under this subsection (in this section referred to as a <quote>workforce Federal Pell Grant</quote>) shall have the same terms and conditions, and be awarded in the same manner, as a Federal Pell Grant awarded under subsection (a), except as follows:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDD7660D478724BB38D2F7556509FCB52"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A student who is eligible to receive a workforce Federal Pell Grant under this subsection is a student who—</text>
 <clause id="H099C493851654CFB9D05ED59F70D2478"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has not, on or after the date that is 10 years before the date on which the student applies for such grant, attained a baccalaureate degree or post baccalaureate degree;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H36D96AAC41604BCFB2B15287E0E2F2A1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>attends an eligible institution, but was not previously enrolled in an eligible institution on or after the date that is 5 years before the date on which the student applies for such grant;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H504F8B64840142A384A2F85802CDAE3C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is enrolled, or accepted for enrollment, in a short-term workforce program at such institution;</text> </clause><clause id="HE09279173A834A5F825F7CB4A77AC5F3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>is determined, solely by the institution, that the student is unemployed or underemployed; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H1F3C643EDB994E178BFEFB92A4FEF30A"><enum>(v)</enum><text>meets all other eligibility requirements for a Federal Pell Grant (except as otherwise provided in this paragraph).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92A1DE134020475C9590ACE1EE86B1DA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The amount of a workforce Pell Grant for an eligible student shall be determined under subsection (b)(2)(A), except that—</text>
 <clause id="H45E4958ACE49422AA4D30B5D3E883592"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the maximum Federal Pell Grant awarded under this subsection for an award year shall be 50 percent of the maximum Federal Pell Grant awarded under subsection (b) applicable to that award year;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCBDCA046E67A4EBBBCD98A03F1D3E772"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>no increase shall be calculated under subsection (b)(7)(B) for a student receiving workforce Pell Grant under this subsection; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H13B433FF0A9D446AA580DFF649F8A108"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>subsection (b)(4) shall not apply.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8DEFC6CEC673418EBA8932717E6822C5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Inclusion in total eligibility period for recent students</header><text>Any period during which a student described in paragraph (2)(A) receives a workforce Federal Pell Grant under this subsection shall be included in calculating the student’s period of eligibility for Federal Pell Grants under subsection (c), and any regulations under such subsection regarding students who are enrolled in an undergraduate program on less than a full-time basis shall similarly apply to students who are enrolled in a short-term workforce program at an eligible institution on less than a full-time basis.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1734A107345042A2815098C037B7A310"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection, the following definitions apply:</text> <subparagraph id="H10D19A1F4E924307ACC79EA8F1EDE9DF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Eligible career pathway program</header><text>The term <quote>eligible career pathway program</quote> means a program that is a combination of rigorous and high-quality education, training, and other services that—</text>
 <clause id="H0D5F14EBB4884D92AEA363A4888955E9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>aligns with the skill needs of industries in the State or regional economy involved;</text> </clause><clause id="H4868FF3D2D82407AAAD538282232691D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>prepares an individual to be successful in any of a full range of secondary or postsecondary education options, including apprenticeships registered under the Act of August 16, 1937 (commonly known as the <quote>National Apprenticeship Act</quote>; 50 Stat. 664; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/50">29 U.S.C. 50</external-xref> et seq.);</text>
 </clause><clause id="H436C869A76BE45A8807A47E285D9FB68"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>includes counseling to support an individual in achieving the individual’s education and career goals;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC137582EC8764DB1937A64840724D66E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>includes, as appropriate, education offered concurrently with and in the same context as workforce preparation activities and training for a specific occupation or occupational cluster;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEADE59B078E64E1A972E9774167E0BE6"><enum>(v)</enum><text>organizes education, training, and other services to meet the particular needs of an individual in a manner that accelerates the educational and career advancement of the individual to the extent practicable; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDDACDBF2C4504D71ABA03FC94A74E387"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>helps an individual enter or advance within a specific occupation or occupational cluster.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H119F208EAB264E51AB906FFA543BB002"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Short-term workforce program</header><text>The term <quote>short-term workforce program</quote> means a career and technical education program at an institution of higher education that—</text>
 <clause id="H7545868ABE3B4BE5A98614A5246C74D4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provides not less than 150 clock hours of instructional time over a period of not less than 8 weeks or more than 12 weeks;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H90AE623ADCAE47B3AF3C66117624D8DB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provides training aligned with the requirements of employers in the State or local area, which may include in-demand industry sectors or occupations in the State or local area, as defined under section 3(23) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102(23)</external-xref>);</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB0B770AF98704087A063F2D462B2572D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provides a student, upon completion of the program, with a recognized postsecondary credential, as defined under section 3(52) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102(52)</external-xref>), that is recognized by employers in the relevant industry, including credentials recognized by industry or sector partnerships in the State or local area where the industry is located;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0C155F408E5D4BB19AE9EBDF44DDA35B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>has been determined, by the institution of higher education, to provide academic content, an amount of instructional time, and a recognized postsecondary credential that are sufficient to—</text>
 <subclause id="HCA868C483FE44E7F90315A9100563947"><enum>(I)</enum><text>meet the hiring requirements of potential employers; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H48067FB93EC54A5CBDC933CA5CEEAEB4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>allow the students to apply for any licenses or certifications that may be required to be employed in the field for which the job training is offered;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HCCBC6F47DF3E4B87AA3150CECA0BDE49"><enum>(v)</enum><text>may include integrated or basic skills courses; and</text> </clause><clause id="H81C99E9AEC4A4941BD5B7CC4DFFD2675"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>may be offered as part of an eligible career pathway program.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H88FB2CAE65154A56A86E201F6169D4B0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Special Rule</header><text>In the case of a career pathway program being determined eligible for the first time under this subsection, such determination shall be made by the Secretary before such program is considered to be an eligible career pathway program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE9C5AA1D233F4673AD0085591BAD3632"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Ineligibility for double benefits</header><text>No student may receive both a workforce Federal Pell Grant under this subsection and an additional Federal Pell Grant under subsection (b)(8).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="H8BD679F8BBFE43CA823CE67AC7342807"><enum>4.</enum><header>Connecting apprenticeships to academic degrees</header>
 <subsection id="H231D099282F74022B2AF6537C0B22A12"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 is amended by inserting after section 486A (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1093a">20 U.S.C. 1093a</external-xref>) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H5A20C54AE76D427582A22FCA608CC041" style="OLC">
					<section id="H11CBF13448524835BBC41EA6344F9E2F"><enum>486B.</enum><header>Apprenticeship expansion through articulation agreements</header>
 <subsection id="HD2241AA5D47A4B388AC0201EA853048E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H8669F1B020534DAC9FD1105FB24239E3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Apprenticeship articulation agreement</header><text>The term <quote>apprenticeship articulation agreement</quote> means an agreement between or among institutions of higher education that specifies the college credit value of and acceptability of certificates received through specific apprenticeship programs, for purposes of transferring such credits toward meeting specific degree or program requirements.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H145650E0FDA74C23B11FF7E6DACE1EB4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Apprenticeship program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>apprenticeship program</quote> means an apprenticeship registered under the Act of August 16, 1937 (commonly known as the <quote>National Apprenticeship Act</quote>; 50 Stat. 664, chapter 663; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/50">29 U.S.C. 50</external-xref> et seq.).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF113489B15D3488F9EB0BBC01DC237A8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program to encourage apprenticeship articulation agreements</header> <paragraph id="H131782F0F8354DCDA093D449A166B3B9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Program established</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out a program in cooperation with States, institutions of higher education (including proprietary institutions), and sponsors of apprenticeships programs, to develop, enhance, and implement comprehensive apprenticeship articulation agreements between or among such institutions. Such apprenticeship articulation agreements shall be made widely and publicly available on the websites of such States, sponsors and institutions. In developing, enhancing, and implementing apprenticeship articulation agreements, States, sponsors and institutions of higher education may employ strategies, where applicable, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2DF2167CF379472398BF7A3F060EF462"><enum>(A)</enum><text>improving awareness of existing apprenticeship articulation agreements;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC803EB6601F84624B1C8D642B37E5BCB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>expanding participation of a wide variety of institutions of higher education;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB15C2B8D892647DC813A33B6D0DFBDD6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>improving management systems to regarding course equivalency, transfer of credit, and articulation; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3DC39C76B7E1415DBB170108CD5807CC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>strategies to ensure widespread acceptance for the transfer of credits awarded to apprentices pursuant to apprenticeship articulation agreements.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9727E43FE9BD42BB9432D61313419DC1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination and technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Labor, shall provide technical assistance to States, sponsors and institutions of higher education for the purposes of developing and implementing apprenticeship articulation agreements in accordance with this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H0B5B035051224209A2C008BE76DFA34B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Enhancing transfer of credit among schools</header>
 <subsection id="HA61D2B1931F44246956D0F54B5D655E9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Transfer of credit policies</header><text>Section 485(h)(1) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1092">20 U.S.C. 1092(h)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HB15CFA2A6D2B4EACB9088AAA27668774"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (A); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1A7736358B6649FA90982D63D586003D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFA281146FEB84CD990BCBD05CBF7D7BC" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H39DA9C0C7B7F4F77BB214B9A1B6658CF"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assurance that for each credit earned at another institution of higher education that is accepted and rejected by the institution, such credit will be publicly disclosed, and disaggregated by type of institution at which such credit was earned, accrediting agency or association, program, and if applicable, the primary reason for the credit not being accepted; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FDBA90571EE4D5FA7056CA690EB3A26"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an assurance of the acceptance of credits earned at another institution for an identical course offered at the institution that has been reviewed by the same accrediting agency or association at both such institutions, and is at the introductory level as determined by the agency or association, or in a case in which the transfer of such credits is initially denied by the institution, an assurance the student will have the opportunity to take an assessment administered by the institution to demonstrate competency in such course for purposes of the transfer of such credits.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF02160A1052E418EA3B52325B024CFB4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Articulation agreements</header><text>Section 486A(b) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1093a">20 U.S.C. 1093a</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HFF2670D40F5E4AB59B976EEF0ED8DE8B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7E83B4B163964FD29BD7FA10C3928539"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (C) and (D) as subparagraphs (D) and (E), respectively; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67C90A943D5E44CF84D4233CFEB71D4D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (B) the following:</text>
						<quoted-block id="HB8891FF962354443AAFE12DBD37AE0AD" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="HD63B7C00C40F46CA8E9E40088F8B7256"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identification of courses at each institution in which an articulation agreement has been developed to enable the transfer of credit for such courses to, at a minimum, all other institutions accredited by the same accrediting agency or association;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H21A699FBFFFF4E92835DBE88B67BDAF5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>public</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4A531931D5CD43CEA469C6931CD5DEE5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Education shall submit a report to Congress on a review of transfer of credit policies across institutions of higher education that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB68587E52CCB43C0AD848B53A2C4F0AF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determines the extent to which articulation agreements (defined in section 486A of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1093a">20 U.S.C. 1093a</external-xref>)) have resulted in reduced costs for students; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8C40C629E19F41888817711DF989B47F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provides recommendations on how to incentivize the expanded use of such articulation agreements.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H174D32ABE6C848FD8B75D86D04509D48"><enum>6.</enum><header>Competency-based education</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 481(b)(4) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1088">20 U.S.C. 1088(b)(4)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBEAC645BDC334D62A868E87C025B0E9C" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H6FBF8076D6F5416F8BF81E774A15133A"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of this title, the term <quote>eligible program</quote> includes an instructional program that measures knowledge, skills, and experience through assessments of such knowledge, skills, or experience in lieu of or in addition to the use of credit hours or clock hours. In the case of a program being determined eligible for the first time under this paragraph, such determination shall be made by the Secretary before such program is considered to be an eligible program.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


