<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC419D70C8308468797838FD777240154" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2795 IH: Yemen Security and Humanity Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2795</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170607">June 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001038">Mr. Crowley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000588">Mr. Richmond</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To increase coordination among relevant Federal departments and agencies to address United States
			 security and humanitarian interests in Yemen, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H1DC07C96C39B4739AA22E40349ED0E1D" style="OLC">
 <section id="HBDFDAC20FCFD483E8181FFC5F67B42EC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Yemen Security and Humanity Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H39A65410991A4CDB91EB06B6DDC6C467"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H84767989C17441A9B629FCF9086E4035"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Yemen, a country that has been plagued by violence and insurgency for many years, has been locked in a devastating civil war since 2015.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H468685294DE54E0EB852ECC1A397C451"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In April 2017, the World Food Programme announced that Yemen is on the brink of <quote>full-scale famine</quote> and classified approximately 7,000,000 Yemenis, including 2,200,000 children, as <quote>severely food insecure</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H686FD3F5F9F64760935EC2F493D7086B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Although many factors account for the famine conditions in Yemen, including years of government mismanagement, corruption, and natural disasters, the World Food Programme indicates that the impact of the conflict—including the destruction of public services, infrastructure, transport, and Yemen’s economy—is having a significant impact on Yemen’s food insecurity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFDEC7F2240A249798394F758515C7941"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to the United Nations International Children’s Emergency Fund, a Yemeni child dies every ten minutes, on average, from malnutrition, diarrhea, or respiratory tract infections.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6FA982725F2F4BCD860328F4850CCB18"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Disease, war, and desperate poverty in Yemen threaten United States core values and strategic priorities for combating global terror.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3B0378FA93404FF08043099DB7BED7B7"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to the January 2014 <quote>Worldwide Threat Assessment of the US Intelligence Community</quote>—</text> <subparagraph id="H3FFCB21BD5FD457380ACA3B436445947"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a <quote>[l]ack of adequate food will be a destabilizing factor in countries important to US national security that do not have the financial or technical abilities to solve their internal food security problems</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HECB8563C75304CEEB1AFC067A4000B62"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><quote>[f]ood and nutrition insecurity in weakly governed countries might also provide opportunities for insurgent groups to capitalize on poor conditions, exploit international food aid, and discredit governments for their inability to address basic needs</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF300637EA384897869AF182367A5AC6"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Yemen imports 90 percent of its food, a majority of which enters the country through the port of Hodeida, currently a Houthi-controlled city.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7089ABD935C84FFB8886D00DC8107440"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In response to the August 2015 bombing of the port of Hodeida, the United States Agency for International Development funded, in part, the replacement of port cranes destroyed in the bombing, though the replacements have not been delivered because of current conditions on the ground despite being essential to accelerate the rapid delivery of food from the port.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA1D5AE382C5E4BE7AEFD27F8CCFF22BE"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Relief organizations are concerned that the closure of the port of Hodeida for any reason could further exacerbate famine in Yemen because the majority of humanitarian aid enters the country through that port.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H09A607C5E46C426CACB46BA3C0533478"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="H4B75C7FCB96E4664A4F1BDE31EEE54F3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">effectively addressing the famine conditions in Yemen is in the national security interests of the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA61AF826FB5C4E31866C31CE040787AA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">interventions supported by the United States to advance national security should also consider the impact of military engagement on humanitarian operations in such regions; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4E07205237A34F9DA8FD96A8F6AC34D3"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">bureaucratic procedures with respect to humanitarian aid must be urgently improved and expedited to allow for an expansion of the scale of the humanitarian operations providing such aid.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H9EFD6EE571934E438FA0B0E93C25E778"><enum>4.</enum><header>Coordination in famine-risk areas</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5(a) of the Global Food Security Act of 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9304">22 U.S.C. 9304(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H2BE95D3B406E43ABBA2DB03B1776C20D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (16), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H585164535FA2489D93C5ED325971ADB8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (17), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H572AA07DEC2A4152AB324824A32E378C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5C62ECA173F04B0F8761C76449BEC7E2" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H7CE971A4FA2746A9B7CE405FCE76CB86"><enum>(18)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilitate coordination between the United States Agency for International Development, the United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs, and United States military personnel, with respect to famine-risk areas.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H8433F1FEC29D4DABACC2AD2BB100BF82"><enum>5.</enum><header>United States security and humanitarian support strategy for Yemen</header>
 <subsection id="HD85ED1FE5E56477FB76505B326EB638B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, shall jointly submit to Congress a comprehensive report on United States security and humanitarian interests in Yemen, including each of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HB0F8EC0F1FFF4E3BA3F3CB2FCD67DB55"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The strategic objectives of the United States in Yemen, including humanitarian support to civilian populations under threat of famine, and the criteria for determining the success of such objectives.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEF4B91BFEEBE4B7492235A09EAF480D7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of efforts to coordinate civilian and military efforts with respect to Yemen.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H958245D68F8F4E73BA82433180D53794"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the diplomatic strategy with respect to regional partners seeking to end the civil war in Yemen.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


