<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H9ECEB27BAE9741ADBECFD2EC929E2562" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2335 IH: Equal Access to Congressional Research Service Reports Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2335</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170503">May 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000567">Mr. Lance</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Director of the Government Publishing Office to provide members of the public with
			 Internet access to Congressional Research Service reports, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HA093CD3C22F544CDBB038DDED02DC055" style="OLC">
 <section id="HC8DC390858E8414393BF10372DFA81F5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Equal Access to Congressional Research Service Reports Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HDF40DB99FA4F42CABD5BEACE58C54FDB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header> <subsection id="H97DAF26C785941239B715524F954B740"><enum>(a)</enum><header>CRS product</header><text>In this Act, the term <term>CRS product</term> means any final work product of CRS in any format.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HD71975C1B3E047B7B0FF0C3C8710CD42"><enum>(b)</enum><header>CRS Report</header>
 <paragraph id="HA9DA02CC58B54350BD00A70E03BBFE48"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In this Act, the term <term>CRS Report</term> means any written CRS product, including an update to a previous written CRS product, consisting of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCFA8E6D04CFB49A0AE4EF0EBC98087B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a Congressional Research Service Report;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE653DF63CB3A4C63BE8E9C4DA9D683CB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a Congressional Research Service Authorization of Appropriations Product and Appropriations Product; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H542302620099403A91F6559B616B1D9E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>subject to paragraph (2)(C), any other written CRS product containing CRS research or CRS analysis which is available for general congressional access on the CRS Congressional Intranet.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2B2B3D7F46E47A6805FE344FA8DF470"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The term <term>CRS Report</term> does not include—</text> <subparagraph id="H84CEFE40DF444AD7AF299320C70970D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any CRS product that is determined by the CRS Director to be a custom product or service because it was prepared in direct response to a request for custom analysis or research and is not available for general congressional access on the CRS Congressional Intranet;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F11279753EB4201B46035C5868CD036"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any Congressional Research Service Report or any Congressional Research Service Authorization of Appropriations Product and Appropriations Product which, as of the effective date of this Act, is not available for general congressional access on the CRS Congressional Intranet; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H612568E130C54DDDB6DD24080B8DEC02"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a written CRS product that has been made available by CRS for publication on a public website maintained by the GPO Director (other than the Website) or the Library of Congress.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDC43320CECB44555B21DD54320E66A84"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Other definitions</header><text>In this Act—</text> <paragraph id="H91A5777B510D48E6932DECAC5337AFEE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>CRS</term> means the Congressional Research Service;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE611F716FAF54C05BE2B903D5917D330"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>CRS Congressional Intranet</term> means any of the websites maintained by CRS for the purpose of providing to Members and employees of Congress access to information from CRS;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H26613CEFBEA448D1BD29C0B618B2EA0B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>CRS Director</term> means the Director of CRS;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE1B1BE72B85A49068A1C7F98CCB3F52A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>GPO Director</term> means the Director of the Government Publishing Office;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB295E376121F46D280899511E8E279BB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>Member of Congress</term> includes a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to Congress; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8A93362AE07746D68FDF11B7D3677531"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the term <term>Website</term> means the website established and maintained under section 3.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE7E3E5B3819845F4ACA36D18F0AF9304"><enum>3.</enum><header>Availability of CRS reports through GPO website</header>
			<subsection id="HD157B0CEED4C40398D9F1EA9BA26E048"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Website</header>
 <paragraph id="H37EB81854F784ACBB47CCDDB2A0523DF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment and maintenance</header><text>The GPO Director, in consultation with the CRS Director, shall establish and maintain a public website containing CRS Reports and an index of all CRS Reports contained on the website, in accordance with this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD7729D02CC7040E497463CA407A9FB88"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Format</header><text>On the Website, CRS Reports shall be searchable, sortable, and downloadable, including downloadable in bulk.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H879778A5B5E1408B8951AD1B81F14D3D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Free access</header><text>Notwithstanding section 4102 of title 44, United States Code, the GPO Director may not charge a fee for access to the Website.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3C91BFFC5CCC43CDB69C65F5D8BCB3A1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Updates; disclaimer</header><text>The GPO Director, in consultation with the CRS Director, shall ensure that the Website—</text> <paragraph id="HEE1D3AB0E765458484625162C1216D9C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is updated contemporaneously, automatically, and electronically to include each new or updated CRS Report released on or after the effective date of this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H055ADC93BCB74AF9B2974AF8EDBB605C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shows the status of each CRS Report as new, updated, or withdrawn; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H282EAC8F3C9F4BA2BBA467B2B6428110"><enum>(3)</enum><text>displays the following statement in reference to the CRS Reports included on the Website: <quote>These documents were prepared by the Congressional Research Service (CRS). CRS serves as nonpartisan shared staff to congressional committees and Members of Congress. It operates solely at the behest of and under the direction of Congress. Information in a CRS Report should not be relied upon for purposes other than public understanding of information that has been provided by CRS to Members of Congress in connection with CRS’s institutional role. CRS Reports, as a work of the United States Government, are not subject to copyright protection in the United States. Any CRS Report may be reproduced and distributed in its entirety without permission from CRS. However, as a CRS Report may include copyrighted images or material from a third party, you may need to obtain the permission of the copyright holder if you wish to copy or otherwise use copyrighted material.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEA278F91064A41BBAAB54666BFA1FC99"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Furnishing of necessary information and technology</header><text>The CRS Director shall consult with and provide assistance to the GPO Director to ensure—</text> <paragraph id="HC0CE089CBC034C1688CDB4BAA7975D1E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>that the GPO Director is provided with all of the information necessary to carry out this Act, including all of the information described in subparagraphs (A) through (E) of section 4(a)(1), in such format and manner as the GPO Director considers appropriate; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA3CFE06BC1254B34AFEC4728A6CA44AA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that CRS makes available and implements such technology as may be necessary to facilitate the contemporaneous, automatic, and electronic provision of CRS Reports to the GPO Director as required under this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H328567D10D2B4DFF9A496685944633F6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Nonexclusivity</header><text>The GPO Director may publish other information on the Website.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HB5F3077DD28A40B4BFC67A8D6E67C814"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Additional techniques</header><text>The GPO Director and the CRS Director may use additional techniques to make CRS Reports available to the public, if such techniques are consistent with this Act and any other applicable laws.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCDA3128C1B7142758FBFCDB7A4AF3FBE"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Additional information</header><text>The CRS Director is encouraged to make additional CRS products that are not custom products or services available to the GPO Director for publication on the Website, and the GPO Director is encouraged to publish such CRS products on the Website.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HEEB8BC60E3FA4D1487F29D8D4388D880"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Expansion of contents of annual report to Congress To include information on efforts To make
 additional products available on Website</header><text>Section 203(i) of the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/166">2 U.S.C. 166(i)</external-xref>) is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting the following: <quote>, and shall include in the report a description of the efforts made by the Director to make additional Congressional Research Service products that are not custom products or services available to the Director of the Government Publishing Office for publication on the website established and maintained under the Equal Access to Congressional Research Service Reports Act of 2017.</quote>.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H4725D5125C044A1B8D8676FAEDA9E546"><enum>4.</enum><header>Website contents</header>
			<subsection id="H5EE8F3BD42704177BF168AE59A67FE84"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Specific requirements for reports posted on Website</header>
 <paragraph id="HB888D2753E9C41ACA68432A64842353A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Responsibilities of GPO Director</header><text>With respect to each CRS Report included on the Website, the GPO Director shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="HE072CB4262F34DAA938D01A60A9304F3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name and identification number of the CRS Report;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3ED6E6A0EFF44D238110AC91379E5225"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an indication as to whether the CRS Report is new, updated, or withdrawn;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9BA0291515B4AB7B60050D6381A2FE4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the date of release of the CRS Report;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AEA9797FB7E4F73A110F61DCDAD5E14"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the division or divisions of CRS that were responsible for the production of the CRS Report; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E2487D0FC744CC7B4DD20314F22F152"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any other information the GPO Director, in consultation with the CRS Director, considers appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H86F25BE173734A938B3E7F4F8A7DAD61"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Responsibilities of CRS Director</header><text>With respect to each CRS Report included on the Website, the CRS Director shall, prior to transmitting the Report to the GPO Director—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H849BFDC01546480BA6BE1ACD2BB7DDB7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>at the discretion of the CRS Director, remove the name of and any contact information for any employee of CRS; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2547EA9C0C334695ADA1C120281E7C69"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include in the CRS Report the following written statement: <quote>This document was prepared by the Congressional Research Service (CRS). CRS serves as nonpartisan shared staff to congressional committees and Members of Congress. It operates solely at the behest of and under the direction of Congress. Information in a CRS Report should not be relied upon for purposes other than public understanding of information that has been provided by CRS to Members of Congress in connection with CRS’s institutional role. CRS Reports, as a work of the United States Government, are not subject to copyright protection in the United States. Any CRS Report may be reproduced and distributed in its entirety without permission from CRS. However, as this CRS Report may include copyrighted images or material from a third party, you may need to obtain the permission of the copyright holder if you wish to copy or otherwise use copyrighted material.</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF3199201BA744A898A9B5797335F4F34"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Specific requirements for index on Website</header><text>The GPO Director shall ensure that the index of all CRS Reports published on the Website is—</text> <paragraph id="HBCB45911E7BA40E2BC3B5387B79E1658"><enum>(1)</enum><text>comprehensive;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6496A262472947A1A72BE98C1C0DC6A9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>contemporaneously updated;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE4FC29F13EC44DD2B7CCC37BC26A602B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>searchable;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H38CF421B0F0A417A8509D4F19A9CC117"><enum>(4)</enum><text>sortable;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H87E9FF42F90A4164BF521B9C226787EA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>maintained in a human-readable format;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA0EC15B6A9BD4DB28F23F38A90EECA17"><enum>(6)</enum><text>maintained in a structured data format;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4DFA1A152F754871805EB22BB66D1FCC"><enum>(7)</enum><text>downloadable; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC1354960B2584F7BACAECD94C3D88181"><enum>(8)</enum><text>inclusive of each item of information described in subsection (a)(1) with respect to each CRS Report.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H81690BC251F841B98DF578131EF6949C"><enum>5.</enum><header>Conforming amendment to duties of CRS</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 203(d) of the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/166">2 U.S.C. 166(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H8C4E1CD9772A492192E55D8386AD32D7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (7);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9E45EAF7DDEC4BD8854B85B15C9FA0EF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of paragraph (8) and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAA7BFEC7CC6D4A5FA87EF4E5B54ED9A4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H04B17EA5CA6B499E9CFC3B3AB8F09D4E" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H11A8A6DECD6B4F17A48B064B51DFDE69"><enum>(9)</enum><text>to comply with the requirements of, and provide information and technological assistance consistent with, the <short-title>Equal Access to Congressional Research Service Reports Act of 2017</short-title>.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HCE1F691A310C4E218AB0EABD94154BA3"><enum>6.</enum><header>Rules of construction</header>
 <subsection id="HB3AA4EB9AD0E45A2A697A64F181CF271"><enum>(a)</enum><header>No effect on speech or debate clause</header><text>Nothing in this Act may be construed to diminish, qualify, condition, waive, or otherwise affect the applicability of clause 1 of section 6 of article I of the Constitution of the United States (commonly known as the <quote>Speech or Debate Clause</quote>) or any other privilege available to Congress or Members, offices, or employees of Congress with respect to any CRS Report made available online under this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7D662B1B60AE410C9EACC7CFC48EA9A8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Confidential communications</header><text>Nothing in this Act may be construed to waive the requirement that any confidential communication by CRS to a Member, office, or committee of Congress shall remain under the custody and control of Congress and may be released only by Congress and its Houses, Members, offices, and committees, in accordance with the rules and privileges of each House and the requirements of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF5902356C5514FFF9EF8ABBD187C5B4F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Dissemination of CRS products</header><text>Nothing in this Act may be construed to limit or otherwise affect the ability of a Member, office, or committee of Congress to disseminate CRS products on a website of the Member, office, or committee or to otherwise provide CRS products to the public, including as part of constituent service activities.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H02E7A9AB69C348C187554910298486D4"><enum>7.</enum><header>Effective date</header>
 <subsection id="H6DCAE9D8B00D4AF984DA2CBBB98B85D1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), this Act and the amendments made by this Act shall take effect 90 days after the date on which the GPO Director submits the certification described in subsection (b)(2).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HBC599D346E2C4A1BBF5ED95FCBC3E3BC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Provision of information and technology</header>
 <paragraph id="H0EC254DD2E964DDF94A4A2C723684C34"><enum>(1)</enum><header>CRS deadline</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the CRS Director shall provide the GPO Director with the information and technology necessary for the GPO Director to begin the initial operation of the Website.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H35311373D9854A939DB69AD5537DC0A3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>Upon provision of the information and technology described in paragraph (1), the GPO Director shall submit to Congress a certification that the CRS Director has provided the information and technology necessary for the GPO Director to begin the initial operation of the Website.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


