<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HEBDA0331C17F4689BFB5C028C295DE4C" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1325 IH: To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to provide States with flexibility with respect to providing premium assistance under the Medicaid program.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1325</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170302">March 2, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001275">Mr. Bucshon</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to provide States with flexibility with respect to
			 providing premium assistance under the Medicaid program.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H3CA799658AB6454E8AA123679C5B71AC" style="OLC">
		<section id="HE05E764C20AE4EE2A3FBBA0677C8089A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Providing flexibility with respect to premium assistance under Medicaid</header>
 <subsection id="H0221C4173ED44289AC21D98BD7E87911"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1906 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396e">42 U.S.C. 1396e</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HFD3A14087FD5453C8DF1AC82E6F1FF66"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c)(2), by striking <quote>such plan.</quote> and inserting <quote>such group health plan.</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8D9D5F308DC84CCF835922CA5DA4E0F9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (c) the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0ABABA8FBF97436695FCF2382CAEDFD0" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H2EFE9E51E7D54687BB68B3442D7AF105"><enum>(d)</enum><header>State option for nonelderly, nondisabled adults</header> <paragraph id="HBB8099A6A96442238B6F1C8258FE09D3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on January 1, 2018, in the case of a State electing the option described in paragraph (2) of subsection (a), the Secretary may, upon the approval of a State plan amendment submitted by the State, waive the requirement of paragraph (3) of such subsection to the extent such requirement provides for payment of premiums and deductibles and other cost-sharing obligations with respect to the items and services described in such paragraph furnished to individuals described in paragraph (3) of this subsection.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H580ED145CBE54A3D9DB1FA7D677388CE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cost-effectiveness</header>
 <subparagraph id="HFF2825E87F8C461DA6B082B26DF99FBB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may approve a State plan amendment under this subsection if the Secretary determines that the payment of premiums and deductibles and other cost-sharing obligations under the group health plan or plans involved is cost-effective relative to the amount of expenditures under the State plan, including administrative expenditures, and excluding payments for copayments or coinsurance, that the State would have made to provide comparable coverage of the individuals described in paragraph (3) involved.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28A2075AB9CE43D18335CD0623B2C497"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Determination</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), cost-effectiveness shall be determined—</text> <clause id="HCCBB3F39DC5F48418EC3C39020812E06"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on an annual basis by comparing—</text>
 <subclause id="H0F31E159D8754DC2BEC8E4B712F9028A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the amount of expenditures per employer for coverage under the group health plan or plans involved of the individuals described in paragraph (3) for the preceding 4 calendar quarters; to</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H9DD94056552A43E593F37D91CF77F212"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the average per capita amount of expenditures that the State made under the State plan to provide comparable coverage of such individuals for such calendar quarters; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HF0098407A44D406B8A715A7BF26626B9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of individuals described in paragraph (3) who are parents of children—</text> <subclause id="HB1B964D37FAA4082B03B4FD88BD7C295"><enum>(I)</enum><text>if the parent is eligible for enrollment in a group health plan, based on the cost of purchasing family coverage under the group health plan; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H0D9884B381944037A396355DEBCFF951"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if the parent is not so eligible, based on the cost of individual coverage for the parent and each child.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F74F699A1864DC28AD25659EC96609C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Child defined</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <quote>child</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 1902(e)(13)(G).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE551B7D248784CE59260915A2AC9C58A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Nonelderly, nondisabled adults</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The individuals described in this paragraph are individuals who are under 65 years of age, not pregnant, not entitled to, or enrolled for, benefits under part A of title XVIII, or enrolled for benefits under part B of title XVIII, are not described in subclauses (I) through (VII) of section 1902(a)(10)(A)(i), and otherwise entitled to medical assistance under this title.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H44B28DBCB3BB47088A3EEFEBDC734084"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Premium assistance subsidy option</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1906A of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396e-1">42 U.S.C. 1396e–1</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC2F922E2B1EF48878E24AC7F70188E7A" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="HFC705569732E4C6294B3F3AACC586507"><enum>(f)</enum><header>State option for nonelderly, nondisabled adults</header>
 <paragraph id="H8469E85FF9224271A445B44A046D6DA3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on January 1, 2018, in the case of a State electing to provide a premium assistance subsidy as described in subsection (a), the Secretary may, upon the approval of a State plan amendment submitted by the State, waive the requirement of subsection (e) to the extent such requirement provides for payment of premiums and deductibles and other cost-sharing obligations with respect to the items and services described in such subsection furnished to individuals described in paragraph (3).</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H55B49BF28C1D40D2A284E2C5CE38BA0B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cost-effectiveness</header>
 <subparagraph id="H16F5E5795DA24EE984C357A0A3FFBBFA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may approve a State plan amendment under this subsection if the Secretary determines that the payment of premiums and deductibles and other cost-sharing obligations under the qualified employer-sponsored coverage involved is cost-effective relative to the amount of expenditures under the State plan, including administrative expenditures, and excluding payments for copayments or coinsurance, that the State would have made to provide comparable coverage of the individuals described in paragraph (3)(B) involved.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9322358AE44A4B8D897D8A99C82764C5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Determination</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), cost-effectiveness shall be determined—</text> <clause id="HF9F2777D9B474B0AB9CD6BE3F5240E81"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on an annual basis by comparing—</text>
 <subclause id="H7CC27F19C5D1446CA55543018F27FC17"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the amount of expenditures per employer for coverage under the qualified employer-sponsored coverage involved of the individuals described in paragraph (3)(B) for the preceding 4 calendar quarters; to</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H6E5D03B9736D44CD869D937D1BE878DA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the average per capita amount of expenditures that the State made under the State plan to provide comparable coverage of such individuals for such calendar quarters; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H39BD9C78B8314AF8A8BA82384FC420D0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of individuals described in paragraph (3) who are parents of individuals under 19 years of age—</text>
 <subclause id="H31B26597DBFC4FB799D7F82139DAB8DD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>if the parent is eligible for enrollment in qualified employer-sponsored coverage, based on the cost of purchasing family coverage under such qualified employer-sponsored coverage; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB30DB8FD21A243E9847F1294C98DF37F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if the parent is not so eligible, based on the cost of individual coverage for the parent and each such individual under 19 years of age.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H52FE27F1DA5B4E8C903A6002BFB10E8D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Nonelderly, nondisabled adults</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The individuals described in this paragraph are individuals (or the parents of individuals) who are—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6D6BE6D88D0A4CECBE8BBB9DFEB75B96"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">participating in a premium assistance subsidy under this section for qualified employer-sponsored coverage; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB25BB3AA7A544BEAA987B058CC9C9544"><enum>(B)</enum><text>under 65 years of age, not pregnant, not entitled to, or enrolled for, benefits under part A of title XVIII, or enrolled for benefits under part B of title XVIII, and are not described in subclauses (I) through (VII) of section 1902(a)(10)(A)(i).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


