<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HA160DC8E6A8B40D5BF3F9760206B4714" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1595 IH: Mutual Bank Capital Opportunity Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1595</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170317">March 17, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000598">Mr. Rothfus</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001187">Mr. Stivers</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to allow mutual capital certificates to satisfy capital
			 requirements for mutual depositories.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H081AFA4E4A0044AF923AF1FF52711FBA" style="OLC">
 <section id="H2B73A421154E4D84B94BFEC4C0ACB82B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Mutual Bank Capital Opportunity Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H467BC46A17AC4134B910B4483B513F13" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Treatment of mutual capital certificates</header> <subsection id="HFE6CA2F71A19478D9D8F324F843E3D66"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 38 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1831o">12 U.S.C. 1831o</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8CD26B5DC7AE4A87A29D1C0CC407ADA8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(2)—</text> <subparagraph id="H8BD58DA84ED44FC89248C7488FE775A0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (F) through (I) as subparagraphs (H) through (K), respectively; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84471CDDC48042C5A64D1F874CAEFD33"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (E) the following new subparagraphs:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3D805441B91B4AEB90053B9AC055F4A7" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H3D11C71008564614B910BC71F5EBB9F8"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Mutual capital certificate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>mutual capital certificate</term> means a financial instrument issued by a mutual depository pursuant to subsection (c)(1)(C) that—</text>
 <clause id="H75F72BD4CEB445A1B84E16865768702D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is subordinate to all claims against such mutual depository;</text> </clause><clause id="HF9D0F16C014F45D9A2BA4D636B9236D7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is unsecured by the assets of such mutual depository;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H103E95D0D8934782B77DEF5323D98EAA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>does not permit preemptive rights;</text> </clause><clause id="H9EB939160E98485DAEBA95A65CAAF524"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not provide voting or member rights to the holder unless the board of directors of such mutual depository proposes to change the specific terms of any class of such certificates in a manner adverse to the interests of the holder;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD2B666063C9D42F4826B06376D6FC85E"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not eligible for use as collateral for any loan made by such mutual depository;</text> </clause><clause id="HFB6AF955A6C1485AA0D0F0EB5B8B60C9"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if declared by the board of directors of such mutual depository, entitles the holder to a payment of fixed, variable, or participating dividends; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB693FB17AF8946B69C1A0532093388C2"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not redeemable until the date that is 5 years after the date of issuance, except in the case of merger, conversion, or consolidation of such mutual depository, or reorganization of such mutual depository into a mutual holding company or a Federal mutual bank holding company (as such term is defined in section 5133A(a) of the Revised Statutes of the United States).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0DDAF6C7A9F24F629EBFA0A84EDF7E14"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Mutual depository</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>mutual depository</term> means an insured depository institution operating in a non-stock form, including a Federal non-stock depository and any form of non-stock depository provided for under State law, the deposits of which are insured by an instrumentality of the Federal Government.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6E7A01BC8B13414189C2576A9FEF85FA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(1)—</text> <subparagraph id="HDE00C82052EC4B7D9D3231F57522AFD0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>and subparagraph (C)</quote> after <quote>subparagraph (B)(ii)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2FC6B0287F7D4656A1AD2BE9670ED118"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (B) the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block id="HEADA203306174F7D9AF2EEE79E273AE9" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H6463807523AA46ACB1AC95458745DC55"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Mutual capital certificates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A mutual depository is authorized to issue mutual capital certificates that shall qualify as common equity Tier 1 capital (as such term is defined by the appropriate Federal banking agency) for purposes of any capital requirements mandated by any Federal law or regulation.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H1AE5D1A5ECBC4CF9A900DD8932DB0CA0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H6E4B7675974A43059D551D58730F386F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the appropriate Federal banking agencies (as defined in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813</external-xref>)) shall jointly issue regulations to implement this section.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE31D75B85C7741D7B9E7AB9E2804A04D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other financial instruments</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HB48DE6329F4340B38E67321206281D81"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the appropriate Federal banking agencies shall jointly issue regulations identifying other financial instruments, aside from mutual capital certificates, that mutual depositories may issue that shall qualify as additional Tier 1 capital (as such term is defined by the appropriate Federal banking agency) for purposes of any capital requirements mandated by any Federal law or regulation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4108C0511CB548308D6EA231D5E73AD8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <quote>mutual capital certificate</quote> and <quote>mutual depository</quote> have the meaning given such terms in section 38(b)(2) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1831o">12 U.S.C. 1831o(b)(2)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H07D4BB2E15274E14903DB58800A8ACDA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this section, and every 6 months thereafter until the date which is 3 years after the date of the enactment of this section, the appropriate Federal banking agencies shall submit a report to Congress on the progress of such agencies in promulgating the regulations described in subsection (b). Such report shall include a description of outreach efforts to the financial industry and any barriers to implementation of the requirements of this section.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


