<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H919E7635707840869D4E4493A3E0C922" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 715 IH: Compassionate Access Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 715</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170127">January 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000568">Mr. Griffith</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the rescheduling of marihuana, the medical use of marihuana in accordance with State
			 law, and the exclusion of cannabidiol from the definition of marihuana,
			 and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H3701A6867C594FBB95CE9F93B767E1BC" style="OLC">
 <section id="HA90BF90AA1B946B1929AB49B00F02709" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Compassionate Access Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HA99B74796A064740AC5D68FFC92495D0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Availability of marihuana for medical use</header> <subsection id="H583AAA545DDF43569EFD5CCBBFCF1C21"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rescheduling</header> <paragraph id="HC395095D714440EE8C86971EDDF7EB7F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Recommendation by HHS</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the Institute of Medicine of the National Academy of Sciences, shall submit to the Administrator of the Drug Enforcement Administration a recommendation to transfer marihuana from schedule I under section 202 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/812">21 U.S.C. 812</external-xref>) to a schedule under such section 202 other than schedule I.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDB8E88692D44476C93587CB0DC8B0F68"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final rule</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Drug Enforcement Administration shall, taking into consideration the recommendation under paragraph (1), issue a final rule to transfer marihuana from schedule I under section 202 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/812">21 U.S.C. 812</external-xref>) to a schedule under such section other than schedule I.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H64C1BF9D630E4F7DB24AE5E0F510EBB9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Cannabidiol</header>
 <paragraph id="H418CBB60AA97437683ED5E1B275DB0B9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Paragraph (16) of section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H137BB647F0C9439EB566DF23AA3AED56"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(16) The</quote> and inserting <quote>(16)(A) The</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4E43691C36444FBAD445841B6A459BD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HC785A8E1B520429097662E03C24D9126" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HE7D187972E5C4F81BE50DA6C2AAC8481" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Cannabidiol—</text>
 <clause id="HBA625BE2A0CB4E028E143441D2F276C7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is excluded from the definition of marihuana under subparagraph (A); and</text> </clause><clause id="H353A8B7775694B4393750593054AEE75"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall not be treated as a controlled substance under this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H32614E5398CD4098BDC79C87F05B9010"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>Section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>), as amended by paragraph (1), is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H63D02A5BDAB541DC8E3346C467109FFA" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HB9EB5201B5934FEBBC22DA7842160952"><enum>(57)</enum><text>The term <term>cannabidiol</term> means the substance cannabidiol, as derived from marihuana or synthetically formulated, that contains not greater than 0.3 percent delta-9-tetrahydrocannabinol on a dry weight basis.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA44E818EC84843B3830C4E190A32B803"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cannabidiol determination by the States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 201 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/811">21 U.S.C. 811</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H21B0253F9F5A49A4B4EBBCFA03104CB6" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H783A1FE1306142D0AB4BA8715F303894"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Cannabidiol determination</header><text>If a person grows or processes marihuana for purposes of making cannabidiol in accordance with State law, the marihuana shall be deemed to meet the concentration limitation under section 102(57), unless the Attorney General determines that the State law is not reasonably calculated to ensure that marihuana grown or processed for purposes of making cannabidiol meets such concentration limitation.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6794C1777480484F89D31C2FE8305293"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regulation under State law</header>
 <paragraph id="H49FCE748870E43D3BF06A2385EFB9954"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In a State in which marihuana may be prescribed by a physician for medical use under applicable State law, no provision of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/801">21 U.S.C. 801</external-xref> et seq.) or of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/301">21 U.S.C. 301</external-xref> et seq.) shall prohibit or otherwise restrict in such State in accordance with such State law—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7712D8C0BF9A4492A6143134361C1878"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the prescription of marihuana by a physician for medical use;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45FD17673C9348128D6DFAA1826C930A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an authorized patient under such State law from obtaining, possessing, transporting, or using marihuana for that patient’s medical use;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C5308C3A8AE430E90997A9B4BAAE0A0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a caregiver for an authorized patient from obtaining, possessing, or transporting marihuana, as authorized under such State law, for the medical use of such authorized patient;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF82FBBF6A1840438EB4CE1FD1972CA5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the legally recognized parent or guardian of a minor who is an authorized patient from obtaining, possessing, or transporting marihuana, as authorized under such State law, for the medical use of such minor;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6FA6B7388C594AA6B33117988CD40C13"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an entity from producing, processing, or otherwise manufacturing marihuana for medical use, as authorized under such State law;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5DE1C29F2D0E478BB0DB7A0B1D3D9B8F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>an entity from distributing marihuana for medical use, as authorized under such State law;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC419647995AA42A28B0559C44A7F6924"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a pharmacy or other health care provider from dispensing marihuana to an authorized patient for medical use, as authorized under such State law; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H59D6BE51B37545C88C82EA530AF9EC4D"><enum>(H)</enum><text>a laboratory or other entity from performing safety, quality, or efficacy testing of marihuana for medical use, as authorized under such State law or under Federal law.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EAD6231DAD345F9BDAA77C6843FFF9A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cannabidiol</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the exclusion of cannabidiol from the definition of marihuana in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>), as amended, and section 5 of this Act, this subsection applies with respect to cannabidiol, as defined in such section 102, to the same extent and in the same manner as this subsection applies with respect to marihuana.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE6DED4BD44E24D0F818136E237C0EDB3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Research into potential medicinal uses of marihuana</header>
 <subsection id="HB69FB05B56E04A8EBFC9DE4119FFFC8B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall delegate responsibility under section 303(f) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/823">21 U.S.C. 823(f)</external-xref>) for control over access to marihuana for research into its potential medicinal uses to an agency of the executive branch that is not focused on researching the addictive properties of substances. Such agency shall take appropriate actions to ensure that an adequate supply of marihuana is available for such medicinal research.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HADDA30302DB048D8995AC8E1A518B3A2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consideration of other research in scheduling</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Research that is performed in a scientifically sound manner in a State where marihuana or cannabidiol is legal for medical purposes, and in accordance with such State’s law, but that does not use marihuana from federally approved sources, may be considered for purposes of rescheduling marihuana under section 202 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/812">21 U.S.C. 812</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H2DE548882FC34C4181641F6C365D3476"><enum>4.</enum><header>Relation of act to certain prohibitions relating to smoking</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act does not affect any Federal, State, or local law regulating or prohibiting smoking in public.</text>
 </section><section id="H9CFCC1125A9F4D83875A37727E0A666F"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HF82C8D4BE7544AB5892F891F5D936EBE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorized patient</header><text>The term <term>authorized patient</term> means an individual using marihuana in accordance with a prescription by a physician for medical use.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2D6A77C2A3674823AC175C87F5A6E051"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Marihuana</header><text>Except as provided in section 2(c)(2), the term <term>marihuana</term> has the meaning given to such term in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>), as amended by section 2(b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBDED0D93699A45AFB428DF24A6FA2B9C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Physician</header><text>The term <term>physician</term> means a practitioner of medicine, who—</text> <subparagraph id="H73CD55B57BDA4F10B3AF6A2820223E3A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>graduated from a college of medicine or osteopathy; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H46607A4741D74A0E849DFA0D87C89FEF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is licensed to practice medicine by the appropriate State board.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE220A1043D6C46C9B641573277F519AC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Prescription</header><text>The term <term>prescription</term> means an instruction written by a medical physician in accordance with applicable State law that authorizes the provision of a medicine or treatment to a patient.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0AE6C10277F541448256EF477A8F8530"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> includes the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, and any other territory or possession of the United States.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


