<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H72F91507A9E64F41B6C73BFFF9C99608" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 390 IH: Iraq and Syria Genocide Emergency Relief and Accountability Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 390</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170110">January 10, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001187">Mr. Meadows</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000449">Mr. Fortenberry</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000563">Mr. Lipinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000606">Mr. Pittenger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001059">Mr. Hultgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000475">Mr. Trott</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000614">Mr. Duffy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001071">Mr. Jody B. Hice of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001105">Mrs. Comstock</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for emergency relief to victims of genocide, crimes against humanity, and war crimes in
			 Iraq and Syria, to provide accountability for perpetrators of these
			 crimes, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H8E8977CDB2E841AFA082EB5660E4F4E8" style="OLC">
 <section id="H5F1E10233C7B42ACBF6C0CD975391838" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Iraq and Syria Genocide Emergency Relief and Accountability Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H9DC9011909EB4C90BBCD8028612F8BCB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H97640F7185BC4FA9BB5C488275C24803"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On March 17, 2016, Secretary of State John Kerry stated, <quote>in my judgment, Daesh is responsible for genocide against groups in areas under its control, including Yezidis, Christians, and Shia Muslims . . . the United States will strongly support efforts to collect, document, preserve, and analyze the evidence of atrocities, and we will do all we can to see that the perpetrators are held accountable</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H30590E0EAE9F4FCABD5A40EA32F2FE37"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Secretary of State Kerry stated in the <quote>Atrocities Prevention Report</quote>, transmitted to Congress on March 17, 2016, <quote>The Department of State has a longstanding commitment to providing support for the urgent humanitarian needs of conflict-affected populations in Iraq, Syria, and across the world, including but not limited to members of ethnic and religious minorities.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA1D6006A7C774E659A70409B0FD4C4B5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Independent International Commission of Inquiry on the Syrian Arab Republic stated in its February 3, 2016, report, <quote>The Government has committed the crimes against humanity of extermination, murder, rape or other forms of sexual violence, torture, imprisonment, enforced disappearance and other inhuman acts. Based on the same conduct, war crimes have also been committed. Both Jabhat Al-Nusra and some anti-Government armed groups have committed the war crimes of murder, cruel treatment, and torture.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H678CE1ED0D0741DDB204A7008998A823"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The International Criminal Investigative Training Assistance Program and the Office of Overseas Prosecutorial Development Assistance and Training of the Department of Justice have provided technical assistance to governmental judicial and law enforcement entities in Iraq, including with funding support from the Department of State.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA02E5937871F40C0B27A5E6CEEBA817E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>There were an estimated 800,000 to 1,400,000 Christians in Iraq in 2002, 500,000 in 2013, and less than 250,000 in 2015, according to the annual International Religious Freedom Reports of the Department of State.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H719345E869DA4BF7AD2E7C6BCC4721DC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Although Christians were an estimated eight to 10 percent of the 21,000,000 person population of Syria in 2010, “media and other reports of Christians fleeing the country as a result of the civil war suggest the Christian population is now considerably lower” as of 2015, according to the annual International Religious Freedom Reports of the Department of State.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6ADBDF856AE04B25879DB38DBF75DBF3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Chaldean Catholic Archdiocese of Erbil (Iraq) is an example of an entity that has not received funding from any government and has been providing assistance to internally displaced families of Yezidis, Muslims, and Christians, including food, resettlement from tents to permanent housing, and rent for Yezidis, medical care and education for Yezidis and Muslims through clinics, schools, and a university that are open to all, and some form of these types of assistance to all of the estimated 10,500 internally displaced Christian families, more than 70,000 people, in the greater Erbil region.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5412C5B1982440F79598F9D6B40B49AA"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In fiscal year 2015, the United States Government admitted to the United States through the United States Refugee Admissions Program persons from Priority 2 groups of special humanitarian concern, as designated by Congress, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H242B95A1F62E44F49AD48363A7A8BE97"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Jews, Evangelical Christians, Ukrainian Catholics, and Ukrainian Orthodox, from the former Soviet Union;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H95D41B2F9B3C4909AB0B951A6D0DB001"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Iraqis at risk because they were, or are, employed in Iraq by the United States Government, a media or nongovernmental organization headquartered in the United States, or an organization or entity that received funding from the United States Government, or are related to someone who is, or was, so employed;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12C1A412B4A846BC8068F7CFCF7AB258"><enum>(C)</enum><text>religious minorities in Iran; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBBB3B747637147A193FCE4816E71DFBA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>members of other groups designated by the United States Government, including—</text>
 <clause id="HB0E309825A0B40E7B3C7A922C2FD4D8C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>former political prisoners, active members of persecuted religious minorities, human rights activists, and forced labor conscripts in Cuba;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3D9C66BD1B324DEE99E2F356309D5E84"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>minors in Honduras, El Salvador, and Guatemala;</text> </clause><clause id="HFCBAFEA783454C6387BC077C55F92584"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>ethnic minorities from Burma in Malaysia;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3FC3D78E21FE41A1B445A1D0A22AC2F7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Bhutanese in Nepal; and</text> </clause><clause id="HCB944BB6A4DC4C2BAA0440B20EE9B358"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Congolese in Rwanda.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H531228DBD3F1431DB44E9EFA2ACFA1B3"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Through the United States Refugee Admissions Program, the United States Government—</text> <subparagraph id="HC2C40148AD6D45568C254F44AEB7E050"><enum>(A)</enum><text>admitted 12,676 Iraqi refugees in fiscal year 2015, including at least 2,113 Christians and 213 Yezidis;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41A6933DE847489ABA9587381A5D0A60"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">admitted 9,880 Iraqi refugees in fiscal year 2016, including at least 1,524 Christians and 393 Yezidis;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37542F7F3AD14F368FDC483371EB8D09"><enum>(C)</enum><text>admitted 1,682 Syrian refugees in fiscal year 2015, including at least 30 Christians; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBD72F83312F450D949F2B6A38EF3181"><enum>(D)</enum><text>admitted 12,587 Syrian refugees in fiscal year 2016, including at least 64 Christians and 24 Yezidis.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H61C58052A2F444C79D0D4C02526ED762"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HBD68FE1ECABE42F9AE9B26A4D2D49B57"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDD79D84C185746D1B65CA8BFC012F7CC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF231B611AF841DE8FF0989B539D4C90"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H38E7DFBDAFC8463FB62FEB625ECAEA20"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Capacity-building</header><text>The term <term>capacity-building</term>, with respect to cases of genocide, crimes against humanity, war crimes, and terrorism in Iraq or Syria, means developing domestic skills to efficiently adjudicate such cases, consistent with due process and respect for the rule of law, through the use of experts in international criminal investigations and experts in international criminal law to partner with, mentor, provide technical advice for, formally train, and provide equipment and infrastructure where necessary and appropriate to, investigators and judicial personnel in Iraq, including the Kurdistan region of Iraq, and domestic investigators and lawyers in Syria.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H880BF3B364B54869B19F657B61EB3BC2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Foreign terrorist organization</header><text>The term <term>foreign terrorist organization</term> mean an organization designated by the Secretary of State as a foreign terrorist organization pursuant to section 219(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189(a)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4DEB333D06ED41E29B920999FB224697"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Humanitarian, stabilization, and recovery needs</header><text>The term <term>humanitarian, stabilization, and recovery needs</term>, with respect to an individual, includes water, sanitation, hygiene, food security and nutrition, shelter and housing, medical, education, and psychosocial needs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1CC63AB5B5F842E984A494F5E2474060"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Hybrid court</header><text>The term <term>hybrid court</term> means a court with a combination of domestic and international lawyers, judges, and personnel.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEA73173A341B488B94B0594D8D9FCED8"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Internationalized domestic court</header><text>The term <term>internationalized domestic court</term> means a domestic court with the support of international advisers.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H02A2BC0902BE468E8914571383097961"><enum>4.</enum><header>Actions to promote accountability in Iraq and Syria</header>
			<subsection id="HB0D1CEA13AD04F72920E0214AEA11D04"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Assistance To support certain entities</header>
 <paragraph id="H455407EA734A4140B99BBD95E6087961"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor, the Assistant Secretary for International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs, and Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, shall provide assistance, including financial assistance, to support entities that are taking the actions described in paragraph (2) with respect to individuals who are suspected to have committed genocide, crimes against humanity, or war crimes in Iraq since January 2014 or Syria since March 2011.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1C08FE5CAB5B4876A0EF976D89B8344D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Actions described</header><text>The actions described in this paragraph are the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HAA66C7BF4CC54BEE8E51CCCC54E619F6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Conducting criminal investigations.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE940F01B62CF40DBB58C77F9592B34E1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Developing investigative and judicial capacities.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED0F2AF5CE284B2EADB9F1030C267828"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Collecting evidence.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C6939CAE67647B1B5AFADC8EE1E0D66"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Preserving the chain of evidence for prosecution in domestic courts, hybrid courts, and internationalized domestic courts.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB85E37EDCD7438C8B9C5B4E8C5E0AB0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Capacity-building.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H916E1A573BE240C2AA86350D70AA035A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Availability of amounts</header><text>Amounts authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available for programs, projects, and activities carried out by the Assistant Secretary for Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor and the Assistant Secretary for International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs are authorized to be made available to carry out this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H929E79868ECC4CECAD0083AC93980B81"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Actions by foreign governments</header><text>The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Attorney General, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, shall seek to encourage governments of foreign countries—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7BE347037A47428FB3CEC1CFB9EFE268"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to include in appropriate security databases and security screening procedures of such countries information to identify individuals who are suspected to have committed genocide, crimes against humanity, or war crimes in Iraq since January 2014 or Syria since March 2011, including individuals who are suspected to be members of foreign terrorist organizations operating within Iraq or Syria; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H782F61572EC5413E900A1703AE3B5FF2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to prosecute such individuals for genocide, crimes against humanity, or war crimes, as appropriate.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H505546EC31F049F893F08564B8854EAD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Review of certain criminal statutes</header><text>The Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall conduct a review of existing criminal statutes concerning genocide, crimes against humanity, and war crimes to determine the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H641A0C41433D479C862EBE8C111BC3FF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The extent to which United States courts are currently authorized by statute to exercise jurisdiction over such crimes where the direct perpetrators, accomplices, or victims are United States nationals, United States residents, or persons physically present in the territory of the United States either during the commission of the crime or subsequent to the commission of the crime.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4F7C173CA958438BBCF8571944EFD428"><enum>(2)</enum><text>What statutes are currently in effect that would apply to conduct constituting war crimes or crimes against humanity, and whether those statutes provide for extraterritorial jurisdiction, what the statute of limitations for offenses under such statutes are, what penalties apply under such statutes, and whether offenders would be subject to extradition or mutual legal assistance treaties.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC28770BF48ED4260AEE77B366A3BBF12"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The extent to which the absence of criminal statutes defining the crimes, or granting jurisdiction, would impede the prosecution of genocide, crimes against humanity, and war crimes in United States courts, including when United States military forces capture persons outside the United States known to have committed such crimes in a third country that is either unable or unwilling to prosecute the crimes.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H472D56D89D8F47A19D4BDBC29537A366"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Whether additional statutory authorities are necessary to prosecute a United States person or a foreign person within the territory of the United States for genocide, crimes against humanity, and war crimes.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC5A94BA5452B40328A654576C3030C18"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary of State shall consult with and consider credible information from entities described in paragraph (1) and paragraph (2) of such subsection.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6DF3117BE9134F7DA82711AC590A687F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that an appropriate amount of the additional amount made available under the heading <quote>Economic Support Fund</quote> in title II of division B of the Further Continuing and Security Assistance Appropriations Act, 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/254">Public Law 114–254</external-xref>) should be made available to carry out subsection (a).</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H14353B5C95CA468387AC0A1E2D50AC8C"><enum>5.</enum><header>Identification of and assistance to address humanitarian, stabilization, and recovery needs of
			 certain persons in Iraq and Syria</header>
 <subsection id="H7C979E91E02241E0B038953BDF181F7D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Identification</header><text>The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, the Ambassador at Large for International Religious Freedom, the Special Advisor for Religious Minorities in the Near East and South/Central Asia, the Assistant Secretary for Population, Refugees, and Migration, the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, and Director of National Intelligence, shall identify the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H1E2AAAC5D11E4F348D67F066D87E13C3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The threats of persecution and other warning signs of genocide, crimes against humanity, and war crimes against individuals—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4B501E3D54B541B2B241A84738F5B936"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who are or were nationals and residents of Iraq or Syria, and are members of the religious or ethnic groups that are minorities in Iraq, or minorities in Syria, and with respect to which the Secretary of State has determined the Islamic State of Iraq and Syria (ISIS) has committed genocide, crimes against humanity, or war crimes in Iraq or Syria since January 2014; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB696BCFE379647EC8352816E5AC6862E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who are members of other religious or ethnic groups that are minorities in Iraq, or minorities in Syria and are identified by the Secretary of State (or the Secretary’s designee) as persecuted groups.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC78BBAC88B1403994FD2516998A2CFA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The humanitarian, stabilization, and recovery needs of individuals described in paragraph (1).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE15A1A60F49041ADB3516549816EC2E9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The religious and ethnic groups that are minorities in Iraq, or are minorities in Syria, with respect to which the Secretary of State has determined ISIS has committed genocide, crimes against humanity, or war crimes in Iraq or Syria since January 2014, or are other religious or ethnic groups that are minorities in Iraq, or are minorities in Syria, identified by the Secretary of State (or the Secretary’s designee) as a persecuted group, and are at risk of forced migration, within or across the borders of Iraq, or Syria, or a country of first asylum, and the primary reasons for such risk.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6F6B51F68DE246348B903BB7E63F0B76"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The assistance provided by the United States to address humanitarian, stabilization, and recovery needs of individuals described in paragraph (1) and groups described in paragraph (3), including assistance to mitigate the risks of forced migration of such persons and groups from Iraq or Syria.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9615DD8EE2E74600B977230974E8F156"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The mechanisms of the United States Government to identify, assess, and respond to humanitarian, stabilization, and recovery needs, and risks of forced migration, of individuals described in paragraph (1) and groups described in paragraph (3).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H07C78822D5544F7494ED4741EE33A3C0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The assistance provided by or through the United Nations, including the Funding Facility for Immediate Stabilization and Funding Facility for Expanded Stabilization, to address humanitarian, stabilization, and recovery needs of individuals described in paragraph (1) and groups described in paragraph (3), including assistance to mitigate the risks of forced migration of such individuals and groups within or across the borders of Iraq, or Syria, or a country of first asylum from Iraq or Syria.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDF0F1327760943B99CBDF820A00D9D99"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The entities, including faith-based entities, that are providing assistance to address humanitarian, stabilization, and recovery needs of individuals described in paragraph (1) and groups described in paragraph (3).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H22CBBF889349480FAB3306218D417D96"><enum>(8)</enum><text>If the United States Government—</text> <subparagraph id="HE11249990A48423D9AEFDFC0416D0D01"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is funding entities described in paragraph (7) for purposes of providing assistance described in such paragraph, the sources of such funding; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A246F27F68E44A58587A4D4DA186D76"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not funding entities described in paragraph (7) for purposes of providing assistance described in such paragraph, a justification for not funding such entities, including whether funding such entities is prohibited under United States law.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0A034E4EBE014285BC5E9636951184B8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional consultation</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary of State shall consult with, and consider credible information from, individuals described in paragraph (1) of subsection (a) and entities described in paragraph (7) of such subsection.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H45209B7958594FF0BC4B1045F97581BE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Assistance</header><text>The Secretary of State and Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development shall provide assistance, including cash assistance, to support entities described in paragraph (7) of subsection (a) that the Secretary and Administrator determine are effectively providing assistance described in such paragraph, including entities that have received funding from the United States Government for such purposes before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB6BDB8A2C3E84C89A7C56C3A11AA97E2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that an appropriate amount of the additional amount made available under the heading <quote>Economic Support Fund</quote> in title II of division B of the Further Continuing and Security Assistance Appropriations Act, 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/254">Public Law 114–254</external-xref>) should be made available to carry out subsection (c).</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H0503C8C80E6548AB80EA63022B09C996" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>6.</enum><header>Refugee admissions of nationals and residents of Iraq or Syria</header>
 <subsection id="H0B807E1798C34894BD293A36E372AE99"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Aliens who are, or were, a national and a resident of Iraq or Syria, and who share common characteristics that identify them as targets of persecution on account of membership in a religious or ethnic minority in that country, in particular being survivors of genocide, crimes against humanity, or war crimes, or being the surviving spouse or child of an individual who was killed by a perpetrator of such a crime—</text>
 <paragraph id="H44EF3D6888BA45AAAC3E0AFD9334E2AE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are deemed to be of special humanitarian concern to the United States; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE8638B0BA30444EC8DE277F9818169A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall be eligible for Priority 2 processing under the refugee resettlement priority system.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1C649F912BD54679984048FA9E2EF2E6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>In-Country and out-of-Country processing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Aliens described in subsection (a) shall be allowed to apply, and interview, for admission to the United States through refugee processing mechanisms in countries where aliens may apply, and interview, for admission to the United States as refugees.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H45444CA7678248708F092ABC55BD7E7E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability of other requirements</header><text>Aliens who qualify under this section for Priority 2 processing under the refugee resettlement priority system may only be admitted to the United States after satisfying the requirements of section 207 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1157">8 U.S.C. 1157</external-xref>) and having cleared a background check and appropriate screening, as determined by the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H77C4056FF2674340BD292B733C580700"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Waiver of certain grounds of inadmissibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an alien described in subsection (a), the Secretary of State, after consultation with the Attorney General and the Secretary of Homeland Security, or the Secretary of Homeland Security, after consultation with the Secretary of State and the Attorney General, may waive, in such Secretary’s sole and unreviewable discretion, paragraph (3)(B) (other than clause (i)(II)) of section 212(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)</external-xref>) with respect to activities undertaken by such an alien in the course of avoiding or evading persecution by an organization described in section 212(a)(3)(B)(vi) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(3)(B)(vi)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H3CC3AF1A89444CBDA4EEC2C5D7EA9431"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Categorical eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Foreign Operations, Export Financing, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/101/167">Public Law 101–167</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7F09AA8FBEC8451496A0650A522AAEB9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 599D (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1157">8 U.S.C. 1157</external-xref> note)—</text> <subparagraph id="HB80B289E7D494740BE6E3E724B8BF3C1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(3), by striking <quote>and 2016</quote> and inserting <quote>2016, 2017, and 2018</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3B0D74320B84D459C1B237FC0628B09"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (e), by striking <quote>2016.</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>2018.</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H35817FE892024166B0504112651D9DE6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 599E(b)(2) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1255">8 U.S.C. 1255</external-xref> note), by striking <quote>2016,</quote> and inserting <quote>2018,</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA69EA917DC5D45108A7343CDB6040603"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section may be construed to lessen the protections under United States law for bona fide refugees who are not described in this section.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H2DC3E1A08610435E8AA4DEA4D60DD423"><enum>7.</enum><header>Reports</header>
 <subsection id="HD57ECDF35A244765A7338DC17041B4B8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Section 4(<enum-in-header>a</enum-in-header>) and (<enum-in-header>b</enum-in-header>) report</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H2197658683D647A09759321C06426D51"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A detailed description of the efforts taken, and efforts proposed to be taken, by the Secretary of State to implement section 4(a) and section 4(b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA1D037F9069F43FDBC99C66C96CEAF67"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An assessment of the feasibility and advisability of prosecuting individuals who are suspected to have committed genocide, crimes against humanity, or war crimes in Iraq since January 2014 or Syria since March 2011 in domestic courts in Iraq, hybrid courts, and internationalized domestic courts, and of the capacity-building, and other measures, needed to ensure effective criminal investigations of such individuals.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE2886093FFB94F28A44ACC55CEC00952"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Section 4(<enum-in-header>c</enum-in-header>) report</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H4FF2C84AF1C248FF9063D0F3F09C2764"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The results of the review conducted under section 4(c).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H366527EB55464F54B985EDFCA43811F7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Such recommendations for legislative and administrative actions to implement the results of the review as the Attorney General determines appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF64F5CD07EFE4A77978A8E281BD4581D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sections 5 and 6 report</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HA0DA34F747454DC1B233DFE3F4C32280"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A detailed description of the efforts taken, and efforts proposed to be taken, by the Secretary of State to implement section 5.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H10CDAE1502CD4721906567C8A3E2FCBD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A detailed description of the identifications under section 5(a).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H457923C32A5C4066907D7BA344368AF1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A detailed description of the efforts taken, and efforts proposed to be taken, by the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Homeland Security to implement section 6.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB3A10DEBB73A403B84D1FDEB72971419"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Form</header><text>Each report required under this section shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex if necessary.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


