<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H92D4952AE9724EC0B48251311B42D75A" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2653 IH: STEM Opportunities Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2653</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170525">May 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000523">Mr. Price of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000293">Ms. Esty of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000608">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000593">Mr. Perlmutter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000379">Mr. Kennedy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000563">Mr. Lipinski</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy to carry out programs and
			 activities to ensure that Federal science agencies and institutions of
			 higher education receiving Federal research and development funding are
			 fully engaging their entire talent pool, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H9564CF96825B4F0AB9B34E2D1FC107A1" style="OLC">
		<section id="H14F20CE35A5F49CBA5EE0565A08DD277" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; findings</header>
 <subsection id="H686011CAA485422F97F22002824A984A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>STEM Opportunities Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HFDEED542D6C746C9B5FC3CE21BFA7B8F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HAD08797B36F1490487E87802CD28CB69"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Many reports over the past decade have found that it is critical to our Nation’s economic leadership and global competitiveness that we educate and train more scientists and engineers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0461FAAB76B847D1A065CF1C5EAECBCD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Research shows that women and minorities who are interested in STEM careers are disproportionately lost at nearly every educational transition.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD77203809A37457D97F0EF8820E017DF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The National Center for Science and Engineering Statistics at the National Science Foundation collects, compiles, and publishes data on the demographics of STEM degrees and STEM jobs in the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H274481B7935E4609832C01A021B8639D"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Women now earn nearly 37 percent of all STEM bachelor’s degrees, but major variations persist among fields. In 2015, women earned only 19 percent of all bachelor’s degrees awarded in engineering and 18 percent in computer sciences. Based on Bureau of Labor Statistics data, jobs in computing occupations are expected to account for nearly <fraction>2/3</fraction> of the projected annual growth of newly created STEM job openings from 2014 to 2024.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBF8A00113564415988462E3B7841B4D4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In 2015, underrepresented minority groups comprised 39 percent of the college-age population of the United States, but only 17 percent of students earning bachelor’s degrees in STEM fields. The Higher Education Research Institute at the University of California, Los Angeles, found that, while freshmen from underrepresented minority groups express an interest in pursuing a STEM undergraduate degree at the same rate as all other freshmen, only 22.1 percent of Latino students, 18.4 percent of African-American students, and 18.8 percent of Native American students studying in STEM fields complete their degree within 5 years, compared to approximately 33 percent and 42 percent 5-year completion rate for White and Asian students, respectively.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC744DDF6B7874924AC110282993CDCA0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In some STEM fields, including the computer sciences, women persist at about the same rate through doctorate degrees. In other fields, including the physical sciences and mathematics, their numbers decrease by as much as 1 in 3. Overall, women earned 39 percent of STEM doctorate degrees in 2014. The number of minority students earning STEM doctorate degrees drops by nearly 40 percent. Students from underrepresented minority groups accounted for only 10.5 percent of STEM doctorate degrees awarded in 2014.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4D03A591E0764CA98A14359062C417C0"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The representation of women in STEM drops significantly again at the faculty level. Overall, women hold only 23 percent of all tenured and tenure-track positions and 24 percent of full professor positions in STEM fields in our Nation’s universities and 4-year colleges. Black and Hispanic faculty together hold about 6.4 percent of all tenured and tenure-track positions and 7 percent of full professor positions. Many of the numbers in the American Indian or Alaskan Native and Native Hawaiian or Other Pacific Islander categories for different faculty ranks were too small for the National Science Foundation to report publicly without potentially compromising confidential information about the individuals being surveyed.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H221F447BA18B474CA305E83B470DE39D"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The representation of women is especially low at our Nation’s top research universities. Even in the biological sciences, in which women now earn more than 50 percent of the doctorates and passed the 25 percent level 37 years ago, women make up only 25 percent of the full professors at the 100 or so most research-intensive universities. In the physical sciences and mathematics, they make up only 11 percent of these senior positions, in computer sciences only 10 percent, and across engineering fields only 7 percent. The data suggest that approximately 6 percent of all tenure-track STEM faculty members at the most research intensive universities are from underrepresented minority groups, but in some fields the numbers are too small to report publicly.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4618F1ACEC774005A31E3D6FE63F9405"><enum>(9)</enum><text>By 2050 underrepresented minorities will comprise 52 percent of the college-age population of the United States. If the percentage of female students and students from underrepresented minority groups earning bachelor’s degrees in STEM fields does not significantly increase, the United States will face an acute shortfall in the overall number of students who earn degrees in STEM fields just as United States companies are increasingly seeking students with those skills. With this impending shortfall, the United States will almost certainly lose its competitive edge in the 21st century global economy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9F49E9E5E7C04D8BADE8DD50817C8A99"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to a recent Association for Women in Science survey of over 4,000 scientists across the globe, 70 percent of whom were men, STEM researchers face significant challenges in work-life integration. Researchers in the United States were among the most likely to experience a conflict between work and their personal life at least weekly. One-third of researchers surveyed said that ensuring good work-life integration has negatively impacted their careers, and, of researchers intending to leave their current job within the next year, 9 percent indicated it was because they were unable to balance work and life demands.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H604318A612A943A78CDE875802A4FE42"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Female students and students from underrepresented minority groups at institutions of higher education who see few others ‘‘like themselves’’ among faculty and student populations often do not experience the social integration that is necessary for success in all disciplines, including STEM.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE425D410224F489180085FD0B2BC5495"><enum>(12)</enum><text>A substantial body of evidence establishes that most people hold implicit biases. Decades of cognitive psychology research reveal that most people carry prejudices of which they are unaware but that nonetheless play a large role in evaluations of people and their work. Unintentional biases and outmoded institutional structures are hindering the access and advancement of women and minorities in science and engineering.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H217691CAFB1E4950A1160C137BF40B4E"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Workshops held to educate faculty about unintentional biases have demonstrated success in raising awareness of such biases.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H424E8A29865A4DCB8D07285898022BC3"><enum>(14)</enum><text>In 2012 the National Aeronautics and Space Administration’s Office of Diversity and Equal Opportunity completed a report specifically designed to help NASA grant recipients identify why the dearth of women in STEM fields continues and to ensure that it is not due to discrimination. The report provides guidance to institutions of higher education on how to conduct meaningful self-evaluations of campus culture and policies. This report and its guidance are equally applicable to all institutions of higher education receiving significant Federal research funding.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4CFCAD3B3F004781818FA1CAE65746F0"><enum>(15)</enum><text>The Federal Government provides over 60 percent of research funding at institutions of higher education and, through its grant-making policies, has had significant influence on institution of higher education policies, including policies related to institutional culture and structure.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8014E5C4760D4DB480B1FE49C4987A56" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header>
 <subsection id="H9BD36928B90E4E3A8EFC8EC137717744"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director, acting through the Federal science agencies, shall carry out programs and activities with the purpose of ensuring that Federal science agencies and institutions of higher education receiving Federal research and development funding are fully engaging their entire talent pool.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H42A1C38479114DBF9E31567D7F37CC03"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this Act are as follows:</text> <paragraph id="HC27B6F35E14A4B19AF6B04D4D8EA1E63"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To promote research on and increase understanding of the participation and trajectories of women and underrepresented minorities in STEM careers at institutions of higher education and Federal science agencies, including Federal laboratories.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H75E3F0F61E7F4C829891CB6361080EB6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To raise awareness within Federal science agencies, including Federal laboratories, and institutions of higher education about cultural and institutional barriers limiting the recruitment, retention, promotion, and other indicators of participation and achievement of women and underrepresented minorities in academic and Government STEM research careers at all levels.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H21B0D23279584DBD967C2D3909893437"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To identify, disseminate, and implement best practices at Federal science agencies, including Federal laboratories, and at institutions of higher education to remove or reduce cultural and institutional barriers limiting the recruitment, retention, and success of women and underrepresented minorities in academic and Government STEM research careers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H41FBEF9E90FD42BE96333CE8ADA2A516"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To provide grants to institutions of higher education to recruit, retain, and advance STEM faculty members from underrepresented minority groups and to implement or expand reforms in undergraduate STEM education in order to increase the number of students from underrepresented minority groups receiving degrees in these fields.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HAD5353F78F414694BA8022564CEF4E25"><enum>3.</enum><header>Federal science agency policies for caregivers</header>
 <subsection id="H0A716B450C9F41429D528C6238AAAA6B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>OSTP guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall provide guidance to Federal science agencies to establish policies that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HCD22A327CA4540A1976C599E6226C237"><enum>(1)</enum><text>apply to all—</text> <subparagraph id="HA72D6D611E0641BC815267D972EFB278"><enum>(A)</enum><text>intramural and extramural research awards; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70BA30C353F54293ACAF40770455915E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">primary investigators who have caregiving responsibilities, including care for a newborn or newly adopted child and care for an immediate family member who is sick or disabled; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2480088FEB444363A6E72C129DF6CA9F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide—</text> <subparagraph id="HA44657A0736E49C99E7E1F0C26D82813"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">flexibility in timing for the initiation of approved research awards;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H52A1536773A141B9995D8C4AECB1679E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>no-cost extensions of research awards;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5736125978A041B882CB03DE08BFD058"><enum>(C)</enum><text>grant supplements as appropriate to research awards for research technicians or equivalent to sustain research activities; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA24FBD56DBEE467CA6A3290869C963CA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other appropriate accommodations at the discretion of the director of each agency.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8E339057F3D6499982A0F368BC066587"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Uniformity of guidance</header><text>In providing such guidance, the Director shall encourage uniformity and consistency in the policies across all agencies.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0A396EAAA6AD4AB68D44C25114B1B32A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Establishment of policies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consistent with the guidance provided under this section, Federal science agencies shall maintain or develop and implement policies for caregivers and shall broadly disseminate such policies to current and potential grantees.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9B917DB1027D4ABF96ED7918FF7DB009"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Data on usage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal science agencies shall—</text> <paragraph id="HE9815E1E93B142E6B9035A7E9F077C4A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>collect data on the usage of the policies under subsection (c), by gender, at both institutions of higher education and Federal laboratories; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8665CDAC309948C3A7E371835E9B0FC8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>report such data on an annual basis to the Director in such form as required by the Director.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6E453049884446C98F4E548B48E1FAD0"><enum>4.</enum><header>Collection and reporting of data on Federal research grants</header> <subsection id="H5F12DD4018724D778B17E779F33A0490"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Collection of data</header> <paragraph id="H51AABF59C1D045248793F87DB4F20660"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each Federal science agency shall collect standardized record-level annual information on demographics, primary field, award type, review rating (as practicable), budget request, funding outcome, and awarded budget for all applications for merit-reviewed research and development grants to institutions of higher education and Federal laboratories supported by that agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF75EF6D37EAC41D5BD26D767C8C24725"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Uniformity and standardization</header><text>The Director shall establish a policy to ensure uniformity and standardization of the data collection required under paragraph (1).</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H003F2960CE104E708A261576925E96ED"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Record-level data</header>
 <subparagraph id="HBD6DED4A191C4089A22731B3A5FDBEA4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>On an annual basis, beginning with the deadline under subparagraph (C), each Federal science agency shall submit to the Director of the National Science Foundation record-level data collected under paragraph (1) in the form required by such Director.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6246E32F263455CBC23C1F8BAC69D72"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Previous data</header><text>As part of the first submission under subparagraph (A), each Federal science agency, to the extent practicable, shall also submit comparable record-level data for the 5 years preceding the deadline under subparagraph (C).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H395507B1DA0945928425AA343C00050F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>The deadline under this paragraph is a date that is not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE5521E8DE1E94A12B102CF4D9CF69A6D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reporting of data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Science Foundation shall publish statistical summary data collected under this section, disaggregated and cross-tabulated by race, ethnicity, gender, age, and years since completion of doctoral degree, including in conjunction with the National Science Foundation’s report required by section 37 of the Science and Technology Equal Opportunities Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1885d">42 U.S.C. 1885d</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/96/516">Public Law 96–516</external-xref>).</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H6D7DAE6DD06F4F23AADDB8531BE5F630"><enum>5.</enum><header>Policies for review of Federal research grants</header>
 <subsection id="H1C81E882E93F4F4183885B2BED85A3E1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director, in collaboration with the interagency working group on inclusion in STEM, shall identify information and best practices useful for educating program officers and members of standing peer review committees at Federal science agencies about—</text>
 <paragraph id="H777E387316434403B366E46F027FD0A8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>research on implicit bias based on gender, race, or ethnicity; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6929E99345D244BBBE450C3331BFA6A6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>methods to minimize the effect of such bias in the review of extramural and intramural Federal research grants.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H015716B9869B41DDA1FA8C0316945AC8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Guidance to all Federal science agencies</header><text>The Director shall disseminate the information and best practices identified in subsection (a) to all Federal science agencies and provide guidance as necessary on policies to implement such practices within each agency.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H400A0817C35A445E8BE9360819236616"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Pilot program at Federal science agencies</header><text>In consultation with the National Science Foundation and consistent with guidance provided in subsection (b), each Federal science agency shall implement a 2-year pilot orientation activity for program officers and members of standing review committees to educate reviewers and mitigate the effects of implicit bias in the review of extramural and intramural Federal research grants.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H29695C03049641B5BAD65EE6AF1E3431"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Establishment of policies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Drawing upon lessons learned from the pilot activity in subsection (c), Federal science agencies shall maintain or develop and implement policies and practices to minimize the effects of implicit bias in the review of extramural and intramural Federal research grants.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBBDC9B91AD0B4EB8A3F1BB8DF9629575"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Assessment of policies</header><text>Federal science agencies shall regularly assess and amend as necessary the policies and practices in subsection (d) to ensure effective measures are in place to minimize the impact of implicit bias on the grant review process.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H80024357945A400BBEEDEE28C045D5D2"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 4 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall report to Congress on what steps all Federal science agencies have taken to implement policies and practices to minimize the effects of bias in the review of extramural and intramural Federal research grants.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HBE7AD7CE85024D2590142E1B5B7635DC"><enum>6.</enum><header>Collection of data on demographics of faculty</header>
			<subsection id="H776461F0E57C434498F362F4E70B6070"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Collection of data</header>
 <paragraph id="HF45773BA8A0A4AD1A40187A9947A7F45"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and at least every 5 years thereafter, the Director of the National Science Foundation shall carry out a survey to collect institution-level data on the demographics of STEM faculty, by broad fields of STEM, at different types of institutions of higher education.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H80CD885846FC46568B92133F8724B3A6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>To the extent practicable, the Director of the National Science Foundation shall consider, by gender, race, ethnicity, citizenship status, age, and years since completion of doctoral degree—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3CA12B3A66F949079A0ACBB979E6E96F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number and percentage of faculty;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFBDF861913E48DB8521942A0022A4D2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number and percentage of faculty at each rank;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H91278C95ADA54B2497FC9145410BB17E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number and percentage of faculty who are in nontenure-track positions, including teaching and research;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8DE4AE23A5A34311862B518225915D10"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number and percentage of faculty who are reviewed for promotion, including tenure, and the percentage of that number who are promoted, including being awarded tenure;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H792A00758D3C4AE092C65E067D1B68C2"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">faculty years in rank;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83E7072A8DBD44AAB3E9F690513C2A14"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number and percentage of faculty to leave tenure-track positions;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A29E44F45BE44B9A24202FCB0D0080B"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number and percentage of faculty hired, by rank; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H428ACFC915F44E1B83B303BA85FC5451"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number and percentage of faculty in leadership positions.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H38F85214A47F43D9A00A77BA73735FE4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Existing surveys</header><text>The Director of the National Science Foundation—</text> <paragraph id="HE0206F399B7D49AA9F583C3871FAD9A5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may carry out the requirements under <internal-xref idref="H776461F0E57C434498F362F4E70B6070" legis-path="6.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref> by collaborating with statistical centers at other Federal agencies to modify or expand, as necessary, existing Federal surveys of higher education; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H98DAB11AB25249D78311696D707643C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may award a grant or contract to an institution of higher education or other nonprofit organization to design and carry out the requirements under <internal-xref idref="H776461F0E57C434498F362F4E70B6070" legis-path="6.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0103C0B87569448F88000C409EB2317C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reporting data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Science Foundation shall publish statistical summary data collected under this section, including as part of the National Science Foundation’s report required by section 37 of the Science and Technology Equal Opportunities Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1885d">42 U.S.C. 1885d</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/96/516">Public Law 96–516</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H233FBF3400E24344BE810755A6AFA5C3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Director of the National Science Foundation $3,000,000 in each of fiscal years 2018 through 2020 to develop and carry out the initial survey required in <internal-xref idref="H776461F0E57C434498F362F4E70B6070" legis-path="6.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HE6C60762EF784D4CB1ED714BBC752DDD"><enum>7.</enum><header>Cultural and institutional barriers to expanding the academic and Federal STEM workforce</header>
			<subsection id="H6A3F37FAA61D444A85D45B96C21C9BCF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Best practices at institutions of higher education</header>
 <paragraph id="HB25194F33D66412680229ED725E6D036"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Development of guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the National Science Foundation shall develop written guidance for institutions of higher education on the best practices for—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC0AE3CFD6DD7444687C56E241518E30C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conducting periodic campus culture surveys of STEM departments, with a particular focus on identifying any cultural or institutional barriers to or successful enablers for the recruitment, retention, promotion, and other indicators of participation and achievement, of women and underrepresented minorities in STEM degree programs and academic STEM careers; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2518051E4634EACB13B95BAA312576D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>providing educational opportunities, including workshops as described in <internal-xref idref="H139D7AFE60D04703A2E32048076C3219" legis-path="7.(c)">subsection (c)</internal-xref>, for STEM faculty and administrators to learn about current research on implicit bias in recruitment, evaluation, and promotion of faculty in STEM and recruitment and evaluation of undergraduate and graduate students in STEM degree programs.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2770B198C61043D0B7066517650DD5B7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Existing guidance</header><text>In developing the guidance in <internal-xref idref="HB25194F33D66412680229ED725E6D036" legis-path="7.(a)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref>, the Director of the National Science Foundation shall utilize guidance already developed by the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the Department of Energy, and the Department of Education.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF3A9E3D9248148A380DA65396EB565BE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Dissemination of guidance</header><text>The Director of the National Science Foundation shall broadly disseminate the guidance developed in <internal-xref idref="HB25194F33D66412680229ED725E6D036" legis-path="7.(a)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref> to institutions of higher education that receive Federal research funding.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H394E4D2CD0CC43349990384409524725"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reports to the National Science Foundation</header><text>The Director of the National Science Foundation shall develop a policy that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDFD83D62BE8B4EBE9E2F90B9A646423C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">applies to, at a minimum, the institutions classified under the Indiana University Center for Postsecondary Research Carnegie Classification on January 1, 2015, as a doctorate-granting university with a very high level of research activity; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7FA47C27AA7A4C75AE0C285A613227E6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>requires each institution identified in <internal-xref idref="HDFD83D62BE8B4EBE9E2F90B9A646423C" legis-path="7.(a)(4)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref>, not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, to report to the Director of the National Science Foundation on activities and policies developed and implemented based on the guidance provided in <internal-xref idref="HB25194F33D66412680229ED725E6D036" legis-path="7.(a)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref>.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE9C7A09B88F1414B97D0C1F59AFAF971"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Best practices at Federal laboratories</header>
 <paragraph id="HC45476437781495982FD5E1FAD44C8C8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Development of guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall develop written guidance for Federal laboratories to develop and implement practices and policies to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2240269196B242479551B7EA11AFAB99"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct periodic laboratory-wide culture surveys of research personnel at all levels, with a particular focus on identifying any cultural or institutional barriers to the recruitment, retention, and success of women and underrepresented minorities in STEM careers at Federal laboratories; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB77222D16F634EC694F43A4F3D4A2D60"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide educational opportunities, including workshops as described in <internal-xref idref="H139D7AFE60D04703A2E32048076C3219" legis-path="7.(c)">subsection (c)</internal-xref>, for STEM research personnel to learn about current research in implicit bias in recruitment, evaluation, and promotion of research personnel at Federal laboratories.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB446EF283D6C4FC08DD2633DC1586A00"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Establishment of policies</header><text>Consistent with the guidance provided in <internal-xref idref="HC45476437781495982FD5E1FAD44C8C8" legis-path="7.(b)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref>, Federal science agencies with Federal laboratories shall maintain or develop and implement policies for their respective Federal laboratories.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H139D7AFE60D04703A2E32048076C3219"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Workshops To address cultural barriers To expanding the academic and Federal STEM workforce</header>
 <paragraph id="H3512AC50C9F14918BF0137137E98AE1B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director, in consultation with the interagency working group on inclusion in STEM, shall recommend a uniform policy for Federal science agencies to carry out a program of workshops that educate STEM department chairs at institutions of higher education, senior managers at Federal laboratories, and other federally funded researchers about methods that minimize the effects of implicit bias in the career advancement, including hiring, tenure, promotion, and selection for any honor based in part on the recipient’s research record, of academic and Federal STEM researchers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8BFC21EB29834B5E83456C9C66188829"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Interagency coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall ensure that workshops supported under this subsection are coordinated across Federal science agencies and jointly supported as appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA9F4CDB53AC6492FAA907EA69DCAF448"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Minimizing costs</header><text>To the extent practicable, workshops shall be held in conjunction with national or regional STEM disciplinary meetings to minimize costs associated with participant travel.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4DF1E488814640D7857FFAC12AB8263D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Priority fields for academic participants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In considering the participation of STEM department chairs and other academic researchers, the Director shall prioritize workshops for the broad fields of STEM in which the national rate of representation of women among tenured or tenure-track faculty or non-faculty researchers at doctorate-granting institutions of higher education is less than 25 percent, according to the most recent data available from the National Center for Science and Engineering Statistics.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H86FB34F84B614BF9B18F85463398966E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Organizations eligible to carry out workshops</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal science agencies may carry out the program of workshops under this subsection by making grants to eligible organizations. In addition to any other organizations made eligible by the Federal science agencies, the following organizations are eligible for grants under this subsection:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF397F56736794C3092A391E7C5A7A24E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Nonprofit scientific and professional societies and organizations that represent one or more STEM disciplines.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB531BE6BDDF04DFEA021BE36FB71AF0F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Nonprofit organizations that have the primary mission of advancing the participation of women or underrepresented minorities in STEM.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H28E58B489C4A4F5DAC29F25EFC273F25"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Characteristics of workshops</header><text>The workshops shall have the following characteristics:</text> <subparagraph id="HC941A52A9F5F45E09ECFC6AE7F9E3EB8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Invitees to workshops shall include at least—</text>
 <clause id="H515B153680D84B1CBD745C29E0FCB88F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the chairs of departments in the relevant STEM discipline or disciplines from at least the top 50 institutions of higher education, as determined by the amount of Federal research and development funds obligated to each institution of higher education in the prior year based on data available from the National Science Foundation; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H805428ABA6D04C6FB72A02967E2DC150"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of Federal laboratories, individuals with personnel management responsibilities comparable to those of an institution of higher education department chair.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H95C663FF38464FA3B06A206EF86EF3B3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Activities at the workshops shall include research presentations and interactive discussions or other activities that increase the awareness of the existence of implicit bias in recruitment, hiring, tenure review, promotion, and other forms of formal recognition of individual achievement for faculty and other federally funded STEM researchers and shall provide strategies to overcome such bias.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H412C3E16A8D04D288B1B251866E6C13D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Research presentations and other workshop programs, as appropriate, shall include a discussion of the unique challenges faced by underrepresented sub-groups, including minority women, minority men, and first generation minority graduates in research.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1E2D3C4F5BA489A99A4380EE555B32B"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Workshop programs shall include information on best practices for mentoring undergraduate and graduate women and underrepresented minority students.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H79D0236A550247CF8CBD44ECE8E11D08"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Data on workshops</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any proposal for funding by an organization seeking to carry out a workshop under this subsection shall include a description of how such organization will—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7132348A00834E08BCA0A838CEDFC7DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>collect data on the rates of attendance by invitees in workshops, including information on the home institution and department of attendees, and the rank of faculty attendees;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56FD7C6867024B7DB739905FDF3EF949"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conduct attitudinal surveys on workshop attendees before and after the workshops; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0C1CECCA8C446BDB2205FC4B9A74792"><enum>(C)</enum><text>collect follow-up data on any relevant institutional policy or practice changes reported by attendees not later than one year after attendance in such a workshop.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0607BC606144E75BDE3D029E13543ED"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Report to NSF</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Organizations receiving funding to carry out workshops under this subsection shall report the data required in <internal-xref idref="H79D0236A550247CF8CBD44ECE8E11D08" legis-path="7.(c)(7)">paragraph (7)</internal-xref> to the Director of the National Science Foundation in such form as required by such Director.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC476F20F0C2A49D483F6971B03056E15"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 4 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the National Science Foundation shall submit a report to Congress that includes—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4C4929366E4B4B93A83FF355BE4AF252"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary and analysis of the types and frequency of activities and policies developed and carried out under <internal-xref idref="H6A3F37FAA61D444A85D45B96C21C9BCF" legis-path="7.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref> based on the reports submitted under paragraph (4) of such subsection; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7DF35048071143FC8694EAFFE38737CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description and evaluation of the status and effectiveness of the program of workshops required under <internal-xref idref="H139D7AFE60D04703A2E32048076C3219" legis-path="7.(c)">subsection (c)</internal-xref>, including a summary of any data reported under paragraph (8) of such subsection.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H737612B560DE4D37827EB3AEB9B3FE24"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Director of the National Science Foundation $2,000,000 in each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022 to carry out this section.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H2C98AAC46DB2412396B4094F34BC37EB"><enum>8.</enum><header>Research and dissemination at the National Science Foundation</header>
 <subsection id="H40ADA24880F948C1B8633B0C5467FCA8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Science Foundation shall award research grants and carry out dissemination activities consistent with the purposes of this Act, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC9B91507A6E94CB191A0B9975AD4C67B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>research grants to analyze the record-level data collected under <internal-xref idref="H6E453049884446C98F4E548B48E1FAD0" legis-path="4.">section 4</internal-xref> and <internal-xref idref="HBE7AD7CE85024D2590142E1B5B7635DC" legis-path="6.">section 6</internal-xref>, consistent with policies to ensure the privacy of individuals identifiable by such data;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H57D1BCC0617B45C3AF0FA58EC7DB7347"><enum>(2)</enum><text>research grants to study best practices for work-life accommodation;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2455470D0D8042D0BA53A67E24EA4EAB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>research grants to study the impact of policies and practices that are implemented under this Act or that are otherwise consistent with the purposes of this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB777B5D2FAEF45C599A39447182A4EE1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collaboration with other Federal science agencies and professional associations to exchange best practices, harmonize work-life accommodation policies and practices, and overcome common barriers to work-life accommodation;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF056A37E0F194FEBAA9B4461B17892EC"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collaboration with institutions of higher education in order to clarify and catalyze the adoption of a coherent and consistent set of work-life accommodation policies and practices; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4F4AD300FD6F434882187B02B5DE5583"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">research grants to study the use of standardized graduate student admission exams and its impact on the recruitment, retention, and success of women, underrepresented minorities, and first generation graduates in graduate STEM degree programs.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7F96C4E0BCC94E92AF6D49FDE02CED2F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Director of the National Science Foundation $5,000,000 in each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022 to carry out this section.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H5CED0837798A458A920D734557F1DAC5"><enum>9.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 4 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall submit a report to Congress that includes—</text>
 <paragraph id="H59A9A3D4189244D8BD3F0DDC1AD2E066"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description and evaluation of the status and usage of caregiver policies at all Federal science agencies, including any recommendations for revising or expanding such policies;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7574157A9D324C1684C58B6A0F73555D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of any significant updates to the policies for review of Federal research grants required under <internal-xref idref="H6D7DAE6DD06F4F23AADDB8531BE5F630" legis-path="5.">section 5</internal-xref>, and any evidence of the impact of such policies on the review or awarding of Federal research grants; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H096C73470CFE4B44AD3C4C9D458B8743"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description and evaluation of the status of Federal laboratory policies and practices required under <internal-xref idref="HE9C7A09B88F1414B97D0C1F59AFAF971" legis-path="7.(b)">section 7(b)</internal-xref>, including any recommendations for revising or expanding such policies.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HE70F6A29589D44459DEE886A3817769D"><enum>10.</enum><header>National Science Foundation support for increasing diversity among STEM faculty at institutions of
			 higher education</header>
 <subsection id="H28D4442B7421483FB9C93DE85C444B6F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants</header><text>The Director of the National Science Foundation shall award grants to institutions of higher education (or consortia thereof) for the development of innovative reform efforts designed to increase the recruitment, retention, and advancement of individuals from underrepresented minority groups in academic STEM careers.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8F5D2AD1408B4E0E8AD9379E4C14D798"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Merit review; competition</header><text>Grants shall be awarded under this section on a merit-reviewed, competitive basis.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H08399B69C46B4E2A976C2FCA1D7FC4A2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Activities supported by grants under this section may include—</text>
 <paragraph id="H706B4D0489474FFBB64A4326F2DA7264"><enum>(1)</enum><text>institutional assessment activities, such as data analyses and policy review, in order to identify and address specific issues in the recruitment, retention, and advancement of faculty members from underrepresented minority groups;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H85CF01B1C86A4C4086D046D15E77C12F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">implementation of institution-wide improvements in workload distribution, such that faculty members from underrepresented minority groups are not disadvantaged in the amount of time available to focus on research, publishing papers, and engaging in other activities required to achieve tenure status and run a productive research program;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFC2065E9B2EF47FEBA94178F260B1542"><enum>(3)</enum><text>development and implementation of training courses for administrators and search committee members to ensure that candidates from underrepresented minority groups are not subject to implicit biases in the search and hiring process;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7E077CFCBD3D410394EBDAAC3A2FEBA2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>development and hosting of intra- or inter-institutional workshops to propagate best practices in recruiting, retaining, and advancing faculty members from underrepresented minority groups;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H68EB3B6903834C28A5C3DA9A4B73E844"><enum>(5)</enum><text>professional development opportunities for faculty members from underrepresented minority groups;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H70FFAE718F50461E92154B5CCDE843D5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>activities aimed at making undergraduate STEM students from underrepresented minority groups aware of opportunities for academic careers in STEM fields;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2851C597578948A0B83A8793ABE8DE08"><enum>(7)</enum><text>activities to identify and engage exceptional graduate students from underrepresented minority groups at various stages of their studies and to encourage them to enter academic careers; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H284AD05DA14D45F897732732CA3643AE"><enum>(8)</enum><text>other activities consistent with <internal-xref idref="H28D4442B7421483FB9C93DE85C444B6F" legis-path="10.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>, as determined by the Director of the National Science Foundation.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H451EDDA43ABE4C99B271D66B82F4CDA7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Selection process</header> <paragraph id="HA1FA8B09507A477A82C4829488D7225A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An institution of higher education (or consortia thereof) seeking funding under this section shall submit an application to the Director of the National Science Foundation at such time, in such manner, and containing such information and assurances as such Director may require. The application shall include, at a minimum, a description of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6FDF93760D234FABB44C78BB390DD380"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the reform effort that is being proposed for implementation by the institution of higher education;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE642FF0603E49C6A54A0B0E46C4996A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any available evidence of specific difficulties in the recruitment, retention, and advancement of faculty members from underrepresented minority groups in STEM academic careers within the institution of higher education submitting an application, and how the proposed reform effort would address such issues;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0DDA0E44899E4916BF6B0A99B04FCE31"><enum>(C)</enum><text>how the institution of higher education submitting an application plans to sustain the proposed reform effort beyond the duration of the grant; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD02BFFAA1A5A4BC483372351FC84E751"><enum>(D)</enum><text>how the success and effectiveness of the proposed reform effort will be evaluated and assessed in order to contribute to the national knowledge base about models for catalyzing institutional change.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H82F4697328F143E2A0D86CC2D1633294"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review of applications</header><text>In selecting grant recipients under this section, the Director of the National Science Foundation shall consider, at a minimum—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H67D10A534C1E436AA75DBB8F66C13C7E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the likelihood of success in undertaking the proposed reform effort at the institution of higher education submitting the application, including the extent to which the administrators of the institution are committed to making the proposed reform effort a priority;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE41424E74F104C9589D57CACF485CABE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the degree to which the proposed reform effort will contribute to change in institutional culture and policy such that greater value is placed on the recruitment, retention, and advancement of faculty members from underrepresented minority groups;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8862E6403FC149EBA9B3496A3A5CB890"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the likelihood that the institution of higher education will sustain or expand the proposed reform effort beyond the period of the grant; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08D604DFA94549D0822EED399FD4A284"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the degree to which evaluation and assessment plans are included in the design of the proposed reform effort.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9FE68E0059143C09B8B9D27759F765E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Grant distribution</header><text>The Director of the National Science Foundation shall ensure, to the extent practicable, that grants awarded under this section are made to a variety of types of institutions of higher education.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBBBA095FFE1342DDB08CEAF145C4B489"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Director of the National Science Foundation $10,000,000 in each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022 to carry out this section.</text>
			</subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF19B614A420C4BE68D963783A3705D3F"><enum>11.</enum><header>National Science Foundation support for broadening participation in undergraduate STEM education</header>
 <subsection id="HE2076B116F364383B25C1372DF923322"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants</header><text>The Director of the National Science Foundation shall award grants to institutions of higher education (or consortia thereof) to implement or expand research-based reforms in undergraduate STEM education for the purpose of recruiting and retaining students from minority groups who are underrepresented in STEM fields, with a priority focus on natural science and engineering fields.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC9087EBC963647019E71E716C912DFC8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Merit review; competition</header><text>Grants shall be awarded under this section on a merit-reviewed, competitive basis.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HC65BB2A363A14466A5FBE9248B285E9B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Activities supported by grants under this section may include—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB5E44794847B4BBBA64E4C82D8C43CA7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>implementation or expansion of innovative, research-based approaches to broaden participation of underrepresented minority groups in STEM fields;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H873164012BC54DF3A559D8E8590C6544"><enum>(2)</enum><text>implementation or expansion of bridge, cohort, tutoring, or mentoring programs designed to enhance the recruitment and retention of students from underrepresented minority groups in STEM fields;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H72F452A4B1E2425C9DD597CCDE4C045F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>implementation or expansion of outreach programs linking institutions of higher education and K–12 school systems in order to heighten awareness among pre-college students from underrepresented minority groups of opportunities in college-level STEM fields and STEM careers;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H338DA4437C964C339E8B347BE536855D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>implementation or expansion of faculty development programs focused on improving retention of undergraduate STEM students from underrepresented minority groups;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBE2F87F943394515A6B351866D4D4A48"><enum>(5)</enum><text>implementation or expansion of mechanisms designed to recognize and reward faculty members who demonstrate a commitment to increasing the participation of students from underrepresented minority groups in STEM fields;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4F48F9BD03D6481E9C8884F0E0CBF7FE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>expansion of successful reforms aimed at increasing the number of STEM students from underrepresented minority groups beyond a single course or group of courses to achieve reform within an entire academic unit, or expansion of successful reform efforts beyond a single academic unit to other STEM academic units within an institution of higher education;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB9CD9A0F92D5445792BA205A0CAABBE8"><enum>(7)</enum><text>expansion of opportunities for students from underrepresented minority groups to conduct STEM research in industry, at Federal labs, and at international research institutions or research sites;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H41F17AFA014A472A800E5A4D86A8DA6D"><enum>(8)</enum><text>provision of stipends for students from underrepresented minority groups participating in research;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2C67DCC3B15E4E59BE8F5C2D7C3C1CBE"><enum>(9)</enum><text>development of research collaborations between research-intensive universities and primarily undergraduate minority-serving institutions;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H13C409824CBE4D89919AAA2BA7FD6897"><enum>(10)</enum><text>support for graduate students and post­doctoral fellows from underrepresented minority groups to participate in instructional or assessment activities at primarily undergraduate institutions, including primarily undergraduate minority-serving institutions and two-year institutions of higher education; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF7047676F4EA443B9EF34EDBC4BDCAE5"><enum>(11)</enum><text>other activities consistent with <internal-xref idref="HE2076B116F364383B25C1372DF923322" legis-path="11.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>, as determined by the Director of the National Science Foundation.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2C4C9289DB5C4316AB12D8066BE8DFA5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Selection process</header> <paragraph id="H53D906CE867B43469237D81D1303B484"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An institution of higher education (or consortia thereof) seeking a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Director of the National Science Foundation at such time, in such manner, and containing such information and assurances as such Director may require. The application shall include, at a minimum—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE64D0BF75A054FA5B9DB85D82E0230D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the proposed reform effort;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HACED06A316434D0FB31A0E491A9000F5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of the research findings that will serve as the basis for the proposed reform effort or, in the case of applications that propose an expansion of a previously implemented reform, a description of the previously implemented reform effort, including data about the recruitment, retention, and academic achievement of students from underrepresented minority groups;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97A62137F6744E159CC7FE5219FF5F3A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>evidence of an institutional commitment to, and support for, the proposed reform effort, including a long-term commitment to implement successful strategies from the current reform beyond the academic unit or units included in the grant proposal;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H277B1570CB9F4263812B2F940125A2B0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a description of existing or planned institutional policies and practices regarding faculty hiring, promotion, tenure, and teaching assignment that reward faculty contributions to improving the education of students from underrepresented minority groups in STEM; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE899485BCA194B2DBC28EDF4853D070D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>how the success and effectiveness of the proposed reform effort will be evaluated and assessed in order to contribute to the national knowledge base about models for catalyzing institutional change.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H498381F87C0744DDAF1C832157ED226E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review of applications</header><text>In selecting grant recipients under this section, the Director of the National Science Foundation shall consider, at a minimum—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE65D211A4D5D464E83C2B4559FB58EC9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the likelihood of success of the proposed reform effort at the institution submitting the application, including the extent to which the faculty, staff, and administrators of the institution are committed to making the proposed institutional reform a priority of the participating academic unit or units;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05506C126F454D9EAD46C53929AF64B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the degree to which the proposed reform effort will contribute to change in institutional culture and policy such that greater value is placed on faculty engagement in the retention of students from underrepresented minority groups;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1727706C138C4FF4B36B3596C2736CAF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the likelihood that the institution will sustain or expand the proposed reform effort beyond the period of the grant; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H346052E52D734296BE6E9024A67504A6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the degree to which evaluation and assessment plans are included in the design of the proposed reform effort.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EA0C9CE43654EB084569131E315C547"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>For applications that include an expansion of existing reforms beyond a single academic unit, the Director of the National Science Foundation shall give priority to applications for which a senior institutional administrator, such as a dean or other administrator of equal or higher rank, serves as the principal investigator.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9B94EF9A4CA649BC8C1A414DB7B7A566"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Grant distribution</header><text>The Director of the National Science Foundation shall ensure, to the extent practicable, that grants awarded under this section are made to a variety of types of institutions of higher education, including two-year and minority-serving institutions of higher education.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H85EED4F6C28B46F5B8C64B19BA226CC6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Education research</header>
 <paragraph id="HF2058E4F1B7B4921A6477E8D61EA563F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>All grants made under this section shall include an education research component that will support the design and implementation of a system for data collection and evaluation of proposed reform efforts in order to build the knowledge base on promising models for increasing recruitment and retention of students from underrepresented minority groups in STEM education at the undergraduate level across a diverse set of institutions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H82F33AAEC79C4E0982B856981DB8503B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Dissemination</header><text>The Director of the National Science Foundation shall coordinate with relevant Federal agencies in disseminating the results of the research under this subsection to ensure that best practices in broadening participation in STEM education at the undergraduate level are made readily available to all institutions of higher education, other Federal agencies that support STEM programs, non-Federal funders of STEM education, and the general public.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7C17E9C94CAD4150A6AC05346CE6A73C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Director of the National Science Foundation $15,000,000 in each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022 to carry out this section.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H93E45F7F170F4300BACC3A7E5D513021"><enum>12.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HEAB566AB08704104AF8C9E095DABE35E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Director</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy (<quote>OSTP</quote>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0E2AE968FF0A4EE794CCE4C38E6E9B08"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal laboratory</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Federal laboratory</term> has the meaning given such term in section 4 of the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3703">15 U.S.C. 3703</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H471FFA98465B4AFD8C1ABB21B8C80BA0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federal science agency</header><text>The term <term>Federal science agency</term> means any Federal agency with at least $100,000,000 in research and development expenditures in fiscal year 2016.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB892031704E940BDAEC919745329AAE5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0E070A92D4424E7893D260B27771B39F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Interagency working group on inclusion in STEM</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>interagency working group on inclusion in STEM</quote> means the interagency working group established by section 308 of the American Innovation and Competitiveness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6626">42 U.S.C. 6626</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA311D11EBB334004BF41F9CE10BB6E09"><enum>(6)</enum><header>STEM</header><text>The term <term>STEM</term> means the academic and professional disciplines of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


