<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H95896A2AA16C478D87DA2A30847ADF57" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4143 IH: Dialysis Patient Access To Integrated-care, Empowerment, Nephrologists, Treatment, and Services Demonstration Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4143</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171026">October 26, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001195">Mr. Smith of Missouri</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001159">Mrs. McMorris Rodgers</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a demonstration program to provide integrated care for Medicare beneficiaries with
			 end-stage renal disease, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H0F7DBCEF7C514CC3B81F133CB830FBB4" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE183121D283045638323547CCCB81C4A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Dialysis Patient Access To Integrated-care, Empowerment, Nephrologists, Treatment, and Services Demonstration Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Dialysis PATIENTS Demonstration Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="H391AE21C71F1442E856326E58AE777DF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Demonstration program to provide integrated care for Medicare beneficiaries with end-stage renal
			 disease</header>
 <subsection id="H5A970A0413ED4FC7BE4FC6988283E3E0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title XVIII of the Social Security Act is amended by inserting after section 1866E the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HC5072A465E57491AB27EB824E9DD24D0" style="traditional">
					<section id="HEF8B69FF554A4BAAB28C4703AED63A12"><enum>1866F.</enum><header>Demonstration program to provide integrated care for Medicare beneficiaries with end-stage renal
			 disease</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC9D189C8C4234871B045EF032AE86E47"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header>
 <paragraph id="H1F1161C95750481B98E09508F63DE2E0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall conduct under this section the ESRD Integrated Care Demonstration Program (in this section referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>) which is voluntary for patients and providers to assess the effects of alternative care delivery models and payment methodologies on patient care improvements under this title for Program-eligible beneficiaries (as defined in paragraph (2)). Under the Program—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H813FBAAB92DD40268729E9BA1320EEB2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Program-eligible beneficiaries shall be considered enrolled under the original Medicare fee-for-service program under parts A and B;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7C46D2AAB5046C7A7DC932CE1D34A6B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">eligible participating providers (as defined in such paragraph) may form an ESRD Integrated Care Organization (in this section referred to as an <quote>Organization</quote>); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F80DC535A5C422395949A40611421F5"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an Organization shall integrate care and serve as the medical home under the original medicare fee-for-service program under parts A and B for Program-eligible beneficiaries.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H22315BAE838342FB93CA2FA100549CE3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <subparagraph id="H853A0E0BDA394CA1BE00737EA6E47247"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Eligible participating provider</header><text>The term <term>eligible participating provider</term> means the following:</text>
 <clause id="H9117263027194F208ED4DDC15366EDC8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A facility certified as a renal dialysis facility under this title.</text> </clause><clause id="H7BAD6A416CB744AB914553378C36DA1C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A dialysis organization that owns one or more of such facilities described in clause (i).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9C2BAB605F5C428F85B788461E910E8C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A nephrologist or nephrology practice.</text> </clause><clause id="HE3BF2CD9DA4647CAAC874615A0BDF5F2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Any other physician group practice or a group of affiliated physicians or providers.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H117EA8B9841F4640A4D5873C4E56E5BF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligible participating partner</header><text>The term <term>eligible participating partner</term> means, with respect to an Organization, the following:</text> <clause id="H1CADB622CE7C4A11B9B75EFB249DB334"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A Medicare Advantage plan described in section 1851(a)(2) or a Medicare Advantage organization offering such a plan.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA7E9C2A44D674FCFA48E42BA726AECB7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A prescription drug plan (as defined in section 1860D–41(a)(14)).</text> </clause><clause id="H560D32DF72FB438CB276723ACC5796E1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A medicaid managed care organization (as defined in section 1903(m)).</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA8772187FC734410895F33DF68B898A7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>An entity that is able to bear risk as deemed by a State, including public medical educational institutions experienced in the care of patients receiving dialysis, and that chooses to bear risk as a condition of partnership in such organization.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBD7DA4992C2A4BBCAAF4186AD1658DFE"><enum>(v)</enum><text>A third-party administrator organization.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74BE8A74E62741209D1C84BA0C85EAC3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Program-eligible beneficiary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Program-eligible beneficiary</term> means, with respect to an Organization offering an ESRD Integrated Care Model, an individual entitled to benefits under part A and enrolled under part B who—</text>
 <clause id="H767FD1C170D14DE3ADE49E36C688482A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is identified by the Secretary or the Organization as receiving renal dialysis services under the original medicare fee-for-service program under parts A and B;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2E982CB1A8F649A5816C1A3AA9429BA6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>resides in the service area of such Organization;</text> </clause><clause id="HD6B24EA294054302A59FC8F52CBB1087"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>receives renal dialysis services primarily from a facility that participates in such Organization;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H683422FCD024495A9290BE1DE7E3E123"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>has not received a successful kidney transplant; and</text> </clause><clause id="H76F058D8AFFA40998B7AB819272BCAA2"><enum>(v)</enum><text>has experienced a failed transplant.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1F7986ABD5BD41FD8039DFACA60FCF6F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>ESRD integrated care organization eligibility requirements</header>
							<paragraph id="H1D54B764B28C4AA3975E5FC147B8219F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Organizations</header>
 <subparagraph id="HBC3314B6AF1B42B499147E3FD7ABAD05"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">One or more eligible participating providers may establish an Organization or may enter into, subject to subparagraph (B), one or more partnership, ownership, or co-ownership agreements with one or more eligible participating partners to establish an Organization.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25635B2EE01F4BC8BB9CC19763F4F5F0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation on number of agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may specify a limitation on the number of Organizations in which an eligible participating partner may participate under agreements described in subparagraph (A).</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF99AB103B4204AA2A1B7CDB0AE7D672F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>ESRD integrated care model</header>
								<subparagraph id="H1F7EEB4BCEAF47B59E43B6A5C29CDA5F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Benefits requirements</header>
 <clause id="H1C822F61E06F44A1B1D52A5BBE1627E6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to clause (iii), an Organization shall offer at least one ESRD Integrated Care Model that is an open network model (as described in subparagraph (B)(i)) in each of its service areas and may offer one or more ESRD Integrated Care Models that is a preferred network model (as described in subparagraph (B)(ii)) in each of its service areas. For purposes of this section an ESRD Integrated Care Model (in this section referred to as the <quote>Model</quote>), subject to subsection (f)(3)(B)—</text>
 <subclause id="HAC67C4184A9F45BBB838E514969BF58F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall cover all benefits under parts A and B (other than hospice care) and include benefits for transition (particularly including education) into transplantation, palliative care, or hospice; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H4CE900DBF8BE4AF3A86C9EAAC43F061C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>may, through a partnership or other agreement with an MA–PD plan under part C or prescription drug plan under part D, cover all prescription drug benefits under such part D.</text>
										</subclause></clause><clause id="H381C2DD10ACD414AA3D90F4CF02280C1"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Treatment of savings</header>
 <subclause id="HC769A743AE1E4A5FA1D684A9D5F167FB"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any Organization offering an ESRD Integrated Care Model shall provide for the return under subclause (IV) to a Program-eligible beneficiary enrolled in the Organization of the amount, if any, by which the payment amount described in subclause (III) with respect to the Program-eligible beneficiary for a year exceeds the revenue amount described in subclause (II) with respect to the Program-eligible beneficiary for the year.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H45155B31550D49CBB3633AF11DCFA073"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Revenue amount described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The revenue amount described in this subclause, with respect to an Organization offering an ESRD Integrated Care Model and a Program-eligible beneficiary enrolled in such Organization, is the Organization’s estimated average revenue requirements, including administrative costs and return on investment, for the Organization to provide the benefits described in clause (i) under the Model for the Program-eligible beneficiary for the year.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HAD4DB484E18A440D8BB8F177914006F4"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Payment amount described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The payment amount described in this subclause, with respect to an Organization offering an ESRD Integrated Care Model and a Program-eligible beneficiary enrolled in such Organization, is the payment amount to the Organization under subsection (f)(1) made with respect to the Program-eligible beneficiary for the year.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H465CBE95FFA848ADBC4C124E31FE2D7D"><enum>(IV)</enum><header>Means of returning savings to program-eligible beneficiaries enrolled in Organizations</header><text>An Organization shall return the amount under subclause (I) to a Program-eligible beneficiary enrolled in the Organization in a manner specified by the Organization, which may include, as applicable, cost-sharing lower than otherwise applicable, benefits not covered under the original medicare fee-for-service program (including preventive services related to chronic kidney disease and education surrounding the importance of transplantation), or financial incentives (such as reduced cost sharing) for Program-eligible beneficiaries enrolled in the Organization to promote the delivery of high-value and efficient care and services.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HE2365DD37D6848C9B9AC23AEB7024364"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Benefit requirements for dual eligibles</header><text>In the case of a Program-eligible beneficiary who is eligible for benefits under this title and title XIX, an Organization, in accordance with an agreement entered into under subsection (f)(4)—</text>
 <subclause id="H0334BA36CB3F4476BFD3DEE553EF77A9"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may be responsible for providing, or arranging for the provision of, all benefits (other than long-term services and supports) for which the Program-eligible beneficiary is eligible for under the State Medicaid program under title XIX in which the Program-eligible beneficiary is enrolled; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H9A8C532906024D8DB0DE6F1FEE2DC6C5"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may elect to provide, or arrange for the provision of, long-term services and supports available to the Program-eligible beneficiary under the State Medicaid program, including services related to the transition into palliative care or hospice.</text>
										</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A5CD38C4FAC46FCA482B482FBA93EB1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements for open network and preferred network models</header>
 <clause id="HA1F704BA9C154F9CA16A0294C5C184E4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Open network model</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under an ESRD Integrated Care Model offered by an Organization that is an open network model, the Organization shall—</text>
 <subclause id="HEFF5A7AA3D2B479CB3CD4858BFC72ADD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>allow Program-eligible beneficiaries to receive such covered benefits from any provider of services or supplier regardless of whether such provider is within the network assembled under clause (ii)(I);</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HF5EA712C9C714B7783FCDF4488AB217A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>pay any Medicare-certified provider or supplier that is not within the network assembled under subclause (I) for such covered benefits an amount equal to the amount the provider or supplier would otherwise receive under this title; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H8A4C3E0A0D1546569F244B1F3C02DBBC"><enum>(III)</enum><text>not apply any additional premium or cost sharing requirements for such covered benefits in addition to premium or cost sharing requirements, respectively, that would be applicable under part A or part B for such benefits.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HF0DA12AD2C7A4984B45449DAA69DBB87"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Preferred network model</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under an ESRD Integrated Care Model offered by an Organization that is a preferred network model, the Organization—</text>
 <subclause id="H0510046EB51C436DA0051CE8BCE497BC"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall assemble a network of providers of services and suppliers identified by the Organization and confirmed by the Secretary as including providers of services and suppliers with significant expertise in caring for individuals with end-stage renal disease through which Program-eligible beneficiaries shall receive covered benefits as described in subparagraph (A) that are required to be covered under the Model;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H6D35FAF691F44AD18F71DBB8578A9835"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall provide for payment for items and services furnished by providers of services and suppliers within such network to Program-eligible beneficiaries enrolled in such Organization in accordance with payment rates determined pursuant to an agreement entered into between the Organization and such providers of services and suppliers and shall provide for payment for items and services furnished by providers of services and suppliers not within such network to such beneficiaries so enrolled in accordance that would be determined under section 1853(a)(1)(H);</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE56DA9BB4C1044F2A697506774FA72D9"><enum>(III)</enum><text>may apply premium and cost-sharing requirements, in addition to premium or cost-sharing requirements, respectively, that would be applicable under part B, for benefits in addition to those required to be covered under the Model; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HF4A731E9D567416188A3A0CD63FD57D5"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall apply network standards as defined by the Secretary.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HEDE623F37C3B406284CE6B171A985205"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Promoting access to high-quality providers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An Organization offering an ESRD Integrated Care Model may develop and implement performance-based incentives for providers of services and suppliers to promote delivery of high quality and efficient care. Such incentives shall be based on clinical measures and non-clinical measures, such as with respect to notification of patient discharge from a hospital, patient education (such as with respect to treatment options, including chronic kidney disease maintenance, and nutrition), and the interoperability of electronic health records developed by an Organization according to requirements and standards specified by the Secretary pursuant to subparagraph (C).</text>
									</clause><clause id="H373317C0DAA94DB78BC677A159A6DB2A"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Application of medicare advantage requirement with respect to medicare services furnished by
			 out-of-network providers and suppliers</header>
 <subclause id="H1221FB7AAA6943B79EDB989E091884E3"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1852(k)(1) (relating to limitations on balance billing against MA organizations for noncontract physicians and other entities with respect to services covered under this title) shall apply to Organizations, Program-eligible beneficiaries enrolled in such Organizations, and physicians and other entities that do not have a contract or other agreement with the Organization establishing payment amounts for services furnished to such a beneficiary in the same manner as such section applies to MA organizations, individuals enrolled with such organizations, and physicians and other entities referred to in such section.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H79E1C8DF82284CF28DA7B766D011D71E"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Reference for additional provision</header><text>For the provision relating to limitations on balance billing against Organizations for services covered under this title furnished by noncontract providers of services and suppliers, see section 1866(a)(1)(O).</text>
										</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC882D78276E3411D9DE9D536CA505B17"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Quality and reporting requirements</header>
 <clause id="H9B69217CFEDC47018BF469BC000E2BBD"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Clinical measures</header><text>Under the Program, the Secretary shall—</text> <subclause id="HA2AEEDF5B7324A1BB9B682297E46B77F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>require each participating Organization to submit to the Secretary data on clinical measures consistent with those measures submitted by organizations participating in the Comprehensive ESRD Care Initiative operated by the Center for Medicare and Medicaid Innovation as of October 1, 2016, to assess the quality of care provided;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H6A448244CC4D4817BE86D9A1CB5FC073"><enum>(II)</enum><text>establish requirements for participating Organizations to report to the Secretary, in a form and manner specified by the Secretary, information on such measures; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H4D3D1D8AF6974FB09C15B7C5A2549C42"><enum>(III)</enum><text>establish quality performance standards on such measures to assess the quality of care.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HD37184D49AFA4073801FC2790F3A486E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Requirement for stakeholder input</header><text>In developing requirements and standards under subclauses (II) and (III) of clause (i), the Secretary shall request and consider input from a stakeholder board, at least one nephrologist, other suppliers and providers of services, renal dialysis facilities, and beneficiary advocates.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1738F724E5F348498C12CBC7EBB24476"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Additional assessments and reporting requirements</header><text>The Secretary shall assess the extent to which an Organization delivers integrated and patient-centered care through analysis of information obtained from Program-eligible beneficiaries enrolled in the Organization through surveys, such as the In-Center Hemodialysis Consumer Assessment of Healthcare Providers and Systems.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD552E988CBD14D439DFC0A8F550503DC"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Requirements for esrd integrated care strategy</header>
 <clause id="H491095418290465486175E88060345A0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An Organization seeking a contract under this section to offer one or more ESRD Integrated Care Models must develop and submit for the Secretary’s approval, subject to clauses (ii) and (iii), an ESRD Integrated Care Strategy.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6685905EA8134BBDA059120C7000BB37"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>ESRD integrated care strategy</header><text>In assessing an ESRD Integrated Care Strategy under clause (i), the Secretary shall consider the extent to which the Strategy includes elements, such as the following:</text>
 <subclause id="H57AAE3C2FAC1409DB109BEB6B794108A"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Interdisciplinary care teams led by at least one nephrologist, and comprised of registered nurses, social workers, renal dialysis facility managers, and other representatives from alternative settings described in subclause (VIII).</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H3C85B638C6374673931A2B2C5CC495B0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>A decision process for care plans and care management that includes the nephrologist and other practitioners responsible for direct delivery of care to Program-eligible beneficiaries enrolled in the Organization involved.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HCDD668E677664A25BBD1914564F8EB38"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Health risk and other assessments to determine the physical, psychosocial, nutrition, language, cultural, and other needs of Program-eligible beneficiaries enrolled in the Organization involved.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD08B4CE9FBF549C68F9A7DC88E0C148D"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Development and at least annual updating of individualized care plans that incorporate at least the medical, social, and functional needs, preferences, and care goals of Program-eligible beneficiaries enrolled in the Organization.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H0FD03FF837BB4240BD31737619728707"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Coordination and delivery of non-clinical services, such as transportation, aimed at improving the adherence of Program-eligible beneficiaries enrolled in the Organization with care recommendations.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HF981F01380BB4CB2B4580D88EAC5E815"><enum>(VI)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Services, such as transplant evaluation, palliative care, evaluation for hospice eligibility, and vascular access care.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE903BA0FF8FF4B4E9F57193558C5975B"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>In the case of an individual who, while enrolled in the Organization, receives confirmation that a kidney transplant is imminent, the provision by an interdisciplinary care team described in subclause (I) of counseling services to such individual on preparation for and potential challenges surrounding such transplant.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H1AA179E7699B49D78FF81EB2C4EDA8A9"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>Delivery of benefits and services in alternative settings, such as the home of the Program-eligible beneficiary enrolled in the Organization, in coordination with the provider or other appropriate stakeholder involved in such delivery serving on an interdisciplinary care team described in subclause (I).</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H0DF676A781E442D28F7B7ED5AD238EAB"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>Use of patient reminder systems.</text> </subclause><subclause id="HA1DF41E435E247B790067AF52A264EA3"><enum>(X)</enum><text>Education programs for patients, families, and caregivers.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H044E38F4DDF2461DBCFEC61893FEFD48"><enum>(XI)</enum><text>Use of health care advice resources, such as nurse advice lines.</text> </subclause><subclause id="HC976252E1ADC4CFBB1BC9B91C0E496CB"><enum>(XII)</enum><text>Use of team-based health care delivery models that provide comprehensive and continuous medical care, such as medical homes.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HFE8D658013824476A22A93D410A9308D"><enum>(XIII)</enum><text>Co-location of providers and services.</text> </subclause><subclause id="H80C1A0DFF2CA45E984E08479913FB0CB"><enum>(XIV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Use of a demonstrated capacity to share electronic health record information across sites of care.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H54A182FE107F4BC6B69E252A8364CD2D"><enum>(XV)</enum><text>Use of programs to promote better adherence to recommended treatment regimens by individuals, including by addressing barriers to access to care by such individuals.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD44EB050FFD7436EA790516ACF53BE4F"><enum>(XVI)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Defined protocols to facilitate the transition of pediatric patients into adult end stage renal disease care, developed in conjunction with the pediatric nephrology community.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H92CB9DF314194E7BA47DD3BED5A3FA96"><enum>(XVII)</enum><text>Other services, strategies, and approaches identified by the Organization to improve care coordination and delivery.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H3858F2C3B53C4806A3DFD88DA0FA3BB2"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not approve an ESRD Integrated Care Strategy of an Organization unless under such Strategy the Organization—</text>
 <subclause id="H03265B23D5F049338077692A862FA345"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides services to Program-eligible beneficiaries enrolled in the Organization through a comprehensive, multidisciplinary health and social services delivery system which integrates acute and long-term care services pursuant to regulations;</text>
										</subclause><subclause id="H1D587E15688B4AF69BF7286465E787CA">
											<enum>(II)</enum>
 <text>specifies the covered items and services that will not be provided directly by the Organization, and to arrange for delivery of those items and services through contracts meeting the requirements of regulations; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE9C4FB2D0BBD4117A014561BAEF2E1B2"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishes a governing body that—</text> <item id="H44AB8457F05D45E6A9433BFF4CFD02CD"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>consists of representation from each eligible participating provider of such Organization;</text>
 </item><item id="H3971B6BFE56D4E03A73891CD949BCF49"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>includes at least one nephrologist who may be affiliated with a participating provider in the preferred network, at least one nephrologist in the open network, and at least one beneficiary advocate; and</text>
 </item><item id="HA6B7B70410694F8383F39749775AC555"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>has responsibility for the oversight of the activities of the Organization.</text> </item></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1FE5A7EBF77C4C4787A9B293E36C529B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirement for capital reserves</header> <subparagraph id="HC727FF75FB1D4C539AE4FC5AF05D634B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall enter into contracts under this section only with Organizations that demonstrate sufficient capital reserves, measured as a percentage of capitated payments and consistent with requirements established by the State in which the Organization operates.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4D894F032C9F46F68411C462CD6CD456"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Alternative mechanism to demonstrate capacity to bear risk</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An Organization shall be considered to meet the requirement in subparagraph (A) if the Organization includes at least one eligible participating provider or eligible participating partner that—</text>
 <clause id="H3933EB66DE18444C91302361E2C40D77"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is licensed as a risk-bearing entity or deemed by a State as able to bear risk; and</text> </clause><clause id="H8AE6959E372C41B5B5891C77780C5FA9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>chooses to bear risk as a condition of partnership in such Organization.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H687E36073DDE44DDA97D45EFD19B030E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Beneficiary protections</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HA6DCD1E04668497C90E4AEFEA3FD7DF4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Seamless access to care</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish processes and take steps as necessary, including educating Medicare-certified providers and suppliers about the Program, to ensure that Program-eligible beneficiaries assigned into an open network model or who elect into a preferred network model offered by an Organization experience no disruption of access to Medicare-certified providers or suppliers furnishing items or services to such beneficiary immediately before such assignment or election and for purposes of receipt of such items or services. Assignment into an open network model or election into a preferred network model under the Program shall in no way be construed as affecting a Program-eligible beneficiary’s ability to receive covered benefits from any Medicare-certified provider or supplier as described in subsection (b)(2)(A).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H99A9BADF81E241EFB0BD540805555C03"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Continuity of care</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To provide for continuity of care, each contract entered into with an Organization under this section shall provide for a transition period during which a Program-eligible beneficiary who is first enrolled in the Organization or who elects to opt out of the Program or otherwise disenroll from the Organization maintains access to eligible participating providers furnishing items or services to such beneficiary immediately before such enrollment or election for purposes of receipt of such items or services. Payment for such items or services covered under this title furnished to such Program-eligible beneficiary during such transition period shall be made in accordance with this title and in such amounts as would otherwise be determined for such items and services provided to such a beneficiary not enrolled under the Program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H45AA1720FE9549FABE859EBEB394EC19"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Antidiscrimination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each contract entered into with an Organization under this section shall provide that each eligible participating provider of such Organization may not deny, limit, or condition the furnishing of services, or affect the quality of services furnished, under this title to Program-eligible beneficiaries on whether or not such a beneficiary is enrolled with the Organization.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5E9C46EF62A144C4AEF369C1771B5C7F"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Quality assurance; patient safeguards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each contract entered into with an Organization under this section shall require that such Organization have in effect at a minimum—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H33BF3FD11794492B993C5201482F542D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a written plan of quality assurance and improvement, and procedures implementing such plan, in accordance with regulations; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HA79CF63412A7454AA3AADF44A253A251"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">written safeguards of the rights of Program-eligible beneficiaries enrolled in the Organization (including a patient bill of rights and procedures for grievances and appeals) in accordance with regulations and with other requirements of this title and Federal and State law that are designed for the protection of patients.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13FD6A5B84D249B88CA8A8CB21DE46B5"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Oversight</header><text>The Secretary shall oversee the marketing and assignment practices of each Organization entering into a contract under this section as part of the approval and renewal processes of Organizations under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6639996E0F5E4DC38360E74AB79A013C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Non-Application of certain provisions of law</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of sections 162(m)(6) and 414(m) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and section 9010 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4001">26 U.S.C. 4001</external-xref> note prec.), in the case of an eligible participating provider that establishes an Organization or that enters into a partnership, ownership, or co-ownership agreement to establish an Organization, or an Organization with a contract under this section, risk-based payments in exchange for providing medical care shall not be considered premiums for health insurance coverage.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H15D04C17BF3A4156A8D88927D4CA8432"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Treatment as Medicare advanced alternative payment model</header><text>Alternative care delivery models under the Program shall be treated under this title as an advanced alternative payment model.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8E9E02D453AC456EAE18D59CD829B724"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Program operation and scope</header>
 <paragraph id="HAA9F8134B02D43859FB9CE766398C88B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall establish a process through which an Organization can apply to offer one or more ESRD Integrated Care Models. Such application shall include information on at least the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H23BEBA89097647A99B559B932A7D3E35"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The estimated average revenue amount described in subsection (b)(2)(A)(ii)(II) for the Organization to deliver benefits described in subsection (b)(2)(A).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E1792C31F5241B08257A1E8E151ACE7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Any benefits offered by the Organization beyond those described in such subsection.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2008E301C6984392974E6AF6D820D538"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A listing of network providers of services and supplier.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB26BD624CA8546B9AAA848C7A8391EA0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Information on the expertise of network providers of services and suppliers in serving ESRD patients.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5189DBFB232D43B7871F9D51C66276E1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A description of the ESRD Integrated Care Strategy of the Organization described in subsection (b)(2)(D).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3DD3621800984F6C89B5EA920185F57B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Program initiation</header><text>The Secretary shall initiate the Program such that Organizations begin serving Program-eligible beneficiaries not later than January 1, 2018.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H517CF108794C46C285DDF2AD47581689"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contract award and period</header><text>The Secretary shall enter into contracts for an initial period of not less than 5 years with all Organizations that meet Program requirements.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9066783A072442F3B221B50EC22C0B37"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Allowance for larger service areas and expansion of service areas</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Organizations shall demonstrate in their application that the proposed service area has the capacity to serve Program-eligible beneficiaries through an adequate provider network and is reflective of the communities in which beneficiaries live, work, and obtain health care services.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="HDFE08596CD8542348DB0830726AA4632"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Contract termination and suspension</header>
 <subparagraph id="HC40EFF450F0B40A9A673313B7D41DBC1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may terminate a contract with an Organization under this section if the Secretary determines that an Organization has failed to meet quality requirements described in subsection (b) or (e)(2)(C)(iii) or violates other terms of the contract.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8EDE887640BF4190B4F4A78466470E06"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Insufficient beneficiary participation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, in the case of an Organization with a contract under this section with respect to which, for any period of at least 30 consecutive days during a year for which such contract applies, fewer than 50 percent of the total number of Program-eligible beneficiaries served by the Organization receive benefits through the Organization under this section—</text>
 <clause id="HAD290B74D7EA4D95964F252DA3A00E20"><enum>(i)</enum><text>suspend such contract for the remainder of such year; and</text> </clause><clause id="H8C5F93A295D04E8CBFF48507A86A2FDD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide for the Organization to return any prospective payments made to the Organization under this section for items and services not provided pursuant to clause (i).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84A0D70EB8F143D69B463DE29682A9C3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Remedy and appeals process</header><text>Prior to the Secretary terminating or suspending a contract with an Organization under this section, the Secretary shall afford such Organization sufficient opportunity to remedy any contract violations and appeal a contract termination.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5B4DC7E5BBC4622892CEB5BFEE5A4F8"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Program-eligible beneficiary Notice at Time of Contract Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each contract under this section with an Organization shall require the Organization to provide (and pay for) written notice in advance of the contract’s termination or suspension, as well as a description of alternatives for obtaining benefits under this title, to each Program-eligible beneficiary assigned to or who elected to receive benefits through the Organization under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3C58129E907A4092A173C29C769433D8"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Program expansion</header><text>The Secretary may, through rulemaking, expand the duration and scope of the Program under this section, to the extent determined appropriate by the Secretary, if—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HA6F086348C124201B75F46E2F3F063CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary determines that such expansion is expected to—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HECB9C253C3824F0897C36A1668C741AB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>reduce spending under this title without reducing the quality of patient care; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H00E55477B7B04BAF976F3FEEF638E18F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>improve the quality of patient care without increasing spending under this title;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HBA692AE4E2814DD190AA440DC8C6B793"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Chief Actuary of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services certifies that such expansion would reduce (or would not result in any increase in) net program spending under this title; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H199D7F308AA84305BDE4E6E9DE097557"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Secretary determines that such expansion would not deny or limit the coverage or provision of benefits under this title for applicable individuals.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9D196805BC44D498405105E7A126444"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall conduct a study on an appropriate payment adjustor under the Program to ensure there are not disincentives in under the payment method under the Program from providing proper transplant evaluations.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA18CFDCBCC494F5D89DF5D6E1943D981"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Identification of program-Eligible beneficiaries</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a process for the initial and ongoing identification of Program-eligible beneficiaries.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H3D4057FB97194E01BDB345E3F5AC2093"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Program-Eligible Beneficiaries assigned Into an ESRD Integrated Care Organization Open Network
			 Model</header>
							<paragraph id="H4EF1D4862D5D4E35B1F04D8130C1AE57"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Assignment</header>
 <subparagraph id="H13715AA448BC45F7BC5781856510D492"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under the Program, subject to the succeeding provisions of this paragraph, the Secretary shall, upon the Secretary identifying a beneficiary as a Program-eligible beneficiary, assign all such Program-eligible beneficiary to an open network model offered by an Organization that includes the dialysis facility at which the Program-eligible beneficiary primarily receives renal dialysis services.</text>
								</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD9EFD57D7CC645D784F7078D2A2A1B80"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Program-eligible beneficiary notification of assignment</header>
 <clause id="H35BD65C9167945FE994D2B486091A34E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon assignment of a Program-eligible beneficiary to an Organization, the Secretary shall provide to the Organization written notification of such assignment of such Program-eligible beneficiary and not later than 15 business days after the date of receipt of such notification, the Organization shall provide written notice to the Program-eligible beneficiary—</text>
 <subclause id="HC4F6665600C3476EB06C127C64F8843F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>of such assignment; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H1705FD70B26A45E78B1A1877D7686507"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">including education regarding the importance of transplantation as the best health outcome, as well as the minimum health requirements for transplant eligibility before and during dialysis treatment.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H3FFF85D516774E329CE8BD8A42AF1CCB"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Opt-out period and changes upon initial assignment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide for a 75-day period beginning on the date on which the assignment of a Program-eligible beneficiary into an open network model offered by an Organization becomes effective during which a Program-eligible beneficiary may—</text>
 <subclause id="H9C1F86E884134BB898CA7EA02E9CBC6B"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">opt out of the Program;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HB39BCC95932D45AA8CEBA55D67358C66"><enum>(II)</enum><text>make a one-time change of assignment into an open network model offered by a different Organization; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H1CFC677577B745158415CFE75EF46A6F"><enum>(III)</enum><text>elect a preferred network model offered by the same or different Organization.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA7DE5882E3DA4BDA96301607A755CB8F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Additional opt-in population in case of beneficiary relocation or choice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual who, without application of clause (iv) of subsection (a)(2)(C), would be treated as a Program-eligible beneficiary, may elect to enroll in an Organization under the Program under this section if such individual agrees to receive renal dialysis services primarily from a facility that participates in such Organization. For purposes of this section (other than subparagraphs (A) and (B) of this paragraph, paragraph (2), and subsection (d)), an individual making an election pursuant to the previous sentence shall be treated as a Program-eligible beneficiary.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H288497AA9F1343808E38884B2713D674"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Deemed re-enrollment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Program-eligible beneficiary assigned under this paragraph to an ESRD Integrated Care Model offered by an Organization with respect to a year is deemed, unless the individual elects otherwise under this paragraph, to have elected to continue such assignment with respect to the subsequent year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D09558DACB9454A8F1F095C39EF08C8"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Additional opportunity to opt out or elect different model or organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On the date that is one year after the effective date of the initial assignment of a Program-eligible beneficiary to an open network model offered by an Organization (and annually thereafter), a Program-eligible beneficiary shall be given the opportunity to—</text>
 <clause id="H78DE100246E3451B8C83D0ACB12BFC86"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">opt out of the Program;</text> </clause><clause id="HE035DE8F505E4738ACE5A118B6827580"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>make a one-time change of assignment into an open network model offered by a different Organization; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDD39654BE07E42C8BF00A2E05E9BCF3D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>elect a preferred network model offered by the same or different Organization.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA304FBA74B0B481587D3D08A7652C1A4"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Change in principal diagnosis opt out</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to any other period during which a Program-eligible beneficiary may, pursuant to this paragraph, opt out of the Program, in the case of a Program-eligible beneficiary who, after assignment under this paragraph, is diagnosed with a principal diagnosis (as defined by the Secretary) other than end-stage renal disease, such individual shall be given the opportunity to opt out of the Program during such period as specified by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE86D3C7C97314530844891142D1C7768"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Special election periods</header><text>The Secretary shall offer Program-eligible beneficiaries special election periods consistent with those described in section 1851(e)(4).</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7598A4F538694BEABF8AB9B2A7303E5C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Program-eligible beneficiary notification</header>
 <subparagraph id="HD64D80E1C1F84F59B6A4B3BD5F6B82A6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall notify Program-eligible beneficiaries about the Program under this section and provide them with information about receiving benefits under this title through an Organization.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6FA78FC5E3C9482EAC33AA162E9BFE22"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, subject to subparagraph (C), such notification shall allow for eligible participating providers that are part of an Organization to—</text>
 <clause id="HF3FAB32070F54BBD91E4B8F6ABEC4477"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inform Program-eligible beneficiaries about the Program;</text> </clause><clause id="H7E74DDE0FD2B42AB9EC809EA508D813E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>distribute Program materials to Program-eligible beneficiaries; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF01D63F8F3EC410EA433C644CE349111"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>assist Program-eligible beneficiaries in assessing the options of such beneficiaries under the Program.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA7AB473B780E48B2B93169C75C862B9B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Limitation on unsolicited marketing</header>
 <clause commented="no" id="H2C7EB2C7F13645468DFF41504E17037B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under the Program, an eligible participating provider may not provide marketing information or materials, including information, materials, and assistance described in subparagraph (B), to a Program-eligible beneficiary unless the Program-eligible beneficiary requests such marketing information or materials.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HF5A3B811C21C463799A64D9B1ABE5889"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exception for providers treating beneficiaries</header><text>An eligible participating provider that is part of an Organization may provide information, materials, and assistance described in subparagraph (B) to a Program-eligible beneficiary, without prior request of such beneficiary, if such beneficiary is receiving renal dialysis services from such provider.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1D9C5CE8250940FAA41C87C63B7E746F"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Parity in marketing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any case that an Organization participates in any form of marketing, such form of marketing shall be the same for all Program-eligible beneficiaries to which, pursuant to (ii), the Organization may provide information, materials, and assistance described in such clause.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H95634204076E4D148BCB4E012FD5AF45"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Program-eligible beneficiary appeal rights</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Program-eligible beneficiaries enrolled in an Organization shall have the same right to appeal any denial of benefits under this title as such a Program-eligible beneficiary would have under this title if such Program-eligible beneficiary were not so enrolled.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5290FE041DC047C6ABF4E1710D1CBD69"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Payment</header>
 <paragraph id="HE9E5A02DD22040E5A0E4B05CAD0ACA67"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For each Program-eligible beneficiary receiving care through an Organization, the Secretary shall make a monthly capitated payment in accordance with payment rates that would be determined under section 1853(a)(1)(H), as adjusted pursuant to paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H931565BB1EB54C2A857B297E5CA085FF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application of health status risk adjustment methodology</header><text>The Secretary shall adjust the payment amount to an Organization under this subsection in the same manner in which the payment amount to a Medicare Advantage plan is adjusted under section 1853(a)(1)(C).</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H90D4D73BCDCF4391BD4F5B952A821894"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Treatment of kidney acquisition costs</header>
 <subparagraph id="H7129175CE50A4CCAAEDBEC45AB465304"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Excluding costs for kidney acquisitions from ma benchmark</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall adjust the payment amount to an Organization to exclude from such payment amount the Secretary’s estimate of the standardized costs for payments for organ acquisitions for kidney transplants in the area involved for the year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF64939727344977A7BE43C087415AF2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>FFS converge of kidney acquisitions</header><text>An Organization shall provide all benefits described in subclause (I) of subsection (b)(2)(A)(i), except for kidney acquisition costs. Payment for kidney acquisition costs covered under this title furnished to a Program-eligible beneficiary shall be made in accordance with this title and in such amounts as would otherwise be made and determined for such items and services provided to such a beneficiary not enrolled under the Program.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8161C8DD94904821A60ECE291E2BF7EF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Payment for part D benefits</header><text>In the case where an Organization elects to offer part D prescription drug coverage under the Program under this section, payments to the Organization for such benefits provided to Program-eligible beneficiaries by the Organization shall be made in the same manner and amounts as those payments would be made in the case of an organization with a contract under such part.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEA7F7FE5A8D041E88ED929E4EF6C35DC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Agreement with State Medicaid Agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the event of an Organization that elects to cover benefits under title XIX for Program-eligible beneficiaries eligible for benefits under this title and title XIX such Organization shall enter into an agreement with the State Medicaid agency to provide benefits, or arrange for benefits to be provided, for which such beneficiaries are entitled to receive medical assistance under title XIX and to receive payment from the State for providing or arranging for the provision of such benefits.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="HBABA6B29E9AD41D595CD66A6B68C6C32"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Affirmation of State obligations to pay premium and cost-sharing amounts</header>
 <subparagraph id="H40B10D2C9529451491910355D962FE58"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State shall continue to make medical assistance under the State plan under title XIX available in the amount described in subparagraph (B) for the duration of the Program for cost-sharing (as defined in section 1905(p)(3)) under this title for qualified medicare beneficiaries described in section 1905(p)(1) and other individuals who are Program-eligible beneficiaries enrolled in an Organization and entitled to medical assistance for premiums and such cost-sharing under the State plan under title XIX.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H599D463A7BB84C148527559BAB0E397B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Amounts made available for cost-sharing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subparagraph (A):</text> <clause id="H027E151EE8C6484C85FD993877B7587B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to clause (ii), the amount of medical assistance described in this clause to be made available for cost-sharing pursuant to subparagraph (A) for an individual described in such subparagraph entitled to medical assistance for such cost-sharing under a State plan under title XIX shall be equal to the amount of medical assistance that would be made available under such State plan as in effect as of January 1, 2016.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB0C4E8C817E045299298D90F43625301"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Amounts in the case of a State that increases payments for cost-sharing</header><text>If a State increases the amount of medical assistance made available under the State plan under title XIX for cost-sharing described in subparagraph (A) after such date, such increased amounts shall be made available under subparagraph (A) for the remaining duration of the Program.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2375066112F74BC9A1E30474BC55D73A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Waiver authority</header>
 <paragraph id="HD3F99BF6502149FC9A1A4F6EEB2D26E4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In order to carry out the Program under this section, the Secretary shall waive those requirements waived under section 1899 and may waive such additional requirements consistent with those waived under programs administered through the Center for Medicare and Medicaid Innovation as may be necessary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0DC2D259412542249F3D3244F34E1827"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice of waivers</header><text>Not later than 3 months after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall publish a notice of waivers that will apply in connection with the Program. The notice shall include the specific conditions that an Organization must meet to qualify for each waiver, and commentary explaining the waiver requirements.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD91A1C11F40A46019BAC177213B312A2"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than December 31, 2024, the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission shall submit to Congress an interim report on the Program.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB5560A2E72F4403D95C7DBC7F281DECB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment relating to balanced billing</header><text>Section 1866(a)(1)(O) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395cc">42 U.S.C. 1395cc(a)(1)(O)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H36EFEAD0ACF542FFB615AE699C827ED4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>with an ESRD Integrated Care Organization under section 1866F,</quote> after <quote>with a PACE provider under section 1894 or 1934,</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6326069869D343389C748BFED0ABFAE7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or ESRD Integrated Care Organization</quote> after <quote>in the case of a PACE provider</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H67E322B9E3FF4E7AA1630C0445B31483"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or PACE program eligible individuals enrolled with the PACE provider</quote> and inserting <quote>, Program-eligible beneficiaries enrolled in the ESRD Integrated Care Organization, or PACE program eligible individuals enrolled with the PACE provider</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD75EA8AF163A49C6A7A6B16CEFE831AB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(or in the case of a Program-eligible beneficiary enrolled in the ESRD Integrated Care Organization, the amounts that would be made in accordance with payment rates that would be determined under section 1853(a)(1)(H))</quote> after <quote>the amounts that would be made</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA8C5BCD5D6014D66B0823F6B39B49F0C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Extension of guaranteed issue rights under Medigap</header>
 <paragraph id="H6704FE273EFD4C7F931D138E256CA5A5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1882(s)(3)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ss">42 U.S.C. 1395ss(s)(3)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new clause:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H15D82E8750634676A5C32C8449E43E99" style="OLC">
 <clause id="HE2FA5EB5F4C64D989FAAB1FCB389C6CC"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The individual is participating in the demonstration program established under section 1866F, regardless of the duration of the individual’s participation in the program and regardless of any previous enrollment in, or disenrollment from, a medicare supplemental policy under this section.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF218F254402A4C67AF6A66678EFA67C0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall develop a process to notify (and shall notify) individuals described in clause (vii) of section 1882(s)(3)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ss">42 U.S.C. 1395ss(s)(3)(B)</external-xref>), as added by paragraph (1), of their guaranteed issue rights under such section.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


