<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HFD7AA681FE48497F9DF21C937624A4DD" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2419 IH: To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the process by which the Secretary of Veterans Affairs pays non-Department of Veterans Affairs health care providers for hospital care or medical services furnished to veterans pursuant to the laws administered by the Secretary.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2419</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170511">May 11, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the process by which the Secretary of Veterans
			 Affairs pays non-Department of Veterans Affairs health care providers for
			 hospital care or medical services furnished to veterans pursuant to the
			 laws administered by the Secretary.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H0D727E3E5C07446D9EFE49EA8D30F170" style="OLC">
		<section id="H1C5B9B6CBC08496787DB58825F070999" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Payment of non-Department of Veterans Affairs health care providers</header>
			<subsection id="H772E28A56A8042A78B55E7FEB550D6D6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Payment of providers</header>
 <paragraph id="HF7B517FE24804F66B381879B84BFEA8B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/17">chapter 17</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code is amended by inserting after section 1703 the following new section:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2301A4507C954A7A8E69CB268A66A5D9" style="USC">
						<section id="H16C52A968CF44B3097596E987DDE60F9"><enum>1703A.</enum><header>Payment of non-Department health care providers</header>
 <subsection id="HAE8B8F66AAB841589D9A6C637B784088"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prompt payment compliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that payments made to non-Department health care providers, including under the Veterans Choice Program established by section 101 of the Veterans Access, Choice, and Accountability Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/146">Public Law 113–146</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/1701">38 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note), comply with <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/39">chapter 39</external-xref> of title 31 (commonly referred to as the <quote>Prompt Payment Act</quote>) and the requirements of this section. If there is a conflict between the requirements of the Prompt Payment Act and the requirements of this section, the Secretary shall comply with the requirements of this section.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="H6278575F961A4700B478B6BDF4F13554"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Payment schedule</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB84CD7806A6041529B834F3FAE3DFC08"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall reimburse a non-Department health care provider for care or services furnished under the laws administered by the Secretary—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H211B0F2583EB459BB2B225574B5A3DA4" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a clean claim submitted to the Secretary electronically, not later than 30 days after receiving the claim; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H568B039333164F73B06185426644DB7D" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a clean claim submitted to the Secretary in a manner other than electronically, not later than 45 days after receiving the claim.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDFD59452A78048999399DF7227AA5BE4" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H651E3D5E65A648BC9D7F7D1CA71BCC4B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary determines that a claim received from a non-Department health care provider is a non-clean claim, the Secretary shall submit to the provider, not later than 10 days after receiving the claim—</text>
 <clause id="H15ACCBC4E3134E3E8605072C47541AB9" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a notification that the claim is a non-clean claim;</text> </clause><clause id="HFA3E371609BB4F1C81ED1CF6DCD5EB0A" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an explanation of why the claim has been determined to be a non-clean claim; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA3230C7EB46947FBBF31C8AC4B016A8B" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an identification of the information or documentation that is required to make the claim a clean claim.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1008A1D67E474AE9B8D5BF0D8E118252" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If the Secretary does not comply with the requirements of subparagraph (A) with respect to a claim, the claim shall be deemed a clean claim for purposes of paragraph (1).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB96424E70B6F498BB7141D678E996ABA" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon receipt by the Secretary of information or documentation described in subparagraph (A)(iii) with respect to a claim, the Secretary shall reimburse a non-Department health care provider—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF0C6E51195C34AB5B883D7BE085310F1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a claim submitted to the Secretary electronically, not later than 30 days after receiving such information or documentation; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFEA63A3482F5409D872687B9AE5CB5F7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of claim submitted to the Secretary in a manner other than electronically, not later than 45 days after receiving such information or documentation.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB071A92DD21946FAB1F70A9B88A792EF" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>If the Secretary fails to comply with the deadlines for payment set forth in this subsection with respect to a claim, interest shall accrue on the amount owed under such claim in accordance with section 3902 of title 31.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H588CB835E24640198501A382713CF80E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Information and documentation required</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HCA0E6DADE82A497EABF213B68B24B6B6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pursuant to regulations prescribed by the Secretary, the Secretary shall provide to non-Department health care providers that furnish hospital care or medical services to veterans pursuant to the laws administered by the Secretary information and documentation that is required to establish a clean claim under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H126421FB72AD47249B5B2E8F18D84DAB" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary shall consult with entities in the health care industry, in the public and private sector, to determine the information and documentation to include in the list under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H512D908DD17A4897924F96D19127F692"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Electronic claim submittal</header><text>On and after January 1, 2019, the Secretary shall not accept any claim under this section that is submitted to the Secretary in a manner other than electronically.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCDFC4FEDFE234C8C9BCB89427E5E1001"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H51FBD3464F3B4EF8A2215866119EABC9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>clean claim</term> means a claim for reimbursement for hospital care or medical services furnished by non-Department health care providers to veterans pursuant to the laws administered by the Secretary, on a nationally recognized standard format, that includes the information and documentation necessary to adjudicate the claim.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H23E17B30E62C4543A62C92F628877B87"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>non-clean claim</term> means a claim for reimbursement for hospital care or medical services furnished by non-Department health care providers to veterans pursuant to the laws administered by the Secretary, on a nationally recognized standard format, that does not include the information and documentation necessary to adjudicate the claim.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8FD92CA5642240F8AF3C79C32103E68D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 17 of such title is amended by inserting after the item related to section 1703 the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H71B8C8F05559485AA619615D15CD5949" style="USC">
						<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
							<toc-entry level="section">1703A. Payment of non-Department health care providers.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0A391E275D1746DEA004609146952616"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Electronic submittal of claims for reimbursement</header>
				<paragraph id="H1DFC51ECB6284FF380DCD5F36AEA09D4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition on acceptance of non-electronic claims</header>
 <subparagraph id="HBDF2C07C78504C938DA9632E1AC52CE4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), on and after January 1, 2019, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall not accept any claim for reimbursement under section 1703A of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), that is submitted to the Secretary in a manner other than electronically, including medical records in connection with such a claim.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD3B6BFD08FFD4AAE91E554FEF6977887"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>If the Secretary determines that accepting claims and medical records in a manner other than electronically is necessary for the timely processing of claims for reimbursement under such section 1703A due to a failure or malfunction of the electronic interface established under paragraph (2), the Secretary—</text>
 <clause id="H8DAEEF8E859B4C9EB6697578BD673160"><enum>(i)</enum><text>may accept claims and medical records in a manner other than electronically for a period not to exceed 90 days; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD2EF237570A0441D82D4416957AE091C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report setting forth—</text>
 <subclause id="HD87D7DDF81CB4F5A8FF7E95A579E49DC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the reason for accepting claims and medical records in a manner other than electronically;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HB9C8A63A1BE54917BF7FC57E29B5E799"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the duration of time that the Department of Veterans Affairs will accept claims and medical records in a manner other than electronically; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H1B9EEBD9D3EE49A68DE0DAD733B88BA0"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the steps that the Department is taking to resolve such failure or malfunction.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E92650817E84A72A7C778C453DF6655"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Electronic interface</header> <subparagraph id="H79278FB6EF6F4346BC1FF6CB81E8AF2F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than January 1, 2019, the Chief Information Officer of the Department of Veterans Affairs shall establish and make operational an electronic interface for health care providers to submit claims for reimbursement under such section 1703A.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6DF32A22598B46DFBB3022A2A771DE1E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The electronic interface established under subparagraph (A) shall include the following functions:</text> <clause id="HB76AC9455D80478F9209730F0CEEE816"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A function through which a health care provider may input all relevant data required for claims submittal and reimbursement.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4D53FC3B96B44880B42D9A4C87B466DA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A function through which a health care provider may upload medical records to accompany a claim for reimbursement.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H801D123DC317478DB9367144D6BD6056"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A function through which a health care provider may ascertain the status of a pending claim for reimbursement that—</text>
 <subclause id="H9CC51EAEC8A1472DA54EAECB9363B179"><enum>(I)</enum><text>indicates whether the claim is a clean claim or a non-clean claim; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H24D6F07A4DA34777AE81D2ACFA34142D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the event that a submitted claim is indicated as a non-clean claim, provides—</text>
 <item id="H85605AB3A600468D8EAA66662147075B"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>an explanation of why the claim has been determined to be a non-clean claim; and</text> </item><item id="H5F4D0D0BB8534BBFB4DA816E22526649"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>an identification of the information or documentation that is required to make the claim a clean claim.</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause id="H9965CFD62E2647708FDD7EC770BEDA6D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A function through which a health care provider is notified when a claim for reimbursement is accepted or rejected.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCA40C4A22A7B4DD7B6F79770822862E1"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Such other features as the Secretary considers necessary.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE43E3EBF2968492A8376BE718F3556DA"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Protection of information</header> <clause id="H29523963A1334B17AB93ED3CA2FA7D6F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The electronic interface established under subparagraph (A) shall be developed and implemented based on industry-accepted information security and privacy engineering principles and best practices and shall provide for the following:</text>
 <subclause id="H3C2A0C99025C49DEAB25EC3F2C6E2E29"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The elicitation, analysis, and prioritization of functional and nonfunctional information security and privacy requirements for such interface, including specific security and privacy services and architectural requirements relating to security and privacy based on a thorough analysis of all reasonably anticipated cyber and noncyber threats to the security and privacy of electronic protected health information made available through such interface.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H13A8B24484E24AA2B7548BA36DEF7823"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The elicitation, analysis, and prioritization of secure development requirements relating to such interface.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H4DF22CBF6A2A4A69AAB11182DB34E576"><enum>(III)</enum><text>The assurance that the prioritized information security and privacy requirements of such interface—</text> <item id="H251A5D6BA6234957BD85BFCF58107DF8"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>are correctly implemented in the design and implementation of such interface throughout the system development lifecycle; and</text>
 </item><item id="HCD8D0B4700574D03907D07A10FA619A8"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>satisfy the information objectives of such interface relating to security and privacy throughout the system development lifecycle.</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause id="H34F1A9264B684162A8256E107B2D4A06"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subparagraph:</text> <subclause id="H65ADE0FA9457482CA8A9F9659692D055"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Electronic protected health information</header><text>The term <term>electronic protected health information</term> has the meaning given that term in section 160.103 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB12592089DDE4E20B3DCFF55D3A22A9A"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Secure development requirements</header><text>The term <term>secure development requirements</term> means, with respect to the electronic interface established under subparagraph (A), activities that are required to be completed during the system development lifecycle of such interface, such as secure coding principles and test methodologies.</text>
							</subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5525F1A801954D1AA534CE85EAA5C62D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Analysis of available technology for electronic interface</header>
 <subparagraph id="H9147377754AC454CAC1C0B9CA32B568E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than January 1, 2018, or before entering into a contract to procure or design and build the electronic interface described in paragraph (2) or making a decision to internally design and build such electronic interface, whichever occurs first, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <clause id="H6D8E02F9F794439FB32C90C7CAFBB69A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>conduct an analysis of commercially available technology that may satisfy the requirements of such electronic interface set forth in such paragraph; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9A7786C093BA4D2EAB4A2FEAE40CFD72"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report setting forth such analysis.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCEBF40C1C89484984C7683E58645B2F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required under subparagraph (A)(ii) shall include the following:</text> <clause id="H15363DD8F2DD425C96EBFE9DA92C02EE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>An evaluation of commercially available systems that may satisfy the requirements of paragraph (2).</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFB72DF927D7E4C439062A8C5B5B259DC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The estimated cost of procuring a commercially available system if a suitable commercially available system exists.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA42D3ABC7C4C4B2C9D6C12606E0C44EE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>If no suitable commercially available system exists, an assessment of the feasibility of modifying a commercially available system to meet the requirements of paragraph (2), including the estimated cost associated with such modifications.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H029EC28B44C04E5FB27D780BBC9BEE4A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>If no suitable commercially available system exists and modifying a commercially available system is not feasible, an assessment of the estimated cost and time that would be required to contract with a commercial entity to design and build an electronic interface that meets the requirements of paragraph (2).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6102ED48FD6D4F3E99C6FD36B3FA82FF"><enum>(v)</enum><text>If the Secretary determines that the Department has the capabilities required to design and build an electronic interface that meets the requirements of paragraph (2), an assessment of the estimated cost and time that would be required to design and build such electronic interface.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA07C7DF423BB41D2ABB32C045E5C4116"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>A description of the decision of the Secretary regarding how the Department plans to establish the electronic interface required under paragraph (2) and the justification of the Secretary for such decision.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H53333D3497E24720B3B0E5EFFD80616D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitation on use of amounts</header><text>The Secretary may not spend any amounts to procure or design and build the electronic interface described in paragraph (2) until the date that is 60 days after the date on which the Secretary submits the report required under paragraph (3)(A)(iii).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8AD37C56A92D456B85670EEB1388CE88"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clarification of application of HIPAA transaction standards to Veterans Choice Program and other
			 veterans health care programs using non-Department providers; addressing
			 multi-Year backlog in claims</header>
				<paragraph id="H6B4654AF34684C299E0FC60CE799D9FB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application of HIPAA administrative simplification standards</header>
 <subparagraph id="HA6A1EA18C2674DB7B23DAE00E655A60E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The definition of the term <quote>health plan</quote> under section 1171(5)(J) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320d">42 U.S.C. 1320d(5)(J)</external-xref>) is deemed to include the Veterans Choice Program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H022A59AA9D874DF7B72C84F67A5A9082"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall make such modifications as may be necessary to implement the amendment made by subparagraph (A) with respect to claims for hospital care or medical treatment furnished under the Veterans Choice Program.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB73DF81C595480F90128584DC96B048"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Addressing backlog of claims by non-department providers</header>
 <subparagraph id="H2E504E62CAC7419E86E1F775A8316E21"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Adjudication</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall adjudicate all claims submitted before such date of enactment by non-Department of Veterans Affairs health care provider under the Veterans Choice Program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5689AAB177A41988D8BE612F772B21B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Use of payment schedule for non-department health care providers</header><text>Section 1703A(b) of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a)(1), shall apply to claims adjudicated pursuant to subparagraph (A), except that the timeframe involved shall begin on the date of such adjudication.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4377E42D52F74304B17CA1BD21B8BE48"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Veterans Choice Program defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <quote>Veterans Choice Program</quote> means hospital care or medical treatment furnished to veterans pursuant to section 101 of the Veterans Access, Choice, and Accountability Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/146">Public Law 113–146</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/1701">38 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) or any other law administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs under which a non-Department of Veterans Affairs health care provider furnishes such care or services.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


