<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H114C3D72D2F84F37A3488A45EDEEE2F6" key="H" public-private="public"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1422 RH: Private Flood Insurance Market Development Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code> 
<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 155</calendar> 
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1422</legis-num> 
<associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 115–220]</associated-doc> 
<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20170308">March 8, 2017</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000593">Mr. Ross</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<action>
<action-date date="20170714">July 14, 2017</action-date>
<action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="H001074">Mr. Hollingsworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001195">Mr. Mooney of West Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000599">Mr. Posey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000583">Mr. Loudermilk</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000601">Mr. Palazzo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000583">Mr. Thomas J. Rooney of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000592">Mr. Rokita</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000600">Mr. Diaz-Balart</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001305">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001077">Mr. Coffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000627">Mrs. Demings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000569">Mr. Luetkemeyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001195">Mr. Smith of Missouri</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000816">Mr. Williams</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000586">Mr. Renacci</cosponsor></action-desc>
</action>
<action> 
<action-date date="20170714">July 14, 2017</action-date> 
<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc> 
<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction> 
<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on March 8, 2017</action-instruction> 
</action> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-desc display="yes"><pagebreak/></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973 to require that certain buildings and personal property be covered by flood insurance, and for other purposes.<pagebreak/></official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="no-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HBA00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HC3705BF37A1E463F8F6DE7F1EA6EA364"> 
<section id="HBA5FACE2F93546C5AB9748D586EF63C9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Private Flood Insurance Market Development Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H29DD090C50154F7B92C66E6101EA1CCE" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Private flood insurance</header> <subsection id="HACC7DC11CF874BC5B2CF6D795DD2D3DE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Mandatory purchase requirement</header> <paragraph id="HBB345D04DD6D4BADB32761692A70D567"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Amount and term of coverage</header><text>Section 102 of the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4012a">42 U.S.C. 4012a</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>Sec. 102. (a)</quote> and all that follows through the end of subsection (a) and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA8BE26EE87E74D169F69AF0EA87136F6" style="traditional"> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H30B1A6A95C034007B5861BAB2CB09696" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>102.</enum> 
<subsection id="H9ABA58ADD9A342A8AC0D8B6DC79E5746" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amount and term of coverage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After the expiration of sixty days following the date of the enactment of this Act, no Federal officer or agency shall approve any financial assistance for acquisition or construction purposes for use in any area that has been identified by the Administrator as an area having special flood hazards and in which the sale of flood insurance has been made available under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968, unless the building or mobile home and any personal property to which such financial assistance relates is covered by flood insurance: <italic>Provided,</italic> That the amount of flood insurance (1) in the case of Federal flood insurance, is at least equal to the development or project cost of the building, mobile home, or personal property (less estimated land cost), the outstanding principal balance of the loan, or the maximum limit of Federal flood insurance coverage made available with respect to the particular type of property, whichever is less; or (2) in the case of private flood insurance, is at least equal to the development or project cost of the building, mobile home, or personal property (less estimated land cost), the outstanding principal balance of the loan, or the maximum limit of Federal flood insurance coverage made available with respect to the particular type of property, whichever is less: <italic>Provided further,</italic> That if the financial assistance provided is in the form of a loan or an insurance or guaranty of a loan, the amount of flood insurance required need not exceed the outstanding principal balance of the loan and need not be required beyond the term of the loan. The requirement of maintaining flood insurance shall apply during the life of the property, regardless of transfer of ownership of such property.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6C6A8657BC3B4074B5AB92EA48E32318"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement for mortgage loans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (b) of section 102 of the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4012a">42 U.S.C. 4012a(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9892A961AACC491C93C1D38A77E0A606"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (7);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFBE706C4778F47B6A12CA654F2937233"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (6) as paragraph (7);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H281C0B77BBD44A92A4479566CADE8EB1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking the subsection designation and all that follows through the end of paragraph (5) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H534FA9706DB8469ABBD22F3CB691C329" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H42CB0B742F6A49C5A6D5D1A5A48B4E76" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement for mortgage loans</header> <paragraph id="HDBF6674207124239AB945B55829AAAEC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Regulated lending institutions</header><text>Each Federal entity for lending regulation (after consultation and coordination with the Financial Institutions Examination Council established under the Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council Act of 1974) shall by regulation direct regulated lending institutions not to make, increase, extend, or renew any loan secured by improved real estate or a mobile home located or to be located in an area that has been identified by the Administrator as an area having special flood hazards and in which flood insurance has been made available under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968, unless the building or mobile home and any personal property securing such loan is covered for the term of the loan by flood insurance: <italic>Provided,</italic> That the amount of flood insurance (A) in the case of Federal flood insurance, is at least equal to the outstanding principal balance of the loan or the maximum limit of Federal flood insurance coverage made available with respect to the particular type of property, whichever is less; or (B) in the case of private flood insurance, is at least equal to the outstanding principal balance of the loan or the maximum limit of Federal flood insurance coverage made available with respect to the particular type of property, whichever is less.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9C664E7DE67A4AB4A2F5691DE46603B1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal agency lenders and mortgage insurance and guarantee agencies</header> 
<subparagraph id="H3D7F24AF49614C50AEFD6F3D1112517B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Federal agency lenders</header><text>A Federal agency lender may not make, increase, extend, or renew any loan secured by improved real estate or a mobile home located or to be located in an area that has been identified by the Administrator as an area having special flood hazards and in which flood insurance has been made available under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968, unless the building or mobile home and any personal property securing such loan is covered for the term of the loan by flood insurance in accordance with paragraph (1). Each Federal agency lender may issue any regulations necessary to carry out this paragraph. Such regulations shall be consistent with and substantially identical to the regulations issued under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H19218B768AC845B4B38F28DB52BA4CD7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other Federal mortgage entities</header> <clause id="HAFC1735D12904E218313B86BB6A6FF83"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Coverage requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each covered Federal mortgage entity shall implement procedures reasonably designed to ensure that, for any loan that—</text> 
<subclause id="HA0C6B1E150754B85B81259670D1AFA91"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is secured by improved real estate or a mobile home located in an area that has been identified, at the time of the origination of the loan or at any time during the term of the loan, by the Administrator as an area having special flood hazards and in which flood insurance is available under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968, and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H27D0966F596D4769912EE55D125220FE"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is made, insured, held, or guaranteed by such entity, or backs or on which is based any trust certificate or other security for which such entity guarantees the timely payment of principal and interest,</text></subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">the building or mobile home and any personal property securing the loan is covered for the term of the loan by flood insurance in the amount provided in paragraph (1).</continuation-text></clause> 
<clause id="H5B2708C9D9874307B5EBF59A8F8D4656"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>For purposes of this subparagraph, the term <quote>covered Federal mortgage entity</quote> means—</text> <subclause id="H41EC00CDBCE844C991D7A16FB0FA0DCA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, with respect to mortgages insured under the National Housing Act;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H05CD68096654498195477EE6AB8367B1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to loans made, insured, or guaranteed under title V of the Housing Act of 1949; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H2C1C69E458BF43EF98A5E31A9483B025"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the Government National Mortgage Association.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H07C67BB922AE42909BD4D1B405DE2CFA"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Requirement to accept flood insurance</header><text>Each Federal agency lender and each covered Federal mortgage entity shall accept flood insurance as satisfaction of the flood insurance coverage requirement under subparagraph (A) or (B), respectively, if the flood insurance coverage meets the requirements for coverage under such subparagraph and the requirements relating to financial strength issued pursuant to paragraph (4).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB726E96DBD3F4B96ACBB91BF3215E785"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Government-sponsored enterprises for housing</header><text>The Federal National Mortgage Association and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation shall implement procedures reasonably designed to ensure that, for any loan that is—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HFD25BA362FC645B888F19AE775430E20"><enum>(A)</enum><text>secured by improved real estate or a mobile home located in an area that has been identified, at the time of the origination of the loan or at any time during the term of the loan, by the Administrator as an area having special flood hazards and in which flood insurance is available under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968, and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0964F9F5191C4DD585B0143EF2A8D203"><enum>(B)</enum><text>purchased or guaranteed by such entity,</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">the building or mobile home and any personal property securing the loan is covered for the term of the loan by flood insurance in the amount provided in paragraph (1). The Federal National Mortgage Association and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation shall accept flood insurance as satisfaction of the flood insurance coverage requirement under paragraph (1) if the flood insurance coverage provided meets the requirements for coverage under that paragraph and the requirements relating to financial strength issued pursuant to paragraph (4).</continuation-text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9FDB1E3AD7B64DCA9C8EE708EF74D121"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Requirements regarding financial strength</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency, in consultation with the Federal National Mortgage Association, the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Government National Mortgage Association, and the Secretary of Agriculture shall develop and implement requirements relating to the financial strength of private insurance companies from which such entities and agencies will accept private flood insurance, provided that such requirements shall not affect or conflict with any State law, regulation, or procedure concerning the regulation of the business of insurance.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2B107A1C1F0E4DDFB75889A3F1650BFC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Applicability</header> <subparagraph id="HE67D20A4396145E48C82A68511848527"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Existing coverage</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), paragraph (1) shall apply on the date of enactment of the Riegle Community Development and Regulatory Improvement Act of 1994.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF3A77B3F8EC047118508B4DB221D3730"><enum>(B)</enum><header>New coverage</header><text>Paragraphs (2) and (3) shall apply only with respect to any loan made, increased, extended, or renewed after the expiration of the 1-year period beginning on the date of enactment of the Riegle Community Development and Regulatory Improvement Act of 1994. Paragraph (1) shall apply with respect to any loan made, increased, extended, or renewed by any lender supervised by the Farm Credit Administration only after the expiration of the period under this subparagraph.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7E39D6396C1D4C4F829347AE51C4F821"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Continued effect of regulations</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this subsection, the regulations to carry out paragraph (1), as in effect immediately before the date of enactment of the Riegle Community Development and Regulatory Improvement Act of 1994, shall continue to apply until the regulations issued to carry out paragraph (1) as amended by section 522(a) of such Act take effect.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H178F88B444714DF5A13F6F69E917EB2A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise specified, any reference to flood insurance in this section shall be considered to include Federal flood insurance and private flood insurance. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to supersede or limit the authority of a Federal entity for lending regulation, the Federal Housing Finance Agency, a Federal agency lender, a covered Federal mortgage entity (as such term is defined in paragraph (2)(B)(ii)), the Federal National Mortgage Association, or the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation to establish requirements relating to the financial strength of private insurance companies from which the entity or agency will accept private flood insurance, provided that such requirements shall not affect or conflict with any State law, regulation, or procedure concerning the regulation of the business of insurance.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H23E6E433A04C47A0BAD80D91BEC62F59"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H34B218993FD14C41AD882002C2BD4A59" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H7ED3970553FD4B84A7B7D21979EAB072"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <subparagraph id="H4E23774B112A4F2FAA1C347F0914C399"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Flood insurance</header><text>The term <term>flood insurance</term> means—</text> 
<clause id="H99DC0CE036544C008E22AE42BBDAB446"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Federal flood insurance; and</text></clause> <clause id="H97340AE4B3F246F290F5B87197DFF917"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>private flood insurance.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB0D76C1C5D8D46878B43665EC73F110E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Federal flood insurance</header><text>The term <term>Federal flood insurance</term> means an insurance policy made available under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4001">42 U.S.C. 4001</external-xref> et seq.).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB89EFA3587B24C59A7AA1285437BE464"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Private flood insurance</header><text>The term <term>private flood insurance</term> means an insurance policy that—</text> 
<clause id="HE451EC703A4B49E789D37BF1DCFE449D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is issued by an insurance company that is—</text> <subclause id="HCAB11BE9144D49C7A2ECBA8376446D62"><enum>(I)</enum><text>licensed, admitted, or otherwise approved to engage in the business of insurance in the State in which the insured building is located, by the insurance regulator of that State; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H3C2A39B97CB84CC395D433C1D9E541E2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>eligible as a nonadmitted insurer to provide insurance in the home State of the insured, in accordance with sections 521 through 527 of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/8201">15 U.S.C. 8201</external-xref> through 8206);</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HDCF94F15D472475F8F3AD355F06CE7C6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is issued by an insurance company that is not otherwise disapproved as a surplus lines insurer by the insurance regulator of the State in which the property to be insured is located; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H544B40C64E484DFC9B9BBDD82CA02DF9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provides flood insurance coverage that complies with the laws and regulations of that State.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H80AA616F6B9140E080F6E71FD2300D30"><enum>(D)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, the Northern Mariana Islands, the Virgin Islands, and American Samoa.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB5881A11C4A54ED9A054D1DFFCC1F5DB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effect of private flood insurance coverage on continuous coverage requirements</header><text>Section 1308 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4015">42 U.S.C. 4015</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3AD94CD70C484F9483A233C2F51313A6" style="OLC"> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFDD9D051289042EEA70AADD4F253D27D"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Effect of private flood insurance coverage on continuous coverage requirements</header><text>For purposes of applying any statutory, regulatory, or administrative continuous coverage requirement, including under section 1307(g)(1), the Administrator shall consider any period during which a property was continuously covered by private flood insurance (as defined in section 102(b)(8) of the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4012a">42 U.S.C. 4012a(b)(8)</external-xref>)) to be a period of continuous coverage.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
<endorsement display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20170714">July 14, 2017</action-date> 
<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement> 
</bill> 


