<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H74A8B7393A6E487187AE5283FD77D75B" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1933 IH: Health Care Options Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1933</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170405">April 5, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000533">Mr. Duncan of Tennessee</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000582">Mr. Roe of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000392">Mr. Kustoff of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000459">Mr. Fleischmann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000616">Mr. DesJarlais</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001243">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001273">Mrs. Black</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow individuals to receive a premium assistance
			 credit for insurance not purchased on an Exchange, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HBF3CAC60D06947458EB0AEBDA47BEAAD" style="OLC">
 <section id="H9DBD709FFF9B4EC7B2A2F087C170B0CD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Health Care Options Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H04C6BE00470E496ABC39E0E516FF9460" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Premium assistance credit allowed for insurance outside an Exchange</header> <subsection id="HEEB34AC14ADE42EBBDB2E7C44D155564"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">Section 36B</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by redesignating subsection (g) as subsection (h) and by inserting after subsection (f) the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block act-name="" id="H38474EDAD1C942C7AFF5EBE4EA3D900C" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H8067BE9720AE4D1DA78DFA32B7A7FA6A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Special rules relating to certain off-Exchange plans</header>
 <paragraph id="H68CF86B29BD74B45B7F09991DEE1BFF4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a taxpayer described in paragraph (2) who is covered, or whose spouse or dependent is covered, by a plan described in paragraph (3) for a coverage month beginning after December 31, 2017, and before January 1, 2020, this section shall be applied with the following modifications:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1D12E0A78CB24344944CFBBC82074BBF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Such plan shall be treated as a qualified health plan.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8ADE5CD9E0A8413487F6C60A689E8CB7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Subparagraph (A) of subsection (b)(2) shall be applied without regard to so much of such subparagraph as follows <quote>of the taxpayer</quote> and precedes <quote>, or</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93A8DC1C9F75436FA52C3F4FFD4B6595"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Clause (i) of subsection (b)(3)(B) shall be applied by substituting <quote>through an Exchange</quote> for <quote>through the same Exchange through which the qualified health plans taken into account under paragraph (2)(A) were offered</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8B25FE636BE4E889B73F17A6F5CEDE2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Clause (i) of subsection (c)(2)(A) shall be applied without regard to so much of such clause as follows <quote>(b)(2)(A)</quote> and precedes <quote>, and</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5496679AA174BCB99900715D1DD5249"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Subsection (d)(3)(B) shall be applied without regard to <quote>through an Exchange</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C725BC8090846FB9D437AE5BAFC6B2B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Taxpayer described</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, a taxpayer is described in this paragraph if the taxpayer resides in a rating area or county in which the Secretary of Health and Human Services certifies that no qualified health plans are offered through an Exchange established under Section 1311 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF3EA29450B4346B9B5A8A0AE65C037C9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Plans described</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, a plan is described in this paragraph if—</text> <subparagraph id="H1EFD3CB6CF324E0DB0183E410A316F12"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enrollment in the plan was not done through an Exchange, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB90B049BA6D34A8DA62870F744163EB4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the plan is authorized by the State in which the taxpayer resides to be offered in the individual market in the State other than through an Exchange, or is a not-for-profit membership organization organized under State law and authorized under State law to accept member contributions to fund health care benefits for members and their families.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA2CE7506E7C94CA3AB13CF493DABE8A0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Off-Exchange plans excluded from advance payments</header><text>Section 1412 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18082">42 U.S.C. 18082</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block act-name="" id="H0962B2992FA24E408402683B4315572F" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HA85F34697F274AD18F7D9F655D59E326"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Nonapplication to off-Exchange plans</header><text>This section and section 1411 shall not apply, and no advance determination or advance payment shall be made, in the case of an individual enrolling in a plan described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">section 36B(g)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H38E3C5DB222B47C39808C0D1C354E00A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>Subsection (b) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6055">section 6055</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB80820C267E64D3588AB90E5A437AAE6" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H6E4696D1EBA1435BAC22339AF7CEFE09"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Information relating to off-Exchange coverage</header><text>If minimum essential coverage provided to an individual under subsection (a) consists of coverage described in section 36B(g)(3), a return described in this subsection for taxable years beginning before January 1, 2020, shall include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H48DAE1C19EB0443A90BF141739BAFE5E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a statement that such plan is coverage not enrolled in through an Exchange,</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD11D7BB0448F4CFE8D87E072B8C30656"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the premiums paid with respect to such coverage,</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F0F67112F6E4955A7B4CDA760C1C5D6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the months during which such coverage is provided to the individual,</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF88798FDA3E5433E80402A5DFB536ED2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the adjusted monthly premium for the applicable second lowest cost silver plan (as defined in section 36B(b)(3), determined without regard to whether such plan is offered through an Exchange if the Secretary of Health and Human Services has made the determination under section 36B(g)(2) with respect to the rating area) for each such month with respect to such individual, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E7E462D71F64A34BD9745C877FAEFF1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary may prescribe.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="HDB8037A71D1D40969F0CB05B6F9E465B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Waiver of individual mandate in areas with no Exchange plans</header> <paragraph id="H9B6AE6DCD7C9467BB25636D6D2C06B82"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Paragraph (1) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5000A">section 5000A(d)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>or (4)</quote> and inserting <quote>(4), or (5)</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7760D93BC5D84DF0BA1B64E63693D312"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Individuals residing in exempted areas</header><text>Subsection (d) of section 5000A of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block act-name="" id="H56CDDB9722D440A5A43DC801224CF338" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H61AD242F700D43DC8030678D49CA1951"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Individuals residing in exempted areas</header><text>For purposes of months beginning after December 31, 2017, and before January 1, 2020, such term shall not include an individual who resides in a rating area or county in which the Secretary of Health and Human Services certifies for purposes of section 36B(g)(2) that no qualified health plans are offered through an Exchange established under Section 1311 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCEF358313A1942F68FDF488EC6AF8486"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable and plan years beginning after December 31, 2017.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


