<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1D099DE2C61C4B10A825701733C121C4" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3135 IH: Community Flood Insurance Savings Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3135</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170629">June 29, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Maxine Waters of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to make grants to
			 consortia of States and communities to hire individuals to coordinate the
			 Community Rating System program under the National Flood Insurance Program
			 for the States and communities who are members of the consortia, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H8EBBCDE0543A4600894DC64D1248D7D9" style="OLC">
 <section id="H4A768735D27041F89CC91C4C88D338EC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Community Flood Insurance Savings Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H0446E3315384409495A2D170FFADD7AA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants for Community Rating System program coordinators</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1315 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4022">42 U.S.C. 4022</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6845FD309EE441B491C96F3D2A264D2C" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="HA1CAEC071F744F6880C880D7A9EA183B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grants for Community Rating System program coordinators</header>
 <paragraph id="HC7975DB97FDF4D63B47910CDD2B07BC4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall carry out a program to make grants to consortia of States and communities for use only for costs of employing or otherwise retaining an individual or individuals to coordinate and carry out responsibilities relating to participation in the community rating system program under subsection (b) for States and communities that are members of such consortia.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBC3C5664FA05404DA62BC5B73B168097"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall establish such criteria as the Administrator considers appropriate for a consortium of States and communities to be eligible for grants under this subsection, which shall include requiring a consortium to provide evidence to the Administrator that the consortium has sufficient authority and administrative capability to use grant amounts in accordance with this subsection on behalf of its member jurisdictions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8189BC8B70DA44FDB5BC4BD2E60ACF40"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Timing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A consortium receiving a grant under this section shall establish the position or positions described in paragraph (1), and employ or otherwise retain an individual or individuals to fill such position or positions, not later than the date that all such grant amounts are expended.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H05FBC6D7FD8646FDA2D154448F91135F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>The Administrator shall provide for consortia of States and communities to submit applications for grants under this subsection, which shall include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8CADCDD5CBA646FEB897D3388B575782"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the evidence referred to in paragraph (2);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D65F1875B184DCBB9C47159487B7B61"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such assurances as the Administrator shall require to ensure compliance with the requirement under paragraph (3);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H26AEE7598E1E4D5FBEC25149BFEE1BCD"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such assurances as the Administrator shall require to ensure that the consortia will provide funding sufficient to continue the position or positions funded with the grant amounts, in the same annual amount as under such grant funding, after such grant funds are expended; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A8ADDFDFA2845F1A64BD8D2EE184178"><enum>(D)</enum><text>such other information as the Administrator may require.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0590182BB9A84F4AADEB37B5D7AB974D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Selection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From among eligible consortia of States and communities submitting applications pursuant to paragraph (3), the Administrator shall select consortia to receive grants under this subsection in accordance with such competitive criteria for such section as the Administrator shall establish.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1CBA77D0379445A7AA7B62D6F7D7A689"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Definition of community</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <quote>community</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 1366(h) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4104c">42 U.S.C. 4104c(h)</external-xref>), except that such term includes counties and regional planning authorities that do not have zoning and building code jurisdiction.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H974E546A652743AD91757447E599ED5F"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated for grants under this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="HB9184F4B96E0411A93B1E5D723B05D60"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$7,000,000 for the first fiscal year commencing after the expiration of the 4-month period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5DE1A3B274A240788DFC9826FC1EEFDE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$7,000,000 for each of the four consecutive fiscal years thereafter.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section></legis-body></bill> 

