<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB6E09FD08A674C068C29D4BE46E577FC" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2779 IH: Assessing Critical Care Efforts to Strengthen Services (ACCESS) Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2779</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170606">June 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000612">Mr. Denham</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XI of the Social Security Act to provide through the Center for Medicare and
			 Medicaid Innovation (CMMI) for a Medicaid payment model demonstration
			 project on Medicaid reimbursement for physicians’ services in counties
			 with a disproportionately high proportion of Medicaid enrollees.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H4A7574887B1E482CA2FDA92CC6828C44" style="OLC">
 <section id="H21E81C8698084CD3A0057B2F7469AB6A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Assessing Critical Care Efforts to Strengthen Services (ACCESS) Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H1939BBCBE6A94063B32CD47D7DF961BA"><enum>2.</enum><header>CMMI Medicaid payment model demonstration project on Medicaid reimbursement for physicians’ services in counties with a disproportionately high proportion of Medicaid enrollees</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1115A(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1315a">42 U.S.C. 1315a(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H49C7D930DF5646E18CDBA778FC05B5AC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(B), by adding at the end the following new clause:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H205380E2B089497F9C860A1C484F8813" style="OLC"> <clause id="H9C11C53DD9714C139A6480F7C015337C"><enum>(xxv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Focusing on payment models under title XIX for recruiting and retaining physicians to serve low-income applicable individuals residing in disproportionate share counties (as defined in paragraph (5)(D)).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCEF1C2C1BF8C48BEA1688F2CFAA5FB95"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA3FE46E90D854240A122B7EBD292DA56" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HC80731AD3E324D29878D3E861DC4C0F0"><enum>(5)</enum><header> Medicaid physicians’ service model for low-income individuals in disproportionate share counties</header> <subparagraph id="HEBFE13CC73014F69A7CE73C5396E8396"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Selection</header><text>Beginning not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this paragraph, the Secretary shall select for testing one or more models described in paragraph (2)(B)(xxv).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4F5C0CF839B4361B900B94A06F9B474"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Design</header><text>In selecting, and designing the testing for, such a model under this subsection, CMI shall—</text> <clause id="H3C2E93F8B76A4CE8934291CB7CB5E1F3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>review the most successful models for recruiting and retaining physicians to serve low-income applicable individuals residing in a disproportionate share county (as defined in subparagraph (D)); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H54A0DC00A0724D3393B4E95512636868"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">incorporate lessons from successful strategies that take into account how access to physicians’ services has improved for such individuals.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E75BF3F512348C992842A2581FDF7D2"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>In evaluating the performance of such a model under paragraph (4), CMI shall—</text> <clause id="H6FB62840F3B24B358A1A0644D3B7712D"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluate the applicability and expansion of the model to inform national strategies to best leverage funds under title XIX to improve access to physicians’ services for low-income applicable individuals residing in a disproportionate share county; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEF23E8E5E7294C69B86D7AC2DAF07000"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">examine the degree to which Medicaid payment strategies (such as the use of primary case management, medical homes, and palliative care, the use of payment rates for physicians’ services that are not less than the Medicare payment rates that apply to such care and services under part B of title XVIII, and allowing Federally-qualified health centers to contract with specialty physicians to be paid at Federally-qualified health center payment rates for services furnished in a physician’s office), including such strategies as modified through such a model, improve access, outcomes, and patient satisfaction for such individuals and reduce emergency department utilization by such individuals.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HADD04B320194417CBA0CA38F8F7CF34B"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Disproportionate share county defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this paragraph, the term <term>disproportionate share county</term> means a county in which at least 35 percent of the residents of the county are enrolled under the State plan under title XIX (or under a waiver of such plan).</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


