<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HBDA4C56809734B118655FD67F1E56438" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3789 IH: High School Football Safety Study Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3789</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170914">September 14, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000588">Mr. Richmond</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000374">Mr. Abraham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000063">Mr. Yoder</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001170">Ms. Shea-Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000619">Mr. Rodney Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000248">Mr. Serrano</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Centers
			 for Disease Control and Prevention, and in consultation with the Secretary
			 of Education and the President’s Council on Fitness, Sports, and
			 Nutrition, to conduct a study on the causes of deaths related to high
			 school football and formulate recommendations to prevent such deaths.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HC5B94F548D1A43C39B6E9614D1FD9F90" style="OLC">
 <section id="H0B4F0F85FA6141209888D3A199E8F2FB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>High School Football Safety Study Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H7881F689356B4BFC85699146BCDDA6A9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="H8350F8F9AE8445DC902C7A533C3A78AB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As of August 14, 2017, two high school football players—Kamari McGowan and Joshua Mileto—have passed away during the 2017 calendar year during football practice from causes directly or indirectly related to football.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9B5E74D41C6649BA827D2630EF7C89DB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to the National Center for Catastrophic Sports Injury Research, 1,222 high school and middle school football players have passed away between 1931 and 2016 from causes directly or indirectly related to football.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3FC6A7015051475F8151D3853160E0FC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Over the past several years, the negative health effects of repeated head trauma have become clearer.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFACC6C47069A463DA12E8A59B38ADE02"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Protecting the Nation’s children is one of the most important responsibilities of parents and Members of Congress.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H334D517B3FA94F97B8D252E59C96B70C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Studying high school football deaths and developing recommendations to prevent future tragedies</header>
 <subsection id="HA2DCBE71DBB44C42929C63F645C71884"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, and in consultation with the Secretary of Education and the President’s Council on Fitness, Sports, and Nutrition, shall conduct a study—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4999445A349D4318A187E800CB164834"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to more precisely identify the causes of deaths related to high school football; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA2EA71FFE9C84CD089D86B7A87098A61"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to develop recommendations to prevent such deaths in the future.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC6204530041144829156C2CC2CCCE768"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Soliciting input</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall seek input from nongovernmental entities, including organizations representing football coaches, athletic trainers, parents, and health care professionals.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H91F379C675D34F89BF866B6778568001"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Congress and publish on the public Website of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality a report on the results of the study under subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9B57A9FCC2054929BA5DFF1FF2C8BFF4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report under subsection (a) shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H0DA43A206F26472B94C51E15DEC075DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a comprehensive review of research conducted on deaths in high school football;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE48C0963FD7B4019974EFE785EDBC239"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an evaluation of causes of deaths related to high school football; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H19E856FA1EDD4DD888130173524612D6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommendations on actions that can be taken by schools, coaches, trainers, and governmental entities to prevent high school deaths from occurring in the future, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6F1267D727EA42C0BE783DC384273F0F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>measures to prevent life-threatening injury from occurring;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D731B8D09DE409A9349C92E0AC7C2E3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>medical treatment protocols to treat these injuries when they occur; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7814150D49524C0A8C7D49F681DDDD0D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ways in which technology and data analytics can be used to prevent serious injury and death.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

