<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H214BD94809DD46F6A722DE34B9CA5A84" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2871 IH: Preserving Patient Access to Compounded Medications Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2871</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170612">June 12, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000568">Mr. Griffith</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001063">Mr. Cuellar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to compounding pharmacies, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H0104B924266247EF8E28202845D52D30" style="OLC">
 <section id="H45C9E653314943F9B8963012289A057D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preserving Patient Access to Compounded Medications Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HE9084244CC03442687DABF487433DCD6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Office-use compounding when authorized by State law</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 503A(a) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/353a">21 U.S.C. 353a(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H65C03CC53ABF46A6884944A69DE4330D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>or drug order for administration to a patient in an office or clinical setting</quote> after <quote>is necessary for the identified patient</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAD7E4571C24043AEAE9DDDF4B9A99DD0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H42A73CB6306B4171B2672D3C4416B74D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB61A36768878439599C5C014E8F665EF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HF5C63208E9B84C259D99EF6E7BDBBBCF" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H21F29B7E2D4C46EC8C75737815C67C1B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is by a licensed pharmacist or licensed physician pursuant to a valid prescription order or drug order and the compounded drug is distributed or dispensed to a licensed prescriber in accordance with State law, for administration to a patient in an office or clinical setting.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H3A99877465CE46829F3EE83B9DCAD5E4"><enum>3.</enum><header>United States pharmacopoeia or national formulary monograph requirement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 503A(b)(1)(A) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/353A">21 U.S.C. 353A(b)(1)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H09250267BCFD454EACFAA6E3782A24CF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subclause (i), by inserting <quote>, or dietary supplements</quote> after <quote>Regulations</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8E4DDE11E54143DBAB724A305A09125F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (i)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFEAD83A5389140FB9863B4FF0515ED2B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by amending subclause (I) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="HCBF7156C1BF74D89B6AB50C4893B73B7" style="OLC"> <subclause id="H39488B2EEFF44E2F8B124E1AC6CBB9FC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>comply with the monograph standards in any section of the of the United States Pharmacopoeia or National Formulary, including drug substance or dietary supplement monograph, if a monograph exists.</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF547D3BB2F16409B9AC674D2DBD847C3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by amending subclause (III) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="H51A12D30318C4200A9D91DC63C3DABDF" style="OLC"> <subclause id="H6C2EB36CC7C241C0B5CB77B3705A6664"><enum>(III)</enum><text>if such monograph does not exist and the drug substance or dietary supplement is not a component of a drug approved by the Secretary, but appears on a list developed by the Secretary through regulations issued by the Secretary under subsection (c) of this section;</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H2EA9880AA4A9485AB68A9AAD1FC6C923"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subsection (e) of section 503A of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/353a">21 U.S.C. 353a</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
			<quoted-block id="HD4CAC4C1402A4723A173E243F86550C8" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H9E4987F5AD8346359618F4589D5EFCC3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HF86DD62E93F84E7382CE71F87BA9CCEE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Compounding</header><text>The term <quote>compounding</quote> does not include mixing, reconstituting, or other such acts that are performed in accordance with directions contained in approved labeling provided by the product’s manufacturer and other manufacturer directions consistent with that labeling.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H946211FC596A422EB92D981C57DF7D5D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Distribute or distribution</header><text>The terms <quote>distribute</quote> or <quote>distribution</quote> do not include the act of dispensing of a compounded drug product in accordance with this section.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H564E0E02CD4F464187C07C9FDCD4A7E4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Dispense</header><text>The term <quote>dispense</quote> means for a drug product compounded in accordance with this section, the act of the drug product leaving the facility in which it was compounded for delivery to a patient, patient’s agent, or health care facility (including a hospital, physician’s office, or other health care setting) pursuant to a valid prescription order for an identified patient.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="H446572BFE1DC44B8B0CF88AF8788C629"><enum>5.</enum><header>Applicability of records exemption for compounding pharmacies</header>
 <subsection id="H7C25BEF73AF64C098E0EC75DD344AEAF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 704(a)(2)(A) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/374">21 U.S.C. 374(a)(2)(A)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H85966EF6ECB64EF7AFA7515A2D112CBB" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H0C2C89CD2D7F40438963621CCFA4AD81"><enum>(A)</enum><text>pharmacies which maintain establishments in conformance with any applicable local laws regulating the practice of pharmacy and medicine and, for compounding pharmacies, the provisions of section 503A, and which are regularly engaged in dispensing or distributing prescription drugs or devices, upon prescriptions or drug orders of practitioners licensed to administer such drugs or devices to patients under the care of such practitioners in the course of their professional practice, and which do not, either through a subsidiary or otherwise, manufacture, prepare, propagate, compound, or process drugs or devices for sale other than in the regular course of their business;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF713A00F895448989713127137A63BEB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Registration exemption</header><text>Section 510(g)(1) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360">21 U.S.C. 360(g)(1)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H6FC306FDA6204FB2B5110F21CB9DCB14" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H8319220356544921B41849F3A9C0429C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>pharmacies which maintain establishments in conformance with any applicable local laws regulating the practice of pharmacy and medicine and, for compounding pharmacies, the provisions of section 503A, and which are regularly engaged in dispensing or distributing prescription drugs or devices, upon prescriptions or drug orders of practitioners licensed to administer such drugs or devices to patients under the care of such practitioners in the course of their professional practice, and which do not manufacture, prepare, propagate, compound, or process drugs or devices for sale other than in the regular course of their business;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="HD1E647E57D5E4512991271EC121417A2"><enum>6.</enum><header>Regulations</header>
 <subsection id="H1CC1C93AD2C54FB5A29F6DD348730D3B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rules implementing new requirements</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall promulgate rules on the record to carry out the amendments made by this Act, in accordance with <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA241498DEE3F4BD1A3E0853603CFC7BD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Other rules</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall promulgate rules on the record to carry out any of the provisions of section 503A of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/353a">21 U.S.C. 353a</external-xref>) other than those amended by this Act, in accordance with <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


