<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H5669516A43CE46618D8BDC7215CE95FB" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1579 IH: Secure and Resilient Water Systems Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1579</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170316">March 16, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require drinking water systems to assess and address their vulnerabilities to climate change,
			 source water degradation, and intentional acts to ensure security and
			 resiliency.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H9C6F93F57AB143E6B790D1E1079D6805" style="OLC">
 <section id="HB9FF5007EDA640698D689B20C5FF5A2C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Secure and Resilient Water Systems Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HE4B609CB0BDE4F688493F644B543E23F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Climate resiliency, security, and source water protection planning</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1433 of the Safe Drinking Water Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300i-2">42 U.S.C. 300i–2</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H615916D731FE4790B51D3DFED762468E" style="OLC">
				<section id="H6E568C3717574AB4BD6D289C0BF778DB"><enum>1433.</enum><header>Climate resiliency, security, and source water protection</header>
					<subsection id="H5F650D8478934847804B264F40402B79"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Source water and distribution system vulnerability assessments</header>
 <paragraph id="HA959A116574F4041983B3B3FAC8D01D9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 24 months after the date of enactment of the Secure and Resilient Water Systems Act, each community water system shall submit to the Administrator source water and distribution system vulnerability assessments.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBA4AB748EB7F4B8D981985B1817EDD7E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Identification of threats</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assessments submitted pursuant to paragraph (1) shall identify—</text> <subparagraph id="H2ED692D2F00D49C9A5DC386DA4C9A158"><enum>(A)</enum><text>threats to the community water system’s source water from industrial activity, pipelines and storage tanks, contaminated sites, agricultural activity, and oil and gas exploration;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFAC2F0F2F2774772A8EABAC92349C2DF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">threats to the community water system’s source water and distribution system from climate change, extreme weather, drought, and temperature changes; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H526965F7091347D0B9DB7F4754F87234"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">threats to the community water system’s source water and distribution system from intentional acts, including intentional contamination, sabotage, and theft of any chemical of interest (as designated under Appendix A to part 27 of title 6, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor thereto).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H58CC0D0E305A4111806CE4512777A8FD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Assessment of alternatives</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assessments submitted pursuant to paragraph (1) shall include a comparison of the disinfection methods used by the community water system and reasonably available alternative disinfection methods, including a determination of whether reasonably available alternative disinfection methods could reduce the community water system’s vulnerability to the threats identified pursuant to paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0065C8F8CA4B4B38AF4BCA9ACF45264C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Periodic review and resubmission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each community water system submitting a vulnerability assessment pursuant to paragraph (1) shall review, revise as necessary, and resubmit such assessment not less often than every 5 years.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4DABF657445A4115A59A8C89339058A7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of enactment of the Secure and Resilient Water Systems Act, the Administrator shall provide guidance to community water systems for the preparation of vulnerability assessments under this subsection.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD4073EB3926B44DCAB7D4A71A7AB5898"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Source water and distribution system protection plans</header>
 <paragraph id="H710CB670915D4F8CBB713B43C2ED5AEB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 4 years after the date of enactment of the Secure and Resilient Water Systems Act, each community water system shall submit to the Administrator source water and distribution system protection plans.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB16B85C4D7C04AF0BB4BDF4EB1674B55"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Mitigation of identified threats</header><text>Plans submitted pursuant to paragraph (1) shall identify strategies and resources to mitigate the threats identified in assessments prepared pursuant to subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC00CD121C6F844428B4491D742454ACF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Emergency response planning</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Plans submitted pursuant to paragraph (1) shall include specific emergency response plans for the threats identified in assessments prepared pursuant to subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB28B43590ABD4F59A00A4EDDA45CFD1A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Periodic review and resubmission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each community water system submitting a plan pursuant to paragraph (1) shall review, revise as necessary, and resubmit such plan not less often than every 5 years.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H335429A898BE45999DC931CF63914921"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of enactment of the Secure and Resilient Water Systems Act, the Administrator shall provide guidance to community water systems for the preparation of plans under this subsection.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9A7829725D2D4299A108D04A84904EA4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Technical assistance and grants</header>
 <paragraph id="HB72629551B734F49BAAE3257CF93AFFE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall establish and implement a program, to be known as the Drinking Water Infrastructure Resiliency and Sustainability Program, under which the Administrator may award grants in each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022 to owners or operators of community water systems for the purpose of increasing the resiliency or adaptability of the community water systems to threats identified pursuant to subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H20B6F908A64F450AB54E941C66AF3589"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a condition on receipt of a grant under this section, an owner or operator of a community water system shall agree to use the grant funds exclusively to assist in the planning, design, construction, implementation, operation, or maintenance of a program or project consistent with a plan developed pursuant to subsection (b).</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="HE7D99E8DF98D4719B0CDA986365CC8E1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Priority</header>
 <subparagraph id="HCEB6ECAEE3F642E19D82F5CCCD357228"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Water systems at greatest and most immediate risk</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In selecting grantees under this subsection, the Administrator shall give priority to applicants that are owners or operators of community water systems that are, based on the best available research and data, at the greatest and most immediate risk of facing significant negative impacts due to threats described in subsection (a)(2).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H002446602CB74276851A1C0DAAB7407A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Goals</header><text>In selecting among applicants described in subparagraph (A), the Administrator shall ensure that, to the maximum extent practicable, the final list of applications funded for each year includes a substantial number that propose to use innovative approaches to meet one or more of the following goals:</text>
 <clause id="HC2AF48D6DC0C4C7A9FD2390874F12315"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Promoting more efficient water use, water conservation, water reuse, or water recycling.</text> </clause><clause id="HAE4B26041AC94CA6B248E8ED84BB1852"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Using decentralized, low-impact development technologies and nonstructural approaches, including practices that use, enhance, or mimic the natural hydrological cycle or protect natural flows.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H17E1AFE6D70D4190B09685FE6EB9BBE6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Reducing stormwater runoff or flooding by protecting or enhancing natural ecosystem functions.</text> </clause><clause id="H9B2EFB939D894CE59783DC66D7535062"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Modifying, upgrading, enhancing, or replacing existing community water system infrastructure in response to changing hydrologic conditions.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDE08F732643145D0A9A113B198AC7085"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Improving water quality or quantity for agricultural and municipal uses, including through salinity reduction.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H15B1B04A47204520A3F203C8A427005E"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Providing multiple benefits, including to water supply enhancement or demand reduction, water quality protection or improvement, increased flood protection, and ecosystem protection or improvement.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C94622D51914121A4368610FECFB0D0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Cost-sharing</header>
 <subparagraph id="H3C86942265A247EC8CB6B46CC304B849"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Federal share</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The share of the cost of any activity that is the subject of a grant awarded by the Administrator to the owner or operator of a community water system under this subsection shall not exceed 50 percent of the cost of the activity.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1904C6EEFD554A6C8AF425A92D1485F2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Calculation of non-Federal share</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In calculating the non-Federal share of the cost of an activity proposed by a community water system in an application submitted under this subsection, the Administrator shall—</text>
 <clause id="HFF68677696934EE29D32E6BF6F7CE7ED"><enum>(i)</enum><text>include the value of any in-kind services that are integral to the completion of the activity, including reasonable administrative and overhead costs; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0160EE7706D645289811DBB23DB88E4D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not include any other amount that the community water system involved receives from the Federal Government.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4B5DE43DE00D45F99A0996A24145B316"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of the Secure and Resilient Water Systems Act, and every 3 years thereafter, the Administrator shall submit to the Congress a report on progress in implementing this subsection, including information on project applications received and funded annually.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H591C885BB12C4EA393B186D0B93A55E8"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out this subsection, there are authorized to be appropriated $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


