<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE04549260C124630BA520BDD528C51AA" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2414 IH: SWAMP Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2414</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170511">May 11, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To limit the amount of expenditure on Presidential travel, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H637F2D1F97D649B9A2DAB8CC80ACB3AB" style="OLC">
 <section id="HECE43BA6D6104ED5A5D831771C21775A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Waste And Misuse by the President Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or as the <quote>SWAMP Act of 2017</quote>.</text> </section><section id="H2C58435587D346998499A8832F144E5D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="H77E6FB731B004864A5C99CD9E7204CF6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Presidential travel to commercial entities owned in whole or in part by the President or First Family results in the American taxpayer effectively subsidizing the President’s businesses.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE9E90BCC07FB439489697753AC65CD3F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Given current expenditures, President Trump is on track to spend more during his first year of office than all eight years of the Obama administration combined.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H295C6942E73E41D5BF06AE37B17C9F64"><enum>(3)</enum><text>It is unacceptable for the President to maintain an interest in traveling to properties in which he has a direct financial interest, as the U.S. Government is responsible for renting space for personnel in said private commercial entities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H19C60858D86A4562B87B980CF7A4CB85"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Every time the President travels to Mar-a-Lago, he necessarily promotes his private business interests via free press at the Government’s expense.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0309E8A877AE4DA7BFE8319A63601402"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The State Department’s recent promotion of Mar-a-Lago on its official website raises serious ethics concerns.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3F56D39044534BABBBAB6BA6A9328A60"><enum>(6)</enum><text>As of April 14, 2017, President Trump has cost the U.S. taxpayer unprecedented amounts of money, including the following estimated costs:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFA6947B1702B4725BD0EC5974ED3664C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>For trips to Mar-a-Lago:</text> <clause id="HB34DE7DEB20A4165B38BFFD11B0EC6BC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Total cost for security in Palm Beach: $3,700,000 (each trip).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H36655110368941A686CB875B4D360BE9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Roundtrip flights from Joint Base Andrews, Maryland, to West Palm, Florida: $700,000.</text> </clause><clause id="H774575DE81EC44DAB3265DFC17FD73FA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Overtime for local law enforcement during Trump’s trips: $60,000/day.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H73D2EFC8E0D448EF8B1374D12A66A3EF"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Total golf cart rentals ordered by the Secret Service <quote>for POTUS visit</quote>: $35,185.</text> </clause><clause id="H3049EA30029B44C89585A0EF14D579DD"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Estimated loss of business due to airport closure: $30,000/weekend.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5362F91E8D55491AAFA03A62343A1569"><enum>(B)</enum><text>For Trump Tower:</text> <clause id="HC421287FCE394B15BD2D7F878B4F5D45"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Request for additional Secret Service funding to secure Trump Towers: $60,000,000.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4DD74CBF945244F788A57E9741EAA0C9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>New York Police Department security costs: $127,000–$146,000/day.</text> </clause><clause id="H5686AB894BA14F19B18D91058584FDA2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text><quote>Elevator services</quote> ordered by the Secret Service: $64,000.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H07A2237CF9E2431B944F3FABFBD63B8E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Air Force One flights to New York City: $180,000/hour.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H59B81C7DF9E74864B0FA5081F38B47ED"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The proposed 2017 Federal spending bill includes reimbursements for millions of dollars spent by Florida and New York to protect the President and First Family, and facilitate their travel. While localities should be reimbursed, the taxpayer should not be responsible for said reimbursement.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HD82BBDB54AF244FE9AA7E2D4C78478EE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reimbursal for costs of protection</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In the case of a person whom the United States Secret Service is authorized to protect under paragraph (1) or (2) of section 3056(a) of title 18, United States Code, if that person, while traveling for official business or for personal purposes, stays in a hotel or other establishment providing daily-rate accommodation in which that person has an ownership or financial interest, that person shall reimburse to the Treasury—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF06175905DC34896A86D6C59D26BCD2A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any amount expended by the United States Secret Service for the provision of such protection; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H555A2EF442BA49D8935CB3FB87A0613F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any amount expended for other costs incurred by the Government pertaining to that stay.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


