<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0D625E1F66B04DE8A78A1E5506794C75" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2703 IH: Legal Services for Homeless Veterans Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2703</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170525">May 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to enter into agreements with public and private entities to provide pro bono legal services to homeless veterans and veterans at risk of homelessness, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDC7337ED5AE944C5B8C7F70104B9F69B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8427C834A1BD4B64BF8344EF885D863E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Legal Services for Homeless Veterans Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H037B00DE870B415CB6CE4B6BE488B8FB" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Agreements with public and private entities to provide legal services to homeless veterans and veterans at risk of homelessness</header> <subsection id="HE059ECDC956A4CE587DEE922A97F5416"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/20">Chapter 20</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/2022">section 2022</external-xref> the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA497A3B943E74B06B1EDB7511CE651E7" style="USC"> 
<section id="H0944C17DDCF14966A84DE374B403E155"><enum>2022A.</enum><header>Agreements with public and private entities to provide pro bono legal services to homeless veterans and veterans at risk of homelessness</header> 
<subsection id="H41C5CE15E98D44D9A2EE7A3FE5F8939F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Agreements authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the availability of funds for that purpose, the Secretary may enter into an agreement with a public or private entity, through the award of a grant or the use of a contract, to fund a portion of legal services described in subsection (b).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H88542905F6F548A885D3011821CD8BC5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Pro bono legal services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Legal services described in this subsection are provided pro bono to a homeless veteran or veteran at risk of homelessness, including the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H77A3459BD2004E6081E74DD64516EA0C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Legal services related to housing, including eviction defense and representation in landlord-tenant cases.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H37116BC7945847EC9F93469745CA1349"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Legal services related to family law, including assistance in court proceedings for child support, divorce, and estate planning.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1BFF6B5C9EE84E18AE55CF2374FF4E6E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Legal services related to income support, including assistance in obtaining public benefits.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HED2658836256469ABA4125A2AE6E3B78"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Legal services related to criminal defense, including defense in matters symptomatic of homelessness, such as outstanding warrants, fines, and driver’s license revocation, to reduce recidivism, and facilitate the overcoming of reentry obstacles in employment or housing.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA2A1597E36C3461F91011B188B15DCFD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing and carrying out agreements under this section, the Secretary shall, to the extent practicable, consult with appropriate public and private entities—</text> <paragraph id="H1FA8E769100948BE8B839E1432D69B58"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for assistance in identifying and contacting organizations that offer legal services described in subsection (b); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB2B08E050B9E4EEB8BEDD7F637F08B3B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to coordinate appropriate outreach relationships with such organizations.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5F7631286D49418CAAE9C8D9EC507CBF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Locations</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H609EFB2524D449DEAA90258D158BA5B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that, to the extent practicable, agreements under this section are made with entities equitably distributed across the geographic regions of the United States, including rural communities, tribal lands of the United States, Native Americans, and tribal organizations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H06E9C19C5DA14EBC8AF29D897D9ED9DC" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the terms <quote>Native American</quote> and <quote>tribal organization</quote> have the meanings given such terms in section 3765 of this title.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H90E001E2E7B84824BC0264B8E1F98A55"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may require an entity that enters into an agreement under this section to submit to the Secretary periodic reports on legal services provided pursuant to the agreement.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8C28BFB2B5FD4106A7E3E877B6555EF8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 20 of such title is amended by adding after the item relating to section 2022 the following new item:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5901211AA67443D2B020EAC3EA032CBF" style="USC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">2022A. Agreements with public and private entities to provide pro bono legal services to homeless veterans and veterans at risk of homelessness.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

