<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HFCAD95081BDB4EF18CDB747AE0A11AE7" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4071 IH: Startup Opportunity Accelerator Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4071</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171016">October 16, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001303">Ms. Blunt Rochester</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Small Business Act to create a program to provide funding for organizations that
			 support
			 startup businesses in formation and early growth stages by providing
			 entrepreneurs with resources and services to produce viable businesses,
			 and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HF5A0D36D506A4B1D9653E2290804E015" style="OLC">
 <section id="HA41114DFD7E04E9B84215B78FF985133" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Startup Opportunity Accelerator Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SOAR Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H862D8CCFEE2240F1A77C9EF117AD34FE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H44FB9C828A04457CBA9395A68F4F42E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>startups face common challenges as they seek to transform their ideas into successful, high-growth businesses;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB9395E32E9954EC2B9191AC75772C769"><enum>(2)</enum><text>incubators and accelerators are new models of growth that drive innovation by connecting entrepreneurial individuals and teams to create viable business ventures and social initiatives;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC991C323DD1B482BB34BEE9A142F46A9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>startups have contributed greatly to the United States economy, with research showing that between 1982 and 2011, businesses 5 years or younger were responsible for nearly every net new job created;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H90922FFF12274A6585A8FB16426FFDC8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>incubators and accelerators support promising startups through partnerships, mentoring, and resources connecting them with seasoned entrepreneurs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0683899B02E7405899E028F7C6627DCF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the goal of an incubator or an accelerator is to help create and grow young businesses by providing them with necessary financial, technical, and industry support and financial and technical services; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H77850D41692A4C9FADAEA9FBEB333D4B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>startups offer unique opportunities for growth and development for women, minority, and veterans to become successful entrepreneurs and leaders in new and developed fields.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H5D3842A269574392ACF75CC6A2ABE3F2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Funding for organizations that support startup businesses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/631">15 U.S.C. 631</external-xref> et seq.) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H390B0D4DCAE740629006468D780232E6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating section 47 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/631">15 U.S.C. 631</external-xref> note) as section 48; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1998B911D68340688AE50206C5D806F4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after section 46 the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HDB21389D9D504B9F9FED83614D523A01" style="OLC"> <section id="HD9721018070D4835B8226C131FCB7924"><enum>47.</enum><header>Funding for organizations that support startup businesses</header> <subsection id="H21EDE8C038F4464B9A61CBB65B9B9092"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text>
 <paragraph id="HBE1F2CFA92724EF79D94AB72CF85F827"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>accelerator</term> means an organization that—</text> <subparagraph id="HAB4E779885074942A853FEB309317EC5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>frequently provides, but is not exclusively designed to provide, seed investment in exchange for a small amount of equity;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8887EBCB9B94722B16B4E3E6620A212"><enum>(B)</enum><text>works with a startup for a predetermined amount of time;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H99C52082D8994EC9AA377876F2A38942"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provides mentorship and instruction to scale businesses; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F65B281393B415E83B05CF31785B900"><enum>(D)</enum><text>offers startup capital or the opportunity to raise capital from outside investors;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3527843059364A538A148D75C9C01226"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>eligible entity</term> means an organization—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H89182A54C2234FEE90454CEFDE972673"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that is located in the United States;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80DB8A5544114FD78BE4954393D25916"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the primary purpose of which is to support new small business concerns; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3475D51E34514F1EBDBAF729077BF54E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that is often classified as an accelerator;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H26CB1D20E7C04B37BB835C24C18130DF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>new small business concern</term> means a small business concern that has been in operation for not more than 5 years;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H56349366F3B64D0BA2FBBD26CF272FCF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>small business concern owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals</term> has the meaning given the term in section 8(d)(3)(C); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H42A32AF0998A49F9A2A86317A2CA5E16"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>State</term> means any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and any territory or possession of the United States.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA2E28F77B62F4CE9BDBDBA1E61B56CD7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Funding</header>
 <paragraph id="H8B63C63F95184B9DB4E111847D610738"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator shall develop and begin implementing a program to award cash prizes or grants of not more than $50,000 to eligible entities to support new small business concerns.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFA4E7CDEB9174C8FAE078C374C460FF8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A prize or grant under this section—</text> <subparagraph id="HCA20B5CC9E78468A97E0FE490E3BFA8F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may be used for construction costs, space acquisition, and programmatic purposes; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0AF810FB00B04A949CA8527C404E4E9B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may not be used to provide capital or professional services to new small business concerns directly or through the subaward of funds.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H85ED6719BEED45908F700F4A4E21DABA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Disbursal of funds</header><text>In disbursing funds under this section, the Administrator may use incremental or scheduled payments.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3265F8FCDFF14ED99B50C50279ED7A4E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header>
 <paragraph id="H6738BE13C990431E8AD1C4F9341FCE95"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity desiring a prize or grant under this section shall demonstrate that the eligible entity will use the prize or grant to provide assistance to not less than 10 new small business concerns per year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5B5E3F42A10A41B38A372281A396DA35"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In soliciting applications and awarding prizes or grants to eligible entities under this section, the Administrator shall employ a streamlined and inclusive approach that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF9B8FC4DC9464D6BAD539EDE571C9C91"><enum>(A)</enum><text>widely publicizes funding opportunities to a broad audience;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB25F68E0095D481C82EF059820D4FE99"><enum>(B)</enum><text>utilizes an easily accessible submission process or platform;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB242B6BB17BD4120948D3F4459F0D890"><enum>(C)</enum><text>does not mandate the use of forms, detailed budgets, supporting documentation, or written submissions or impose other burdensome requirements;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H102D8576A8E142D9B7376B9591861D58"><enum>(D)</enum><text>focuses on solution-based approaches and results-based outcomes;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA23A90DE4BA445F0A801298341A5298E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>encourages innovation; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H18D9AE5EC9B243FB8A981D56027B4E21"><enum>(F)</enum><text>allows proposals or pitches to be presented using various formats or media.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFD468FA80BDF4FAB9D684B108DF38004"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>The Administrator shall establish criteria for a prize or grant under this section that shall give priority to eligible entities that are providing or plan to provide to new small business concerns—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4CFCCBDA75454117889D4E016A98AF3E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>office, manufacturing, or warehouse space, including appropriate operations infrastructure;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4A2F64618F764D7D967BD73D2E3E781A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>access to capital either directly from the eligible entity (using amounts other than the amounts provided under the prize or grant) or through guidance and contacts for acquiring capital from outside investors;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0D9477A717034755B7FF1337789D5469"><enum>(3)</enum><text>access to professional services either directly from the eligible entity (using amounts other than the amounts provided under the prize or grant) or through guidance and contacts for acquiring professional services, including accounting and legal services; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H03F8084EE668470194D71226C5A09212"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a formal structured mentorship or developmental program that assists new small business concerns with building business skills and competencies.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBD76720AEB7D4A8D8302E4C4E206E367"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Considerations in choosing recipients</header><text>In determining whether to award a prize or grant under this section to an eligible entity, the Administrator shall take into account—</text>
 <paragraph id="H084B69173D064D7BAC91246235323472"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for eligible entities that have in operation a program to support new small business concerns, the record of the eligible entity in assisting new small business concerns, including, for each of the 3 full years before the date on which the eligible entity applies for a prize or grant under this section—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4D8E9C84CA7D4A41B97659E8CE50AED8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the retention rate of new small business concerns in the program of the eligible entity;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42CA1579081049AFAD02BA119B0A4C95"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the average period of participation by new small business concerns in the program of the eligible entity;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H056D244711D44E4B879711F9D3B61A72"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the total, average, and median capital raised by new small business concerns participating in the program of the eligible entity; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F3D7D8053F743DCA31E29ADFB8201AE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the total, average, and median number of employees of new small business concerns participating in the program of the eligible entity;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H29CAD2B5801741B6BD5609A6D6F0B57F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for all eligible entities—</text> <subparagraph id="HD294E4C799674B4FA33DAB006B72DF9A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of new small business concerns assisted or anticipated to be assisted by the eligible entity;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H79B7AAA0594341B5BDBE30C019F38279"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of new small business concerns applying or anticipated to apply for assistance from the eligible entity;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2C08654CA854605ADDA67304776BB9B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whether the program of the eligible entity provides or would provide assistance to individuals in gender, racial, or ethnic groups underrepresented by existing programs to assist new small business concerns; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08FDE6B0DF464EE7AF919E1999BADABF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>other metrics determined appropriate by the Administrator;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H83CDAED4DB0A4A6C9CF1BF0739D11F38"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the need in the geographic area to be served by the program to be carried out using the prize or grant for additional assistance for new small business concerns, if the area has sufficient population density, as determined by the Administrator;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE06377E347ED4656A52682A34AD70725"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the level of experience of the entrepreneurial leadership of the eligible entity;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6D3C194682A440E39FF7036DD5BA9141"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the ability of the eligible entity to use and leverage local strengths, including human resources, infrastructure, and educational institutions; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF8C38D0E167A4A2CA02B865AC782E80A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the desire to promote diversity in entrepreneurship by ensuring that not less than 50 percent of prizes or grants shall be awarded annually to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2859F0B4A88D483D8742B71D82060DE3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>accelerators located in geographically underserved areas; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75C2BAE3741742DE90EF10D155B32EF4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>accelerators serving—</text>
 <clause id="HEC1322DA16AD4A11BD721DC541F80766"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Native Americans;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H57A9DE94EC0D4FCAA2FEE3844040547C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>small business concerns owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC5BE62C1F452451AA3A71D65EEF52AF9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>individuals participating in the Transition Assistance Program of the Department of Defense;</text> </clause><clause id="HCDA703FF043D4319AC0E96F8FB3334BE"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>individuals who—</text>
 <subclause id="H299D1EF9346C430FAFF91D6A4DB9F792"><enum>(I)</enum><text>served on active duty in any branch of the Armed Forces, including the National Guard and Reserves; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H98ECBE942FB74DEBB5B720F513C1752D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>were discharged or released from such service under conditions other than dishonorable;</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H5102BB0DB261400E9E0E6AFDA212351A"><enum>(v)</enum><text>individuals with disabilities;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD8299BE448A44CCAB65F1462DD4679C4"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>women; and</text> </clause><clause id="H58BDFE5411D6449C91C9709F8DFDD3D7"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>formerly incarcerated individuals.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H317551FE6AB34D6BB57542BD9316EF76"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Matching nonpublic funding requirement</header>
 <paragraph id="H697EBF2323754061B91A56EE3CC5F241"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity receiving a prize or grant under this section shall obtain funds from a private individual or entity (including a for-profit or nonprofit entity) that are—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBEB7FCAA3B3E41A29793EE42DD021083"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for the same purposes as a prize or grant may be made under this section;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC556F2BC333A431DA6815C660A185BA8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>used to carry out the program of the eligible entity carried out using the prize or grant under this section; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0483F452BF82483B9FF276BD3459EDE9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in an amount that is not to be less than 50 percent of the amount of the prize or grant under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B779164EF0542068F2179FEEA65A3A3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form of non-Federal share</header><text>Not more than 25 percent of the funds obtained under paragraph (1) may be in the form of in-kind contributions.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H980238C0236346B387974147ABAF820A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Consequences of failure To abide by terms and conditions of prize or grant requirements of this
 section</header><text>The Administrator shall notify each eligible entity receiving a prize or grant under this section that failure to abide by the terms and conditions of the prize or grant or the requirements of this section may, in the discretion of the Administrator and in addition to any other civil or criminal consequences, result in the Administrator withholding payments or ordering the eligible entity to return the prize or grant funds.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF5DF5C82F0F640178A9C8070E33A4FAA"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Annual progress reporting by recipients of prize or grant</header><text>Each eligible entity receiving a prize or grant under this section shall submit to the Administrator an annual report on the progress of the program carried out using the amounts received under the prize or grant, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="H57E6719DF2AC4CF7BC5A0E3AC3583D41"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of new small business concerns participating in the program during each of the previous 3 years;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H041A9B2F7B974FF4A32B2855EA5C6769"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of new small business concerns applying to participate in the program during each of the previous 3 years;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H56FE220183DB4405A57F111C1E5F050E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the retention rate of new small business concerns in the program;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB69D074371E840BEB4CB7C8074C24074"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the average period of participation in the program by new small business concerns;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8033127EE7674F1BB5B88173DA118A8B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the total, average, and median capital raised by new small business concerns participating in the program;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H060DEFDD73E04D57A875EE5B6DE7F96E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the total, average, and median number of employees of new small business concerns participating in the program;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC917883616994EB19AD36575B34C67E9"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the number of new small business concerns owned and controlled by—</text> <subparagraph id="HA0C81A20BF4B4807B8DE0C0100C32BA5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Native Americans;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF9E39E66BA1E465D8CB5A747BF1792EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>socially and economically disadvantaged individuals;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CFBCD11B017450C90C65CA04931824E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>individuals participating in the Transition Assistance Program of the Department of Defense;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H654AF8CC892B4A948DBD26D5606AFA34"><enum>(D)</enum><text>individuals who—</text> <clause id="H2A70A8AE9A5F43428A3F81E914997221"><enum>(i)</enum><text>served on active duty in any branch of the Armed Forces, including the National Guard and Reserves; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H446BA79BAD9C499BA1C4D154CB0466B4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>were discharged or released from such service under conditions other than dishonorable;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A84911CFCFF4F708169DFF943D7557C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>women; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H071C276FCD384EE090AC21AC88AB2AB7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>formerly incarcerated individuals; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H04DA1489721649DABF576502AF9C3D2B"><enum>(8)</enum><text>other metrics determined appropriate by the Administrator.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3698AA2D5ABB4EE78008ADBB538D958D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Report to congress</header><text>The Administrator shall submit to Congress an annual report on the program under this section, which shall include an assessment of the effectiveness of the program, including an assessment based on the metrics listed in subsection (h).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBD389C72DADA418A8630D855CE18972B"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Coordination with other small business administration programs</header><text>The Administrator shall take appropriate action to encourage eligible entities receiving a prize or grant under this section to use and incorporate other programs of the Administration, such as small business development centers, small business investment companies, loans under section 7(a), and assistance under title V of the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/695">15 U.S.C. 695</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC385B0F3F77649439DBB9BB021B5A449"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Coordination with the Department of Veterans Affairs</header><text>In consultation with the Secretary of Veteran Affairs, the Administrator shall make available outreach materials regarding the opportunities for veterans within the program under this section for distribution and display at local facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9C5B223A6D5A4FF98553B7EC6A411752"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Listing on website</header><text>The Administrator shall include a list of eligible entities receiving a prize or grant under this section on the website of the Administration.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6CE901DF3D814904B081AA0FAAD05072"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $6,000,000 for each of the first 5 fiscal years beginning after the date of enactment of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


