<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC4B850ED480F40558EA00A061695EDEF" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 943 IH: Finding Innovative Lionfish Elimination Technologies Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 943</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170207">February 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001107">Mr. Curbelo of Florida</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of Commerce to award competitive grants to combat the certain species of
			 lionfish in the Atlantic Ocean and the Gulf of Mexico.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HBC659B0C74564793AD4646619B3D1933" style="OLC">
 <section id="HC7AF2E712B354FA5910985ABF8752B28" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Finding Innovative Lionfish Elimination Technologies Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H5B2FCA04F55C4F1FB36856E6981052A7" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Competitive grants to institutions of higher education and nonprofit research organizations to combat lionfish in the Atlantic Ocean and the Gulf of Mexico</header> <subsection id="HFC7237CE5E494B2B8CB621F69856F4DE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce, through the Cooperative Science and Education Program of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration conducted under <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/86/685">Public Law 86–685</external-xref> (74 Stat. 733), the Fish and Wildlife Coordination Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/661">16 U.S.C. 661</external-xref> et seq.), and the Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1999 (section 101(b) of division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/105/277">Public Law 105–277</external-xref>; 112 Stat. 2681–50), shall award competitive grants to institutions of higher education and nonprofit research organizations to combat the species of lionfish Pterois miles and Pterois volitans, in the Atlantic Ocean and the Gulf of Mexico.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF14F94B2394247DC8E2499719B0CC3C4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible for a grant under this section, an institution of higher education or nonprofit research organization must—</text>
 <paragraph id="H358AE7B5C67944AD86342A37DE86DCD2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>have established research infrastructure and proven capabilities of understanding the behavior of such species and the ecosystems of the Atlantic Ocean or the Gulf of Mexico; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAAB2F89977DC41F4B31B7B2022590753"><enum>(2)</enum><text>demonstrate a clear appreciation and understanding of the biological, chemical, and physical aspects of such ecosystem.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBED0FEF593CF4840BB71F177849E61DE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Encouragement of collaboration</header><text>In selecting projects for grants under this section, the Secretary of Commerce may encourage collaborative work with stakeholder groups having practical experience with gear, harvest techniques, and knowledge of local ecosystems.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H71AE0C51A4F246149308B03457416972"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use</header><text>Amounts awarded as grants under this section shall be used—</text> <paragraph id="HEA3B8389F6704E3791925219FF266461"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for lionfish research and the impact of such species on the ecosystems of the Atlantic Ocean or the Gulf of Mexico;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC375979444304CE988C77BD657C41B06"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to develop innovative technologies, including autonomous cameras and active acoustic systems appropriate for coastal environments, for detection of lionfish and determination of priority areas for removal of invasive species; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC6558920C88C40E385AC9B7A4C107F61"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to develop lionfish mitigation technologies, including traps and countermeasures.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCA6FB4D1C53A4CFA8113427397F4D8E5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of amounts available for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022 for the Coastal Ecosystem Resiliency Grant program of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, $1,500,000 may be used to carry out this section.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


