<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1E8A0E1C2ACA49E78A0A2A87C6E0282C" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2011 IH: Carbon Capture Improvement Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2011</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170406">April 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001107">Mr. Curbelo of Florida</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for the issuance of exempt facility bonds for
			 qualified carbon dioxide capture facilities.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HCAA38EEF20C24A5DA4E0A61D2E81F030" style="OLC">
 <section id="HF8ED76F462754104989C1D1EA6314A9E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Carbon Capture Improvement Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HE4EEE3ABDD5C476EA2A46BF2AC0DD475"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HD414B71F134742F796DD0CF5536338DB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Capture and long-term storage of carbon dioxide from coal, natural gas, and biomass-fired power plants, as well as from industrial sectors such as oil refining and production of fertilizer, cement, and ethanol, can help protect the environment while improving the economy and national security of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4457BF45C59D4C7DBB986FFB86F2BB21"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The United States is a world leader in the field of carbon dioxide capture and long-term storage, as well as the beneficial use of carbon dioxide in enhanced oil recovery operations, with many manufacturers and licensors of carbon dioxide capture technology based in the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD01825C944854C3CBA929DB80960D425"><enum>(3)</enum><text>While the prospects for large-scale carbon capture in the United States are promising, costs remain relatively high. Lowering the financing costs for carbon dioxide capture projects would accelerate the deployment of this technology, and if the captured carbon dioxide is subsequently sold for industrial use, such as for use in enhanced oil recovery operations, the economic prospects are further improved.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H688DD3EA30784802B4F6E7255455A4E3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Since 1968, tax-exempt private activity bonds have been used to provide access to lower-cost financing for private businesses that are purchasing new capital equipment for certain specified environmental facilities, including facilities that reduce, recycle, or dispose of waste, pollutants, and hazardous substances.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE922BD8ECE554EF8BEE7488A319265D8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Allowing tax-exempt financing for the purchase of capital equipment that is used to capture carbon dioxide will reduce the costs of developing carbon dioxide capture projects, accelerate their deployment, and, in conjunction with carbon dioxide utilization and long-term storage, help the United States meet critical environmental, economic, and national security goals.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H329154B355484B09BC72868E639B04F7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Carbon dioxide capture facilities</header>
 <subsection id="H00E410B7264C45AAB5F977E711489D56"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/142">Section 142</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HB504DECE529F4DCD9541C8559DD5D395"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2642E1D41CC2440A89A406A0DA25782D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (14), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end,</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E0ACBB0C1DF435695637CDF75371755"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (15), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>, or</quote>, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFAAD6F57371C483E8A821DB7E80696D1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H77E3321FE23849A1A12B14A124E2A869" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H9EB3D7D31FCF438FBE45D7508627CB93"><enum>(16)</enum><text>qualified carbon dioxide capture facilities.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>, and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F06A805C9084C4D92AF1CDDF4100EA0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE70C3369A5AE42EA9FCF01D3A8197D6D" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H4820FB48B8814150886A92CC3A41F598"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Qualified carbon dioxide capture facility</header> <paragraph id="HC0408305BAFC483EA49A543A1D7516A5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a)(16), the term <term>qualified carbon dioxide capture facility</term> means the eligible components of an industrial carbon dioxide facility.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF9539C8324F2434B8ECD6945B3705810"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="H90EB8AF0EEFB4300B4398524EC83FEB7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Eligible component</header> <clause id="H9FCD1E6162E44B31AE9BB60C7AC12058"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>eligible component</term> means any equipment installed in an industrial carbon dioxide facility that satisfies the requirements under paragraph (3) and is—</text>
 <subclause id="HBD54521AB18A4C4594A21903F28D774D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>used for the purpose of capture, treatment and purification, compression, transportation, or on-site storage of carbon dioxide produced by the industrial carbon dioxide facility, or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H0C2AC52641A344918FBB054D5FAE758D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>integral or functionally related and subordinate to a process described in section 48B(c)(2), determined by substituting <quote>carbon dioxide</quote> for <quote>carbon monoxide</quote> in such section.</text>
										</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E0EA0938B7F4DE6A546AEC479BB2E8C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Industrial carbon dioxide facility</header>
 <clause id="H17CC34FA605B496DA23D41490BB8D3D0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (ii), the term <term>industrial carbon dioxide facility</term> means a facility that emits carbon dioxide (including from any fugitive emissions source) that is created as a result of any of the following processes:</text>
 <subclause id="H8DAFA7A549B04F76A61E9DAF1C0CBAE2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Fuel combustion.</text> </subclause><subclause id="HB4D0BFDE47614882B7629D6A0476A50F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Gasification.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HADBBE720C0A24560B668660D662A8A21"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Bioindustrial.</text> </subclause><subclause id="HB57BAEAD25154F71B86C32C41F3EF6E2"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Fermentation.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H012956F519484117A72F325A693A6558"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Any manufacturing industry described in section 48B(c)(7).</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HFD737D39A3964DE38192A7E0C56C20B9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>For purposes of clause (i), an industrial carbon dioxide facility shall not include—</text>
 <subclause id="H3F31BE4928CD400099EBB70DE01B997D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any geological gas facility (as defined in clause (iii)), or</text> </subclause><subclause id="HEE4C68622FCF4830B6C96ECBF3FC7485"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any air separation unit that—</text>
 <item id="H1D1A515F21364993A175DF562BB134B1"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>does not qualify as gasification equipment, or</text> </item><item id="HE7AF02AFB7D542EB8C33F3AA44DD8991"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>is not a necessary component of an oxy-fuel combustion process.</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause id="HE3A4EA5E2098462686EBAC3E44825A4E"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Geological gas facility</header><text>The term <term>geological gas facility</term> means a facility that—</text> <subclause id="H747D3C6C5219420098C91309CDCB0D64"><enum>(I)</enum><text>produces a raw product consisting of gas or mixed gas and liquid from a geological formation,</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HAF035CA3F4F040A4B1BFA94F5F53ACB9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>transports or removes impurities from such product, or</text> </subclause><subclause id="H8F531467CF8E417BAD0E5724DCD18F59"><enum>(III)</enum><text>separates such product into its constituent parts.</text>
										</subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F55171695B24CE79963731DC48D2E51"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Capture and storage requirement</header>
 <subparagraph id="HA3CF72134F0645A28A838AB288AE50F1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), the eligible components of an industrial carbon dioxide facility shall have a capture and storage percentage (as determined under subparagraph (C)) that is equal to or greater than 65 percent.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA81FC77094364F6BAF0FE9DCE7BEE025"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>In the case of an industrial carbon dioxide facility with a capture and storage percentage that is less than 65 percent, the percentage of the cost of the eligible components installed in such facility that may be financed with tax-exempt bonds may not be greater than the capture and storage percentage.</text>
								</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D160F2045E0476E98F55B627A72973A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Capture and storage percentage</header>
 <clause id="HEE820F218E984620A9E814CD4A1766BD"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to clause (ii), the capture and storage percentage shall be an amount, expressed as a percentage, equal to the quotient of—</text>
 <subclause id="H1763988B3EBA4D478F1F6A4ED3C15AE0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the total metric tons of carbon dioxide annually captured, transported, and injected into—</text> <item id="H6B383D5BF28541A68C86105EC477694D"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>a facility for geologic storage, or</text>
 </item><item id="H284588CE25B348799CC2AA9461D53E57"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>an enhanced oil or gas recovery well followed by geologic storage, divided by</text> </item></subclause><subclause id="HA242ED6FA7A046868CAB39C5E696CE0A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the total metric tons of carbon dioxide which would otherwise be released into the atmosphere each year as industrial emission of greenhouse gas if the eligible components were not installed in the industrial carbon dioxide facility.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H478D3D502EF841A4BC2FF062BAF8A50F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limited application of eligible components</header><text>In the case of eligible components that are designed to capture carbon dioxide solely from specific sources of emissions or portions thereof within an industrial carbon dioxide facility, the capture and storage percentage under this subparagraph shall be determined based only on such specific sources of emissions or portions thereof.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAD9966824C514DBF809293D9020FDA1F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Volume cap</header><text>Section 146(g)(4) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>paragraph (11) of section 142(a) (relating to high-speed intercity rail facilities)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (11) or (16) of section 142(a)</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H1DA166435348474AB01DB535B141EF9F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clarification of private business use</header><text>Section 141(b)(6) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6BD78A6DF005485FA7E258047061C54C" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H81129207D0984CE6852D3674894DD694"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Clarification relating to qualified carbon dioxide capture facilities</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the sale of carbon dioxide produced by a qualified carbon dioxide capture facility (as defined in section 142(n)) which is owned by a governmental unit shall not constitute private business use.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H169A5BA743204FD6BF7DC6CC45ADC21E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to obligations issued after December 31, 2017.</text> </subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

