<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H5D4F31DF12C94DB189E96BBBFA09B630" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3894 IH: Tribal Heritage and Grizzly Bear Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3894</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171002">October 2, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To protect grizzly bear populations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HC71D36DF5FF4405781B4F837860732D2" style="OLC">
 <section id="H439FE4169F1148B3B5F10DB60CFE7DDD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Tribal Heritage and Grizzly Bear Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HD39E5F4E5E9B413291E6D2356F7D0C08" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Protection of grizzly bears</header> <subsection id="H5978D351E23947C29B0921275189B6F5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibited acts</header><text>Except as provided in section 3, it is unlawful for any person—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC9BB01831D5946E2AB94698C7CD9CC12"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to take, possess, or transport a grizzly bear, or any part thereof;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H272DA5E8ABC54440A48404FF5DD3200A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to violate any condition of a permit issued under section 3; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H63A341D71140494198E78F5BD7622240"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to violate any regulation issued by the Secretary pursuant to this Act.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9268A450E3AC44619C2B63300AA46A55"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Nonapplication</header><text>This Act shall not apply to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H451C7F0E7F6045DD85AEEFA367812BDC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a grizzly bear, or any part thereof, in a population that is listed as a threatened species or an endangered species under section 4 of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1533">16 U.S.C. 1533</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6BBA8847FF1C47B0A67EBB2FF1D333E4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a grizzly bear, or any part thereof, taken, possessed, or transported in the State of Alaska; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBB75A501C54A4FE29AB2AFA03DB54C90"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a taking that is imminently necessary for self-defense or to save the life of a person in immediate danger.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HDB87C038190C491EA896E620D4C42214"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Civil penalty</header>
 <paragraph id="H75497C372EA04BECA5D58F0D426575D6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Knowing violation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person who knowingly violates subsection (a) may be assessed a civil penalty by the Secretary under the first sentence of section 11(a) of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1540">16 U.S.C. 1540(a)</external-xref>) as if such person has knowingly violated a provision of such Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0A214F90A9D34121843044480E2BDCBD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Unknowing violation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person who, other than knowingly, violates subsection (a) may be assessed a civil penalty by the Secretary under the third sentence of section 11(a) of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1540">16 U.S.C. 1540(a)</external-xref>) as if such person has otherwise violated a provision of such Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H2752375725DC4800993311C5498CA9BC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Criminal penalty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person who knowingly violates subsection (a) shall, upon conviction, be punished in the same manner as a person who commits a violation punishable under the first sentence of section 11(b) of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1540">16 U.S.C. 1540(b)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HA1C56514C8FE4E5CA43876F06BAF9931"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Cancellation of grazing authorizations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any lease, license, permit, or agreement issued by the head of any Federal agency to a person authorizing the grazing of domestic livestock on Federal lands shall have no force or effect upon the conviction of such person of a violation of subsection (a). The United States shall not be liable for the payment of any compensation, reimbursement, or damages in connection with the cancellation of any lease, license, permit, or agreement pursuant to this subsection.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HCBC7B7E956694E95BED7A6C3A8E1B0A8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Permitted taking of grizzly bears</header>
 <subsection id="H54FB129610EC454997C0CE7B2299A3B5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may issue a permit in accordance with this section authorizing the taking, possession, or transport of a grizzly bear, or any part thereof, that is otherwise prohibited by section 2.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF0E1D01D6ED541468B131FC47509702A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conditions</header><text>The Secretary may issue a permit under this section only if the Secretary has—</text> <paragraph id="H7C5B22748CB64376948D11BEE95CB197"><enum>(1)</enum><text>investigated the circumstances that gave rise to the permit application;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H214417EDE7EC453A8708CC9B99608D23"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determined that such taking, possession, or transport is compatible with the protection of the grizzly bear species or a population of grizzly bears occupying a geographically distinct area; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H25321810CCC045B39E99D8EC307920AE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>determined that such taking, possession, or transport is an allowable taking, possession, or transport under subsection (c).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H677122329F0B4F47A1216CD495C8063D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Allowable takings, possessions, or transports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purpose of subsection (b)(3), an allowable taking, possession, or transport is any of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H37549C368D0D462AB5B5C5740093D89B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Scientific or exhibition purposes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Taking, possessing, or transporting a grizzly bear, or any part thereof, for the scientific or exhibition purposes of a—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD3BD8C389F304A77827C6BCDD04D69C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>public museum;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC3F8B513C8B461CBBC1AFC540175A68"><enum>(B)</enum><text>scientific society; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB824F62CF2CD4272862CD270442B0A1E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>zoological park that is accredited by the Association of Zoos and Aquariums.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9DD044B1DFCD414C8FDE49EDED64005F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Religious purposes of federally recognized Indian Tribe</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Taking, possessing, or transporting a grizzly bear, or any part thereof, for the religious purposes of a federally recognized Indian Tribe.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H44AFB839DEFE4642B3B93C627D62615D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Protection of agricultural interests or public safety</header>
 <subparagraph id="H7C01E695D4E84A968D6B802A7C135A2B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), taking, possessing, or transporting a grizzly bear, or any part thereof, during such time period and in such location as the Secretary determines to be necessary to protect agricultural interests or public safety in such location.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F2437D963DB4A4D9A842E82DE8F4FE0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements for taking</header><text>Before making a determination under subparagraph (A) with respect to a taking—</text> <clause id="H8E3D0EACFF3742D3820493101BA7695C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Governor of the State in which the taking will occur must request, in writing, that the Secretary make such determination;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H64F87156C9564FCAA1105553C6549056"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary must conclude that nonlethal deterrents have been used in such location and proven ineffective to mitigate the threat of the grizzly bear to agricultural interests or public safety; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC823DE7C5EDF481F8B7C264C76D4EB7C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary must determine, in consultation with the Interagency Grizzly Bear Study Team and each federally recognized Indian Tribe identified in the report required under section 6(a)(2), that the grizzly bear cannot be relocated to support—</text>
 <subclause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7D6CF7E4F6484D858A91A1E56D76D685"><enum>(I)</enum><text>efforts under section 6 to reintroduce grizzly bears on Tribal land; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="HC538FCE9531D4F70AE947F96429537DA"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recovery efforts for a grizzly bear population listed as a threatened species or an endangered species under section 4 of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1533">16 U.S.C. 1533</external-xref>).</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H867EB76975944158BB8FB1B9D95F8671"><enum>(d)</enum><header>No permits for takings that would exceed mortality limit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not issue a permit under this section for the taking of a grizzly bear if such taking would cause the total mortality for any population or subpopulation of grizzly bears to exceed the scientifically recommended limit determined by the Interagency Grizzly Bear Study Team.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6B4277716C39439FB195FD2497A6962E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Sport hunting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section may be construed to allow sport hunting of grizzly bears.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H25FCFC4A4B78469E91C84F36CF4DD208"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Nonalienability</header><text>A person who has been issued a permit under this section may not sell, transfer, assign, or otherwise alienate the authority granted to such person by such permit.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HF568E61C8EF74351A00F750E5F4A2725"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Conduct requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Taking, possessing, or transporting a grizzly bear, or any part thereof, under this Act shall be conducted in a manner consistent with—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB2B401D1B43041FE97168536894389DA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the conditions of the permit authorizing such taking, possession, or transport; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H1A82D93CC65D464A904113210624E1B5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the provisions of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC70ACCEF403543F1BD6D16380EF84C66"><enum>4.</enum><header>Livestock loss prevention</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Public Law 111–11 is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H4A7A304FCEC148ADA8BA908044246FA0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 6202 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/426">7 U.S.C. 426</external-xref> note)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0ADCFF845FC04336A6F19E2D5DA84035"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the heading of such section, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">and grizzly bear</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Wolf</header-in-text></quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F12E908B9DE49B686888B7F8407D16A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the matter preceding subsection (a)(1), by striking <quote>5-year</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05BA86F7BCE4433AA7DF03832F0A4BDA"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a)(1), by inserting <quote>and grizzly bears</quote> after <quote>wolves</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2BBBBB0F49CE47A1AC3B216CD7D92031"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b)(2)(A), by inserting <quote>and grizzly bears</quote> after <quote>wolves</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H85E00AC52B6C4025BB367FB1E839F554"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 6203 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/426">7 U.S.C. 426</external-xref> note), by striking <quote>$1,000,000 for fiscal year 2009</quote> and inserting <quote>$5,000,000 for fiscal year 2018</quote>.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H878FCD5421BA4A9D9B019EAB7C5FB404"><enum>5.</enum><header>Consultation with Indian Tribes</header> <subsection id="HFA4937C1CCC043C489539022A6AA1AF0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Consultation required before issuing permit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before issuing a permit under this Act that authorizes an activity to be carried out on the Tribal land of a federally recognized Indian Tribe, the Secretary shall consult with such federally recognized Indian Tribe.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2E8E8F654C0E4DD1B258EB43A0F62D0D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation required before taking major Federal action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before taking any Federal action that may negatively impact grizzly bear habitat or increase grizzly bear mortality the Secretary or the Secretary of Agriculture, respectively, shall consult with—</text>
 <paragraph id="H894F48CE3BEB4A75A7B7E1FC177ABC15"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Interagency Grizzly Bear Study Team; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3631BEBA51A94566991FBAC3AE3AF79D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the relevant federally recognized Indian Tribe.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H58A15CCBFD644ED29732ECDE10E6C04B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Any consultation conducted with a federally recognized Indian Tribe under this section—</text> <paragraph id="H4002EA94F1CC4E328F467B264C9720C2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be meaningful and be conducted within a framework developed with the free, prior, and informed consent of that Indian Tribe;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0BC3B0FAA6E34B81B33D89E399AC2279"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be carried out through cooperative management agreements between the Secretary, the Secretary of Agriculture, and that Indian Tribe; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H14D00983547D435389EBA26CA061B2E2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>may, at the option of the Indian Tribe, be entered into under the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5301">25 U.S.C. 5301</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HEBBF46A038574E238A6CBAC1557E83DD"><enum>6.</enum><header>Reintroduction of grizzly bears on Tribal land</header>
			<subsection id="HA2B57F8C7732418EAC4201F14AFB0047"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Public report required</header>
 <paragraph id="HB871DE78EF3D4049AFDE3E984730A431"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Interagency Grizzly Bear Study Team, in consultation with each federally recognized Indian Tribe whose Tribal land is located within the historical range of the grizzly bear, shall conduct a study to identify Tribal land that is located within the historical range of the grizzly bear and is suitable to support grizzly bear populations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1D8C2F10076342E786EF5D5D649FA351"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Interagency Grizzly Bear Study Team shall make publically available on the website of the Interagency Grizzly Bear Study Team a report containing the results of the study conducted under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3E4D0908FEF849C1AA0AB0F52F823464"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the report is made available under subsection (a)(2), the Secretary shall notify each federally recognized Indian Tribe whose Tribal land was identified in the report required under subsection (a)(1) that grizzly bears may be reintroduced on the identified Tribal land in accordance with this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFA9F1672A807477591DCE33FE09A7E7E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reintroduction</header><text>If a federally recognized Indian Tribe notified under subsection (b) notifies the Secretary that it agrees to have grizzly bears reintroduced on its Tribal land, the Secretary shall coordinate with that federally recognized Indian Tribe to reintroduce grizzly bears to such Tribal land.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H82A57E57CF734CA2A303EF6BB0FCC924"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Manner of relocation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The relocation of grizzly bears under subsection (c) shall be carried out by the Secretary in a manner that is consistent with—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7B8119ABFB5B4FA08F0707082AA5F28F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the scientific advice of the Interagency Grizzly Bear Study Team;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9CBA21774647447A958EAC5B2E0AC393"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the traditional ecological knowledge of the respective federally recognized Indian Tribe; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB23095C6ADFC48E58CA61A2FBF4174C5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Secretarial Order 3342, dated October 21, 2016.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3A4E27BEE70B4B5A827D5A4F5D3BD475"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Protection of public safety</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grizzly bear that has been identified by the Secretary as a threat to public safety shall not be eligible for reintroduction under this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H43C6FB063B714B5A91DF5DB6F43CAF5E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Other reintroduction efforts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall affect any effort by the Secretary to reintroduce a grizzly bear on lands other than the lands specified in this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HAA57C12EAA8D481FBC19296F86406EEC"><enum>7.</enum><header>Miscellaneous</header>
 <subsection id="H29EC68FA31854A1A8D3C943752410D79"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Limitation on use of predator control measures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary or the Secretary of Agriculture, respectively, shall prohibit on lands under such Secretary’s jurisdiction the use of predator control measures that the Interagency Grizzly Bear Study Team has determined may result in the inadvertent taking of grizzly bears.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6913166919FB449FA5DF5C1F7754CB73"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Meeting and advisement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Interagency Grizzly Bear Committee and the Interagency Grizzly Bear Study Team shall meet with and advise State and Federal wildlife managers and affected federally recognized Indian Tribes.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE11D408522BD47F890B953D133C8686A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Inclusion of members of federally recognized Indian Tribes on Interagency Grizzly Bear Committee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Interagency Grizzly Bear Committee shall include not less than 1 member of each federally recognized Indian Tribe whose Tribal land is—</text>
 <paragraph id="H96F07C3869124FE88E6CFD2520A97E04"><enum>(1)</enum><text>inhabited by grizzly bears; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2674CB49A138419B8956E8ED35A886FD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identified in the report required under section 6(a)(2) as suitable to support grizzly bear populations.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2A1856E7982E404FBBC16D58F522326B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Partnership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, the Secretary of Agriculture, and relevant federally recognized Indian Tribes shall manage grizzly bears reintroduced on Tribal land under this Act using the best available science and consistent with the cultural imperatives of those federally recognized Indian Tribes, as defined in The Grizzly: A Treaty of Cooperation, Cultural Revitalization and Restoration.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HC85643A3A5DD43E882C906994D374E47"><enum>8.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H1DF5D3D04AC44F069F8C54130A2BF2F2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Grizzly bear</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>grizzly bear</term> means a member of the subspecies Ursus arctos horribilis.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA0E83D2FBE0044F4B9484EEB4A9F30FC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Historical range of the grizzly bear</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>historical range of the grizzly bear</term> means the range determined by the Interagency Grizzly Bear Study Team using the best available scientific and historical information.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1FB39437B14E47ACA29B0789DACAC9C2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3EBF449A4AAC40C4A5FF2F1E784DA0A2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Take</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>take</quote> means to harass, harm, pursue, hunt, shoot, wound, kill, trap, capture, or collect, or to attempt to engage in any such conduct.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H94BC090096EB444DA47E6B0474167355"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Tribal land</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Tribal land</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H30A70BCD91D4477C9A0223F159F1983A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>land located within the boundaries of an Indian reservation, pueblo, or Rancheria;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87ECFFAABE42401E951921C070B36D75"><enum>(B)</enum><text>land not located within the boundaries of an Indian reservation, pueblo, or Rancheria, title to which is held—</text>
 <clause id="H08FB984476274CADAEE31290F972E01D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in trust by the United States for benefit of an Indian tribe or an individual Indian;</text> </clause><clause id="HB2273B19451A43F09AA9D111F0DCA00F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by an Indian tribe or an individual Indian, subject to restriction against alienation under laws of the United States; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFBB05BBFE3F14C809422AC96DBE50793"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by a dependent Indian community; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H43EF2F8CD0154AE29FD056841231CBC1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>land that is owned by an Indian tribe and was conveyed by the United States to a Native Corporation pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1601">43 U.S.C. 1601</external-xref> et seq.) or that was conveyed by the United States to a Native Corporation in exchange for such land.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


