<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HBC3AE1738C10491489B1E1C68476E732" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1397 : To authorize, direct, facilitate, and expedite the transfer of administrative jurisdiction of certain Federal land, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1397</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date date="20170712">July 12, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To authorize, direct, facilitate, and expedite the transfer of administrative jurisdiction of
			 certain Federal land, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H292D550C04D3407D96BF70A3F10831BC" style="OLC">
		<section id="H9B2884E4AC694AD1BF560965D2838E04" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Interagency transfer of land along George Washington Memorial Parkway</header>
 <subsection id="HA82561B99576476C8AC68D589B461058"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HBC0AA45697D142DCA2C9975CBA95BE41"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Map</header><text>The term <quote>Map</quote> means the map entitled <quote>George Washington Memorial Parkway—Claude Moore Farm Proposed Boundary Adjustment</quote>, numbered 850_130815, and dated February 2016.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDE4A6F938278466299ED19B51880A9AD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Research center</header><text>The term <quote>Research Center</quote> means the Turner-Fairbank Highway Research Center of the Federal Highway Administration.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H22932B4DA0074DB4B842670050ADE1BF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0BB92011C8C04FE096D3A84EBC055AB8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administrative jurisdiction transfer</header>
				<paragraph id="H3712DED72E7C4F60BB8D661EE65803B3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Transfer of jurisdiction</header>
 <subparagraph id="H86AA07C8766645C888BAECD333C96D10"><enum>(A)</enum><header>George Washington Memorial Parkway land</header><text>Administrative jurisdiction over the approximately 0.342 acres of Federal land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary within the boundary of the George Washington Memorial Parkway, as generally depicted as <quote>B</quote> on the Map, is transferred from the Secretary to the Secretary of Transportation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H32DB1C5B71DF431DB83339A98C289B89"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Research center land</header><text>Administration jurisdiction over the approximately 0.479 acres of Federal land within the boundary of the Research Center land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Transportation adjacent to the boundary of the George Washington Memorial Parkway, as generally depicted as <quote>A</quote> on the Map, is transferred from the Secretary of Transportation to the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HECA5F6A11D134F5EA20AD5D223958BB3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use restriction</header><text>The Secretary shall restrict the use of 0.139 acres of Federal land within the boundary of the George Washington Memorial Parkway immediately adjacent to part of the perimeter fence of the Research Center, generally depicted as <quote>C</quote> on the Map, by prohibiting the storage, construction, or installation of any item that may interfere with the access of the Research Center to the restricted land for security and maintenance purposes.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H913FADAF3BDA4EBF905E4453CCEBFC33"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reimbursement or consideration</header><text>The transfers of administrative jurisdiction under this subsection shall not be subject to reimbursement or consideration.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HA7DD1CB8E96A4F5A9372EE11A665A39C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Compliance with agreement</header>
 <subparagraph id="HED3674CFC25C48C7BDE6EA63F0AB8442"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Agreement</header><text>The National Park Service and the Federal Highway Administration shall comply with all terms and conditions of the agreement entered into by the parties on September 11, 2002, regarding the transfer of administrative jurisdiction, management, and maintenance of the land described in the agreement.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCDED827D319B4FF8B63026152F4BF05A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Access to restricted land</header><text>Subject to the terms of the agreement described in subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall allow the Research Center—</text>
 <clause id="H6761970F88F14D0485788BA069E7E91E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to access the Federal land described in paragraph (1)(B) for purposes of transportation to and from the Research Center; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE5BB830A260446BAA3676FB995B291DE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to access the Federal land described in paragraphs (1)(B) and (2) for purposes of maintenance in accordance with National Park Service standards, including grass mowing, weed control, tree maintenance, fence maintenance, and maintenance of the visual appearance of the Federal land.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H43E66ED3A8A24B1F921AAF3272C4DFC1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Management of transferred land</header>
 <paragraph id="H533029F876B84AD5B89E20681A07A564"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Interior land</header><text>The Federal land transferred to the Secretary under subsection (b)(1)(B) shall be—</text> <subparagraph id="HBA0EE22F33A2492DA3A52C04AF2784E6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>included in the boundary of the George Washington Memorial Parkway; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H417AAD4A08874824AD44EA4A6993A624"><enum>(B)</enum><text>administered by the Secretary as part of the George Washington Memorial Parkway, subject to applicable laws (including regulations).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C04FCB483ED4ED1876356F720C0ED90"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transportation land</header><text>The Federal land transferred to the Secretary of Transportation under subsection (b)(1)(A) shall be—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF64812797C5D4ACC992834570E5C40CC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>included in the boundary of the Research Center land; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H304CE61698504F228B0A3CFAA9C7E30E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>removed from the boundary of the George Washington Memorial Parkway.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC65AD778A8F74482AC3B9164DEDC5F9E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Restricted-use land</header><text>The Federal land that the Secretary has designated for restricted use under subsection (b)(2) shall be maintained by the Research Center.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H82078F1708254DD495AF24A75B7524D0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Map on file</header><text>The Map shall be available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
	<attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20170711">Passed the House of Representatives July 11, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill>


