<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HBFAB00131B134283B5FE3CFBAB13D8C0" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4419 IH: Bureau of Reclamation and Bureau of Indian Affairs Water Project Streamlining Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4419</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171116">November 16, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000578">Mr. Reichert</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To facilitate and streamline the Bureau of Reclamation and Bureau of Indian Affairs processes for
			 creating or expanding certain water projects, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H36101DFFEF5B473FA7679607DCF0A80B" style="OLC">
 <section id="H318834127CA1494EAEB9F05CFBABB302" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bureau of Reclamation and Bureau of Indian Affairs Water Project Streamlining Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H3949ED7F068641E4ACD8446713801146"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="H8BCBEC134C144FD4B64984A3287C0008"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Environmental impact statement</header><text>The term <term>environmental impact statement</term> means the detailed statement of environmental impacts of a project required to be prepared pursuant to the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H9061D475B30D45168251923DE449CEDE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Environmental review process</header>
 <subparagraph id="HDCDC945D57A44921A4987BB8787AAEA7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>environmental review process</term> means the process of preparing an environmental impact statement, environmental assessment, categorical exclusion, or other document under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.) for a project study.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H29084DC8885A4FD18021FBBC7E72F1F8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The term <term>environmental review process</term> includes the process for and completion of any environmental permit, approval, review, or study required for a project study under any Federal law other than the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6014622D825244059136A251BF7CB093"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federal jurisdictional agency</header><text>The term <term>Federal jurisdictional agency</term> means a Federal agency with jurisdiction delegated by law, regulation, order, or otherwise over a review, analysis, opinion, statement, permit, license, or other approval or decision required for a project study under applicable Federal laws (including regulations).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H05AF40E38B2149239C574B99BE35AF1D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Federal lead agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Federal lead agency</term> means the Bureau of Reclamation or Bureau of Indian Affairs.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE1007E4896D4EA3A0DDDCA874C7C93A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Project</header><text>The term <term>project</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD22D47CE74374C9B8DEB5B8933E1139F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a surface water project, a project under the purview of title XVI of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/102/575">Public Law 102–575</external-xref>, a rural water supply project investigated under <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/451">Public Law 109–451</external-xref>, or a Federal portion of an integrated water resource management plan that has been subject to a review under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.) and is to be carried out, funded or operated in whole or in party by the Secretary pursuant to the Act of June 17, 1902 (32 Stat. 388, chapter 1093), and Acts supplemental to and amendatory of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/371">43 U.S.C. 371</external-xref> et seq.); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17772A3C91A74A90B76E5B1FE87FF1FA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Indian irrigation projects in the western United States that, on the date of enactment of this Act, are owned by the Federal Government, as listed in the Federal inventory required by Executive Order 13327 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/40/121">40 U.S.C. 121</external-xref> note; relating to Federal real property asset management).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H05F638728353426E98D192A0B64BAC85"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Project sponsor</header><text>The term <term>project sponsor</term> means a State, regional, tribal, or local authority or instrumentality or other qualifying entity, such as a water conservation district, irrigation district, water conservancy district, joint powers authority, mutual water company, canal company, rural water district or association, or any other entity that has the capacity to contract with the United States under Federal reclamation law.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0804F3A29CB34DE19BC24F207AE8AB8E"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Project study</header><text>The term <term>project study</term> means a feasibility study for a project carried out pursuant to the Act of June 17, 1902 (32 Stat. 388, chapter 1093), and Acts supplemental to and amendatory of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/371">43 U.S.C. 371</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H84EFACA3946B4D8885F68B716A4421D9"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFF6F3B2694644DE3BDF115F255B6F7E7"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Surface water storage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>surface water storage</term> means any surface water reservoir or impoundment that would be owned, funded or operated in whole or in part by the Bureau of Reclamation or the Bureau of Indian Affairs or that would be integrated into a larger system owned, operated or administered in whole or in part by the Bureau of Reclamation or the Bureau of Indian Affairs.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H0F2D39F4D0614A8C98973C196E4672E4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Acceleration of studies</header>
 <subsection id="H9A70AFFA4C854A989C597058D6253E31"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To the extent practicable, a project study initiated by the Secretary, after the date of enactment of this Act, shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HEB00EC5937274CE2BFF82322143199E3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>result in the completion of a final feasibility report not later than 3 years after the date of initiation;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDA078E30FCB04363B69EDAA08ADE10CE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>have a maximum Federal cost of $3,000,000; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H11D80BF9C1864A28B6BB9BE6930AFCB1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that personnel from the local project area, region, and headquarters levels of the Bureau of Reclamation or the Bureau of Indian Affairs concurrently conduct the review required under that section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7C3D20FAE64E4AA7B1D56212D59F3E55"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>If the Secretary determines that a project study described in subsection (a) will not be conducted in accordance with subsection (a), the Secretary, not later than 30 days after the date of making the determination, shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H092A6FF8365B4F96B800F8EA54FD9E00"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prepare an updated project study schedule and cost estimate;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7CCA747740674FF0BE6FAD4FE162F767"><enum>(2)</enum><text>notify the non-Federal project cost-sharing partner that the project study has been delayed; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H83A584C0CCC9464E85AB9BA1C784E3FB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide written notice to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate as to the reasons the requirements of subsection (a) are not attainable.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD8D8F3B08AC04F38950356386F56183A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exception</header>
 <paragraph id="H2EE345759E054C1EA854490529F6EED1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding the requirements of subsection (a), the Secretary may extend the timeline of a project study by a period not to exceed 3 years, if the Secretary determines that the project study is too complex to comply with the requirements of subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC6761E6C65514BD791DF5150FE85E9E9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Factors</header><text>In making a determination that a study is too complex to comply with the requirements of subsection (a), the Secretary shall consider—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H64EB2205CDC24BA2AEACE8653581249D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the type, size, location, scope, and overall cost of the project;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00F8C613A1BA4169A4D273BACD2CFC73"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether the project will use any innovative design or construction techniques;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9650B4CDFB14CC8A7BDDE79287AD65E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whether the project will require significant action by other Federal, State, or local agencies;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H030106299557453CB37AB6327ED85449"><enum>(D)</enum><text>whether there is significant public dispute as to the nature or effects of the project; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H32D0E2D98A2F4684B0B40B5171AF7D59"><enum>(E)</enum><text>whether there is significant public dispute as to the economic or environmental costs or benefits of the project.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HABDA8636EBD240F2819D340CC8338E63"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>Each time the Secretary makes a determination under this subsection, the Secretary shall provide written notice to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Energy and Natural Resources and Indian Affairs of the Senate as to the results of that determination, including an identification of the specific one or more factors used in making the determination that the project is complex.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEE9ABAAE13174E69B0EF1BEB699014FA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Secretary shall not extend the timeline for a project study for a period of more than 7 years, and any project study that is not completed before that date shall no longer be authorized.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4EDC58148850406BBA5F48E7CDD8443D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reviews</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the initiation of a project study described in subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD19A4AD2E1CA407A819AE5F45D0B9494"><enum>(1)</enum><text>take all steps necessary to initiate the process for completing federally mandated reviews that the Secretary is required to complete as part of the study, including the environmental review process under section 5;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2D95CBFA5BC4402889A0FE73430FD95C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>convene a meeting of all Federal, tribal, and State agencies identified under section 5(d) that may—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7D454779DC704265B3B40B6D8524BFAF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have jurisdiction over the project;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BB6852E6FE940398343ABF38D411A2F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be required by law to conduct or issue a review, analysis, opinion, or statement for the project study; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF34D97A324041ADB51DB7F0B20CFF16"><enum>(C)</enum><text>be required to make a determination on issuing a permit, license, or other approval or decision for the project study; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H23F2FDB01FC74325AF71224258565FA0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>take all steps necessary to provide information that will enable required reviews and analyses related to the project to be conducted by other agencies in a thorough and timely manner.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H57BA1A88D47E46328CD797B125016431"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Interim report</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Energy and Natural Resources and Indian Affairs of the Senate and make publicly available a report that describes—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF7C2CE3981D949E689B76B55D5A9A8B7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the status of the implementation of the planning process under this section, including the number of participating projects;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB6EF8A4550144E42A77D169AC10E1614"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a review of project delivery schedules, including a description of any delays on those studies initiated prior to the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2DDBB8BEB7CB4704936F739E1AC84B8D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any recommendations for additional authority necessary to support efforts to expedite the project.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF20D9A11092D4D9CB629FA9654E9DFCD"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>Not later than 4 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Energy and Natural Resources and Indian Affairs of the Senate and make publicly available a report that describes—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFBE3855D2C3346A6855138694C344DF7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the status of the implementation of this section, including a description of each project study subject to the requirements of this section;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H37CB81533E2A4CD48A1C33339D2394B9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the amount of time taken to complete each project study; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2FF3B05CCA794E5B9A5C434AA3CE4750"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any recommendations for additional authority necessary to support efforts to expedite the project study process, including an analysis of whether the limitation established by subsection (a)(2) needs to be adjusted to address the impacts of inflation.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H91A8DC01102645B18D4785C51AD9D509"><enum>4.</enum><header>Expedited completion of reports</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="H2F9BD6C722054A5EA2E73D7621980503"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expedite the completion of any ongoing project study initiated before the date of enactment of this Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H531584A7FE384D638F607AE937526931"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if the Secretary determines that the project is justified in a completed report, proceed directly to preconstruction planning, engineering, and design of the project in accordance with the Reclamation Act of 1902 (32 Stat. 388), and all Acts amendatory thereof or supplementary thereto.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H174EF8EC696A4B06B49606E92328F534"><enum>5.</enum><header>Project acceleration</header>
			<subsection id="HADE782E0ABEF42F7B1B3CBBF31935C03"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Applicability</header>
 <paragraph id="HE924C558A9184DBAAB17F89C83431FF1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>This section shall apply to—</text> <subparagraph id="H65A287A0496243C0B79C6FB13BC17E4B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each project study that is initiated after the date of enactment of this Act and for which an environmental impact statement is prepared under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A1FFA29E8AE4CC6B3A7F71949C8FB0F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the extent determined appropriate by the Secretary, to other project studies initiated before the date of enactment of this Act and for which an environmental review process document is prepared under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H939B034FA8B644A29C4A8DFDDFEEE653"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any project study for the development of a non-federally owned and operated surface water storage project for which the Secretary determines there is a demonstrable Federal interest and the project—</text>
 <clause id="HE92324D1278741269471AF86EFC6C655"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is located in a river basin where other Bureau of Reclamation or the Bureau of Indian Affairs water projects are located;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB9F35678AFB5421B836AEF3C51462ECD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">will create additional water supplies that support Bureau of Reclamation or the Bureau of Indian Affairs water projects; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE557FD59A0944CB5920710CEE44A5CFF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">will become integrated into the operation of Bureau of Reclamation or the Bureau of Indian Affairs water projects.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H35606D4F55F942ED9BD9505219D04CB3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Flexibility</header><text>Any authority granted under this section may be exercised, and any requirement established under this section may be satisfied, for the conduct of an environmental review process for a project study, a class of project studies, or a program of project studies.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H654DF1CA158B4805A167CB205A4E81D0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>List of project studies</header>
 <subparagraph id="HA0569EFA58FE477B986A6514C9D87F89"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall annually prepare, and make publicly available, a list of all project studies that the Secretary has determined—</text>
 <clause id="H7C385BFA9AB34D7A81D3B71B9493ECFD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>meets the standards described in paragraph (1); and</text> </clause><clause id="H9651A9C4BA7A474CAB851ADA71AC70B9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>does not have adequate funding to make substantial progress toward the completion of the project study.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFFF4EA37EF8345A6ABBAE0C7BB24BF68"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The Secretary shall include for each project study on the list under subparagraph (A) a description of the estimated amounts necessary to make substantial progress on the project study.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H09FB8B9513464AD284CBEA9AEB0E6F42"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Project review process</header>
 <paragraph id="H12D41F41A96D4327A62473E11FB4D37D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall develop and implement a coordinated environmental review process for the development of project studies.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H88946A525747462EA0C6263935F9822A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordinated review</header><text>The coordinated environmental review process described in paragraph (1) shall require that any review, analysis, opinion, statement, permit, license, or other approval or decision issued or made by a Federal, State, or local governmental agency or an Indian tribe for a project study described in subsection (b) be conducted, to the maximum extent practicable, concurrently with any other applicable governmental agency or Indian tribe.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBA2B0EFD4F704109AE189145ABD61978"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>The coordinated environmental review process under this subsection shall be completed not later than the date on which the Secretary, in consultation and concurrence with the agencies identified under section 5(d), establishes with respect to the project study.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H856C40274A664EE784C1D9679897819B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Lead agencies</header>
				<paragraph id="H0D04E09FE2814D6C95DFC194E449E9A2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Joint lead agencies</header>
 <subparagraph id="H5E3C3EB770D34F8885A923DC0C208285"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to the requirements of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.) and the requirements of section 1506.8 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations), including the concurrence of the proposed joint lead agency, a project sponsor may serve as the joint lead agency.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC818B260A374E2DA537304E3B19BDFF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Project sponsor as joint lead agency</header><text>A project sponsor that is a State or local governmental entity may—</text> <clause id="HFEBF72BE549D4CF7B51B7C4D3A0C571B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with the concurrence of the Secretary, serve as a joint lead agency with the Federal lead agency for purposes of preparing any environmental document under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9F59AC8DFEFA43CCA98B681CCE097CAE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>prepare any environmental review process document under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.) required in support of any action or approval by the Secretary if—</text>
 <subclause id="H22DA64E53D9644B69A27F9594CEAA143"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Secretary provides guidance in the preparation process and independently evaluates that document;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H93FB2A9FE49146E3B9C307EB2F417E17"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the project sponsor complies with all requirements applicable to the Secretary under—</text> <item id="H369F891F350440B6AADB52D1E58E5B38"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.);</text>
 </item><item id="HFC2DAEA3822E4331BCD4F7F6BF4D2D18"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>any regulation implementing that Act; and</text> </item><item id="HCDBE58D9FE12418DBB4DAF873EE76DF3"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>any other applicable Federal law; and</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H6A4E2EC6AD4F440193EE153714670BC2"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the Secretary approves and adopts the document before the Secretary takes any subsequent action or makes any approval based on that document, regardless of whether the action or approval of the Secretary results in Federal funding.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H51583B7EEFC244FA9BBF0381ED4B0652"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that—</text> <subparagraph id="HDAECC1514EFF45F5992C0311AE886906"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the project sponsor complies with all design and mitigation commitments made jointly by the Secretary and the project sponsor in any environmental document prepared by the project sponsor in accordance with this subsection; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED857ACAA08B443FBF00925F2AB85B78"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any environmental document prepared by the project sponsor is appropriately supplemented to address any changes to the project the Secretary determines are necessary.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9AAE2D1B1C3E48B8AF9EC56D618955F5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Adoption and use of documents</header><text>Any environmental document prepared in accordance with this subsection shall be adopted and used by any Federal agency making any determination related to the project study to the same extent that the Federal agency could adopt or use a document prepared by another Federal agency under—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF590CA2550FA428FB1CD35E9108D793C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C8C75875E344E2085C63C18510106A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>parts 1500 through 1508 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H13F9A02875D44B689202F17AEBC5495D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Roles and responsibility of lead agency</header><text>With respect to the environmental review process for any project study, the Federal lead agency shall have authority and responsibility—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7979B51149844C279822876383B16F86"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to take such actions as are necessary and proper and within the authority of the Federal lead agency to facilitate the expeditious resolution of the environmental review process for the project study; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF00F4593D32D446B90C19FA91C76AC49"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to prepare or ensure that any required environmental impact statement or other environmental review document for a project study required to be completed under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.) is completed in accordance with this section and applicable Federal law.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H22576895C60246CC91054FE80D97D8FD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Participating and cooperating agencies</header>
 <paragraph id="H81D81E8CB39743E3B6024CE9576A01F5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Identification of jurisdictional agencies</header><text>With respect to carrying out the environmental review process for a project study, the Secretary shall identify, as early as practicable in the environmental review process, all Federal, State, and local government agencies and Indian tribes that may—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H535415F522094FE09A9A26D0110B4BEA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have jurisdiction over the project;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AA531448DE644769A65AEC95F7FE53A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be required by law to conduct or issue a review, analysis, opinion, or statement for the project study; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8FA4741AD7924CF8B168854948E8F7D1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>be required to make a determination on issuing a permit, license, or other approval or decision for the project study.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEFB9EED09A8842B089BD2A06C402240C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State authority</header><text>If the environmental review process is being implemented by the Secretary for a project study within the boundaries of a State, the State, consistent with State law, may choose to participate in the process and to make subject to the process all State agencies that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H29265DBC64B145508B55E4A9C6974643"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have jurisdiction over the project;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B051E59CA4E4C4DA6513B29E7135DA3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are required to conduct or issue a review, analysis, opinion, or statement for the project study; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC5B1ACDCD2143A2B5C37635CB86B12E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>are required to make a determination on issuing a permit, license, or other approval or decision for the project study.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3D64855C4F2443EA8BF311A0172B704"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Invitation</header>
 <subparagraph id="H6BB2BE1388184BFE95DCB13A0E5B5803"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Federal lead agency shall invite, as early as practicable in the environmental review process, any agency identified under paragraph (1) to become a participating or cooperating agency, as applicable, in the environmental review process for the project study.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB12E101A6304417BA73D4BBA97598ABD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>An invitation to participate issued under subparagraph (A) shall set a deadline by which a response to the invitation shall be submitted, which may be extended by the Federal lead agency for good cause.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD849B70D9D8440DBC0DD66F4EF84E78"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text>Section 1501.6 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act), shall govern the identification and the participation of a cooperating agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H74158FD81AFB4802A5B682ABC2391E5D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Federal cooperating agencies</header><text>Any Federal agency that is invited by the Federal lead agency to participate in the environmental review process for a project study shall be designated as a cooperating agency by the Federal lead agency unless the invited agency informs the Federal lead agency, in writing, by the deadline specified in the invitation that the invited agency—</text>
					<subparagraph id="H676567C841924D0EABB9E55BC4FCAA3A"><enum>(A)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0EF79F8460824197BB4EABF239D540E8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has no jurisdiction or authority with respect to the project;</text> </clause><clause id="HB84D76F59DF84105A8DD89AB4F55ECA5" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has no expertise or information relevant to the project; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8AB9A833FC764AF2A332A6B75335DC33" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>does not have adequate funds to participate in the project; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C0DC1A4B31747F6AD39597E7682DA27"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not intend to submit comments on the project.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E7BE067F040434FBE0599D13E873019"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>A participating or cooperating agency shall comply with this section and any schedule established under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H69CDB0B39E49415599D06F6359017E0C"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Effect of designation</header><text>Designation as a participating or cooperating agency under this subsection shall not imply that the participating or cooperating agency—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H929E2188EAC7463B8688C8907F47CC68"><enum>(A)</enum><text>supports a proposed project; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E1EE6267E114717A661E7A3C2A1B018"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has any jurisdiction over, or special expertise with respect to evaluation of, the project.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H834955745F5B45EF9121D15DF44C7214"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Concurrent reviews</header><text>Each participating or cooperating agency shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HF6935244D7C64595BFA6B0F9A395A20F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>carry out the obligations of that agency under other applicable law concurrently and in conjunction with the required environmental review process, unless doing so would prevent the participating or cooperating agency from conducting needed analysis or otherwise carrying out those obligations; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H721F2CC2299F407EB5EDE182F2BF8829"><enum>(B)</enum><text>formulate and implement administrative, policy, and procedural mechanisms to enable the agency to ensure completion of the environmental review process in a timely, coordinated, and environmentally responsible manner.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD025037C99E6421283409A38FD109F0C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Non-Federal projects integrated into reclamation systems</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal lead agency shall serve in that capacity for the entirety of all non-Federal projects that will be integrated into a larger system owned, operated or administered in whole or in part by the Bureau of Reclamation or the Bureau of Indian Affairs.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H185D6627B4744B1EAB7A2D6C36375FA1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Non-Federal project</header><text>If the Secretary determines that a project can be expedited by a non-Federal sponsor and that there is a demonstrable Federal interest in expediting that project, the Secretary shall take such actions as are necessary to advance such a project as a non-Federal project, including, but not limited to, entering into agreements with the non-Federal sponsor of such project to support the planning, design and permitting of such project as a non-Federal project.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HE27C38540CFA4683B2058CD040DD40C4"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Programmatic compliance</header>
 <paragraph id="H6C0D36C6848546DE90324513C3D954FB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall issue guidance regarding the use of programmatic approaches to carry out the environmental review process that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1730A349782D4BDC8E6618A0D4490CB5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>eliminates repetitive discussions of the same issues;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69AB6CCFDF634D38A941B9EDF75853FC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>focuses on the actual issues ripe for analyses at each level of review;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD338EF48196644A0B426F82C5FDD3522"><enum>(C)</enum><text>establishes a formal process for coordinating with participating and cooperating agencies, including the creation of a list of all data that are needed to carry out an environmental review process; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C607C0C7B5A402ABB05EF73ED70F26D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>complies with—</text> <clause id="HEFDDD1F23430405CA212B9253F2F54DF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1257266F8E9043C0AAC3E801343171AF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>all other applicable laws.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H26815CFCEECE48408EE45E6F7C0EC9AD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H08EA451A4BA147B7B82BA59B3FA09768"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as the first step in drafting guidance under that paragraph, consult with relevant Federal, State, and local governmental agencies, Indian tribes, and the public on the appropriate use and scope of the programmatic approaches;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6974B4910A894D5F939F1A5E920B73ED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>emphasize the importance of collaboration among relevant Federal, State, and local governmental agencies, and Indian tribes in undertaking programmatic reviews, especially with respect to including reviews with a broad geographical scope;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F497E861E7943B7AF3576B70CE84603"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure that the programmatic reviews—</text> <clause id="H1D5E544114474633827CAEC48C0AB715"><enum>(i)</enum><text>promote transparency, including of the analyses and data used in the environmental review process, the treatment of any deferred issues raised by Federal, State, and local governmental agencies, Indian tribes, or the public, and the temporal and special scales to be used to analyze those issues;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD5B4F031E63849CCBBAD3F97942D8CAF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>use accurate and timely information in the environmental review process, including—</text> <subclause id="H16B35FC1C8B240C9B8CB50FB5F4B38E0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>criteria for determining the general duration of the usefulness of the review; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H04D17B7A20B440F990F63AB4D6EF1057"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the timeline for updating any out-of-date review;</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H88F28E4FDD124FCFAD14DC3BAE56DE7E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>describe—</text>
 <subclause id="H00557FEAB2B749199523A990238F712F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the relationship between programmatic analysis and future tiered analysis; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H9C179FE4F34843029A7BA4D86BA73807"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the role of the public in the creation of future tiered analysis; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H443B01D31DAE468E8C82F261720EBAD2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>are available to other relevant Federal, State, and local governmental agencies, Indian tribes, and the public;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90E8C6F9353F4FA3B1C53D4785E27703"><enum>(D)</enum><text>allow not fewer than 60 days of public notice and comment on any proposed guidance; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H385A637AD6714563A91AE9C24187B813"><enum>(E)</enum><text>address any comments received under subparagraph (D).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5DF1A112D41044E086CDC652FBF8F69E"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Coordinated reviews</header>
				<paragraph id="HF506BAACA47646779B60BCE6D4815C30"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Coordination plan</header>
 <subparagraph id="H9A0B5ABF0662467DB264456898FA69E8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Federal lead agency shall, after consultation with and with the concurrence of each participating and cooperating agency and the project sponsor or joint lead agency, as applicable, establish a plan for coordinating public and agency participation in, and comment on, the environmental review process for a project study or a category of project studies.</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8740903BB2AE47829E5731359CC184B9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Schedule</header>
 <clause id="H855E1E23F58849D3B87950DA5DFDB483"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable but not later than 45 days after the close of the public comment period on a draft environmental impact statement, the Federal lead agency, after consultation with and the concurrence of each participating and cooperating agency and the project sponsor or joint lead agency, as applicable, shall establish, as part of the coordination plan established in subparagraph (A), a schedule for completion of the environmental review process for the project study.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8F34BEE796E64CDCA281199371D4BE9D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Factors for consideration</header><text>In establishing a schedule, the Secretary shall consider factors such as—</text> <subclause id="H69DD6D5D977F4F7C8098DDDE683748D4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the responsibilities of participating and cooperating agencies under applicable laws;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H42CCCBA5E51441B68B53440CBB7C016A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the resources available to the project sponsor, joint lead agency, and other relevant Federal and State agencies, as applicable;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H2594424F48DF4808AD100FF8B3ABF9A8"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the overall size and complexity of the project;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HCF122577A78D41BBB3A47B45BE77D88A"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the overall schedule for and cost of the project; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HBFDF87219F5E41D08DC6D93546345D15"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the sensitivity of the natural and historical resources that could be affected by the project.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H5636CE07BAF34EA6B848537AD8DB05A4"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Modifications</header><text>The Secretary may—</text>
 <subclause id="H42B0A486E27E4D479B8E45B1BCB252A9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>lengthen a schedule established under clause (i) for good cause; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H30E22E175602449D815FAF70D3E1D143"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shorten a schedule only with concurrence of the affected participating and cooperating agencies and the project sponsor or joint lead agency, as applicable.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H75480754F34845DBB0D4BA671B63814F"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Dissemination</header><text>A copy of a schedule established under clause (i) shall be—</text> <subclause id="H732412AB14974C0C921AD7A526EA3769"><enum>(I)</enum><text>provided to each participating and cooperating agency and the project sponsor or joint lead agency, as applicable; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H3CC4AD474F4A4C8B82BFAA1268967929"><enum>(II)</enum><text>made available to the public.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8FF50AA0ABFD451BADEFE0CB73AD2215"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Comment deadlines</header><text>The Federal lead agency shall establish the following deadlines for comment during the environmental review process for a project study:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7B3C543329674B7488C64382EBF8135C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Draft environmental impact statements</header><text>For comments by Federal and State agencies and the public on a draft environmental impact statement, a period of not more than 60 days after publication in the Federal Register of notice of the date of public availability of the draft environmental impact statement, unless—</text>
 <clause id="HBAF8356FF9FD44A18B20CFAD794597AF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a different deadline is established by agreement of the Federal lead agency, the project sponsor or joint lead agency, as applicable, and all participating and cooperating agencies; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA0A962306A7E4833A942563C4DC9783B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the deadline is extended by the Federal lead agency for good cause.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H03FE1AC2D6C8421E9ED8E42B8AC53F52"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other environmental review processes</header><text>For all other comment periods established by the Federal lead agency for agency or public comments in the environmental review process, a period of not more than 30 days after the date on which the materials on which comment is requested are made available, unless—</text>
 <clause id="HB1DEE86CA97B48CDABF2496C4DE11C0E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a different deadline is established by agreement of the Federal lead agency, the project sponsor, or joint lead agency, as applicable, and all participating and cooperating agencies; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB5FFA350D5FE4A0D9D614AC64B881397"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the deadline is extended by the Federal lead agency for good cause.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0769E147A96B4E18A833276E4CDDF970"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Deadlines for decisions under other laws</header><text>In any case in which a decision under any Federal law relating to a project study, including the issuance or denial of a permit or license, is required to be made by the date described in subsection (i)(5)(B), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Energy and Natural Resources and Indian Affairs of the Senate—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAF15FBAF9B8B4EC29799B5C1E428B257"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as soon as practicable after the 180-day period described in subsection (i)(5)(B), an initial notice of the failure of the Federal agency to make the decision; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50EC67CCA95E4B4D9517DF38DC982CB4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>every 60 days thereafter until such date as all decisions of the Federal agency relating to the project study have been made by the Federal agency, an additional notice that describes the number of decisions of the Federal agency that remain outstanding as of the date of the additional notice.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8C6B7EF323545D6BBCB52C6ABAA753F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Involvement of the public</header><text>Nothing in this subsection reduces any time period provided for public comment in the environmental review process under applicable Federal law (including regulations).</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HE91B648047004FCA982EAA93037CD1C7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Transparency reporting</header>
 <subparagraph id="HC89769ECE1C4429FACF78CDD4FCD0719"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish and maintain an electronic database and, in coordination with other Federal and State agencies, issue reporting requirements to make publicly available the status and progress with respect to compliance with applicable requirements of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.) and any other Federal, State, or local approval or action required for a project study for which this section is applicable.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D44B728120A4785823B50CB97AD826F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Project study transparency</header><text>Consistent with the requirements established under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall make publicly available the status and progress of any Federal, State, Tribal, or local decision, action, or approval required under applicable laws for each project study for which this section is applicable.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF904F17B8EE248B9A95C59ED5167BD0C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Issue Identification and Resolution</header>
 <paragraph id="H0DE5383B538B4751BD929616138BF11C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Cooperation</header><text>The Federal lead agency, the cooperating agencies, and any participating agencies shall work cooperatively in accordance with this section to identify and resolve issues that could delay completion of the environmental review process or result in the denial of any approval required for the project study under applicable laws.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HDF5F58C33A5C475CA16DE43DC1193B0E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal lead agency responsibilities</header>
 <subparagraph id="H643B4FFA526440D9BA71EEB5B2EE9158"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Federal lead agency shall make information available to the cooperating agencies and participating agencies as early as practicable in the environmental review process regarding the environmental and socioeconomic resources located within the project area and the general locations of the alternatives under consideration.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD50DB97A101C4AB9A322FFD944D37E49"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Data sources</header><text>The information under subparagraph (A) may be based on existing data sources, including geographic information systems mapping.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB901A203A0CB4B6DB25724A6FC0A664D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cooperating and participating agency responsibilities</header><text>Based on information received from the Federal lead agency, cooperating and participating agencies shall identify, as early as practicable, any issues of concern regarding the potential environmental or socioeconomic impacts of the project, including any issues that could substantially delay or prevent an agency from granting a permit or other approval that is needed for the project study.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H0F147D6494424B9DBA4DEB29C40E384E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Accelerated issue resolution and elevation</header>
 <subparagraph id="H499964AABB684188B7123CEBD48CC51C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On the request of a participating or cooperating agency or project sponsor, the Secretary shall convene an issue resolution meeting with the relevant participating and cooperating agencies and the project sponsor or joint lead agency, as applicable, to resolve issues that may—</text>
 <clause id="H41B62D5625144A1D8A182E2627F301D1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>delay completion of the environmental review process; or</text> </clause><clause id="H49FB27976CE646E6915E19D7F848CEE7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>result in denial of any approval required for the project study under applicable laws.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21AA9DF908B44CB09E49A11990F241C2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Meeting date</header><text>A meeting requested under this paragraph shall be held not later than 21 days after the date on which the Secretary receives the request for the meeting, unless the Secretary determines that there is good cause to extend that deadline.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFBE3DAC39A64516A72E2C88C6D163E8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>On receipt of a request for a meeting under this paragraph, the Secretary shall notify all relevant participating and cooperating agencies of the request, including the issue to be resolved and the date for the meeting.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81ADB25C83E44F47834D0317B01C0C34"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Elevation of issue resolution</header><text>If a resolution cannot be achieved within the 30-day period beginning on the date of a meeting under this paragraph and a determination is made by the Secretary that all information necessary to resolve the issue has been obtained, the Secretary shall forward the dispute to the heads of the relevant agencies for resolution.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H15E960553C094E4E904950E25F0EAB69"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Convention by secretary</header><text>The Secretary may convene an issue resolution meeting under this paragraph at any time, at the discretion of the Secretary, regardless of whether a meeting is requested under subparagraph (A).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF21EE37E4A64FEC809A80005CDFC8F2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Financial penalty provisions</header>
 <subparagraph id="H6A89CEB1653D4758B1779005F11F6DE5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A Federal jurisdictional agency shall complete any required approval or decision for the environmental review process on an expeditious basis using the shortest existing applicable process.</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H59ED939C278A46FAA05262C6CC5313BA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Failure to decide</header>
						<clause id="HDFBF4ECE25034267ACD614AF202A0BB4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <subclause id="H1706395232B5408C8FABB37A73B1FBD0"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Transfer of funds</header><text>If a Federal jurisdictional agency fails to render a decision required under any Federal law relating to a project study that requires the preparation of an environmental impact statement or environmental assessment, including the issuance or denial of a permit, license, statement, opinion, or other approval by the date described in clause (ii), the amount of funds made available to support the office of the head of the Federal jurisdictional agency shall be reduced by an amount of funding equal to the amount specified in item (aa) or (bb) of subclause (II), and those funds shall be made available to the division of the Federal jurisdictional agency charged with rendering the decision by not later than 1 day after the applicable date under clause (ii), and once each week thereafter until a final decision is rendered, subject to subparagraph (C).</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA42DAF5DEDA54A3F8CFD6271C291CD2E"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Amount to be transferred</header><text>The amount referred to in subclause (I) is—</text> <item id="H24A93F0311314034AEF73D939D9A4C36"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>$20,000 for any project study requiring the preparation of an environmental assessment or environmental impact statement; or</text>
 </item><item id="H0B20002022344B939AA306F55571093B"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>$10,000 for any project study requiring any type of review under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.) other than an environmental assessment or environmental impact statement.</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause id="H6974291F224440BE8600B8CB20D23C79"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Description of date</header><text>The date referred to in clause (i) is the later of—</text> <subclause id="H3C41B3C169B140C492B73A13C662DA4B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the date that is 180 days after the date on which an application for the permit, license, or approval is complete; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H8CB97F236A5B4BA8BA6D06E2CD4A9631"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the date that is 180 days after the date on which the Federal lead agency issues a decision on the project under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
							</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04B32692980E471FA73A7B9562BF11DE"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Limitations</header>
 <clause id="H4DCFD3F7FEDF41F7BADD6E2EA794E978"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No transfer of funds under subparagraph (B) relating to an individual project study shall exceed, in any fiscal year, an amount equal to 1 percent of the funds made available for the applicable agency office.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0A25967C9B8A4593A62773B8242EB38F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Failure to decide</header><text>The total amount transferred in a fiscal year as a result of a failure by an agency to make a decision by an applicable deadline shall not exceed an amount equal to 5 percent of the funds made available for the applicable agency office for that fiscal year.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7BD53ACFCBDF49A4B2E6B737A0C9719C"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Aggregate</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, for each fiscal year, the aggregate amount of financial penalties assessed against each applicable agency office under this Act and any other Federal law as a result of a failure of the agency to make a decision by an applicable deadline for environmental review, including the total amount transferred under this paragraph, shall not exceed an amount equal to 9.5 percent of the funds made available for the agency office for that fiscal year.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F743D9A1D6B47ACAF0D760242322E1E"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Notification of transfers</header><text>Not later than 10 days after the last date in a fiscal year on which funds of the Federal jurisdictional agency may be transferred under subparagraph (B)(5) with respect to an individual decision, the agency shall submit to the appropriate committees of the House of Representatives and the Senate written notification that includes a description of—</text>
 <clause id="HAAD7CECBF3B54A8AB7B27A94720744FD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the decision;</text> </clause><clause id="HA227497A45584FC89816FFDA2816B624"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the project study involved;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H23DABE0EB43F43A19EE77CFB8FD80ABC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the amount of each transfer under subparagraph (B) in that fiscal year relating to the decision;</text> </clause><clause id="H39F1122E9CFF466FBCD3538A802BCBA8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the total amount of all transfers under subparagraph (B) in that fiscal year relating to the decision; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H501C1877FF4544A48CD7E7219524AC62"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the total amount of all transfers of the agency under subparagraph (B) in that fiscal year.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDDC7538867B449E99179C52038C1F748"><enum>(E)</enum><header>No fault of agency</header> <clause id="HACE59560527E44C597BD01FAC534227B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A transfer of funds under this paragraph shall not be made if the applicable agency described in subparagraph (A) notifies, with a supporting explanation, the Federal lead agency, cooperating agencies, and project sponsor, as applicable, that—</text>
 <subclause id="H7F8226F6B25649A3AAAC327A09EEBE75"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the agency has not received necessary information or approvals from another entity in a manner that affects the ability of the agency to meet any requirements under Federal, State, or local law;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H64805CC4D7414807BE443ADA3F8DC2B3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>significant new information, including from public comments, or circumstances, including a major modification to an aspect of the project, requires additional analysis for the agency to make a decision on the project application; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H06CC8B87F38F48F480D66E1C500E7A73"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the agency lacks the financial resources to complete the review under the scheduled timeframe, including a description of the number of full-time employees required to complete the review, the amount of funding required to complete the review, and a justification as to why not enough funding is available to complete the review by the deadline.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H3CC42469E3A74D239B972507BC713CAF"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Lack of financial resources</header><text>If the agency provides notice under clause (i)(III), the Inspector General of the agency shall—</text> <subclause id="H61E14523BBD1411A855F1893FD766392"><enum>(I)</enum><text>conduct a financial audit to review the notice; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H50A6AA1770704B44BB7EEC8024E00FAE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>not later than 90 days after the date on which the review described in subclause (I) is completed, submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate the results of the audit conducted under subclause (I).</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13A66EBBAF8B4C0FA83FAADEC1CFCD6C"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Federal agency from which funds are transferred pursuant to this paragraph shall not reprogram funds to the office of the head of the agency, or equivalent office, to reimburse that office for the loss of the funds.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H26C4299211E44F119ABEED02E7A287CB"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Effect of paragraph</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph affects or limits the application of, or obligation to comply with, any Federal, State, local, or tribal law.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4408E7A9FF25490AA9A5A5781E08979D"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Memorandum of agreements for early coordination</header>
 <paragraph id="H977FE3A1317441FDAA9FF81E04100751"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <subparagraph id="H4BDE51B19B304D13AE2FD2864A479B2F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary and other Federal agencies with relevant jurisdiction in the environmental review process should cooperate with each other, State and local agencies, and Indian tribes on environmental review and Bureau of Reclamation project delivery activities at the earliest practicable time to avoid delays and duplication of effort later in the process, prevent potential conflicts, and ensure that planning and project development decisions reflect environmental values; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1526741D935460183B823AF57B91B84"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the cooperation referred to in subparagraph (A) should include the development of policies and the designation of staff that advise planning agencies and project sponsors of studies or other information foreseeably required for later Federal action and early consultation with appropriate State and local agencies and Indian tribes.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B543E71D1BC405289F9B2BB3B499AB6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>If requested at any time by a State or project sponsor, the Secretary and other Federal agencies with relevant jurisdiction in the environmental review process, shall, to the maximum extent practicable and appropriate, as determined by the agencies, provide technical assistance to the State or project sponsor in carrying out early coordination activities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFF6443B9B5854E36B82246B52EA6315E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Memorandum of agency agreement</header><text>If requested at any time by a State or project sponsor, the Federal lead agency, in consultation with other Federal agencies with relevant jurisdiction in the environmental review process, may establish memoranda of agreement with the project sponsor, Indian tribes, State and local governments, and other appropriate entities to carry out the early coordination activities, including providing technical assistance in identifying potential impacts and mitigation issues in an integrated fashion.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H623C17D877FD498A9099314E2C9349F6"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>Nothing in this section preempts or interferes with—</text> <paragraph id="HD36FBAB60A684DB2B3FF35A94F309F53"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any obligation to comply with the provisions of any Federal law, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H98A79167FE61482C84B2397BF8527B03"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3CCDE13001DD44DC92823B1CF63352AD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other Federal environmental law;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H554E9C4258F240BCB4DED769122B09F3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the reviewability of any final Federal agency action in a court of the United States or in the court of any State;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H527F79104F28449DB84BBBA55851C4CB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any requirement for seeking, considering, or responding to public comment; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0CEB78AC501341BCA64718298791E762"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any power, jurisdiction, responsibility, duty, or authority that a Federal, State, or local governmental agency, Indian tribe, or project sponsor has with respect to carrying out a project or any other provision of law applicable to projects.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H05E0485400504123924454A79BB75D0B"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Timing of claims</header>
				<paragraph id="H0A9D4B02E48940B6B108696103D0FE69"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Timing</header>
 <subparagraph id="H858708E4B238474C80699C0A26699E8F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a claim arising under Federal law seeking judicial review of a permit, license, or other approval issued by a Federal agency for a project study shall be barred unless the claim is filed not later than 3 years after publication of a notice in the Federal Register announcing that the permit, license, or other approval is final pursuant to the law under which the agency action is taken, unless a shorter time is specified in the Federal law that allows judicial review.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H54DB34F7E9A24B2BACCD07271C7DB840"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Nothing in this subsection creates a right to judicial review or places any limit on filing a claim that a person has violated the terms of a permit, license, or other approval.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F76377E23AC47F180297735FE857582"><enum>(2)</enum><header>New information</header>
 <subparagraph id="HAB5AFBC753AD41A9886DD80D543BFC48"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall consider new information received after the close of a comment period if the information satisfies the requirements for a supplemental environmental impact statement under title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (including successor regulations).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H79F4D62FF2D04A5F91EDE0CC48AC0E65"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Separate action</header><text>The preparation of a supplemental environmental impact statement or other environmental document, if required under this section, shall be considered a separate final agency action and the deadline for filing a claim for judicial review of the action shall be 3 years after the date of publication of a notice in the Federal Register announcing the action relating to such supplemental environmental impact statement or other environmental document.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA09E06DD98CE4A7E82C16BB4E9077186"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Categorical exclusions</header>
 <paragraph id="H6081DD328CA54AEEAC00582EE2F873D1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H01FDC4D764634D99A2027BCE27C1645C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">survey the use by the Bureau of Reclamation and the Bureau of Indian Affairs of categorical exclusions in projects since 2005;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HADBE91FC5EA842F7A2592D95BFAE79C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>publish a review of the survey that includes a description of—</text> <clause id="H16C62D8D73FC4871A3BE3F09E5F9B84E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the types of actions that were categorically excluded or could be the basis for developing a new categorical exclusion; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HADD300D6F440475DAE77973481A0255D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any requests previously received by the Secretary for new categorical exclusions; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H354C08C6396D498EB0B9E26852E0CFFA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>solicit requests from other Federal agencies and project sponsors for new categorical exclusions.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB3663820A6F5415D8FB612E543A772B0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>New categorical exclusions</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, if the Secretary has identified a category of activities that merit establishing a categorical exclusion that did not exist on the day before the date of enactment of this Act based on the review under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall publish a notice of proposed rulemaking to propose that new categorical exclusion, to the extent that the categorical exclusion meets the criteria for a categorical exclusion under section 1508.4 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulation).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9D8C2A81BAC142E29BF5CF5AEA126CE9"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Review of project acceleration reforms</header>
 <paragraph id="HBA63EDC6D8D84208B99E5F07A439ABC4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H96777B83E35046BB92510352DC7BE047"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assess the reforms carried out under this section; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2DF64E54B0454FDFA839033926B183DF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 5 years and not later than 10 years after the date of enactment of this Act, submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Energy and Natural Resources and Indian Affairs of the Senate a report that describes the results of the assessment.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA3B29385D384F4FBDF191600C1F26A1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The reports under paragraph (1) shall include an evaluation of impacts of the reforms carried out under this section on—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF6D5F6C3D03E49BE8AE757CD3BDF54EF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>project delivery;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1061C6E0104F4F29B5AEE321097E0BAA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>compliance with environmental laws; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42FCABF05A054AC29556D409041C2D4A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the environmental impact of projects.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H235D1F9A9364408E8DDCCA69E2EBD772"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Performance measurement</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a program to measure and report on progress made toward improving and expediting the planning and environmental review process.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB6D399471817471C853E8056CB90123E"><enum>(p)</enum><header>Categorical exclusions in emergencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the repair, reconstruction, or rehabilitation of a Bureau of Reclamation or Bureau of Indian Affairs project that is in operation or under construction when damaged by an event or incident that results in a declaration by the President of a major disaster or emergency pursuant to the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121</external-xref> et seq.), the Secretary shall treat such repair, reconstruction, or rehabilitation activity as a class of action categorically excluded from the requirements relating to environmental assessments or environmental impact statements under section 1508.4 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations), if the repair or reconstruction activity is—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7DBE1F033A0A475CA9EA1FB26822054A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the same location with the same capacity, dimensions, and design as the original Bureau of Reclamation or Bureau of Indian Affairs project as before the declaration described in this section; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6352185946A74BB4A33FF8AFD93A8DD9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commenced within a 2-year period beginning on the date of a declaration described in this subsection.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA6F04A74A98A4A4A9777B1B7B9706348"><enum>6.</enum><header>Annual report to congress</header>
 <subsection id="HE6DA771232784DE98DBF9626CD053180"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than February 1 of each year, the Secretary shall develop and submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Energy and Natural Resources and Indian Affairs of the Senate an annual report, to be entitled <quote>Report to Congress on Future Water Project Development</quote>, that identifies the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H8FBC34531E674093B4404CE5DEC6934B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Project reports</header><text>Each project report that meets the criteria established in subsection (c)(1)(A).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H88221F72E220438189956B7FEE7C0D69"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Proposed project studies</header><text>Any proposed project study submitted to the Secretary by a non-Federal interest pursuant to subsection (b) that meets the criteria established in subsection (c)(1)(A).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9D5086900EE14E3996C72A1901044B50"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Proposed modifications</header><text>Any proposed modification to an authorized water project or project study that meets the criteria established in subsection (c)(1)(A) that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0A88D8917941424CBA7B7C446DF6E9CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is submitted to the Secretary by a non-Federal interest pursuant to subsection (b); or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAEB11A880E6D463997ABDC0A86D820D4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is identified by the Secretary for authorization.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8597BA5A0427422B822C683088CA4AA6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Expedited completion of report and determinations</header><text>Any project study that was expedited and any Secretarial determinations under section 4 of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4A55398C26A94B8CB473427F556FCE3F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requests for proposals</header>
 <paragraph id="H4B533A6946B64BFA81F6124AE5C05126"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>Not later than May 1 of each year, the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register a notice requesting proposals from non-Federal interests for proposed project studies and proposed modifications to authorized projects and project studies to be included in the annual report.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBFDC0152C0ED4205A89929E7A4E58054"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadline for requests</header><text>The Secretary shall include in each notice required by this subsection a requirement that non-Federal interests submit to the Secretary any proposals described in paragraph (1) by not later than 120 days after the date of publication of the notice in the Federal Register in order for the proposals to be considered for inclusion in the annual report.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4F20D79295B04C609EB1405613C50604"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>On the date of publication of each notice required by this subsection, the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H968BDFD10E7B4856A52118EDFB9EA3E9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>make the notice publicly available, including on the Internet; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA5866F206FA45E688D8A3F6122B9006"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide written notification of the publication to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Energy and Natural Resources and Indian Affairs of the Senate.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4EC6F1F94ED0430089A17A3D6E171E9E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Contents</header>
				<paragraph id="H267E84D1D1764E86BDB19172A6B83548"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Project reports, proposed project studies, and proposed modifications</header>
 <subparagraph id="HB28FB5560A874607B64C15BC3844FF01"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Criteria for inclusion in report</header><text>The Secretary shall include in the annual report only those project reports, proposed project studies, and proposed modifications to authorized projects and project studies that—</text>
 <clause id="H04578BBD59184CE38229FC5036A25D0C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are related to the missions and authorities of the Bureau of Reclamation or the Bureau of Indian Affairs;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H664970642FC74E06A24F35FB0A566EC4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>require specific congressional authorization, including by an Act of Congress;</text> </clause><clause id="H32680B3030BE4AB48344343AA71298B8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>have not been congressionally authorized;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB10A2928DF3B42A9A6BD8CAA229DCD71"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>have not been included in any previous annual report; and</text> </clause><clause id="H08E2A6C5AFDF4C52A66F224DCBAC3435"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if authorized, could be carried out by the Bureau of Reclamation or the Bureau of Indian Affairs.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4A16E4EFD4248E6A18D19CB02483468"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Description of benefits</header>
 <clause id="H55461483E7F14EC6BB8A57734526B4A5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Description</header><text>The Secretary shall describe in the annual report, to the extent applicable and practicable, for each proposed project study and proposed modification to an authorized water resources development project or project study included in the annual report, the benefits, as described in clause (ii), of each such study or proposed modification.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB035690E5232460695D8516F647586DD"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Benefits</header><text>The benefits (or expected benefits, in the case of a proposed project study) described in this clause are benefits to—</text>
 <subclause id="H1A78242D0E8843F0935D233EAE209E86"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the protection of human life and property;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HD21CF41380CE49B998778907FBB709D5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>improvement to domestic irrigated water and power supplies;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HFC7E756076D24E619F173EB5A6EE50A6"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the national economy;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H5BE01CFD1A334FEB93786ED8CA3A46D3"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the environment; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H221F8435F5DD4BF983BB2642BB864E62"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the national security interests of the United States.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2240FA7F58C4917B08260F64A837BBE"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Identification of other factors</header><text>The Secretary shall identify in the annual report, to the extent practicable—</text>
 <clause id="H032CB70A9778486392C2A9EC75884B6D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for each proposed project study included in the annual report, the non-Federal interest that submitted the proposed project study pursuant to subsection (b); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEE5EC1053E704447B8F2A47AA950A9CA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for each proposed project study and proposed modification to a project or project study included in the annual report, whether the non-Federal interest has demonstrated—</text>
 <subclause id="H27A97D46CB4349CBA3D0C2F4D7BBFBD5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>that local support exists for the proposed project study or proposed modification to an authorized project or project study (including the surface water storage development project that is the subject of the proposed feasibility study or the proposed modification to an authorized project study); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H2205D8CF4E0141A79850B8D161041211"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the financial ability to provide the required non-Federal cost share.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7A9ECCBE8AF47ECB619F9A7253C5474"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transparency</header><text>The Secretary shall include in the annual report, for each project report, proposed project study, and proposed modification to a project or project study included under paragraph (1)(A)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1DD2E0DB6CEE48E8A751CC2669CFF5CD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name of the associated non-Federal interest, including the name of any non-Federal interest that has contributed, or is expected to contribute, a non-Federal share of the cost of—</text>
 <clause id="H844487BA4E8A468E9949AE8C5A93C88E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the project report;</text> </clause><clause id="H39542B31F41F4A0A84DE176FC8C67987"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the proposed project study;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC2640E737E694224AF5C49769AAEA4CB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the authorized project study for which the modification is proposed; or</text> </clause><clause id="H9535D57E541F44D0872368749C7A2891"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>construction of—</text>
 <subclause id="H55C7C1894F4243139DD008DDC3FC8DC4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the project that is the subject of—</text> <item id="HBF53A6C451B7498B8F00FE9B34243873"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the water report;</text>
 </item><item id="HF101B674D0D24B4B838ACF3D4D44DFF9"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the proposed project study; or</text> </item><item id="H9FC6BDAE87BA46DA963AC25DE6FD1577"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the authorized project study for which a modification is proposed; or</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H3A2C856BE1CF4B5CB55C2C928BB238CE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the proposed modification to a project;</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H256BB232521B42398424873428C4A783"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a letter or statement of support for the water report, proposed project study, or proposed modification to a project or project study from each associated non-Federal interest;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74E6B714C54A494C8BFDCF97D166330B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the purpose of the feasibility report, proposed feasibility study, or proposed modification to a project or project study;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1849B18EED84B6F9957D0299DE3D8B4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an estimate, to the extent practicable, of the Federal, non-Federal, and total costs of—</text> <clause id="HAB1F4B1CAC924B118E8F8C8C3813A555"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the proposed modification to an authorized project study; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA584843848C54CFB98AF1C870C50E801"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>construction of—</text> <subclause id="H3EA97C9E3D3D4E3E963490FE5FAEBB58"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the project that is the subject of—</text>
 <item id="H5E1C8B6352B54AC0B6E2699AD73CBD12"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the project report; or</text> </item><item id="HE61AD2388B1E4811AB5CAF78A1C3C8D8"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the authorized project study for which a modification is proposed, with respect to the change in costs resulting from such modification; or</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="HF1FEDB5293354AC7AA86F73819B3EFEA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the proposed modification to an authorized project; and</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8EE4F2B3C5804C669EF42854049E102C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an estimate, to the extent practicable, of the monetary and nonmonetary benefits of—</text>
 <clause id="H4C09526175224F968EDD1FA437208E2B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the project that is the subject of—</text> <subclause id="H65775E7D200F4448BBCE72F8BA67428C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the project report; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H13ECA73FF13E40B5A929CBBCA8D301E5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the authorized project study for which a modification is proposed, with respect to the benefits of such modification; or</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H2E7D33B887FB4564AF3E49B3739CF874"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the proposed modification to an authorized project.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H366A508E47F144CEBB7D73E77109EBC7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>The Secretary shall include in the annual report a certification stating that each feasibility report, proposed feasibility study, and proposed modification to a project or project study included in the annual report meets the criteria established in paragraph (1)(A).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HADDE0F04093545729F13DC17A5C8DE73"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Appendix</header><text>The Secretary shall include in the annual report an appendix listing the proposals submitted under subsection (b) that were not included in the annual report under paragraph (1)(A) and a description of why the Secretary determined that those proposals did not meet the criteria for inclusion under such paragraph.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAC16CCB391FA427285F75C043625062C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Special rule for initial annual report</header><text>Notwithstanding any other deadlines required by this section, the Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="H35A958B2EBCF4F0C994B0012D10CD572"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, publish in the Federal Register a notice required by subsection (b)(1); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H54CBF119507D43928D352B7DC6097C30"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include in such notice a requirement that non-Federal interests submit to the Secretary any proposals described in subsection (b)(1) by not later than 120 days after the date of publication of such notice in the Federal Register in order for such proposals to be considered for inclusion in the first annual report developed by the Secretary under this section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H932B03FE99E04A6EA91086ACEBA48E98"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>Upon submission of an annual report to Congress, the Secretary shall make the annual report publicly available, including through publication on the Internet.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF2DC5B52704A4F3E8A9416AC70E7A124"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>project report</term> means a final feasibility report developed under the Reclamation Act of 1902 (32 Stat. 388), and all Acts amendatory thereof or supplementary thereto.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H1A7AA5E573344ECF98FF79182FD8E440"><enum>7.</enum><header>Applicability of the WIIN Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Sections 3221 through 3226, 4007 and 4009 of the WIIN Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/322">Public Law 114–322</external-xref>) shall not apply to any project (as defined in section 2 of this Act).</text>
 </section><section id="HC346425FD75B42809DE21D93B662E9BD"><enum>8.</enum><header>Project authorizations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The following projects for water resources development and conservation and other purposes, as identified in the following reports and correspondence are authorized to be carried out by the Secretary substantially in accordance with the plans, and subject to the conditions, described in the respective reports and correspondence designated in this section:</text>
			<table align-to-level="section" blank-lines-before="1" colsep="1" frame="all" line-rules="all-gen" rowsep="1" rule-weights="4.4.4.4.4.0" table-template-name="Generic: 1text, 1num, 1text, 1num" table-type="">
				<tgroup cols="4" grid-typeface="1.1" rowsep="1" thead-tbody-ldg-size="10.10.12"><colspec coldef="txt-no-ldr" colname="column1" colwidth="27pts" min-data-value="12"></colspec><colspec coldef="txt-no-ldr" colname="column2" colwidth="80pts" min-data-value="35"></colspec><colspec coldef="txt-no-ldr" colname="column3" colwidth="68pts" min-data-value="30"></colspec><colspec coldef="txt-no-ldr" colname="column4" colwidth="128pts" min-data-value="56"></colspec><thead>
						<row><entry align="center" colname="column1" morerows="0" namest="column1"><bold>State</bold></entry><entry align="center" colname="column2" morerows="0" namest="column2"><bold>Name</bold></entry><entry align="center" colname="column3" morerows="0" namest="column3"><bold>Date of Feasibility Report</bold></entry><entry align="center" colname="column4" morerows="0" namest="column4"><bold>Estimated Costs</bold></entry></row></thead>
					<tbody>
						<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" leader-modify="clr-ldr" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">WA</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr">Phase III of the Yakima River Basin Water Enhancement Project</entry><entry align="left" colname="column3" leader-modify="clr-ldr">March 2, 2012 </entry><entry align="right" colname="column4" leader-modify="clr-ldr">Non-Federal: $500,000,000 <linebreak></linebreak>Federal: $237,100,000 <linebreak></linebreak>Total: $737,100,000 </entry></row>
						<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" leader-modify="clr-ldr" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">KS</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr">Equus Beds Division of the Wichita Project</entry><entry align="left" colname="column3" leader-modify="clr-ldr">January 19, 2010</entry><entry align="right" colname="column4" leader-modify="clr-ldr">Non-Federal: $90,000,000 <linebreak></linebreak>Federal: $30,000,000 <linebreak></linebreak>Total: $120,000,000 </entry></row>
						<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" leader-modify="clr-ldr" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">MT</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr">Musselshell-Judith Rural Water System</entry><entry align="left" colname="column3" leader-modify="clr-ldr">July 31, 2015</entry><entry align="right" colname="column4" leader-modify="clr-ldr">Non-Federal: $21,801,000 <linebreak></linebreak>Federal: $65,301,000 <linebreak></linebreak>Total: $87,102,000 </entry></row>
						<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" leader-modify="clr-ldr" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">CA</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr">Shasta Lake Water Resources Investigation</entry><entry align="left" colname="column3" leader-modify="clr-ldr">July 29, 2015</entry><entry align="right" colname="column4" leader-modify="clr-ldr">Non-Federal: $350,000 <linebreak></linebreak>Federal: $36,420,000 <linebreak></linebreak>Total: $36,770,000 </entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table>
		</section><section id="H0967B1686C114263934DFADD383763C5"><enum>9.</enum><header>Deauthorizations</header>
			<subsection id="HE8B1BC198348448CBD336E16FD0DB575"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purposes; definitions</header>
 <paragraph id="HEF1F2BA6E1F4461F96DA9CDAFE3E321D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this section are—</text> <subparagraph id="HABB0F926A407480D98BC4EA90A82491D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to identify $368,821,000 in Bureau of Reclamation projects and programs that are no longer feasible due to—</text>
 <clause id="H5C189B3D5EE5484D83BC2DD4CAFED5BE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a lack of local support;</text> </clause><clause id="H12C6966AEAB648DAA72805D930CCED92"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a lack of available Federal or non-Federal resources; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H13FB7E73563545F88C72BFCD57CF9AE0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an authorized purpose that is no longer relevant or feasible;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AC4F3082B894322A16C43CF43E7B14C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to establish an efficient and transparent process for deauthorizing Bureau of Reclamation projects and programs that have failed to receive a minimum level of investment, thereby ensuring active projects can move forward while reducing the backlog of authorized projects;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA812EC677B4645CB9DE65642E3EF9174"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to create an expedited and definitive process to deauthorize Reclamation projects and programs;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0479CA429599411582F678721D4735E4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to allow the continued authorization of programs and projects that are feasible; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF623322604C042B2ADB2A4A063EF5B05"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to establish a process for identifying authorized Bureau of Reclamation projects and programs that are no longer—</text>
 <clause id="HD3A13C5848744EF3B0A951036C3AB45A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the Federal interest; or</text> </clause><clause id="HC15F63F67C584A21AF1753C91C74A724"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>feasible.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B151796E8B74146A58C3FC492FF71B2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <subparagraph id="HB88F1219231D4B7A84C2F315D52CB34B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD358B680FC1046D088E3033ADA0FBF20"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reclamation project or program</header><text>The term <term>Reclamation project and program</term> includes any project or program that is administered by the Bureau of Reclamation.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2E43339F503F4367B8FC714345523660"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Comprehensive reports</header> <paragraph id="H78C75354C055408E93148667B1D725F0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Minimum funding list</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives, and make available on a publicly accessible Internet website in a manner that is downloadable, searchable, and sortable, a list of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H536A13C506AD42459E0141BB40EC546D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reclamation programs that are authorized and for which funding was obligated during the current fiscal year or any of the preceding 5 fiscal years;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7256BC74065B40EDAABE78B2FB26A61C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>projects or separable elements of projects authorized for construction for which funding has been obligated during the current fiscal year or any of the 5 preceding fiscal years; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H032524746A9947929AE66E73C4659A9E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for each project or element of a project listed pursuant to subparagraph (B)—</text> <clause id="H30ECBF6AE7254280B4E34DE03F1B7EA2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount of funding obligated for each such project or separable element per fiscal year;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF259B31959EC453C904C7F6E074177B6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the current phase of each such project or separable element; and</text> </clause><clause id="HC178E973E4E74C19B17DA7152A1C69AF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the amount required to complete the current phase of each such project or separable element.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5E5023AF29F4C7199A3DBDF0CB5C14B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Backlog report</header><text>With the report required under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives, and make available on a publicly accessible Internet website in a manner that is downloadable, searchable, and sortable, a list of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAEFB0DCA15FB4E8BBBF0B9F0B0B7CCC0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>programs that are authorized and for which funding was not obligated during the current fiscal year or any of the preceding 5 fiscal years;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H842A06B115D549C5A7D5693FDB2D6FB3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>projects or separable elements that are authorized for construction but have not been completed; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35966A0595354B90842500CA0DB6D949"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for each project or separable element listed pursuant to subparagraph (B)—</text> <clause id="HA20C1666B124473B83983D1A7990B8C7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the date of authorization of the project or separable element, including any subsequent modifications to the original authorization;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7C66A66B8DA341938FAA7F5EDB824885"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the original budget authority for the project or separable element;</text> </clause><clause id="HF697DE6FAF5045958FD08E26E87467EB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a brief description of the project or separable element;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4CCF14FA005540CC89404B075F1D7300"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the estimated date of completion of the project or separable element;</text> </clause><clause id="H5609A992B532438C8CEAC6FF116B6F39"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the estimated cost of completion of the project or separable element; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H94B944EA2EDA4D49B256487D96413201"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>any amounts appropriated for the project or separable element that remain unobligated.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBDB17941CEF442FCB0809B6354CC7788"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Interim deauthorization list</header> <paragraph id="H0624890557EE4F25938F6F206536B354"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall develop an interim deauthorization list that identifies each Reclamation program or project, or separable element of a program or project, authorized 5 years prior to enactment of this Act, for which Federal and non-Federal funding was obligated to before the date of the enactment of this Act, but for which no Federal or non-Federal funds were obligated for the program, project, or separable element of the program or project during the current fiscal year or any of the 5 preceding fiscal years.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7B8F85B7582045DCAFC43BD773BBE8B2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rule for projects receiving funds for post-authorization study</header><text>A project or separable element of a project may not be identified on the interim deauthorization list, or the final deauthorization list developed under subsection (d), if the project or separable element received Federal funding for a post-authorization study during the current fiscal year or any of the 5 preceding fiscal years.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD70FA6218CBE40F7BD8EF8B7AE189228"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public comment and consultation</header><text>The Secretary shall solicit comments from the public and the Governors of each applicable State on the interim deauthorization list developed under paragraph (1). The public comment period shall be 90 days.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5EBD6AC2BBD74C3DA9ADA0A14B9FD11A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Submission to congress; publication</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the submission of the list required by subsection (b), the Secretary shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF8059FB9AAB64C8CBEBA1F6E3A3EE928"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submit the interim deauthorization list to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HADD9F1D0197C410A8197D216471F1150"><enum>(B)</enum><text>publish the interim deauthorization list in the Federal Register.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H73726802294C461999962C057B6EC67E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Final deauthorization list</header> <paragraph id="HABD6E8EC276D426D9FBFC0744D435667"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall develop a final deauthorization list of each Reclamation program or project, or separable element of a program or project, described in subsection (c)(1) that is identified pursuant to this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBFE848047E804594A3738036FAB98C5B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deauthorization amount</header><text>The Secretary shall include on the final deauthorization list projects and separable elements of projects that have, in the aggregate, an estimated Federal cost to complete that is at least $368,821,000.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HC1DE20522C704CC5BA0DED89A0E652B8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Identification of projects</header>
					<subparagraph id="H5E34C98414124128BFB7DD23F1895737"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Sequencing of projects</header>
 <clause id="H1356C2E2105045658AD8E8EDB804450E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall identify projects and separable elements of projects for inclusion on the final deauthorization list according to the order in which the projects and separable elements of the projects were authorized, beginning with the earliest authorized projects and separable elements of projects and ending once the last project or separable element of a project necessary to meet the aggregate amount under paragraph (2) is identified.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H89712ABC864741019D32106A05D8E1BD"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Factors to consider</header><text>The Secretary may identify programs, projects, and separable elements of programs and projects for exclusion from the final deauthorization list if the Secretary determines, on a case-by-case basis, that a project or separable element of a project is critical for interests of the United States, based on the possible impact of the project or separable element of the project on public health and safety, the national economy, or the environment.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1BDFB122D6A94C8EB53B8F1DD294A6FD"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Consideration of public comments</header><text>In making determinations under clauses (i) and (ii), the Secretary shall consider any comments received under subsection (c)(3).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0443154942864F3F9715106152D3C807"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Appendix</header><text>The Secretary shall include as part of the final deauthorization list an appendix that—</text> <clause id="H7E1A91348CE6424DB0208F6B148DE866"><enum>(i)</enum><text>identifies each program, project, and separable element of a program or project on the interim deauthorization list developed under subsection (c) that is not included on the final deauthorization list; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H67E61087C2434B8794A8F8A2DA2296FA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>describes the reasons why the program, project, or separable element is not included.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF4DFDE038E04431894CB7C6E5642BF2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Submission to congress; publication</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date on which the public comment period under subsection (c)(3) expires, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBCA3E881AF99497C82403072C5E62340"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submit the final deauthorization list and the appendix to the final deauthorization list to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H702FFE49865A49B992672BA7D7F66B49"><enum>(B)</enum><text>publish the final deauthorization list and the appendix to the final deauthorization list in the Federal Register.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3DA8F85A64D84B4E96E5D03375FBE378"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Deauthorization; congressional review</header>
 <paragraph id="H4C14B8B00E9A4DF291EEF25A0EE63760"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), after the date that is 180 days after the date of submission of the final deauthorization report under subsection (d), a program, project, or separable element of a program or project identified in the report is deauthorized, unless Congress passes a joint resolution disapproving the final deauthorization report prior to the end of that period.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H852EE61FA548456BB432151E9454217E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Non-federal contributions</header><text>A program, project, or separable element of a program or project identified in the final deauthorization report under subsection (d) shall not be deauthorized under this subsection if, before the expiration of the 180-day period referred to in paragraph (1), the non-Federal interest of the program, project, or separable element of the project provides sufficient funds to complete the program, project, or separable element of the project.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H36D4EA69E6CC4D6282F2E3AEDC48E6E3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Treatment of project modifications</header><text>For purposes of this section, if an authorized water resources development program, project, or separable element of the program or project has been modified by an Act of Congress, the date of authorization of the program, project, or separable element shall be deemed to be the date of the most recent modification.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEE5B894E81CE42519DE4575815D49D9B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text>This subsection shall not apply to any project that would yield more than 200,000 acre-feet of water per year on average.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


