<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H9AFC5ED96987499A9E7D249FA3BDB75F" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2084 IH: Year-Round Pell Grant Restoration Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2084</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170408">April 8, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000486">Ms. Roybal-Allard</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve the Federal Pell Grant program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HDE48A76DF80042D89E29A77264D20336" style="OLC">
 <section id="H24032E4F5366493786DCB6216504725D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Year-Round Pell Grant Restoration Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H1902C9F763AF4357A2242CDDBAE8AB98"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H469622CB4C2E40EC953209CAF69241D6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Congressional Budget Office reports on any overall financial surplus or shortfall in the funding provided for the Federal Pell Grant program. However, in recent years, in order to meet the maximum Federal Pell Grant level with the provided level of funding, Congress has made cuts to the program through imposing additional eligibility requirements for Federal Pell Grants and limiting the availability of year-round Federal Pell Grants, causing significant uncertainty and reducing access to higher education for millions of hardworking college students.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H13C744AB392540EAB0A0ACF26615E278"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The <quote>traditional student</quote> who attends college for 4 years immediately after high school is now a minority of college students today. Ambitious students now need more flexibility to attend school year-round while juggling work schedules.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H12BEDFE8FA0D49B3873C56A51C1A6B21"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Section 1860 of the Department of Defense and Full-Year Continuing Appropriations Act, 2011 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/10">Public Law 112–10</external-xref>, 125 Stat. 169) eliminated the provision of the Federal Pell Grant program of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a">20 U.S.C. 1070a</external-xref> et seq.) that allowed more than 1 Federal Pell Grant awards per year, creating significant hardship for many students trying to take courses over the summer or outside the traditional school calendar. Allowing students to continue to receive Federal Pell Grants in successive semesters, without a gap, would reduce the time needed to complete their degrees.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H54E55DDD44744228919E3B8444ECE4CC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Year-Round Federal Pell Grant students</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 401(b) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a">20 U.S.C. 1070a(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5358F0AD7DC342FB8A7D247491B5704B" style="OLC">
				<paragraph id="H9519D3939E814F09AE0FDC0D3BBC4ED9" indent="up1"><enum>(8)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H920F189989D94993BB8B3537953C1603"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Effective for the 2018–2019 award year and each award year thereafter, the Secretary shall award an eligible student a total of not more than 1½ Federal Pell Grants during a single award year to permit such student to work toward completion of an eligible program if, during that single award year, the student—</text>
 <clause id="H555156CA19E443A68DCA40ECFAE91847" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has received a Federal Pell Grant for the award year and is enrolled in an eligible program for one or more additional payment periods during the same award year that are not otherwise fully covered by the student's Federal Pell Grant; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H03F1A54B8F154D93A7D6737FA6DA0B33" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is enrolled on at least a half-time basis while receiving any funds under this section.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA967D8D3E5D47F3B0FBA58DECB02A00" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In the case of a student receiving more than one Federal Pell Grant in a single award year under subparagraph (A), the total amount of the Federal Pell Grants awarded to such student for the award year may exceed the maximum Federal Pell Grant available for an award year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1936B70DC4B64F0AAB877D8629A7BDED" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any period of study covered by a Federal Pell Grant awarded under subparagraph (A) shall be included in determining a student's duration limit under subsection (c)(5).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD3A600DC8A9D419487D72A6EED5FEB53" indent="up1"><enum>(9)</enum><text>In any case where an eligible student is receiving a Federal Pell Grant for a payment period that spans 2 award years, the Secretary shall allow the eligible institution in which the student is enrolled to determine the award year to which the additional period shall be assigned, as it determines is most beneficial to the student.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


