<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCC89932CF43B41E09AABB4EF48D5B377" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1266 IH: Vision Zero Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1266</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170301">March 1, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of Transportation to make grants to assist units of local government in developing and implementing plans, known as Vision Zero plans, to eliminate transportation-related fatalities and serious injuries, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H71A87962810E4B48B0239B98D8A086FA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA92A9E82B46B494EBC35018A8DB66CC7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Vision Zero Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H4D7D767A316A4CCDB080C4332668E761"><enum>2.</enum><header>Vision zero planning grants</header> <subsection id="HEEA42699AE8144D79FE0EEBC3DDD7734"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Transportation is authorized to award grants to eligible entities to develop a plan, known as a Vision Zero plan, to eliminate transportation-related fatalities and serious injuries in the jurisdiction of such entity within a specified timeframe, not to exceed 20 years.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H001A91C4E0154790BEDF125A2ABEFA0B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible for a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such form, and containing such information and assurances as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB25951FBBF674B0680F4A7804B24A4AD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Plan contents</header><text>The Vision Zero plan described in subsection (a) shall include—</text> 
<paragraph id="H68549DFFE52641AD9D71DE29583C8B8C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of projects or policies intended to eliminate transportation-related fatalities and serious injuries within a specified timeframe, not to exceed 20 years, using existing transportation and health data and consideration of risk factors, which may include—</text> <subparagraph id="HF9F8747D951D4856A3DF97DFE6176A4F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an examination of how development and implementation of safety-focused automotive technologies, vehicle-to-vehicle communication, and vehicle-to-infrastructure communication can help eliminate transportation-related fatalities and serious injuries; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H23627AE2D7DD4808820F97B29121B0C7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>roadway design guidance that prioritizes the safety of all users, with a focus on reducing speeds to the extent practicable within State law and separating modes of transportation;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H89B8FEAE74DA46BC84F4F1EDF6EBCA0D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">plans for implementation of, education of the public about, and enforcement of such projects or policies;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H71CCF3824EC54135892216BD8339C64A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of how such policies, projects, and enforcement will—</text> <subparagraph id="H5A0F2225405A41E58BEC15324EE900D7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>equitably address the safety needs of low-income and minority communities;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H580373858B7D44A3B5ECDA6B53F73E1B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that such communities are not disproportionately targeted by law enforcement; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA129E895254C4013B708815E44E2DB76"><enum>(C)</enum><text>protect the rights of members of such communities with respect to title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d</external-xref> et seq.);</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAFBD85F4894B4568B65E577B045A2C88"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the required involvement of various subdivisions of a unit of local government in the implementation of the plan, including subdivisions in charge of law enforcement, public health, and public works; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6005D50DA7804331887DBC94114FF14B"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of a mechanism to evaluate progress of the implementation of the plan, including the gathering and use of transportation safety and demographic data.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H6352977735004B8DA4549C925B8ECAC6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Vision Zero Implementation Grant Program</header> 
<subsection id="HC3D04E3365674B4CBB6FF6318B219F6D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation may award grants to not more than 5 eligible entities to support the implementation of a Vision Zero plan to eliminate transportation-related fatalities and serious injuries in the jurisdiction of such entity within a specified timeframe, not to exceed 20 years.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H95EDC5C651EB4336B5FF778EDD2FC880"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible for a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such form, and containing such information and assurances as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H173A6DC0948B4DB09319F0449B20F451"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Vision Zero plan required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible for a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall have in effect a Vision Zero plan that meets the requirements of section 2(c) and has been approved by local resolution, ordinance, or law.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H307E37C47BEF408ABD22828C5405FFD0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Selection criteria</header><text>In selecting from among eligible entities to receive grants under subsection (a), the Secretary shall consider, at a minimum, the extent to which an entity—</text> 
<paragraph id="H440A047445EA405C8B796A1FE9F51756"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provided an opportunity for public input in the development of the plan, including documented engagement with low-income and minority communities;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0B098A9FB1754161A18328B5799CE8B6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">considered existing plans and planning processes in the drafting of the vision zero plan;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H740C10E57D304C95AFC921F42CFD4CFC"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">structured the plan to meet performance measures as described in section 150(c) of title 23, United States Code;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H93E1F10066814BD6B03B731F0512C4B2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>demonstrates broad community support for the plan, including the commitment of community leaders to successful implementation of the plan; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB6F892C51A8B4A9FA282E9888AF39C89"><enum>(5)</enum><text>demonstrates the availability of State, local, or Federal funds, in addition to Federal funds made available under this section, for implementation of the plan. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H99EE93F4AAE74FFE97DF9C79A8D93D3F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Funding limitations</header> <paragraph id="HE29F6DF2A2E04F44AD3742CE765D2E96"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Population limitation</header><text>Not less than 25 percent of the funds made available to carry out this section shall be used to make grants to eligible entities that serve a jurisdiction with a population of fewer than 200,000 individuals.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H87B98A729F384EB2BC587BD0BE6F062B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal share</header> 
<subparagraph id="H20D5238E3411448E96E83D06B836C084"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided by subparagraph (B), the Federal share of the cost of a project or activity carried out using grant funds made available under this section may not exceed 80 percent.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB25240204D754637BFC0ABF3A66BE408"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Funds from other Federal sources</header><text>Amounts made available to an eligible entity under another Federal program may be credited toward the non-Federal share of the cost of a project or activity described in subparagraph (A), at the option of the eligible entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H2FA661CFA95A488AB1036D1C83585606"><enum>4.</enum><header>Eligible entity defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <quote>eligible entity</quote> means a unit of local government including a city, town, township, borough, county, parish, district, village, or other political subdivision of a State.</text></section> <section id="H1C467EFF7C09410891A4B86376E700C4"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> Not later than 2 years after the final grant is awarded under this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress, and make available to the public, a report on the progress of the projects and activities carried out using the grants including—</text> 
<paragraph id="H6F665F611387446A8EF876B2708A2406"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a breakdown of infrastructure and noninfrastructure projects;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9287B86FA40848DF96571835F1B222C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>demographic data, in the aggregate, with respect to individuals charged with a violation of law referenced in the vision zero plan of an eligible entity that received a grant under this Act; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8CDAC24015414E70BDC81A67E2E9F8BA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>best practices from the eligible entities that received a grant under section 3.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HE15AB127D4804960B0D6362E0ACB6F79"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated, for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022, $5,000,000 to carry out section 2 and $25,000,000 to carry out section 3.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

