<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H50BACB7B78164E7F955FDB12C65D8B07" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3465 IH: Julia Carson Responsible Fatherhood and Healthy Families Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3465</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170727">July 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson of Indiana</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title IV of the Social Security Act to ensure funding for grants to promote responsible
			 fatherhood and strengthen low-income families, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HBFEBAC8CB72B46AAA3B513DE3994BCB0" style="OLC">
		<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6D5528A06DE64130BE68B551E515C86C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="H85100DD623CF4EA1B0BFC9C655D49CF9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Julia Carson Responsible Fatherhood and Healthy Families Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H04D047F89FCC4EA7AE98DC2257188C29"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents of this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
					<toc-entry idref="H6D5528A06DE64130BE68B551E515C86C" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H32A0A1A7E2AC44139C1FF95E03DF4A21" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HD1BEA5B5FD134EF2985E9DE98C699DA2" level="title">Title I—Promoting Responsible Fatherhood and Strengthening Low-Income Families</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HA35AC5F032494557B49D8A5631253E2E" level="section">Sec. 101. Healthy marriage promotion and responsible fatherhood programs.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H4F441ECEDC324545BF71A53CF2C0E613" level="section">Sec. 102. Grants supporting healthy family partnerships for domestic violence intervention and
			 preventions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HD884165FA3824ECEA1661551B04A1A76" level="section">Sec. 103. Procedures to address domestic violence.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H91D75AD8538F40E0B14490D091A1568C" level="section">Sec. 104. Grants to States for family strengthening commissions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HC40EACDC83274969A29498466C3B8FF4" level="title">Title II—Temporary Assistance for Needy Families</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HCEC9E5FFDD8644A0A7CAD70DAC42CEA9" level="section">Sec. 201. TANF work participation improvements.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HA316FCC637814E4BBCE332EC2ADB9689" level="section">Sec. 202. TANF Employment Fund.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H23F3F0A27A40471CBC57CC377B1353C1" level="section">Sec. 203. Sense of Congress.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H9CE7CCC8F7CC41769BE7847B6FC51B19" level="title">Title III—Child support</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HD2CF939C66644C85A44B061AC0D5BB48" level="section">Sec. 301. Full family distribution and ban on recovery of Medicaid costs for births.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HA05B4670F1314DD49B8FB546B328F365" level="section">Sec. 302. State assessments of barriers to employment and financial support of children.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H793F80D804F64DC0B9FF5881579408BC" level="section">Sec. 303. Public reporting on consequences for nonpayment.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H7BF64AD38B6C461EA70150DB1D57F103" level="section">Sec. 304. Early intervention to ensure regular payment of support and prevent overdue support.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H73F594B64B4B4400B52428A3AE211B80" level="section">Sec. 305. Improved collection and distribution of child support.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H701C48572DA4401A939336CACEE3955E" level="section">Sec. 306. Services and activities to support noncustodial parenting time.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HD97A3BDFCCE448A38C1592C893D9775F" level="title">Title IV—Revenue provision</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HFAA73AEA59FA4FF1AAA89B16378B5AE1" level="section">Sec. 401. Increase in credit percentage under earned income tax credit for eligible individuals
			 with no qualifying children.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H539090A22B32454DBA9AFFE13A49E7F1" level="title">Title V—Supplemental nutrition assistance</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H60AC4C1A6AD24A21A9F25166F8972A40" level="section">Sec. 501. Collection of child support under the supplemental nutrition assistance program.</toc-entry>
				</toc>
 </subsection></section><section id="H32A0A1A7E2AC44139C1FF95E03DF4A21"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> <paragraph id="HF61CD6354B124DE88A4B2A7AF85C6255"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Fathers play a significant and underappreciated role in the development of their children, with research demonstrating that a supportive and involved father strengthens a child’s emotional, physical, intellectual, and behavioral development. Children with positive relationships with fathers, even if they do not live in the same household, have stronger mental health, economic success, and academic achievement with lower rates of youth delinquency, school dropout, and teen pregnancy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF8BAC32AAF7849B3991494319263F49A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Economic stability also leads to positive outcomes for children, including stronger emotional well-being, physical health, and academic success.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFD0EF09DE3B44792AFB08C88EB2D70CA"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Family patterns in the United States have resulted in fewer children living with their fathers. The October 2016 Child Trends report on family structure shows the proportion of all children who have not attained the age of 18 living with both parents has decreased over the past half century, from 85 percent in 1960 to 65 percent in 2015, with 23 percent of such children living with their mother only and 4 percent of such children living with their father only in 2015.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA70FE09315F64754BA84B1A1EE1289D3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A 2015 United States Census analysis of children’s living arrangements and characteristics showed that a child in a father-absent home is more than 5 times more likely to live in poverty than a child in a married-couple family.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H562DE61878C44C50977544A29A790AEF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Father engagement does not depend on living in the same house as the child, with many nonresidential fathers being actively involved with their children and supportive of their children’s mothers. However, low-income fathers experience multiple challenges to contributing financially and emotionally to their children due to limited education and job skills, unstable employment opportunities, child support enforcement policies, incarceration, and strained relationships with the children’s mothers. Multiple approaches are needed to address these barriers to create opportunities for fathers to sustain their engagement and closeness with their children and families.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H16DB8AE07F9A4E289E06BA007D07771A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Federal programs should encourage responsible fatherhood and healthy families by increasing the upward economic mobility of custodial and noncustodial parents so that they can actively participate in financial support and child-rearing as well as maintain positive, healthy, and nonviolent relationships with their children and coparents, including improving compliance with child support obligations and cooperative parenting.</text>
			</paragraph></section><title id="HD1BEA5B5FD134EF2985E9DE98C699DA2"><enum>I</enum><header>Promoting Responsible Fatherhood and Strengthening Low-Income Families</header>
			<section id="HA35AC5F032494557B49D8A5631253E2E"><enum>101.</enum><header>Healthy marriage promotion and responsible fatherhood programs</header>
				<subsection id="H8B6C4A348DB0410F8BF91D931C992D5B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Voluntary participation</header>
 <paragraph id="H8DFA291085224A1899392A2712ABE085"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Assurance</header><text>Section 403(a)(2)(A)(ii)(II) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/603">42 U.S.C. 603(a)(2)(A)(ii)(II)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5CED49A2FBA24355959776FE471A37C6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in item (aa), by striking <quote>and</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H14CB392480F649E8950D3C3E273535E3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in item (bb), by striking the period and inserting a semicolon; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34F7246DC44B46DC86285D6B02B17B1D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H15B1419BFA6949D8991D3FCD262B8404" style="OLC"> <item id="H3913812ED0464A8EB11A6A3E85D16AB3"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>if the entity is a State or an Indian tribe or tribal organization, to not condition the receipt of assistance under the program funded under this part, under a program funded with qualified State expenditures (as defined in section 409(a)(7)(B)(i)), or under any other program funded under this title, on enrollment in any such programs or activities; and</text>
 </item><item id="H09C91E9894C147D9AE4EC23A4E4A32E5"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>to permit any participant in a program or activity funded under this paragraph, including an individual whose participation is specified in the individual responsibility plan developed for the individual in accordance with section 408(b), to transfer to another such program or activity upon notification to the entity and the State agency responsible for administering the State program funded under this part.</text></item><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA27F0384426E4FDAA50DD810503816F5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>Section 408(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/608">42 U.S.C. 608(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5EFFBA46FD584F4887C10D2C5ADE7318" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HEC28A943D9F24C94B333EA0CE6907BF8"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Ban on conditioning receipt of TANF or certain other benefits on participation in a healthy marriage or responsible fatherhood program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State to which a grant is made under section 403 shall not condition the receipt of assistance under the State program funded under this part, under a program funded with qualified State expenditures (as defined in section 409(a)(7)(B)(i)), or under any other program funded under this title, on participation in a healthy marriage promotion activity (as defined in section 403(a)(2)(A)(iii)) or in an activity promoting responsible fatherhood (as defined in section 403(a)(2)(C)(ii)).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5127A3E36EC644F6807D0D1FD099DFC7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>Section 409(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/609">42 U.S.C. 609(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0C28F587BC7E4984BFF613ABFE9C9290" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H3F12894112F24E5596D8B9B5DDC1A4EA"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Penalty for conditioning receipt of TANF or certain other benefits on participation in a healthy marriage or responsible fatherhood program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary determines that a State has violated section 408(a)(13) during a fiscal year, the Secretary shall reduce the grant payable to the State under section 403(a)(1) for the immediately succeeding fiscal year by an amount equal to 5 percent of the State family assistance grant.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB7C630C325D144B4BB6E7F2F79145A0C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Activities promoting responsible fatherhood</header><text>Section 403(a)(2)(C)(ii) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/603">42 U.S.C. 603(a)(2)(C)(ii)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HE16A5D61FC3C42C6AEF60902C9385EC2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subclause (I), by striking <quote>marriage or sustain marriage</quote> and inserting <quote>healthy relationships and marriages or to sustain healthy relationships or marriages</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8D2E708773644FC8BDDA09CD0440E043"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subclause (II), by inserting <quote>educating youth who are not yet parents about the economic, social, and family consequences of early parenting, helping participants in fatherhood programs work with their own children to break the cycle of early parenthood,</quote> after <quote>child support payments,</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H228B5F3F65F6471489ED29F7EE4804EF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subclause (III), by striking <quote>fathers</quote> and inserting <quote>low-income fathers and other low-income noncustodial parents who are not eligible for assistance under the State program funded under this part</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H38BBF54460F24111ADBD0BCD65BF9480"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reauthorization</header><text>Section 403(a)(2)(D) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/603">42 U.S.C. 603(a)(2)(D)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H5F2D18BFC62949FAB3030A345CAFCAFA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>fiscal years 2017 and 2018</quote> and inserting <quote>fiscal years 2017 through 2023</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7658E2ECBC954591BA00AFFEEBD0ACD5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>fiscal year 2017 or 2018</quote> and inserting <quote>any of fiscal years 2017 through 2023</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H817CC3F5D2DB4F4389F56FD16E1AEE36"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect on October 1, 2017.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H4F441ECEDC324545BF71A53CF2C0E613"><enum>102.</enum><header>Grants supporting healthy family partnerships for domestic violence intervention and preventions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 403(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/603">42 U.S.C. 603(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HED983131CDC943B68441A549485DBF38" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="H437C6484C156445BA928F7769796E4BA"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Grants supporting healthy family partnerships for domestic violence intervention and prevention</header>
 <subparagraph id="HA2907131566F48B5B01148E6343C3697"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall award grants on a competitive basis to healthy family partnerships to develop and implement promising practices for—</text>
 <clause id="HC173A5F4D8D6498DAD998F74794207AD"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assessing and providing services to individuals and families affected by domestic violence, including through caseworker training, the provision of technical assistance to community partners, and the implementation of safe visitation and exchange programs; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB223CB418804402D8B3292741D4E458D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">preventing domestic violence, particularly as a barrier to economic security, and fostering healthy relationships.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0BD8314900A84F06A2A04946EF8A3D22"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Education services</header><text>In awarding grants under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall ensure that 10 percent of the funds made available under such grants are used for high schools and other secondary educational institutions and institutions of higher education to provide education services on the value of healthy relationships, responsible parenting, and healthy marriages characterized by mutual respect and nonviolence, and the importance of building relationship skills such as communication, conflict resolution, and budgeting.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H499B7AA1A9A547E2A9CFF84B4978F217"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The respective entity and organization of a healthy family partnership entered into for purposes of receiving a grant under this paragraph shall submit a joint application to the Secretary, at such time and in such manner as the Secretary shall specify, containing—</text>
 <clause id="HE5C1DE66F5934A59937CE5BC80896AA0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a description of how the partnership intends to carry out the activities described in subparagraph (A);</text>
 </clause><clause id="H59B3B6A418D6406B995C38411B5A3E5E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an assurance that funds made available under the grant shall be used to supplement, and not supplant, other funds used by the entity or organization to carry out programs, activities, or services described in subparagraph (A) or (B); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC948A12062094FC9A77A3785C54640B5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary may require.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H922B81A324834B6C99AA159232613A4B"><enum>(D)</enum><header>General rules governing use of funds</header><text>The rules of section 404, other than subsection (b) of that section, shall not apply to a grant made under this paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9D7C8F82CFA0402DAC1EE0B53268C662"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this paragraph:</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAF9EC959CEBB4085880BE0568A566645"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Domestic violence</header><text>The term <term>domestic violence</term> has the meaning given that term in section 402(a)(7)(B).</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCF5CE1A7F1C64C0885866AC69185E2FF"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Healthy family partnership</header><text>The term <term>healthy family partnership</term> means a partnership between—</text> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H140C44D531484D17837DFEC49FB1181B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an entity receiving funds under a grant made under paragraph (2) to promote healthy marriage or responsible fatherhood; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6AD5DA9FDFFE4959A7A7D87B0D0799C6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an organization with demonstrated expertise working with survivors of domestic violence.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H710394F6358F48CF8CF1C6D4CA3D6E4D"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Appropriation</header><text>Out of any money in the Treasury of the United States not otherwise appropriated, there are appropriated for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2023, $25,000,000 to carry out this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</section><section id="HD884165FA3824ECEA1661551B04A1A76"><enum>103.</enum><header>Procedures to address domestic violence</header>
 <subsection id="H800ED8F35FC84440AE1262E111190DEB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 403(a)(2) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/603">42 U.S.C. 603(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H0F48D84CFCC848819DAA30DDB6694E64"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (D) and (E) as subparagraphs (F) and (G), respectively; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA4C978FED87D44009E396173D6CFA03C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (C) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H307A0C0A4FB441168075AD5F60659799" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HE9423DFC78BB44D18C2D204937FE86B5"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Requirements for receipt of funds</header><text>An entity may not be awarded a grant under this paragraph unless the entity, as a condition of receiving funds under such a grant—</text>
 <clause id="H108EB35EAB6740BB98A084DFFFBD8B9B"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifies in its application for the grant the domestic violence experts at the local, State, or national level with whom the entity will consult in the development and implementation of the programs and activities of the entity;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H471C2A95A36C45A0A8DA0A70055281A1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on award of the grant, and in consultation with such domestic violence experts, develops a written protocol which describes—</text>
 <subclause id="HB33858A3FFBA48A48950C570BF1DD0A6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>how the entity will identify instances or risks of domestic violence;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H4F42072C4A244BDAA9B1156978D0FDA1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the procedures for responding to such instances or risks, including making service referrals and providing protections and appropriate assistance for identified individuals and families;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H4CF5DCDB61A4492C94837C7F2A869928"><enum>(III)</enum><text>how confidentiality issues will be addressed; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H20FF8E10ED00480CA13CE2D6AEEB229F"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the domestic violence training that will be provided to ensure effective and consistent implementation of the protocol; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H6FBB8FB275F54CFF9C17A663A1F1EF02"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in an annual report to the Secretary, includes a description of the domestic violence protocols, and a description of any implementation issues identified with respect to domestic violence and how the issues were addressed.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F581667C97447088AA9FF2D0D422F77"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Domestic violence defined</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>domestic violence</term> has the meaning given the term in section 402(a)(7)(B).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H937909902EEF4580851F0ACAC006F585"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Section 403(a)(2) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/603">42 U.S.C. 603(a)(2)</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (a)(1) of this section, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD7577340D7DF4E2E9245174A23CE7CF3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)(i)—</text> <subparagraph id="H988951DFFF8C40779ED130B0024227DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and (E)</quote> and inserting <quote>(D), and (G)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02E325A49CE245168F76B1AC739A2FC6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(D)</quote> and inserting <quote>(F)</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5D91C569F7B4571BC3079AD54AA4B85"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraphs (B)(i) and (C)(i), by striking <quote>(D)</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>(F)</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H084290FE8B9F443182BAEBE7B4283AB2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to fiscal years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H91D75AD8538F40E0B14490D091A1568C"><enum>104.</enum><header>Grants to States for family strengthening commissions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part D of title IV of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/651">42 U.S.C. 651</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H334462A0D9C6448FBD5384C1323A7E53" style="OLC">
					<section id="H58E8685338E64895BC511A93F9E7CAC6"><enum>469C.</enum><header>Grants to States for family strengthening commissions</header>
 <subsection id="HA8881221C94244DAA1B914E7979F3A02"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall make grants to States under this section to enable States to establish and support commissions to identify methods of expanding access to family strengthening services.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H0528CE94C84A495485D4C9BCAEC29382"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>State</quote> means any State, Indian tribe, or tribal organization (as defined in subsections (e) and (l) of section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b</external-xref>)), having in effect a plan approved under this part.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6306C88F47DF4C3D80EC7D7685BEF6BB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to be eligible for a grant under this section, a State shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9C3BC8E10A3C493BA3CA434468DB6CD4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Family strengthening services</header><text>The commissions described in subsection (a) shall focus on providing family strengthening services that include—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFA5FAD2EF3D04A9D9D291B01B827ACE7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>family and relationship counseling;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA3138EE40A81423FA274541C63C7CC46"><enum>(2)</enum><text>relationship and parenting education; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H35899E2F46144E70ACA4A7BF8B0E1807"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assistance with developing and implementing parenting time arrangements.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD210A9D936A04B1B9E194B7A0C7E8F43"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Families served</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The commissions described in subsection (a) shall focus on serving varying types of families, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB8B4178956234E2BAFFD97A30D3E6319"><enum>(1)</enum><text>families seeking to preserve a marriage or other adult relationship;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H650CD804B38141C5A23BC302E41BDEBD"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">families seeking a divorce or separation and working to maintain coparenting and parent-child relationships;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEFE98AA2C1404694B8D2AD71987194E7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">families seeking to maintain or rebuild family relationships affected by incarceration;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H810A65B9BE484DDF8CBE9BFC6AAA0005"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">families seeking to build a support system around a child who has experienced trauma, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H399F190813F9485D9887FACF30822487"><enum>(A)</enum><text>witnessing violence;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB79665D47CD64D2494286D1770FDB138"><enum>(B)</enum><text>experiencing sexual or physical abuse; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4DD3951443F486C96D1F6EE0F0F0FF2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>having a parent who is experiencing challenges with mental health or substance abuse; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H450E0248547A4FBC98A0AE0B7CC8C8EB"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">families below 250 percent of poverty guidelines applicable to a family of the size involved.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB6D84B47D88C4BD9B156BB9C96476994"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Membership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State seeking a grant under this section shall demonstrate that a family strengthening commission funded by such grant will consist of relevant government and private actors, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDF88378956254EBD8DE790637619189E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>State government agency officials from departments of health, human services, child support, education, youth services, or corrections;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE98E248B9B9D43CB936107044A822050"><enum>(2)</enum><text>local government agency officials from departments of health, human services, child support, education, youth services, or corrections;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBDF61A8ADF62451881721A982E3F21FD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>access to Justice Commissions, bar associations, judicial associations, courts, or other representatives of the legal system;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6BFB3637C5C548BD9485DB452EFDDCE4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>associations of social workers, counselors, psychologists, and other mental health professionals;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3B31F6401E3C4A4C863E84D1A06911AC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>associations of mediators and others who deliver alternative dispute resolution services;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3DEF6125F8FD451EAA7BA6061E4A630B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>healthy marriage and responsible fatherhood programs;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H124739AE88DB416B883B96B260EE8F9E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>youth-serving programs; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8BFB400E6240460D83E29C9BF35227A8"><enum>(8)</enum><text>academics and researchers.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3584B00B0A84484485B533308D5A7D2B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>A commission funded by a grant under this section shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC4DFBD9A8513475BB8CE2FD7F56C3D5E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify the need for potential policy changes;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H659E0D32A8B140FD8B9E17C8935C1E57"><enum>(2)</enum><text>determine methods of leveraging existing resources and growing new resources; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0EC9C55B0BCE4D5C9D0609EFF4D0961B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>explore methods of improving service delivery, including the training of service providers.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD42BD80ED7964913B3FB76D5EB05D303"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Health and Human Services to carry out this section $3,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2020.</text>
						</subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</section></title><title id="HC40EACDC83274969A29498466C3B8FF4"><enum>II</enum><header>Temporary Assistance for Needy Families</header>
			<section id="HCEC9E5FFDD8644A0A7CAD70DAC42CEA9"><enum>201.</enum><header>TANF work participation improvements</header>
				<subsection id="H267901D794CC42309F9B32DE8D87BEBE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Elimination of Separate Work Requirements for 2-Parent Families</header>
 <paragraph id="H37413B58B26D464CA19FE21DF2E0EF75"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Work participation rate</header><text>Section 407 of the <act-name parsable-cite="SSA">Social Security Act </act-name>(<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/607">42 U.S.C. 607</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H4C90B5A9F41E47D381DE668900756CE7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text>
 <clause id="H90A8440E29E4412D81672F63A1A20782"><enum>(i)</enum><text>beginning in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Participation Rate Requirements</header-in-text></quote> and all that follows through <quote>A State</quote> in paragraph (1) and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Participation Rate Requirements</header-in-text>.—A State</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H20E77D678B8343268E03F9E6B0FA0B8A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2); and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC4CD0722D8A4BB2BAE825F8FBC250B5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <clause id="H44E89871F6B84BC4B864CFA0906B0D9E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(A), by striking <quote>subsection (a)(1)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (a)</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE2C91E2AB967498F8085B4EE5CA93A93"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2) and redesignating paragraphs (3), (4), and (5) as paragraphs (2), (3), and (4), respectively;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE0486F36F99D43948681E09DF07D5F1B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in paragraph (3) (as so redesignated), by striking <quote>paragraphs (1)(B) and (2)(B)</quote> and inserting <quote>determining monthly participation rates under paragraph (1)(B)</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H9FB3C016D897496F8052D2E5B94514AD"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in paragraph (4) (as so redesignated), by striking <quote>rates</quote> and inserting <quote>rate</quote>.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H04A0A47E59A446ACA803B7B5F1888B3F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Minimum weekly hours requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 407(c)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/607">42 U.S.C. 607(c)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HFF03E6BEAC474E55B4ECF0385F09504E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">General rules</header-in-text></quote> and all that follows through <quote>For purposes of</quote> in subparagraph (A) and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">General Rules.</header-in-text>—For purposes of</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7C4861B6F184E1D8E49603BC9C833E5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (B).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF1E8DCA3E222424EB72AB3E173CE1DDB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation on penalty imposition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In applying section 409(a)(3) of the Social Security Act for each fiscal year beginning with fiscal year 2007 and ending with the fiscal year in which occurs the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall disregard the requirement imposed by section 407(a)(2) of the Social Security Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HBD0A82660B2F4836A52817E33F6FFAD0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elimination of distinction between core and other work activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 407(c)(1) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/607">42 U.S.C. 607(c)(1)</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (a)(2) of this section, is further amended by striking <quote>not fewer than</quote> and all that follows through <quote>subsection (d),</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HD997A1352647400FAAA451241DEAAF22"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Elimination of special work participation rule for teens attending secondary school</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 407(c)(2) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/607">42 U.S.C. 607(c)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by striking subparagraph (C).</text> </subsection><subsection id="H8C6A4E58715B45AE80DCEF389CF6969A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Elimination of cap on treating vocational educational training as work participation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 407(c)(2) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/607">42 U.S.C. 607(c)(2)</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (c) of this section, is further amended by striking subparagraph (D).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H257E00ACAF5D453DBEE7170EFC365DDB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Increase in months of educational vocational training that may be counted as work participation</header><text>Section 407(d)(8) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/607">42 U.S.C. 607(d)(8)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>12 months</quote> and inserting <quote>24 months</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H6723369AB6E9489AB58DB615948F9FBF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall take effect on October 1 of the first fiscal year beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act and shall apply to the determination of minimum participation rates for months beginning on or after that date.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="HA316FCC637814E4BBCE332EC2ADB9689"><enum>202.</enum><header>TANF Employment Fund</header>
 <subsection id="HE6BF7A1403F541AEA46CD01E3B8DCB81"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 403(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/603">42 U.S.C. 603(b)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H763A16A6EE8248A7AB4EB30451C727FD" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HADEC71916BEA4EFD96D70CD50F76580B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Employment Fund</header> <paragraph id="HD9263D0693794FFCBFCA24B182F6EBB0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is hereby established in the Treasury of the United States a fund which shall be known as the Employment Fund for Needy Families (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Fund</quote>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC9D98475F79F4E9CAAF1C311B2B442DA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deposits into Fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Out of any money in the Treasury of the United States not otherwise appropriated, there are appropriated for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2023, $608,000,000 for payment to the Fund, which shall remain available until expended.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="HD4E4999A9FFF446D9FB8FB3B93FF171A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Grants</header>
 <subparagraph id="HDA72672513E04B8295769DB32ED47593"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each of fiscal years 2017 through 2023, the Secretary shall make grants, on a competitive basis, to qualifying entities as provided in this paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC362934AE654034A8823C52E0B20AD2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Qualifying entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, a qualifying entity for a fiscal year is a State, territory, Indian tribe, or tribal organization, operating a State program funded under this part (or any other State program funded with qualified State expenditures (as defined in section 409(a)(7)(B)(i))), that submits to the Secretary an application for a grant under this paragraph for the fiscal year, in such manner and at such time as the Secretary may require.</text>
								</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F25488003414D24BCC0D5E084AB88F6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Allotment of funds</header>
 <clause id="HCCA6E63150AE4F21A89D98964460AF46"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall reserve $10,000,000 out of the amounts made available under paragraph (2) for each fiscal year to provide technical assistance to qualifying entities receiving a grant under this paragraph for the fiscal year.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE811B0C52BD24E268091F63CB5AE1892"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Territories and Indian tribes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall reserve, from the amount made available under paragraph (2) for a fiscal year that remains after applying clause (i), 3 percent for grants under this paragraph for the fiscal year to qualifying entities that are territories and 1 percent for grants under this paragraph for the fiscal year to qualifying entities that are Indian tribes or tribal organizations, to be allotted in a manner the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text>
									</clause><clause id="H9FDC0B9DEFB0458C9EB18BAC3B4B392E"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>States</header>
 <subclause id="H4FAD451E78F845BA9961FE97B0A61B7F"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of a grant under this paragraph payable for a fiscal year to a qualifying entity that is a State shall be the amount that bears the same ratio to the aggregate amount as the number of individuals residing in the State who have attained 18 years of age but have not attained 67 years of age who are not employed or underemployed (such as involuntarily working part-time), as determined by the Secretary, bears to the total number of such individuals residing in all qualifying entities that are States.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H48F7EC9C6F544AFD8F37E6437D41B4B7"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Aggregate amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this clause, the term <quote>aggregate amount</quote> means the amount made available for a fiscal year under paragraph (2) that remains after applying clauses (i) and (ii).</text>
										</subclause></clause><clause id="H0D888E079ABC4F93B617B2A6C11835CF"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Unused funds</header>
 <subclause id="HE7CD15444E7447798517876EB00232D6"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Reasonable limits on carrying over funds</header><text>The Secretary shall set reasonable limits on the amount of funds a State receiving a grant under this paragraph may carry over for expenditure in fiscal years after the fiscal year for which the grant is awarded.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H2B71CAEB0ACA45D5BAD590C95CA4303E"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Redistribution of unused funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any portion of the amount of a grant made to a State under clause (iii) that the Secretary determines will not be used by the State shall be redistributed among the States that the Secretary determines will not have such an unused amount, using the rules specified in clause (iii). Any amount so redistributed to a State is deemed part of the grant made to the State under the preceding provisions of this paragraph.</text>
										</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8556D954F234A038AC88D19E9A95654"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Use of funds</header>
									<clause id="H8902EC2B9FB94E1EA3BD2EED4E74131B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Employment programs</header>
 <subclause id="H997A81A47C6E46B7B07E0E9636B85F05"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Subsidized employment</header><text>A qualifying entity awarded a grant under this paragraph shall use the grant funds to conduct a subsidized employment program to assist recipients of TANF cash assistance and TANF-eligible individuals who are not recipients of cash assistance in obtaining paid employment.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H5D42CC9B1A744C718696EA894C7B18B3"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Sectoral skills training</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A qualifying entity may use not more than 15 percent of funds awarded to the entity under this paragraph for a fiscal year to conduct a sectoral skills training program to provide sectoral skills training to recipients of TANF cash assistance and TANF-eligible individuals who are not recipients of cash assistance.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H000BD502FDEA4CC19266B0A32189546E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Allowable expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A qualifying entity may use funds awarded under this paragraph to carry out clause (i), including the following activities:</text>
 <subclause id="HDBCD8E51F5A0485D84890623B975C07A"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Administrative expenses.</text> </subclause><subclause id="H61AF96B4AC424E8A93CFACECBB92CE7A"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Supportive services, including transportation and childcare, to enable individuals to participate in a program described in clause (i).</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H273DC27B2CEA4CD3B4E4BB012160EE89"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Wages and associated payroll costs for individuals participating in the subsidized employment program described in clause (i)(I).</text>
										</subclause></clause><clause id="H5746A0706AF347488AA32222E4B4FEEF"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Eligibility for assistance</header>
 <subclause id="HA8D9C0D8ED954E368DE57430B2169874"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Requirement to use 75 percent of funds to assist recipients of TANF cash assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A qualifying entity shall use not less than 75 percent of funds awarded to the entity under this paragraph to assist under the program described in clause (i)(I) (and, if the entity so elects, the program described in clause (i)(II)) recipients of TANF cash assistance and may use the remainder of the funds to assist TANF-eligible individuals who are not recipients of cash assistance.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H35A7C815C19D48F485474931BEF1C1FF"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Recipient of TANF cash assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subparagraph, the term <quote>recipient of TANF cash assistance</quote> means an individual who—</text> <item id="H8835DE43D6D74E73BF8EE4204D9F08F4"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>has attained 18 years of age and has not attained 67 years of age; and</text>
 </item><item id="HF38E6A3F63BE4A68BA1BBCCA9EA7E4C7"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not employed and is determined by the qualifying entity to have been unsuccessful at obtaining paid employment after participating in a job search program; and—</text>
 <subitem id="HBEB35EC2E3814E26ABDFD07AF36F2702"><enum>(AA)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is a member of a family that receives cash assistance under the State program funded under this part or any other State program funded with qualified State expenditures (as defined in section 409(a)(7)(B)(i)); or</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="H902C424C536746589848B962505E4856"><enum>(BB)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is a noncustodial parent of a minor child residing with a family described in subitem (AA), in a case in which the parent is not considered by the State to be a member of the family.</text>
 </subitem></item></subclause><subclause id="H04CCFBE61FBD42C0B75DBCD2679C78A4"><enum>(III)</enum><header>TANF-eligible individual who is not a recipient of cash assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subparagraph, the term <quote>TANF-eligible individual who is not a recipient of cash assistance</quote> means an individual who—</text> <item id="H27AB52DEBD934A43A3CAD01FE09FD220"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has attained 18 years of age and has not attained 67 years of age;</text>
 </item><item id="H592F6D7D4BBD44B4B0112263691764A2"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not employed and is determined by the qualifying entity to have been unsuccessful at obtaining paid employment after participating in a job search program;</text>
 </item><item id="HA25993C2E7FE4AF1B32330B3592D1154"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>is not an individual described in subitems (AA) or (BB) of subclause (II)(bb); and</text> </item><item id="H0B4CD2A011564EF085561EFE8F3E82B8"><enum>(dd)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is a member of a family that includes a minor child residing with the family (including a noncustodial parent of the child) if the family has an income that is less than the poverty line (as defined in section 673(2) of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1981, including any revision required by such section, applicable to a family of the size involved).</text>
											</item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEFF58E23D7CA433DB5AE797DE71E0D25"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Annual report</header>
 <clause id="H610779426E37469AACD755A76FE63A19"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Subsidized employment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each fiscal year for which a qualifying entity receives a grant under this paragraph, the entity shall submit to the Secretary, within 6 months after the end of the fiscal year, a report on the subsidized employment program described in subparagraph (D)(i)(I), which shall—</text>
 <subclause id="HA7BB9E6DF675466581A67A452BDA0DED"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describe the structure of the activities of the entity to use the grant funds to subsidize employment for individuals participating in the program (in this clause referred to as <quote>subsidized employees</quote>), including the amount and duration of the subsidies provided;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HC40BEDD74CC748FB9A7A4D31876952D1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for each month of the fiscal year, specify the number of individuals whose employment is subsidized with these funds and the percentage of such individuals whose employment is in an area that matches their previous training and work experience;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA4527137C85648F8BB0CD76B6515D12B"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describe the qualifying entity’s policies in effect during the fiscal year—</text> <item id="H22980C2D6F4C4849B71FC7C77465C6EA"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to ensure nondisplacement as required under paragraph (4)(A); and</text>
 </item><item id="H715EFD4477904523A0ACF9EE2AD57CEA"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to implement grievance procedures as required in (4)(B), including information on the number of grievance claims filed in the preceding fiscal year and the aggregate results of those claims;</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H0EE1B4E019AF4BD4B1652EE010DF39D8"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describe requirements imposed on employers by the State as a condition of participating in the program;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H71C3F20DA922496DB1634F21EEFA018F"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describe the types of jobs in which subsidized employees are placed;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H63F66E9C84224A2DB99B46D04C92C5A3"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>provide demographic information for subsidized employees and for the target population the entity seeks to assist under the program;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H3B20BBBB63BA4B3296A5DCBB4F2C71D7"><enum>(VII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specify the average number of hours worked per week by a subsidized employee;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HDB3B0EE7C7254E22A9C6AFB898F875D2"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>specify the average length of time for which a subsidized employee participates in the program;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD6D84865856A4E48956C89DC42A61DE6"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>describe the employment outcomes for subsidized employees after participating in the program, including the number of individuals hired by an employer with which the individual was placed during the program and the number of individuals hired by other employers;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HF01983EE8F4E4B50B71EA85F603020B2"><enum>(X)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specify the percentage of subsidized employees who are in unsubsidized employment during the second quarter after the subsidy ended;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H3EF0EBE9A0DB4E2A8E7AB99B7294F12D"><enum>(XI)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specify the percentage of subsidized employees who are in unsubsidized employment during the fourth quarter after the subsidy ended;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H98135BAE632D40A5A6CA4E4A4F6023DE"><enum>(XII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specify the median earnings of subsidized employees who are in unsubsidized employment during the second quarter after the subsidy ended; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HF816E9C3E6DC451DA80AD04184C1FEEA"><enum>(XIII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specify the number of subsidized employees who concurrently received other Federal or State means-tested benefits during their subsidized employment.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H089131F4D5FF43ADB40D4F2E1ED48310"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Sectoral skills training</header><text>If a qualifying entity elects to conduct a sectoral skills training program described in subparagraph (D)(i)(II), the report required under clause (i) of this subparagraph shall also include a description of—</text>
 <subclause id="H2C44BCC32C414B169CAC322ACAC15E14"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the design of the program;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HCB4EF804FFC24A179CD228600BEF9A55"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the industries in which individuals receiving assistance under the program (in this clause referred to as <quote>trainees</quote>) receive training;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H4CB563D6922E44A49744B9C239A95033"><enum>(III)</enum><text>demographic information for trainees and for the target population the entity seeks to assist under the program;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H249325567BED4531B4A95455647216BC"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the total number of trainees participating in the program during the fiscal year;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H8F312F67473246B5AE9CFCED442869A3"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the average number of hours per week for which a trainee receives training;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA6B06B3DC96D40CD87680E110BAC0BBE"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>the average length of time for which a trainee participates in the program; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HD16F968584424AADAF69DBDB35C7567E"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>the employment outcomes for trainees after participating in the program.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A130437321D493A80F7F750A914EF96"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish and implement a rigorous system for evaluating the success of subsidized employment programs and sectoral training programs conducted pursuant to this paragraph.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H48CF30FFA4EB4AC4B4D719E0EF437C1F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitations</header>
 <subparagraph id="H6FFD794D849742369A30840AE00C4B78"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Nondisplacement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State to which a grant is made under this subsection shall ensure that no participant in a subsidized job program funded in whole or in part under this subsection is employed or assigned to a job under the program—</text>
 <clause id="H6DBEF905325C42648F59EAA55302D1F4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>when any other individual is on layoff from the same or any substantially equivalent job; or</text> </clause><clause id="H1FA4BA2FD23F4E5A8BC4F2C04AF39261"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the employer has terminated the employment of any regular employee or otherwise caused an involuntary reduction of its workforce in order to fill the vacancy so created with a participant in such subsidized job program.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H289523D3EC584CADAEF1215CCC8C9712"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Grievance procedure</header><text>A State with a program funded under this subsection shall establish and maintain a grievance procedure for resolving complaints of alleged violations of subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD166034452574C3786684FDA5A928662"><enum>(C)</enum><header>No preemption</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph shall preempt or supersede any provision of State or local law that provides greater protection for employees from displacement.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCFC323EA679A4C28A69D5EDDF9068915"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="H1BEC214F484740A5A3016908D7B27C04"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Indian tribe; tribal organization</header><text>The terms <quote>Indian tribe</quote> and <quote>tribal organization</quote> have the meaning given such terms in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC63D5AF34BB04B0DBC87FECE82694AD0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Sectoral skills training</header><text>The term <quote>sectoral skills training</quote> means training that implements a sectoral skills training strategy established by an industry or sector partnership (as defined in section 3(26) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87B7BCBFE18E4460BBA42EFD94B16503"><enum>(C)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>State</quote> means each of the 50 States of the United States and the District of Columbia.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98F5D28B12C641B7B3CCE4A05D61E831"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Territories</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>territories</quote> means Puerto Rico, Guam, the United States Virgin Islands, the Northern Mariana Islands, and American Samoa.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H396BFFECABFA4308940C83256D1978D2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program participants counted toward work participation rate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 407(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/607">42 U.S.C. 607(b)</external-xref>), as amended by section 201(a)(1)(B) of this Act, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2AD7F1C5EAD84CEA854A72304C862745" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H50DE5FCD8FE0400EB769E54B64F01CEC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State option to include subsidized employment and sectoral skills training participants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an individual who is not a recipient of assistance under the State program funded under this part (or any other State program funded with qualified State expenditures (as defined in section 409(a)(7)(B)(i))) participates in work activities for not less than the minimum average number of hours per week specified in the table in subsection (c)(1) of this section during a month as part of a State’s subsidized employment or sectoral skills training program funded under section 403(b), the State may count the individual as a family that includes an adult or a minor child head of household who is engaged in work for the month for purposes of paragraph (1)(B) of this subsection.</text>
						</paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H47592A1D53284597B662E0EED19D6EC2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>State Plan Required To Include Description of Employment Programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 402(a)(1)(B) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/602">42 U.S.C. 602(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC9A4A6F1C8D54CBEB192DFC5594FAAB5" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H9AFCF0FCE07140CC996905007E3B912E"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The document shall indicate whether the State intends to apply for a grant to conduct a subsidized employment program and, if the State so chooses, a sectoral skills training program, under section 403(b). If so, the document shall include a description of the program or programs the State intends to conduct using the grant funds and a description of how the program or programs will serve noncustodial parents of minor children.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H209F7D031DF34FE6AC981EB7712D5EEE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Grants exempted from territorial payment ceiling</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1108(a)(2) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1308">42 U.S.C. 1308(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>403(b),</quote> after <quote>403(a)(5),</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HD7EC882516914A6A874B711F2A58EC47"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Conforming Amendments To Retain Definition of a Needy State</header> <paragraph id="H708759A7F7ED480DB00779013527925C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Number of weeks for which job search counts as work</header><text>Section 407(c)(2)(A) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/607">42 U.S.C. 607(c)(2)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7727385BE4B24350A35AE7B35A14E877"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>section 409(a)(7)(B)(i))</quote> and inserting <quote>clause (iii)</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5434DAFCAF64B22BB8BE2325814770A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H542F426B9EF6422C893C62FD6B4EE693" style="OLC">
 <clause id="HD3B1C1ED89C646BA9A9A6EF4AD834739"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Needy State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of clause (i), a State is a needy State for a month if—</text> <subclause id="HB0EE5BC457EA4458AFE9CD99311095BD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the average rate of—</text>
 <item id="H9ED58148114641C385F31566395B8CDE"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">total unemployment in such State (seasonally adjusted) for the period consisting of the most recent 3 months for which data for all States are published equals or exceeds 6.5 percent; and</text>
 </item><item id="HD9E29FA94AEC4220B8986B43A816BF18"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">total unemployment in such State (seasonally adjusted) for the 3-month period equals or exceeds 110 percent of such average rate for either (or both) of the corresponding 3-month periods ending in the 2 preceding calendar years; or</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H4EEC689B63E84215BDD94E1F37945169"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as determined by the Secretary of Agriculture (in the discretion of the Secretary of Agriculture), the monthly average number of individuals (as of the last day of each month) participating in the supplemental nutrition assistance program in the State in the then most recently concluded 3-month period for which data are available exceeds by not less than 10 percent the lesser of—</text>
 <item id="H454DCD54AFC2418FAB715ABDFB1CF323"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the monthly average number of individuals (as of the last day of each month) in the State that would have participated in the supplemental nutrition assistance program in the corresponding 3-month period in fiscal year 1994 if the amendments made by titles IV and VIII of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 had been in effect throughout fiscal year 1994; or</text>
 </item><item id="H9768EEB3FFD247C696C98F7D4F332EB4"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the monthly average number of individuals (as of the last day of each month) in the State that would have participated in the supplemental nutrition assistance program in the corresponding 3-month period in fiscal year 1995 if the amendments made by titles IV and VIII of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 had been in effect throughout fiscal year 1995.</text></item></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBDB0C59BBFDE402AA0A63620CF3CBE15"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authority of Secretary to reduce work participation rate penalty due to circumstances that caused
 State to become needy State</header><text>Section 409(a)(3)(C) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/609">42 U.S.C. 609(a)(3)(C)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 403(b)(5)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 407(c)(2)(A)(iii)</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB6B04936232A4B65BD363A0639CD0327"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to fiscal years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H23F3F0A27A40471CBC57CC377B1353C1"><enum>203.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of the Congress that a State to which a grant is made under section 403 of the Social Security Act should consider a noncustodial parent of a minor child, if the child is a recipient of assistance under a State program funded under part A of title IV of such Act (or under any other State program funded with qualified State expenditures (as defined in section 409(a)(7)(B)(i) of such Act)), to be a member of the family of the child for purposes of providing assistance to the family, the child, and the noncustodial parent under the program.</text>
			</section></title><title id="H9CE7CCC8F7CC41769BE7847B6FC51B19"><enum>III</enum><header>Child support</header>
			<section id="HD2CF939C66644C85A44B061AC0D5BB48"><enum>301.</enum><header>Full family distribution and ban on recovery of Medicaid costs for births</header>
				<subsection id="HD89CFE200E1A44A9810B8A522F90E8E8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Ban on recovery</header>
 <paragraph id="H4DB307F159DD4751B72BB9501AFFB41B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 454 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/654">42 U.S.C. 654</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HBE27CAD824A948DEA06829AFB36532B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (33);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H772C23FC110C4912A83CEEE38BDED60E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of paragraph (34) and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3AAD9C50061D4832B6A34AF796201D0E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (34) the following:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H84929F5B70034B5DB8B9316174DE6CBE" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HFD104EEF212042BAAA7B77F7E7FE7C8D"><enum>(35)</enum><text>provide that, except as provided in section 1902(a)(25)(F)(ii), the State shall not use the State program operated under this part to collect any amount owed to the State by reason of costs incurred under the State plan approved under title XIX for the birth of a child for whom support rights have been assigned pursuant to section 1912.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9BCA53655AE4B8E93CC02E74359977B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in section 454(35) of such Act, as added by paragraph (1), shall be construed as affecting the application of section 1902(a)(25) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)(25)</external-xref>) with respect to a State (relating to the State Medicaid plan requirement for the State to take all reasonable measures to ascertain the legal liability of third parties to pay for care and services available under the plan).</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD40703B74798488DACA198402E1BFB4B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clarification that ban on recovery does not apply with respect to insurance of a parent with an
 obligation To pay child support</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Clause (ii) of section 1902(a)(25)(F) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)(25)(F)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>only if such third-party liability is derived through insurance,</quote> before <quote>seek</quote>.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="HC087A1A887CD41DD89C32044847E0DE3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header>
 <paragraph id="H18E7453D4ED34C95A149483711C69B97"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section take effect on October 1, 2017.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA57A97FE700E44308363EF349177784F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Extension of effective date for state law amendment</header><text>In the case of a State plan under title XIX of the Social Security Act which the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines requires State legislation in order for the plan to meet the additional requirements imposed by the amendments made by this section, the State plan shall not be regarded as failing to comply with the requirements of such title solely on the basis of its failure to meet these additional requirements before the first day of the first calendar quarter beginning after the close of the first regular session of the State legislature that begins after the date of enactment of this Act. For purposes of the previous sentence, in the case of a State that has a 2-year legislative session, each year of the session is considered to be a separate regular session of the State legislature.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA05B4670F1314DD49B8FB546B328F365"><enum>302.</enum><header>State assessments of barriers to employment and financial support of children</header>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8515AECB3F384F4796241ADBAF36F5B9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>State assessments and reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a condition of the continued approval of a State plan under part D of title IV of the Social Security Act, each State with such an approved plan, acting through the appropriate State agencies, shall assess the State policies with respect to the issues described in subsection (b) that affect the ability of parents to pay child support, and shall submit a report to the Secretary of Health and Human Services on the results of the assessment not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDCF9AAA2FD9D4C3091BF23B20B94A119"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Issues described</header><text>The issues described in this subsection are the following:</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HC1B73051EFAF476ABDF25C0EDD448548"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The effect of State criminal laws and law enforcement practices on the employment acquisition, retention, and advancement prospects of an individual who is a parent of a minor child following arrest, conviction, or imprisonment, including—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HD1BF0F3B01D34B8082456A2B109C625A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any efforts, including counseling or employment support, to assist individuals released from custody with reentry to a community and successful reunification with their families; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC2B78BE3EF6A4A17B1E62625DF1EFD65"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an assessment of any efforts to seal or expunge arrest and conviction records and any efforts to grant certificates or other acknowledgments of rehabilitation to parents returning from incarceration, and to examine State occupational licensing and certification procedures.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8BC3777134A64045B5E47699C1A009B9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of State practices related to the collection of debts owed by individuals to the State, including criminal justice fees and fines and child support debt.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2A5BB3EE9B094BF29EE214EFD2096A1D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of State practices related to providing parents returning from incarceration with valid identification documents upon release from prison.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7F190570915B4E85AB874A8C784ACE95"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identification of any other barriers to healthy family formation, family reunification, coparenting, or sustainable economic opportunity for custodial and noncustodial parents that are created or exacerbated by Federal or State laws, policies, or procedures, including an examination of the rules of Federal and State means-tested programs, the operation of the State workforce system, the availability of financial education services, and the availability of domestic violence services and child support procedures to help victims of domestic violence stay safe and obtain the child support they are owed.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H793F80D804F64DC0B9FF5881579408BC"><enum>303.</enum><header>Public reporting on consequences for nonpayment</header>
 <subsection id="HA8F26A5542A04F42B95158ECE0226828"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 452(a)(10) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/652">42 U.S.C. 652(a)(10)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HF252C1DAACDE49F9AC36BAFFD567062A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (H), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H60BB67A2E6254A32B1AC9B891EDD4F4A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDCD867EA90DE4226A0F3C9AB3EC764E6" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H88DC15E132844E95A56D29319E9239B7"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of cases, by State, in which each of the following consequences for nonpayment of support was incurred by an obligor:</text>
 <clause id="H62E282B3E4554722B2B5BE9237B72F1F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a loss of liberty due to a criminal conviction or finding of civil contempt;</text> </clause><clause id="HE67F9897A6394E57B9525045E0EE5C64"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a suspension of a driver’s license;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H12D1C88420B84D7EB5FCDAEE7FFD7315"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a suspension of a professional, occupational, or recreational license;</text> </clause><clause id="H475E29823E6E4A618F9B6EA697F77CC8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>withholding of a passport; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H12325492C4D64A02870D1FE6D6D618DC"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">late payment fees, interest charged (including the amount and rate of interest), and other financial sanctions; and</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3663DE79B1AC4AC1A4AF1A11BCA12B5B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 454 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/654">42 U.S.C. 654</external-xref>), as amended by section 301(a)(1) of this Act, is further amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD55DBF1520294F559431595E4F3E12B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (34);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE06DAB1B90F545D184DA5261C8069303"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of paragraph (35) and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE1EAD5F72C644645A24A2368A3959429"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1E609474455F4DBC90301B8BD381C2F7" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H5FED80667F564FDD981BE44D81231F24"><enum>(36)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide that the State will maintain a full record of child support enforcement activities, including the consequences incurred by obligors as described in section 452(a)(10)(J).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF5C29618A8774067B071CA226C326FE2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Collection and reporting of child support enforcement data</header><text>Section 469 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/669">42 U.S.C. 669</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF7835A7A93034C6796EE5236B88489AC" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H06DEE900148B4C4C9DC9138C4995CD65"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Consequences for nonpayment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall collect and maintain up-to-date statistics, by State, and on a fiscal year basis, on the number of cases in which each consequence for nonpayment of support described in section 452(a)(10)(J) was incurred by an obligor.</text>
						</subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection></section><section id="H7BF64AD38B6C461EA70150DB1D57F103"><enum>304.</enum><header>Early intervention to ensure regular payment of support and prevent overdue support</header>
 <subsection id="HB928B53FF5DA4B3A8312253E5EA0314F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Procedures To provide job services for noncustodial parents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 466(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/666">42 U.S.C. 666(a)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after paragraph (19) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5B571CDDBC2F44229591111658614354" style="OLC">
						<paragraph id="HEEA1D257D7BB43EC828904F9AE123654"><enum>(20)</enum><header>Procedures To intervene early To ensure regular payment of support and prevent overdue support</header>
 <subparagraph id="H0EDF117832D04960AB7C28F3E560D28D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the State elects to provide job services to noncustodial parents (as described in the State plan pursuant to section 454(37)), procedures—</text>
 <clause id="HE001A7A0ECD944FCBB23474CE331FB1D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>under which the State shall prioritize early intervention efforts and make such services available on a voluntary basis prior to a determination that the individual owes overdue support as specified in paragraph (15);</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4252005B11194BA5950646CBA893F754"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>under which the State shall establish criteria for eligibility to receive such services, which shall restrict eligibility to noncustodial parents—</text>
 <subclause id="HB6F79825E3934FEBB4E515897F5693DB"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to whom there is an open child support case under the State program funded under this part;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HCE7B6C8614D44A16A86C7E8DA8A13C5F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>who are unemployed or underemployed;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H786344D35B6B4F2FBC456A2121B9E8FC"><enum>(III)</enum><text>who are not making regular child support payments;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H6745D9EF960E43149B1A66CA63C7B922"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who do not receive assistance under a State program funded under part A (or under any other State program funded with qualified State expenditures (as defined in section 409(a)(7)(B)(i)));</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HF24536E746504CEDA3A0A3224CB6F293"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who do not participate in an employment and training program under section 6(d)(4) of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (but who may receive supplemental nutrition assistance benefits under such Act); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HEDEF68539EE747D1B301E14D6D5F0529"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>who do not receive the same job services under the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act;</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H20CC2FC52EC348589A49C72FF2FD55B5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">under which the State agency administering a program under a State plan approved under this part shall provide, including through contract or cooperative agreement, job services that may include—</text>
 <subclause id="HB08C5540BCD1456D9529DA44E6E30335"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">job search assistance;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HE89AF7FEDFEF442BB7576BF81411D242"><enum>(II)</enum><text>job readiness training;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD0C8C4DF61184DC5AC713B7B641F26E2"><enum>(III)</enum><text>job development and job placement services;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H5C427B87FD994814B99B5F6E38019CF1"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>skills assessments to facilitate job placement;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HBD6BB60F1CE4459FAAE1E708B5F31F4A"><enum>(V)</enum><text>job retention services;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H5BE1EBF8320143389F09B3DA6651A3E2"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>certificate programs and other skills training directly related to employment, which may include activities to improve literacy and basic skills, such as programs to complete high school or a General Education Development (GED) certificate, as long as such activities and programs are included in the State job services plan pursuant to section 454(37);</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H6CCAFD4A47874D489C0EA2F68B184CAE"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>long-term and short-term subsidized employment or public-private career pathway partnerships;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H4C826B41602B42E49C3C908CEF370E58"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>substance abuse treatment;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H1B8BDBA0E6174E1E91B6843864139028"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>mental health services;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HDB01DFE444324AAB8AFF303169AB7CB2"><enum>(X)</enum><text>occupational skills training, including college credit programs; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HEB9CEA054C0841A3AD448229C3D922CB"><enum>(XI)</enum><text>work supports, such as transportation assistance, uniforms, and tools; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H0341872540CB4DB580A9FE80082A6687"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">under which the State shall ensure that participation in any such services is voluntary and shall inform potential participants that such participation is voluntary.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B8F68E0997B4D0A8E6AA27F2975CF94"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An Indian tribe or tribal organization (as defined in subsections (e) and (l) of section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b</external-xref>)) operating a child support enforcement program funded by a grant under this part may elect, as part of such program, to provide job services to noncustodial parents, consistent with the requirements of this paragraph and section 455(f).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H96289927E4ED46F28117BB6F9B2CCC57"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Performance tracking</header><text>Section 452(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/652">42 U.S.C. 652(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H2EA513987E67480FB36CB72B00B09376"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEB9FEC7EAA1B487DBA6595E6A810FFC0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (11), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9C87A0D3984C41DB97B97087319DBE00"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEE981DEAE1A44361A8EE44421C7422D9" style="OLC">
							<paragraph id="HEA0DA5835E2943AF939EAFF0BCAB24F5"><enum>(12)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H8EB381827918415E9484AB383F43FD91"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consult with States, Indian tribes, and tribal organizations (as defined in subsections (e) and (l) of section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b</external-xref>)), with a plan approved under this part, to develop data elements to ensure that the child support agency of any State, Indian tribe, or tribal organization administering a voluntary job services program under section 466(a)(20) demonstrates a plan for implementing measures to track the performance of such program with respect to meeting the goals of quality job placement, long-term unsubsidized job retention, increasing child support payments, decreasing child support arrearages, and increasing the involvement of low-income noncustodial parents with their children; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6898E64BC2584092813C35202386ACF4" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in carrying out section 466(a), collaborate with the Secretary of Labor and the Secretary of Agriculture to identify best practices and minimize duplication of services under employment and training programs for noncustodial parents administered by the Departments of Health and Human Services, Labor, and Agriculture.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H382ACED155804267BF04A137084438D5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>State plan</header><text>Section 454 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/654">42 U.S.C. 654</external-xref>), as amended by sections 301(a)(1) and 303(b) of this Act, is further amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H192023A1E8BB413AA2A89BE5180A4609"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (35), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE5BD10040B704952A984C5BF6940E566"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (36), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEF2BC0A68B834AF6A597B65D200B0F95"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (36) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H086A5686AB71494F8837F71F49FE9E2F" style="OLC"> <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8F3DB0A82FF54581B94DC44B9971D486"><enum>(37)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD335EACE7C384E75BD36C9FED0FC7ABA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of work activities in which the State requires noncustodial parents to participate pursuant to section 466(a)(15);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6193ACFA480145BC859D599FDA0A03A9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of any job services the State elects to provide to noncustodial parents, and criteria for eligibility to receive such services, under section 466(a)(20), or an explanation of why the State elects not to provide such services;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA042CD601A5E48EB9C6A93C5D4EB1A18"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an explanation of how the State will coordinate job services and work activities provided under this title with the State workforce development system (as such term is defined in section 3(67) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act), local responsible fatherhood programs (including such programs funded by a grant awarded under section 403(a)(2)), local prisoner reentry programs, and other local employment and training programs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7E13C33D7F4441AA4BA204F3B11B4F9"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if applicable, a description of the State plan for implementing measures for tracking the successful performance of the State voluntary job services program consistent with section 452(a)(12)(A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1A09C3AF75164430B2CF9BB91DE9BFF6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Payments to States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 455(a)(1)(A) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/655">42 U.S.C. 655(a)(1)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end <quote>including public and private non-Federal funds,</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H2CBE0C38B864419DA8C26EA5351F0234"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date that is one year after the date of the enactment of this section.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H73F594B64B4B4400B52428A3AE211B80"><enum>305.</enum><header>Improved collection and distribution of child support</header>
				<subsection id="H0EE7AEDE8076430189C8451CCCCEEFA1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Distribution of child support</header>
					<paragraph id="H2C57E59EAA764093BB6DD440612CC336"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Full distribution of child support collected; reform of rules for distribution of child support
			 collected on behalf of children in foster care</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H28FA9F2C50D64129A9B4FD8E8C20D9DF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 457 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/657">42 U.S.C. 657</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HF754AEA202624D4AA6DE6D7F6AA54CB3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by amending subsection (a) to read as follows:</text>
								<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE17727A4F980405E9F084CF77D99D963" style="OLC">
 <subsection commented="no" id="H3B7AD7AD163540008948105704BE5EE2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Full distribution of amounts collected on behalf of any family</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subsections (b) and (c), the entire amount of support collected by a State on behalf of any family receiving services pursuant to a plan approved under this part shall be paid to the family in accordance with this section.</text>
									</subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause><clause id="H26A1E3F4EC704861933F64848ECD352B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by amending subsection (b) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFD7C0F4C26A64D579FB00F9845081A92" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HA42BAB8154A64496BD49AF06D91223A9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Continuation of assignments</header> <paragraph id="HCE80EEAAD136401E9E3214F40121F21E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any rights to support obligations that are assigned to a State under this part on behalf of a family receiving assistance and in effect before the implementation date of this section may remain assigned after such date and distributed under the provisions and limitations of the Deficit Reduction Act of 2005.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H501EE6965B2640E1971AD21C663A1159"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Option to terminate assignments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State may choose to discontinue any assignment of a support obligation described in paragraph (1) and may treat amounts collected pursuant to the assignment as if the amounts had never been assigned and may distribute the amounts to the family in accordance with subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H5ECA8AE6804E42F4878F9D564AE5BEE0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking subsections (c) and (d) and redesignating subsection (e) as subsection (c); and</text> </clause><clause id="HB436F7162BD1471A98D05F085C3C6EAB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in subsection (c) (as so redesignated), by striking paragraph (1) and all that follows and inserting the following:</text>
								<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA146FE78E32448448FBCAE8FD4FABAF2" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H4EF8A7E3EB8D465698FB753A379CF65A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be used to provide supplemental services that serve the best interests of such child in a manner that best meets the future needs and educational, health, and employment interests of the child, or be deposited in—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEF5955ED1A00455980870AEFBE144712"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an account of the type described in section 1631(a)(2)(F) of this Act;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H932AEC1969C24D1FA59E27E5A43C3BF8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an ABLE account established under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/529A">section 529A</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8600EA6195894E3096EDB73802B08EDA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an individual development account established pursuant to Federal or State law; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F6B32C6A465445D82C3C03BD5A2C860"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other account in which benefits for the child may be conserved in a manner that the State determines, consistent with this paragraph, is in the best interests of the child; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H407E28B28ED84ED49CA401DDE2F0802F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall supplement and not supplant any other Federal funds or programs that may be available for the benefit of the child.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B8CE371E1BE4959A819E3804C95B084"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Foster care state plan amendment</header><text>Section 471(a)(17) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/671">42 U.S.C. 671(a)(17)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <clause id="H053428D33623467DA6B8D4AF8D4CC345"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>and consistent with the child's case plan</quote> after <quote>where appropriate</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H379EC87EFE314AFC879024C66510A0C9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>secure an assignment to the State of any rights to support</quote> and inserting <quote>establish paternity and establish, modify, and enforce child support obligations</quote>.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA86BAB2018F847B28E72AA4A7A1CFFD5"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Child support State plan amendment</header><text>Section 454 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/654">42 U.S.C. 654</external-xref>), as amended by sections 301(a)(1), 303(b), and 304(c) of this Act, is further amended—</text>
 <clause id="HE2F8845383C944F09C74FBF10CA47643"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (36), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text> </clause><clause id="HA46D916FCC144F47BA3BD4C90D4C8EE9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (37), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB0054B4470F34544BFF7781455FD7276"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (37) the following:</text> <quoted-block act-name="" id="H4F64BE1A01534C03A276C47648AD0267" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H3A5A8C9824A8475E97BDB99F0D9FC360"><enum>(38)</enum><text>provide that a State shall pay all collected child support to the family in accordance with section 457.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF025587F8265466F81FF8928B01299C8"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Support payments collected prior to effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 454(5) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/654">42 U.S.C. 654(5)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>such payments</quote> and all that follows through <quote>support payments collected</quote> and inserting <quote>entered into prior to the effective date of section 204 of the <short-title>Julia Carson Responsible Fatherhood and Healthy Families Act of 2017</short-title>, the individual will be notified on a monthly basis of the amount of the support payments collected and retained by the State under section 457(a)(1)(B) (as in effect prior to the effective date of such section)</quote>.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HADCA2BB95E3B40E2964038C52682BE96"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <subparagraph id="H226EACBDA0C74C4BB4D4A2F6F4CFC915"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 409(a)(7)(B)(i)(I)(aa) of such Act (42 U.S.C. 609(a)(7)(B)(i)(I)(aa)) is amended by striking <quote>457(a)(1)(B)</quote> and inserting <quote>457(a)</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA823A33B272456D8196D002B089D4A3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 454(34) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/654">42 U.S.C. 654(34)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>457(a)(2)(B)</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>457(b)</quote>.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H96C6C8830342454CA733B242F68C3B2E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 456(a)(1) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/656">42 U.S.C. 656(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>and shall be distributed in accordance with section 457</quote> after <quote>local processes</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H94E412AD3B3449D9A136FC95CD37FA9B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Section 466(a)(3)(B) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/666">42 U.S.C. 666(a)(3)(B)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <clause id="H5BD61B516BE843E09B885C84024AEA61"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>shall be distributed in accordance with section 457 in the case of overdue support assigned to a State pursuant to section 408(a)(3) or 471(a)(17), or, in any other case,</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA318B6FEE072444D9ACF84C5024A5638"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting <quote>or to the public agency responsible for supervising the placement of the child receiving foster care maintenance payments under section 472, which may use such payments in the manner the public agency determines will serve the best interest of the child, consistent with section 457(c)</quote> before the semicolon.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H0DD3AF0615AC4A2D91A3A4C317E976A7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on conditioning receipt of TANF on assignment of support</header><text>Section 408(a)(3) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/608">42 U.S.C. 608(a)(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H7615F21269D54782BD81A592145C695F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">No assistance for families not</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Prohibition on conditioning assistance for families on</header-in-text></quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H381A7C397F1C490989160FBF3D831E47"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>not</quote> after <quote>shall</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H1939620EE37B43A6B498F034C15A9855"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or under a program funded with qualified State expenditures (as defined in section 409(a)(7)(B)(i))</quote> after <quote>this part</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDF751624C2C14EE5816F278494DC860D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by striking <quote>, not exceeding the total amount of assistance so paid to the family,</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8CD4AC27A8324D7BA159E373677CCF2E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirement To disregard percentage of child support collected in determining amount and type of TANF assistance</header><text>Section 408(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/608">42 U.S.C. 608(a)</external-xref>), as amended by section 101(a)(2) of this Act and subsection (b) of this section, is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9FF5A0727C734750B5FD9D0D85F56F74" style="OLC">
						<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB6328559D07A48EE8A0954244BC9198E"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Requirement to disregard percentage of child support collected in determining amount and type of
 TANF assistance</header><text>A State to which a grant is made under section 403 shall disregard at least the same percentage of amounts collected as support on behalf of a family as the percentage of earned income that the State disregards, in determining the amount or type of assistance provided to the family under the State program funded under this part or under a program funded with qualified State expenditures (as defined in section 409(a)(7)(B)(i)).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE6807DD8537D44FF9469A7CFC07F0AF2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Restoration of Federal funding</header><text>Effective on the date of enactment of this Act, section 7309 of the Deficit Reduction Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/171">Public Law 109–171</external-xref>; 120 Stat. 147) is repealed, and part D of title IV of the Social Security Act shall be applied as if the amendment made by subsection (a) of that section had not been enacted.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H58C4F893DD614CD08EC98A553D624DFC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Repeal of mandatory fee for child support collection</header><text>Effective on the date of enactment of this Act, section 7310 of the Deficit Reduction Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/171">Public Law 109–171</external-xref>; 120 Stat. 147) is repealed, and part D of title IV of the Social Security Act shall be applied as if the amendments made by that section had not been enacted.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H05C826C771AC4FFDA24FCB34828C2C6C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Study and report</header><text>Not later than October 1, 2018, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall study and submit a report to Congress regarding the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H1DCDF0DA09454D36A960695629DCE3E3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The effect of age eligibility restrictions for the earned income tax credit established under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/32">section 32</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 for individuals without qualifying children on—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB4A3E8BFDCC145AB871325BF681C3649"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the ability of young parents to pay child support;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67D7931907FA4D16BD21966968A129DF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>compliance with child support orders; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF8FDC1AFEBF540F2A16852029B991CB5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the relationship between young noncustodial parents and their children.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD29C148262764B18A0832A3D8CCCFC49"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The impact of State earned income tax credit programs, especially such programs with targeted benefits for noncustodial parents, on—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H577FD16BBC0545B186A9C2AB206EF0CD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the ability of noncustodial parents to pay child support;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5EB9A3805E64018BE55B29D3DC68BD5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>compliance with child support orders; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9ECD215F10AF44B4A2F080DC7940AF95"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the relationship between noncustodial parents and their children.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD56C5D177B043A8A419F70C671D6E93"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The challenges faced by legal immigrants and individuals for whom English is not their primary language in fulfilling child support and other noncustodial parenting obligations.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H56E01B1AF810444A9CEF148807E43FBA"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Effective date</header>
 <paragraph id="HBD1C9DD6F19C412BB63DA9E6E02C778A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this section, the amendments made by this section shall take effect on October 1, 2018, and shall apply to payments under parts A and D of title IV of the Social Security Act for calendar quarters beginning on or after that date, without regard to whether regulations to implement the amendments are promulgated by such date.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE583A44F4D1844F2880D3F6686A43E95"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State option to accelerate effective date</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), a State may elect to have the amendments made by the preceding provisions of this section apply to the State and to amounts collected by the State (and to payments under such parts), on and after such date as the State may select that is not later than September 30, 2018.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H701C48572DA4401A939336CACEE3955E"><enum>306.</enum><header>Services and activities to support noncustodial parenting time</header>
 <subsection id="H91E55DA33DA54C3395FBBC3E79F11509"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 452(a)(10) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/652">42 U.S.C. 652(a)(10)</external-xref>), as amended by section 303(a), is further amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2861A7111EFD48DBA03FEB6F2CAA5260"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (J), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H030DB0B718984905BC5B72DB5E5B8249"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD0D90AF7568F4995A2C2F08A8313DCBB" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H971336A39B73424D8C0CDF813C43853E"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary of efforts by the State to provide early intervention services and activities that aim to improve the ability and willingness of noncustodial parents to support their children, including by—</text>
 <clause id="HFD03E85A566A4628ADB7D01B09B7693B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>supporting and improving paternity establishment, child support order establishment, and collections outcomes; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA74D3ADC4B5942848C92214A4E2187B9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilitating and assisting parents in accessing court processes to establish parenting time arrangements, assisting obligors with employment needs, or providing other allowable services or activities to carry out the State responsibilities under this part: and</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HECFFEE5AB281462F9F53E66C4C1E77B6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 454 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/654">42 U.S.C. 654</external-xref>), as amended by sections 301(a)(1), 303(b), 304(c), and 305(a)(1)(C) of this Act, is further amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF1C762025BA94F00ADBB06AE83C59FE8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (37), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC41B73E538464314BCCCD57669EA4FCA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (38), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAE34E4E1D77D4155B60FA0EFA390BBE8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5E19643E68164D52A76B512DFCC5FF66" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H303461BD9DD14CB2AF87ADAEA2B17711"><enum>(39)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describe efforts by the State to provide early intervention services and activities that aim to improve the ability and willingness of noncustodial parents to support their children, including by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H65643091B762491CBBA0D4F1B859C8C0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supporting and improving paternity establishment, child support order establishment, and collections outcomes; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H378A26E09C5A42FFB346EC56E2091F1B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilitating and assisting parents in accessing court processes to establish parenting time arrangements, assisting obligors with employment needs, or providing other allowable services or activities to carry out the State responsibilities under this part.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD072D12CE7074E48BFEB4FCB1E2ACFCB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Determinations of cost-Effectiveness performance level</header><text>Section 458(b)(6)(E) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H361CF8F95BB247C8A761F43662CECBF9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating clause (ii) as clause (iii); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H187C42BA73B147489AB8DECF38442EBE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after clause (i) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H49EE2512AD1D4F3D8689565DC7EBA57A" style="OLC"> <clause id="H11DFEF7E6F664D42B5D7F5B90874063D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exception for amount spent on early intervention services and activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of subsection (i), the total amount expended during the fiscal year under the State plan shall be reduced by an amount equal to the amount expended by the State for the fiscal year on early intervention services and activities intended to improve the ability and willingness of noncustodial parents to support their children, including by—</text>
 <subclause id="H7163B588C94C41B7A177E919953FDB04"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improving paternity establishment, child support order establishment, and collections outcomes; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HE7413C40CD7343B6A2F783D7FA962923"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">offering parenting time arrangements, assisting obligors with employment needs, or providing other allowable services or activities to carry out the State responsibilities under this part,</text>
								</subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">except that such reduced amount may not exceed 10 percent of such total amount expended during the
			 fiscal year under the State plan.</continuation-text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H15130874FA804D5085A664C4F3F88304"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Allotments to States for access and visitation program grants</header><text>Section 469B(c)(1) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/669b">42 U.S.C. 669b(c)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>$10,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$20,000,000</quote>.</text> </subsection></section></title><title id="HD97A3BDFCCE448A38C1592C893D9775F"><enum>IV</enum><header>Revenue provision</header> <section id="HFAA73AEA59FA4FF1AAA89B16378B5AE1" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>401.</enum><header>Increase in credit percentage under earned income tax credit for eligible individuals with no qualifying children</header> <subsection commented="no" id="H1174B096F1294A1AB4FC0725D0C512EA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The row in the table in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/32">section 32(b)(1)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 relating to no qualifying children is amended to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBCF0208ED8514167AB669E17E589284A" style="OLC">
						<table align-to-level="section" blank-lines-before="1" colsep="1" frame="topbot" line-rules="hor-ver" rowsep="0" rule-weights="4.4.4.0.0.0" table-template-name="Generic: 1 text, 2 num" table-type="">
							<tgroup cols="3" grid-typeface="1.1" rowsep="0" thead-tbody-ldg-size="10.10.12"><colspec coldef="txt" colname="column1" colwidth="202pts" min-data-value="180"></colspec><colspec coldef="fig" colname="column2" colwidth="56pts" min-data-value="10"></colspec><colspec coldef="fig" colname="column3" colwidth="56pts" min-data-value="10" rowsep="0"></colspec>
								<tbody>
									<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">No qualifying children</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" rowsep="0">20</entry><entry align="right" colname="column3" rowsep="0">7.65</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H394D224AAFC04D2595D16E5EA6A3E3B3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Income phaseout for eligible individuals with no qualifying children</header><text>The table in section 32(b)(2)(A) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>$5,280</quote> and inserting <quote>$11,500</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H21C99ECE999E4CCA956599AC9691347D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reduction of marriage penalty made permanent</header><text>Section 32(b)(2)(B) of such Code is amended to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HABB8B2D960F14EC6BD6FB8A9F2506587" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H56C082D7FD744CD99CB71C5AE58AC08D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Joint returns</header><text>In the case of a joint return filed by an eligible individual and such individual’s spouse, the phaseout amount determined under subparagraph (A) shall be increased by $5,000.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2C0FD25799D74422B49339C3D622018F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Increase in age range for eligible individuals with no qualifying child</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 32(c)(1)(A)(ii)(II) of such Code is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H7BBEA81752774F8F98A5CFA32A467C64"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>age 25</quote> and inserting <quote>age 21</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA7DD1370F8654444AF1E04F6E74207D4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>age 65</quote> and inserting <quote>age 68</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB2B11B6EBA914342ACB352CDEC7DA9B6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Taxpayer eligible for credit for individuals with no qualifying children if qualifying children do not have valid Social Security numbers</header><text>Section 32(c)(1)(F) of such Code is amended to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H01FC39C6B29D4474B9754BDEBB13104A" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="HE4A3366CFD3D4B54A0189C0DF712455B"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Individuals who do not include TIN, etc., of any qualifying child</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any eligible individual who has one or more qualifying children, if—</text> <clause id="H4DCCE97D9922478A9AE363740FC1CC0B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>no qualifying child of such individual is taken into account under subsection (b) by reason of paragraph (3)(D), and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1BF28F6300EB4A2381C724D9221B0F56"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">no child of such individual is taken into account for purposes of any other child tax benefit under this chapter,</text>
							</clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">for purposes of the credit allowed under this section, such individual may be considered an
			 eligible individual without a qualifying child.</continuation-text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H04B13D6901BA463499037D4103F68B85"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Expanding the EITC for certain former foster youth</header><text>Section 32(c)(1) of such Code, as amended by subsection (e), is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HECC5D78EA2B643E2BCB4872066D8975E" style="OLC">
						<subparagraph id="HDB11CF46A2654EBDBA92E22E12C277AE"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Foster youth</header>
 <clause id="HB63E82CE20DA4D089933561D2E754D82"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term <quote>eligible individual</quote> shall include an individual who is a qualified foster youth.</text> </clause><clause id="H22B54B55A2764C2D9DABC5E8584511DF"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Qualified foster youth defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of clause (i), the term <quote>qualified foster youth</quote> means an individual who—</text>
 <subclause id="H342C6BA8D094412C9E0B69F6279839B7"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has attained age 18 but not attained age 21 before the close of the taxable year, and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HA8CAF12F024E4195974E67EA4555078E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>on or after attaining the age of 14 was placed in a foster family home by an agency of a State or a political subdivision thereof or by a qualified foster care placement agency (as defined by section 131(b)(3)).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC0ECFCF53E0443569837E6C453290BE9"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2017.</text> </subsection></section></title><title id="H539090A22B32454DBA9AFFE13A49E7F1"><enum>V</enum><header>Supplemental nutrition assistance</header> <section id="H60AC4C1A6AD24A21A9F25166F8972A40"><enum>501.</enum><header>Collection of child support under the supplemental nutrition assistance program</header> <subsection commented="no" id="HFF48525CFC78421D911E3A35E59E3D8B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Encouragement of collection of child support</header><text>Section 5 of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2014">7 U.S.C. 2014</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H51D9FBC58DC1490F8B61AA964EDF4BB4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (e)—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HE0627F52BBA54D979B7C89015B3257D7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (5) and (6) as paragraphs (6) and (7), respectively;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H384D8B96A81843AE8E15E08A173A750B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)(B), by striking <quote>paragraph (6)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (7)</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H67A26EA59487485CACF0808C01563E62"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (4) the following:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H908D4A83322A46A0B25B3BDD9BD81B78" style="OLC">
								<paragraph commented="no" id="H3B1CA82C182A4B4B9D26E2FE62118F1E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Deduction for child support received</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H852E0015FC9B4A6EB0EEB5295AB47B79"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A household shall be allowed a deduction of 20 percent of all legally obligated child support payments received from an identified or putative parent of a child in the household if that parent is not a household member.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2551181016B544DEB21E6BF2D0FB1F7D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Order of determining deductions</header><text>A deduction under this paragraph shall be determined before the computation of the excess shelter deduction under paragraph (7).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3DF0EE43D9E24366BCBE4D197C4308B9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (k)(4)(B), by striking <quote>subsection (e)(6)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (e)(7)</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3432A23364AE4E598C21A538A8E6646C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Simplified verification of child support payments</header><text>Section 5(n) of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2014">7 U.S.C. 2014(n)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7C31DA4ACEB44D25ADC58244EB6E7816"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">State options to simplify</header-in-text></quote>, and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Simplified</header-in-text></quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8B0CBC324F6F4FDFB4E52DF2AC8C431D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Regardless of whether</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC5F35AE6FBF64C96A62CBD2FBF1881F4" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H2573D4EE77614C89A8ED06E7AC24D1EA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A household that is paying legally obligated child support through the program under part D of title IV of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/651">42 U.S.C. 651</external-xref> et seq.) shall receive—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H53BA486E3BC14C66B0A859102AB57BE6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a deduction under subsection (e)(4); or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9EE235B164342389E204B46C3FFB73C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an exclusion under subsection (d)(6);</text>
 </subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">for child support payments made.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H26764DC7719D41608ECBF874B23C8EB7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State options</header><text>Regardless of whether</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4BABBC1C99184D12B5A33ABF9C793ADD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Inclusion of economic opportunities programs in definition of work program</header><text>Section 6(o)(2) of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2015">7 U.S.C. 2015(o)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H776994E1BABD479896B7D26927E63EAB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>or </quote> at the end;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA0B0FBABBF124F3F858325FEECF3CB73"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA8478043658544CBA7BED364FE897C40"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEC64FF06504B4F41941EA635F009B442" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H959748C3FFE4436593C77CE15CC53888"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">participate in and comply with the requirements of a State program to provide job services to noncustodial parents as provided in section 466(a)(20) of the Social Security Act;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDED17FA80A024495AA8656B1273C9D9F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header>
 <paragraph id="H90C04C4FB3B741B294DF0B44D8438ACF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>This section and the amendments made by this section take effect on October 1, 2017.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3C3B1F162BC4435295C9237D41FAC23C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>A State shall implement the amendments made by subsections (a) and (b) for participating households at the 1st certification, or 1st recertification, of the household that occurs on or after October 1, 2017.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section></title></legis-body></bill>


