<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H910FCE7CBB2B41E8804C48DF291B0011" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3244 RH: To amend title 5, United States Code, to provide for annual surveys of Federal employees, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
		<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 297</calendar>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3244</legis-num>
		<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 115–403]</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20170714">July 14, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001187">Mr. Meadows</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001071">Mr. Jody B. Hice of Georgia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HGO00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<action>
			<action-date>November 8, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the
			 Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
			<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction>
			<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on July 14, 2017</action-instruction>
		</action>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-desc display="yes"><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To amend title 5, United States Code, to provide for annual surveys of Federal employees, and for
			 other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body changed="added" committee-id="HGO00" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HD54D866F2BE74FC98394081B9DE74C64" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
		<section id="H3D83CAE792C24B75BBA4D5E3CD5AD4CC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Employee surveys</header>
 <subsection id="H8CFA751DDFDD4A07B1A1257E8BF3FE9F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/14">Chapter 14</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HGO00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEB6763758BA84A389FFA2B966763BD8E" reported-display-style="italic" style="USC"> <section id="HB5CF408405954D048E9FFE0E580E3B52"><enum>1403.</enum><header>Employee surveys</header> <subsection id="HB16990DC408648A1935F3A4D47387925"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each agency shall conduct an annual survey of its employees (including survey questions unique to the agency and questions prescribed under subsection (b)) to assess—</text>
 <paragraph id="H813E1805B31E4C7C9CA9D9B0B05D58A2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>leadership and management practices that contribute to agency performance; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD518126EC2914F7DBDF41A2ED6B8A538"><enum>(2)</enum><text>employee satisfaction with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H833982E4FA514DB2ABEAAE02AFFD3AAE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>leadership policies and practices;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE07009BB4DC543689AB94B68AE41BCEF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>work environment;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AA04E9B768B4C59B57A49433A574BB4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>rewards and recognition for professional accomplishment and personal contributions to achieving organizational mission;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H658758264512471A8E51BB4DA3B1BB34"><enum>(D)</enum><text>opportunity for professional development and growth; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC3698C22E784C4B9E6FC483C41BB574"><enum>(E)</enum><text>opportunity to contribute to achieving organizational mission.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA732E9F2200E41B8B6AAD72993A48524"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations; notice</header>
 <paragraph id="H026EE174ABDD4885AAAA077BD95F5B9C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall issue regulations prescribing survey questions that should appear on all agency surveys under subsection (a) in order to allow a comparison across agencies.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H3F3B174AC9244567B21129E1BE0BEA98"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice of change to regulations</header>
 <subparagraph id="H8AF7B8E5096247069D35AF5CAB3F8647"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Office of Personnel Management may not issue a regulation under this section until the date that is 60 days after the date on which the Director submits such regulation to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate unless the Director submitted such regulation to those committees not later than the day after the date on which the notice of proposed rulemaking is published in the Federal Register.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H161A35AEA1C94FA990AD27366D02CC10"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall apply with respect to any regulation promulgated on or after the date of enactment of this paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE92CF52025644BFA5720B7D7BB3E490"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notice of change to survey questions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days before finalizing any change, addition, or removal to any survey question in the annual employee survey administered by the Office pursuant to this section, the Director shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H635BEF8DD73A45A28A6BDBCE924CB8EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make the proposed change, addition, or removal and the proposed final text, if applicable, of any such question publicly available on the agency’s website; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H43F4D2BEA6214A249B1BFA2664210C91"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate—</text>
 <clause id="H25A86983F48647618806B5FE80703EBA"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the proposed change, addition, or removal and the proposed final text, if applicable, of any such question;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H81516DDB5FA44555AE8D5D1955F38B20"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a justification for the proposed change, addition, or removal; and</text> </clause><clause id="HBE296F0934A34F3083E9FC5F1B1C9D21"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of whether the change, addition, or removal will affect the ability to compare results from surveys taken after the change, addition, or removal is implemented with results from surveys taken before the change, addition, or removal is implemented.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H280BA39E007D48A4987E38D39453504D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Occupational data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent practicable, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall, in publishing agency survey data collected under subsection (a), include responses to such surveys by occupation. In carrying out this subsection the Director shall ensure the confidentiality of any agency survey respondent.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5D74C6B7824A42448BD3B2C58A304FAF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Survey incentives</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conjunction with each annual survey required under subsection (a), the head of each agency shall submit to the Director of the Office of Personnel Management information on any monetary, in-kind, leave-related, or other incentive offered to employees in exchange for participation in the survey, including a description of the type of each such incentive offered and the quantity of each such incentive provided to employees.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2F18A5CB828D40E39853C72DC7534B5B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Availability of Results</header><text>The results of the agency surveys under subsection (a) shall be made available to the public and posted on the website of the agency involved, unless the head of such agency determines that doing so would jeopardize or negatively impact national security.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H37FBCD9E1E814B6BB3EE47EA733B6542"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Agency defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>agency</quote> has the meaning given the term Executive agency in section 105.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H29B31CE9DEF14C3A98D21B2C103E37E9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header> <paragraph id="H28057202D0CC4A5EB96BD9B10C0ED7BA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements of section 1403 of title 5, United States Code (as added by this Act) shall apply with respect to any annual survey initiated on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H178C094139BF4BA4B5386AF75DE4F3DE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any annual survey authorized by, and meeting the requirements of, section 1128 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/136">Public Law 108–136</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/7101">5 U.S.C. 7101</external-xref> note) that is in progress on the date of enactment of this Act (or, if no such survey is in progress, was most recently completed prior to the date of enactment of this Act) shall be considered to be a survey authorized by, and that meets the requirements of, section 1403(a) of title 5, United States Code, (as added by this Act) including for purposes of requiring the Office of Personnel Management to give notice of subsequent changes, additions, or removals of survey questions under section 1403(b)(3) of such title.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9D00069965DE4BC78EDB22C94D0B6DDA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="HC2D3CB51CAA5400CAAAB8F8D0ED978E7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Repeal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1128 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/136">Public Law 108–136</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/7101">5 U.S.C. 7101</external-xref> note), and the item relating to such section in the table of sections, is repealed.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB12CE6C293D54B82B221D35902F96D3D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Table of sections</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/14">chapter 14</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/1402">section 1402</external-xref> the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HGO00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB9D9D1A87FD44A6698DFD248F066DF0A" reported-display-style="italic" style="USC">
						<toc changed="added" committee-id="HGO00" regeneration="no-regeneration" reported-display-style="italic">
							<toc-entry level="section">1403. Employee surveys.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H86B44C6FDE3340FEA3F89173401A6BCF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Table of chapters</header><text>The item relating to chapter 14 in the table of chapters for part II of title 5, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HGO00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD2A844276977439B9F97544C2487592A" reported-display-style="italic" style="USC">
						<toc changed="added" committee-id="HGO00" regeneration="no-regeneration" reported-display-style="italic">
							<multi-column-toc-entry level="section"><toc-enum>14.</toc-enum><level-header level="section">Agency Chief Human Capital Officers; Employee Surveys</level-header><target>1401</target></multi-column-toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB144566CA4D949F4A07D978CA5F9E211"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Chapter heading</header><text>The heading for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/14">chapter 14</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended to read as follows: <quote><header-in-text level="chapter" style="USC">Chapter 14—Agency Chief Human Capital Officers; Employee Surveys</header-in-text></quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H4E7E783C7D09497FBF26AA332352D5A2"><enum>2.</enum><header>GAO study on annual survey incentives</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study on the types of incentives offered by agencies to employees in exchange for participation in surveys required by section 1128 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/136">Public Law 108–136</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/7101">5 U.S.C. 7101</external-xref> note) or section 1403 of title 5, United States Code, that includes an evaluation of the impact of such incentives on employee survey responses and response rates, and any recommendations regarding such incentives the Comptroller General considers necessary.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
	<endorsement display="yes">
		<action-date>November 8, 2017</action-date>
		<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the
			 Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill>


