<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1D72E55BBD734A79AA29F102335C9ED0" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2329 IH: Nation Building Here at Home Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2329</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170503">May 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001038">Mr. Higgins of New York</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Transportation to establish a transformational infrastructure
			 competitive grant program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H53633FE21B7D4C258FCFF5AF37483C87" style="OLC">
 <section id="HB1C1E11E94D844B6BD6751598800C688" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Nation Building Here at Home Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H509893D023F4420A98E91DC9C1BD7175"><enum>2.</enum><header>Transformational infrastructure competitive grant program</header> <subsection id="H4F93231CD2B14A69BA2983D5DC370D60"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall establish a transformational infrastructure competitive grant program.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8D28467A8FE84593BC9A59417CF0EFF2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grant authority</header><text>In carrying out the program established under subsection (a), the Secretary may make a grant, on a competitive basis, to any of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H6BF5A34F1D3941F2959443D914AAFF07"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A State government.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBC1C9AD6C7D844C8B6F019763DEAF443"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A local government.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA923FE3BD93049628FA67D8484F9AB7D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A transit agency.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H993E406F41BE4F598C40BA538DC6E92B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A port authority.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDAFCDFCDE70347A3BE623FCDA1B2306B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible projects</header>
 <paragraph id="HA4E5F40AB5B94312A3B8D094BF84AC2D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A grant made under subsection (b) may be used for any of the following, if the Secretary determines that the project will significantly impact a metropolitan area, a region, or all of the United States:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9DF4B5CB56984BEE8F29FE9871DF94A3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A highway or bridge project eligible under title 23, United States Code, including interstate rehabilitation, improvements to the rural collector road system, the reconstruction of overpasses and interchanges, bridge replacements, bridge painting, seismic retrofit projects for bridges, and road realignments.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09095A62C69E456EAAC9DF6E7C01E60D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A public transportation project eligible under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, including investment in a project participating in the New Starts or Small Starts programs that will expedite the completion of that project and its entry into revenue service.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17F6B9BD70CA440DA5EB167CED407CA9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A passenger or freight rail transportation project.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD275FEC61DEA48F687D9D88CAF206597"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A port infrastructure investment, including a project that connects ports to other modes of transportation and improves the efficiency of freight movement.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HACF997E849814942AFA5D89A19B1CF38"><enum>(E)</enum><text>An aviation infrastructure project.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HABD5163E87444DBEADA191D2D1B40858"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A water infrastructure project.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H86EF2DBDA18942D59EF58B4E2938F454"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>With respect to a project described in paragraph (1)(F), the Secretary shall coordinate any grant for such a project with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and the Secretary of the Army (acting through the Chief of Engineers).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H76766A26E10740BDB3E92A65A8E4DF9F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applications and criteria for grant awards</header>
 <paragraph id="H5617D2701F274E5DABF2431A987EC0D8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible for a grant made under subsection (b), an entity described in paragraph (1), (2), (3), or (4) of that subsection shall submit to the Secretary an application in such form, at such time, and containing such information as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H56E5C2A91B654A1298E56141EEE65C3E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Criteria for grant awards</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue regulations specifying the criteria that the Secretary will use to make grants on a competitive basis under subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0DD85F1D16A94869B861D391ABEBC7E7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Financial commitments</header><text>The criteria specified by the Secretary under paragraph (2) shall include criteria for the consideration of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF551335FC5A94ED1863E5A311DD90AFC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether there are financial commitments in place with respect to a proposed project;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E74536B1A384AC4851D7CC3C3C76C7C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the degree of certainty with respect to such financial commitments; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC725AAB989A24ACD9531D2D926163060"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether such financial commitments are from non-Federal sources.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H22351B5E7C9749DFAB7C42F939176A58"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Federal share</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal share of the cost of a project assisted with a grant made under subsection (b) may not exceed 100 percent of that cost.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1FE34F9A09774575AA29ECFEC7482289"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In making grants under subsection (b), the Secretary shall ensure, to the extent practicable, that the grants—</text>
 <paragraph id="HED472B84ACE74A8AAD2F342F931C24B4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are distributed geographically in an equitable manner;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H91AB7E3DBC68417B96053A1B6DD06CA7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>address the needs of both urban and rural areas appropriately;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD06B85520A2D497393EBF184A810DF0E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>promote the training and employment of veterans, including by having applicable contractors provide to veterans a preference during the hiring and referral of laborers;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H189ABFFE6719483390B9F9F6826461B2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>are utilized in a manner that ensures an appropriate percentage of grant amounts are expended through small business concerns owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals (as determined by the Secretary); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB3C2996397B44626BEE4DE8B0D2E0D4D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>promote the utilization of participants in a registered apprenticeship program, including by providing a preference to proposed projects that incorporate such utilization.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0474E901E41241918F97AD0306AB7ACC"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Applicability of title 40</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each project conducted using funds provided with a grant made under subsection (b) shall comply with the requirements of subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HE97A14E7F3D846DBA61F35BE4A023DC7"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Buy America</header>
 <paragraph id="HE47C9E4153E3413B975936CF809267CA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available for a project under this Act may be used for the project unless all of the iron, steel, and manufactured goods used in the project are produced in the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4AC79A139B6F49D0AEF381843BFF0C9E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall not apply in any case or category of cases in which the Secretary finds that—</text> <subparagraph id="H88F215F1FB3E45539C7CE73C1BACCE80"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">applying paragraph (1) would be inconsistent with the public interest;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H745ADF4B248E43CE92FC89449586BCA3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">iron, steel, or the relevant manufactured goods are not produced in the United States in sufficient and reasonably available quantities or to a satisfactory quality; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H324D09A9A25D4943A8D449D490B88DA5"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">inclusion of iron, steel, and manufactured goods produced in the United States will increase the cost of the overall project by more than 25 percent.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H852F358F7AA24CD0A40ED9D975F30CEF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Justifications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary determines that it is necessary to waive the application of paragraph (1) based on a finding under paragraph (2), the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register a detailed justification for the waiver.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC77566F12B404D34B8F1A1E3A89C0CEB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>International agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This subsection shall be applied in a manner consistent with United States obligations under international agreements.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H725BD69A37DA4ED795B4BF111B17FCB9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Transparency and accountability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the program established under subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="HB34E334B58BE415E9F82D4EDD4EC3511"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">take actions to ensure that grants made under subsection (b) are utilized as expeditiously and efficiently as possible;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF3F9B9B7CA4E42179FD269C88B556261"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make available to the public, on an appropriate Web site of the Department of Transportation, information on each grant made under subsection (b); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9989846482DF4E269CC64C88DF2FB929"><enum>(3)</enum><text>submit to Congress, not later than 1 year after the first grant is made under subsection (b), and annually thereafter, information on grants made under subsection (b), including the progress made on projects funded by such grants.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HBC6BDBC710424B5B91B41EB84E470874"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Environmental streamlining</header><text>The Secretary shall coordinate, to the maximum extent practicable, with relevant Federal departments and agencies to ensure that environmental reviews are conducted in a manner that facilitates the accelerated delivery of projects for which a grant is made under this section.</text>
			</subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HAE39ACFA7C4C4B4296DC80557C81AEF8"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HB1F633DB5E2A4D369DA20453FEC15D49"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to make grants under the program established under subsection (a) $1,263,000,000,000, in the aggregate, for fiscal years 2018 through 2022.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H99BDA92CE0864A1697D574F7B4245572"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible project use</header><text>From the amounts made available under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall use—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HBB26147571AB4AE48318A3D5A205C1A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>85 percent of the amounts to make grants for projects described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of subsection (c)(1);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC1DAB79D75F84E01A8817EEBA8BA00C0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>2 percent of the amounts to make grants for projects described in subparagraph (D) of subsection (c)(1);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H883D99A69A1E4F9CA108D90D7BD4E015"><enum>(C)</enum><text>4 percent of the amounts to make grants for projects described in subparagraph (E) of subsection (c)(1); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA674D50A7C3A45C2BE7615A0E434FE34"><enum>(D)</enum><text>9 percent of the amounts to make grants for projects described in subparagraph (F) of subsection (c)(1).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0DFD8BDE6E00452EA0A556FD9DC545D3" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Nation Building Here at Home Financing Initiative</header>
 <subsection id="H5709CFAD123D4443AC2D43F8FD68710D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of Transportation, shall establish a Nation Building Here at Home Financing Initiative in accordance with this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC1D7DCBC57EA4295B414F3E4A1FF99FA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authority To issue bonds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the initiative established under subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury may issue bonds. The aggregate face amount of bonds issued under this subsection may not exceed $300,000,000,000.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB23ABCFA0F2541FDB1072C47288BC160"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Characteristics of bonds</header><text>Bonds issued under subsection (b) shall be issued in such amounts, bear such rates of interest, and be subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary of the Treasury may prescribe.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB82EA2491EA74552A35152923D9F960E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of bond proceeds</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall make available to the Secretary of Transportation the proceeds resulting from bonds issued under subsection (b). The Secretary of Transportation may use such proceeds only to carry out the program established under section 2(a) of this Act.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H26E17FC46C00439CA296C0B2E050CC90"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall submit to Congress a comprehensive report describing the transportation needs of the United States for each of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HFFCF68F570564A94AC925CDDCBD89B4D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The 20-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9DB6E7C4CE094B249E7DAA1996480722"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The 30-year period beginning after the period described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCC314FC97AF74503915C67CDDCDCF393"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The 50-year period beginning after the period described in paragraph (2).</text> </paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

