<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCE454D6A39C541BF94873C6FAB98A536" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2422 IH: Action for Dental Health Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2422</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170515">May 15, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S001148">Mr. Simpson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to improve essential oral health care for low-income and
			 other
			 underserved individuals by breaking down barriers to care, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H3955B8A2318D4AC89433CF1AD49764D3" style="OLC">
 <section id="HA3BB63BA782A409F8F4FD63AEE6A5B0C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Action for Dental Health Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H0E63565368B3494B96A756987FBF98ED"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H71E67BDE606645EDAF9B23B1E3F73BE4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>More than 181 million Americans will not visit a dentist even though nearly half of people over 30 suffer from some form of gum disease and nearly one in four children under the age of five already have cavities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDE4EB3363B7E4420AC63958D9FE39893"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Many volunteer dental projects sponsored by national, State, and local dental societies provide free care now to those most in need. Annually, dentists deliver an estimated $2.6 billion in free and discounted care according to the America’s Dentists Care Foundation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3B11DC63D1FD46918E9BE2F9BF483D44"><enum>(3)</enum><text>It is estimated that emergency department (ED) charges for dental complaints totaled up to $2.1 billion in 2010. Nearly 80 percent of the dental emergency room visits were nonurgent and could have been seen in a dental office. Shifting those ED visits to a dental office translates into potential cost savings of up to $1.7 billion a year and offers the possibility of establishing a <quote>dental home</quote> for these individuals.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H24A4378884DA4734B77AB820F13B469A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Seniors, especially those in nursing homes and long-term care facilities, often have special dental needs and complicated medical histories that require consultation between dentists and fellow medical professionals in providing an interdisciplinary approach to their overall health needs.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HFB86C0656F70420DBA4F0317161E8792"><enum>3.</enum><header>Volunteer dental projects and action for dental health program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 317M of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247b-14">42 U.S.C. 247b–14</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H730E401565F94AB5965326C5E558CE67"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (e) and (f) as subsections (g) and (h), respectively;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3931CE03D62545CAA6A5F4F55D9DC827"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (d), the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block id="H782615D4983F44A3B7BB08D3DD3A0244" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H91C5223E92D0439B907FA5065BC5A403"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Grants To Support Volunteer Dental Projects</header> <paragraph id="H25AC264B33414C5DB07B576EF7A79F2E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, may award grants to or enter into contracts with eligible entities to obtain portable or mobile dental equipment, and pay for appropriate operational costs, for the provision of free dental services to underserved populations that are delivered in a manner consistent with State licensing laws.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H05CDFBE16D594B08A09AB1B02BE5B23C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>eligible entity</term> includes a State or local dental association, a State oral health program, a dental education, dental hygiene education, or postdoctoral dental education program accredited by the Commission on Dental Accreditation, or a community-based organization that partners with an academic institution, that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9F82818C32264A168A17B498A1105C85"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is exempt from tax under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF61537B59B634BE8A402C064B089088A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>offers a free dental services program for underserved populations.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H815346D2E66C4F63A9FA468D57515E5D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Action for Dental Health Program</header>
 <paragraph id="H587821F977CE4E19B3663D12062057E4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, may award grants to or enter into contracts with eligible entities to collaborate with State, county, or local public officials and other stakeholders to develop and implement initiatives to accomplish any of the following goals:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0DBD0384284140B3B3D6AFF8643AA2B8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>To improve oral health education and dental disease prevention, including through community-wide prevention programs, through the use of dental sealants and fluoride varnish, and by increasing oral health literacy.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD396492ECEF045E1ABB89E78E25D2FA9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>To make the health care delivery system providing dental services more accessible and efficient through the development and expansion of outreach programs that will facilitate the establishment of dental homes for children and adults, including for the aged, blind, and disabled populations.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H60EBB4582B844358ABD56E5588A658EE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>To reduce geographic barriers, language barriers, cultural barriers, and other similar barriers to the provision of dental services.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73E4AE0A35BE4030A8896F86D28B825E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>To help reduce the use of emergency departments by individuals who seek dental services more appropriately delivered in a dental primary care setting.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCAAD2AB560FD41F6A7F453ABCC48A56E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>To facilitate the provision of dental care to nursing home residents who are disproportionately affected by the lack of dental care.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B7050F548CF478197C91003700CBAF7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>eligible entity</term> includes a State or local dental association; a State oral health program; or a dental education, dental hygiene, or postdoctoral dental education program accredited by the Commission on Dental Accreditation, or a community-based organization that partners with an academic institution, that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8BAB998980844807BBCBCEAAA8AC7260"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is exempt from tax under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0D825B1F9F74E4FABE7805ADE952D72"><enum>(B)</enum><text>partners with public and private stakeholders to facilitate the provision of dental services for underserved populations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H172C1FBA0AF04D08AF66050FADB018FE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (h), as redesignated by paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>and $18,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2018 through 2022</quote> after <quote>fiscal years 2001 through 2005</quote>.</text> </paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

