<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H6A1AE4186C2D4D3593AE0A92365F97FB" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2378 IH: Save for Success Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2378</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170504">May 4, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000570">Mr. Ben Ray Luján of New Mexico</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to reform the American opportunity tax credit to support
			 college savings.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HB9F3668CB9BA4412BA865270C9D6A3D4" style="OLC">
 <section id="HAB7B2CCCF8D84ED5842443E723A8082D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Save for Success Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H75710D5D7C554D7D8401E94F09A72FDA"><enum>2.</enum><header>American opportunity tax credit savings credit</header> <subsection id="H3D5F6610621F4C47B87F62167B6DB965"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/25A">Section 25A</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by redesignating subsection (j) as subsection (k) and by inserting after subsection (i) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H630817006A764E08BB7F065ABBAC2D42" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H6C44CAD549BD48F59E2EFAE4ABFB06CF"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Special rules relating to AOTC savings credit</header>
 <paragraph id="H8E0ADDECAFE44F72AAFF8FF2CE77FB98"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>qualified tuition and related expenses</term> with respect to any individual includes eligible college savings contributions for such individual. Such contributions shall be taken into account for purposes of subsection (i)(1)(A) before tuition and fees.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H21F24C7F6EFD46C9BABBF84FED490806"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header>
 <subparagraph id="H85FC5633822D422980C795CCEED1C48A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The aggregate amount of contributions with respect to an individual which may be taken into account under paragraph (1) for a taxable year is $250.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6AC039A347B74FF2ABB0A1CBA91041E4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Phase out</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The dollar amount in subparagraph (A) shall be reduced (but not below zero) by the amount which bears the same ratio to such dollar amount as—</text>
 <clause id="H5053C99E99D147F0B99ECB6E4457C706"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of percentage points (if any) in excess of 133 percent that the taxpayer’s household income for the taxable year is of the poverty line for a family of the size involved, bears to</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE6779A7BF5434C22B6DB13CD0C9F51C4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>400 percentage points.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H79DF87C19C654D118CDB477611348797"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Terms relating to income and families</header><text>The terms <term>family size</term>, <term>household income</term>, and <term>poverty line</term> shall have the meanings given such terms by section 36B(d).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE6F284259DB4455AA756CB0B783638B7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligible higher education contribution</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), the term <term>eligible college savings contribution</term> with respect to an individual means the excess of—</text> <subparagraph id="H33CFABA2F8984088B696A934541113F7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>contributions by the taxpayer in the taxable year to qualified college savings accounts of which the individual is the beneficiary, over</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2FBF44089A24BBB821134A9AFB171C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>distributions from all such qualified college savings accounts for the taxable year.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE81538B7A7044C04B8F427B51E277113"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Qualified college savings accounts</header><text>The term <term>qualified college savings account</term> with respect to which such individual is the beneficiary means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H640D58A2A5684EC99A317C36AC86277A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an account under a qualified tuition program (as defined by section 529), and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6DC3610985024E5CB3775FA2E3FA7758"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an account under a program of a State (or political jurisdiction thereof) established exclusively for the purpose of paying for college tuition and other post-secondary educational expenses.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA094E95B52F34513921CAAAD8D046065"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Portion of credit made refundable</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">So much of the credit allowed under subsection (a) as is attributable to this subsection (determined after the application of subsection (i) and without regard to this subsection and section 26(a)) shall be treated as a credit allowable under subpart C (and not allowed under subsection (a)). The preceding sentence shall not apply to any taxpayer for any taxable year if such taxpayer is a child to whom subsection (g) of section 1 applies for such taxable year.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA70E76ACD0EF4F02A37F26F02F1F0D1E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>AOTC lifetime limitation</header><text>Section 25A(i)(2) of such Code is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7CC35E4FC5084905B44D6E1BCDE1768B" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H31821338944746539E873D2897689D7F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>In lieu of subparagraphs (A) and (C) of subsection (b)(2), the amount allowed as a credit under this section for the taxable year with respect to an individual shall not exceed—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H441A7F2B64434278973338C81ED9F6CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$10,000, reduced</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H99B28DF3A6F6455F8D9D0BF1205CD2F5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by the amount allowed under this section with respect to such individual for all prior taxable years.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB3EF6E20ED204FE0835119AEF7B23DC0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Pilot program To make periodic payments as college expenses incurred</header><text>Section 25A(i) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H522F7AC9587A45BAB6C1B04C2BD1BDBA" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H563595A099E04F639D977D2219E7E5E0"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Pilot program to make periodic payments as college expenses incurred</header> <subparagraph id="H47FA0A5763DE45AD84EA41C44CC002C9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of Education shall jointly establish a program designed to make payments periodically to or on behalf of an eligible student as the student incurs qualified expenses during the taxable year. The total amount that may be so paid to or on behalf of an eligible student through this program shall not exceed the credit which would (but for subparagraph (B)) be allowable under this section if subsection (d) were applied by using the taxpayer’s modified adjusted gross income for the preceding taxable year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70FBF2DC8AE3429B80F09987F29F2AE8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Credit reduced by pilot program payments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The credit allowable under this section (without regard to this subparagraph) for any taxable year shall be reduced (but not below zero) by the payments made with respect to a student under subparagraph (A) for expenses which would otherwise be taken into account in determining the credit under this section for such year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE4CBE6731154F5A847A5390FEFAD8A3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Program participation</header><text>Participation in the program established under this paragraph shall be voluntary with respect to both students and educational institutions; except that, institutions which are taxable under this chapter (other than by reason of section 511) may not participate in such program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3317A477E3FA455AA956F7BB119BDA67"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Program period</header><text>The program established under this paragraph shall apply to expenses for academic periods beginning during the 5-year period which begins on the date which is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA946E8A6494E435FA38636813AF3349A"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Payments not treated as resources for financial aid</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Payments made under this paragraph shall not be treated as resources for purposes of determining the amount of any financial aid which is funded in whole or part with Federal funds. Payments under the program shall not be made in a manner that would reduce the State, private, or institutional aid available to an eligible student.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF9C76617711645F9955EBE1253AFFFCE"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Notice of program</header><text>Educational institutions participating in the program established under this paragraph shall provide appropriate notices to parents and students of the option of payments under such program. Such notices shall not be considered tax advice for purposes of any Federal law or regulation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H507E8330DE214FCEBFAC07675AFDA1A5"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of Education shall jointly submit annual reports to Congress on the program established under this subsection, together with any recommendations with respect to such program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HDEC501504B5F4886A8D76742E5F2EBEB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 6211(b)(4)(A) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>or (j)(6)</quote> after <quote>subsection (i)(6)</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H28481CD831164D6FAD9EDFA25E35A1D8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Increased public awareness of American Opportunity Tax Credit</header> <paragraph id="H7E754C7970B7463381E5184AFEB6DEE4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury, or the Secretary’s delegate, in consultation with the Secretary of Education, shall establish a taxpayer awareness program to inform the taxpaying public of the availability of the American Opportunity Tax Credit allowed under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/25A">section 25A</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986. Such public awareness program shall be designed to assure that individuals who may be eligible are informed of the availability of such credit and filing procedures.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H0665509E57BC4417AFE62704953CA92E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Means of communications</header>
 <subparagraph id="H219CA1E9D10D4BC08C2F26CB94BACF3C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury, or the Secretary’s delegate, in consultation with the Secretary of Education, shall use appropriate means of communication to carry out the provisions of this section. The taxpayer awareness program shall include, but not be limited to, prominent display of information about the availability of the American Opportunity Tax Credit on information return forms specified by such Secretary for use by educational institutions to report qualified tuition and related expenses incurred.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H158AC34282AD47EC9E25B8A09F5359B5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional steps</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition, the Secretary of the Treasury, or the Secretary’s delegate, in consultation with the Secretary of Education, should—</text>
 <clause id="H6216175AA6AD4E12AFF3F85D4DE4C07B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>make students aware of the American Opportunity Tax Credit through the data retrieval tool and the student aid report of the Department of Education;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H74528A40FE9942E2A4735D46E7532DDC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>include information on the financial aid shopping sheet;</text> </clause><clause id="H5410F74607E64E44838DF4CBEF54B9AD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include the American Opportunity Tax Credit in the volunteer income tax assistance program; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H17758DF3669B46B0B1F5050F7AFE1AF3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">bring awareness of the American Opportunity Tax Credit in the Federal TRIO Programs (commonly known as “TRIO”) under chapter 1 of subpart 2 of part A of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a-11">20 U.S.C. 1070a–11</external-xref> et seq.) and in the Gaining Early Awareness and Readiness for Undergraduate Programs (commonly known as “GEAR UP”) under chapter 2 of subpart 2 of part A of title IV of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a-21">20 U.S.C. 1070a–21</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H7053BDF2AFA74AEA9BE3549143ACA62F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2016.</text> </subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

