<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H6F78713084DB4DAEB44F724FCDF4F94F" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2491 IH: Global Respect Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2491</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170517">May 17, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Brendan F. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000620">Mr. Delaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000293">Ms. Esty of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000535">Mr. Gutiérrez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000602">Miss Rice of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000380">Mr. Kildee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000480">Mrs. Lowey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001185">Mr. Sean Patrick Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000608">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001170">Ms. Shea-Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001191">Ms. Sinema</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001165">Mr. Sires</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000465">Ms. Tsongas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000799">Mr. Walz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="Y000062">Mr. Yarmuth</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To impose sanctions with respect to foreign persons responsible for gross violations of
			 internationally recognized human rights against lesbian, gay, bisexual,
			 and transgender (LGBT) individuals, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H159EC51ED7574BF79E8FE70CF8B5FCC8" style="OLC">
 <section id="HB03CD9F1B48B4FAAB86D289EF3356285" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Global Respect Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H226C19382F0E4421B194989435322C82"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H29371B670F694D459A9902DA6AB6EC29"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The dignity, freedom, and equality of all human beings are fundamental to a thriving global community.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H87BCDC26EA714CB7BB5D6F05D683855C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The rights to life, liberty, and security of the person, the right to privacy, and the right to freedom of expression and association are fundamental human rights.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6452014084FB4A6E9817EE54DD63CB4D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An alarming trend of violence directed at LGBT individuals around the world continues.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H31A67413085E4371810E1E4898809E13"><enum>(4)</enum><text>More than one-third of all countries have laws criminalizing consensual same-sex relations, and countries such as Nigeria, Russia, Uganda, and Kyrgyzstan have recently considered or passed legislation that would further target LGBT individuals.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0E0B16FA8EB04774928CEF42DC01A572"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Every year thousands of individuals around the world are targeted for harassment, attack, arrest, and murder on the basis of their sexual orientation or gender identity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2BD7AB7E5C7748668C81E969CF28D9BB"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Those who commit crimes against LGBT individuals often do so with impunity, and are not held accountable for their crimes.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF4E014741D534C90A7840B95CC03019B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Homophobic and transphobic statements by government officials in many countries in every region of the world promote negative public attitudes and can lead to violence toward LGBT individuals.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4EDD5E9FC94E416C8F3830EDB7A91B9E"><enum>(8)</enum><text>In many instances police, prison, military, and civilian government authorities have been directly complicit in abuses aimed at LGBT citizens, including arbitrary arrest, torture, and sexual abuse.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC511ACEAFC754A82BF2A3277A08CD741"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Celebrations of LGBT individuals and communities, such as film festivals, Pride events, and demonstrations are often forced underground due to inaction on the part of, or harassment by, local law enforcement and government officials, in violation of freedoms of assembly and expression.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H07D19C8499284FC794072F5696AAF9B8"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Laws criminalizing consensual same-sex relations severely hinder access to HIV/AIDS treatment, information, and preventive measures for LGBT individuals and families.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H44D7076A8176418BB46F76A6080B68A7"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Many countries are making positive developments in the protection of the basic human rights of LGBT individuals.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H51C441B418604D07A180C467AF98EC0D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HB21569FA705843BCA620ED853D05995E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H29EAD444B57940A8802F19A1E9F03BB8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Homeland Security, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D0BFD965051405F9DCDDAF0C4217B76"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H02A93A25DA0F43D5A47B7A77B8AF2F8C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <quote>foreign person</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 595.304 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7C5EC302B8B847F091E1B28AEAA7CC85"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Gross violations of internationally recognized human rights</header><text>The term <quote>gross violations of internationally recognized human rights</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 502B(d)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2304">22 U.S.C. 2304(d)(1)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H704DE6535BA147E183442788E52683A5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Person</header><text>The term <quote>person</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 591.308 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H721DA0DCE26947BB84E119D482BE424B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>United states person</header><text>The term <quote>United States person</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 595.315 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act).</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H66672DE84E22437AB6933B7FED7020C2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Identification of foreign persons responsible for gross violations of human rights</header>
 <subsection id="HCFB63B52418A49F9A504BDA02956481A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and biannually thereafter, the President shall transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a list of each foreign person that the President determines, based on credible information—</text>
 <paragraph id="H978DB44C49324CE5993113EEEB658B75"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is responsible for or complicit in torture or cruel, inhuman, or degrading treatment or punishment, prolonged detention without charges and trial, causing the disappearance of persons by the abduction and clandestine detention of those persons, and other flagrant denial of the right to life, liberty, or the security of person based on actual or perceived sexual orientation or gender identity;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5E83FC758FC84BF799EDA4A1AF4BA2DB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>acted as an agent of or on behalf of a foreign person in a matter relating to an activity described in paragraph (1); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H71E7FE7D111B41048C98B954F82AE654"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is responsible for or complicit in inciting a foreign person to engage in an activity described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBC30D9162CF84F96803AA67EC2C9EAB1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>The President shall transmit to the appropriate congressional committees an update of the list required by subsection (a) as new information becomes available.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2CA813BA5ADC461F9E1085CBA3D39B7F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Guidance relating to submission of certain information</header><text>The Secretary of State shall issue public guidance, including through United States diplomatic and consular posts, relating to how names of foreign persons who may be included on the list required by subsection (a) may be submitted to the Department of State.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HE0FD9C0D17884DC28F28E0B7F787A24F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Form</header>
 <paragraph id="H3A0AF7D145AC470CA84740E4B11A0B40"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The list required by subsection (a) shall be transmitted in unclassified form.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3C0339D8D26540B4A181A0C4717AEEAB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The name of a foreign person to be included in the list required by subsection (a) may be transmitted in a classified annex only if the President—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFE523E200E04482F9DD732A3234E4542"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determines that it is vital for the national security interests of the United States to do so;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H44244B2FE51241B698DA6C05B08899BD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>uses the annex in a manner consistent with congressional intent and the purposes of this Act; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F4FF09CBCE044CD8B72CC4DFBE5E572"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not later than 15 days before transmitting the name in a classified annex, provides to the appropriate congressional committees notice of, and a justification for, including or continuing to include each foreign person in the classified annex despite any publicly available credible information indicating that the foreign person engaged in an activity described in paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (a).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H33AEFCDEBB4F4532AC2851D40AA209DF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consideration of certain information</header><text>In preparing the list required by subsection (a), the President shall consider—</text> <subparagraph id="H89A9E32FE3514AC293126502E9A59B6C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>information provided by the Chairperson or Ranking Member of each of the appropriate congressional committees; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C7E67D033454BE786FA1B837C3C31E2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>credible information obtained by other countries and nongovernmental organizations that monitor violations of human rights.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3063E3E2D3C747EEAB9402C8109947DC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The unclassified portion of the list required by subsection (a) shall be made available to the public and published in the Federal Register.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF343E9657C0947D09B4743EB250C4694"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Removal from list</header><text>A foreign person may be removed from the list required by subsection (a) if the President determines and reports to the appropriate congressional committees not later than 15 days before the removal of the foreign person from the list that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HEEA6B77E577647A39BD3E3ECD34936DA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>credible information exists that the foreign person did not engage in the activity for which the foreign person was added to the list;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H554FAB55D3554B7B846ACA8A27622575"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the foreign person has been prosecuted appropriately for the activity in which the foreign person engaged; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H172628CCADDD47E8BCEF6E5EB447C2A2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the foreign person has credibly demonstrated a significant change in behavior, has paid an appropriate consequence for the activities in which the foreign person engaged, and has credibly committed to not engage in an activity described in paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (a).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7137500FE95D4E5989C854AA89AEF43B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Requests by Chairperson or Ranking Member of appropriate congressional committees</header>
 <paragraph id="HB1B2380D932D4BADB42B816D72BDC55E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after receiving a written request from the Chairperson or Ranking Member of one of the appropriate congressional committees with respect to whether a foreign person meets the criteria for being added to the list required by subsection (a), the President shall transmit a response to that Chairperson or Ranking Member, as the case may be, with respect to the status of the foreign person at issue.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H901270B003724F22B188F7FC171192F6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The President may transmit a response required by paragraph (1) in classified form if the President determines that it is necessary for the national security interests of the United States to do so.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H268AE6CBB68A4971BD55F03585BCFB76"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Removal</header>
 <subparagraph id="HADB279BAF9AC4D4091D4525F2A3BE3C5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the President removes from the list required by subsection (a) a foreign person that has been placed on the list, the President shall provide the Chairpersons and Ranking Members of the appropriate congressional committees with any information that contributed to such removal decision.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE328EAFA10F3453DBEAD706F13F5F6E1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Form of information</header><text>The President may transmit the information requested by subparagraph (A) in classified form if the President determines that it is necessary to the national security interests of the United States to do so.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H57C5F035960F45E0A870AFBEE323C35A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Nonapplicability of confidentiality requirement with respect to visa records</header><text>The President shall publish the list required by subsection (a) without regard to the requirements of section 222(f) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1202">8 U.S.C. 1202(f)</external-xref>) with respect to confidentiality of records pertaining to the issuance or refusal of visas or permits to enter the United States.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HE0D0C7554B8D47529407295751D25476"><enum>5.</enum><header>Inadmissibility of certain individuals</header>
 <subsection id="H4ABEF64ED8284B49B013D3197AF7441F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Ineligibility for visas and admission to the United States</header><text>An individual who is a foreign person on the list required by section 4(a) is ineligible to receive a visa to enter the United States and ineligible to be admitted to the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAF4027D3011C44A783C2610A1AB71FE2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Current visas revoked and removal from United States</header><text>The Secretary of State shall revoke, in accordance with section 221(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1201">8 U.S.C. 1201(i)</external-xref>), the visa or other documentation of an individual who would be ineligible to receive such a visa or documentation under subsection (a), and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall remove from the United States such an individual.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HC5F32889788A4CD6B520AE33254E4235"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver for national security interests</header>
 <paragraph id="H215FE155361D4C699CD9E719C7D5AC39"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State and the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the President, may waive the application of subsection (a) or (b), as the case may be, in the case of an individual if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H64B98A5DB5C64522863AF28AFB1917AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretaries determine that such a waiver—</text> <clause id="H920FFE26D87349888238D243FC2848CE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement between the United Nations and the United States of America regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, or other applicable international obligations of the United States; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBB7D2A4143CC49D99F11D6040822DFF6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is in the national security interests of the United States; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7DDA03D1383146A98622845F28646131"><enum>(B)</enum><text>before granting the waiver, the Secretaries provide to the appropriate congressional committees notice of, and a justification for, the waiver.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H459B74AFBE8F4CB1B77AAF1E14A9C252"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timing for notice of certain waivers</header><text>In the case of a waiver under clause (ii), the Secretaries shall submit the notice required by subparagraph (B) of such paragraph not later than 15 days before granting the waiver.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFDCD4984C36B44B2A1E4238C64B79E9B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulatory authority</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall prescribe such regulations as are necessary to carry out this section.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H23ED068AE7A745B38776D864F9BFE0A5"><enum>6.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter, the President, acting through the Secretary of State, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9227F55C6A6F4DEA9DC189417A14DC49"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the actions taken to carry out this Act, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HEF4423FC75F441C8A2D7EFFC37042384"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of foreign persons added to or removed from the list required by section 4(a) during the year preceding each report, the dates on which those persons were added or removed, and the reasons for adding or removing those persons; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28A6CA60D515401281EA1F34DE4926AC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an analysis that compares increases or decreases in the number of such persons year-over-year and the reasons therefor; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF88853906FA54509BD17B5DDE214FB19"><enum>(2)</enum><text>efforts by the executive branch to coordinate with the governments of other countries to, as appropriate, impose sanctions that are similar to the sanctions imposed under this Act.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H3C0B80100C704AF89CCD89C1699351EE"><enum>7.</enum><header>Discrimination related to sexual orientation or gender identity</header>
 <subsection id="H00AC01E1E76949F6913B0356B2B7821D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Tracking violence or criminalization related to sexual orientation or gender identity</header><text>The Assistant Secretary of State for Democracy, Human Rights and Labor shall designate a Bureau-based senior officer or officers who shall be responsible for tracking violence, criminalization, and restrictions on the enjoyment of fundamental freedoms, in foreign countries based on actual or perceived sexual orientation or gender identity.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3DAD27A697E1491290EE053462F7EB77"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual country reports on human rights practices</header><text>The Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HC4A6C0A0D3644CF9AAB52931988F6714"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 116(d) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151n">22 U.S.C. 2151n(d)</external-xref>)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC0B3648219C34147B69AADF87A94B99D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (11)(C), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70FA8046474E486AB5AC09E4FBC214E2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (12)—</text>
 <clause id="H2B51EC0A0C4C4A81831CEFEC365FC54A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end; and</text> </clause><clause id="H954365EA5B1441AEBAA11227B527F8FF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)(ii), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0DFC509024634F4692EAA7E0F3FA3AF5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block id="H85272BDDB66B4E28A653403A57302FB7" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HDAF47168D3A5466C82001884AECB0064"><enum>(13)</enum><text>wherever applicable, violence or discrimination that affects the fundamental freedoms, including widespread or systematic violation of the freedoms of expression, association, or assembly of an individual in foreign countries that is based on actual or perceived sexual orientation or gender identity.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H05B6E29EDBE34406B968E261AA6989DC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 502B(b) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2304">22 U.S.C. 2304(b)</external-xref>), by inserting after the ninth sentence the following new sentence: <quote>Wherever applicable, such report shall also include information regarding violence or discrimination that affects the fundamental freedoms, including widespread or systematic violation of the freedoms of expression, association, or assembly of an individual in foreign countries that is based on actual or perceived sexual orientation or gender identity.</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


