<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H27D860E496154D1EB3F95633D65DA799" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3097 IH: Holding SSA Employees Accountable Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3097</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170628">June 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000597">Mr. Rice of South Carolina</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000586">Mr. Renacci</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title II of the Social Security Act to prohibit credit for service for purposes of a Federal annuity to employees of the Social Security Administration for certain violations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0F5DD4FF6458433797A4A1816E2E755C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1E1F087E48D64B67A24BB47DF1C189A9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Holding SSA Employees Accountable Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H77949DD092EF47118FE4710AB31756D9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Loss of credit for Federal pension after certain violations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 208 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/408">42 U.S.C. 408</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC9183321FD21474387567900F03541B3" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HCA678B48131E46A39348AD8769E77460"><enum>(f)</enum> 
<paragraph id="H9F9DEEC590694544A4DE71797C4BA65F" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, an individual convicted of an offense under subsection (a) may not receive credit under section 8332 or section 8411 (as the case may be) of title 5, United States Code, for any service that occurs on or after the date on which the offense for which the individual was convicted occurs, if, with respect to such conviction, every act or omission of the individual that is needed to satisfy the elements of the offense—</text> <subparagraph id="HCA5A59E3C1AB4274AC2842DBFD714E79" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is committed while the individual is an employee of the Social Security Administration; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5CA3E9F10C1842D3BA79FC476F759CD5" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>directly relates to the performance of the individual's official duties.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H280D21E11D514AACA991E8C1E6105E4E" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual convicted of an offense described in paragraph (1)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1621F4A6CF9B4E1BA2C24FC1785AAD36"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall not, after the date of the conviction, be further eligible to participate in the retirement system under chapter 83 or 84 of title 5, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3E2A3C7937864CCB8DAAC849EB0CED81"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be entitled to be paid any amounts contributed by the individual towards an annuity that were contributed on or after the date on which the offense for which the individual was convicted under this section occurs pursuant to, or in a similar manner as, the terms of section 8316 of such title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H38E1AD43EAE4460FBD7D7ED9A1C8D19A" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Director of the Office of Personnel Management, in consultation with the Commissioner of Social Security, shall prescribe any regulations necessary to carry out this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8885ECA9EBEC47F09CCB3E0CCA7FAE1A" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This subsection shall apply with respect to any offense that occurs on or after the date of enactment of this subsection.</text></paragraph> </subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>


