<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE9608CDFFA6F45D7910D6D7DBE6B4AA2" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3388 IH: Designating Each Car’s Automation Level Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3388</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170725">July 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000566">Mr. Latta</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for information on highly automated driving systems to be made available to prospective
			 buyers.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HB5EF63209DC94238B73FB88C4B53AFA1" style="OLC">
 <section id="H10494EAFC12C4790AFEBB7C85D2AF48E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Designating Each Car’s Automation Level Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>DECAL Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H28B33A16BAA946538CBC823F76E1D841"><enum>2.</enum><header>Information on highly automated driving systems made available to prospective buyers</header> <subsection id="H6675735533744A8F9037A05D0B80AA23"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Research</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall complete research to determine the most effective method and terminology for informing consumers for each highly automated vehicle or a vehicle that performs partial driving automation about the capabilities and limitations of that vehicle. The Secretary shall determine whether such information is based upon or includes the terminology as defined by SAE International in Recommended Practice Report J3016 (published September 2016) or whether such description should include alternative terminology.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H984A7C8D32B24749A50DC5793470A3D3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After the completion of the study required under subsection (a), the Secretary shall initiate a rulemaking proceeding to require manufacturers to inform consumers of the capabilities and limitations of a vehicle’s driving automation system or feature for any highly automated vehicle or any vehicle that performs partial driving automation.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HD7C686F39FC049DD8662B72A77CF2D2D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header>
 <paragraph id="HA6341044B9CF4ECDB187D1727DD2838F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section—</text> <subparagraph id="H1B3014A372764852A99F879D54D14D99"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>automated driving system</quote> means the hardware and software that are collectively capable of performing the entire dynamic driving task on a sustained basis, regardless of whether such system is limited to a specific operational design domain;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D304FEFDE0E4B36845FA770C8810EBC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>dynamic driving task</quote> means all of the real time operational and tactical functions required to operate a vehicle in on-road traffic, excluding the strategic functions such as trip scheduling and selection of destinations and waypoints, and including—</text>
 <clause id="HF64F4D9187E84EAABDEA7791F09C5B38"><enum>(i)</enum><text>lateral vehicle motion control via steering;</text> </clause><clause id="H750421B0F46E4579BFB011B3AA3E5F54"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>longitudinal vehicle motion control via acceleration and deceleration;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4062DDFED72046D18D5F82489F5EBFCF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>monitoring the driving environment via object and event detection, recognition, classification, and response preparation;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6083CF3879884C7E84D5EE23C0257D78"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>object and event response execution;</text> </clause><clause id="H66F333FEFEF8415291147107D8BA1343"><enum>(v)</enum><text>maneuver planning; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD29C1AF0A89F49C99C71432CC3832F25"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>enhancing conspicuity via lighting, signaling, and gesturing;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78E7383500994B969253A6310908961C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the term <quote>highly automated vehicle</quote>—</text>
 <clause id="H6396A4C2CEFA44068276E9281CF707D4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>means a motor vehicle equipped with an automated driving system; and</text> </clause><clause id="HB1D6C648B8BF4F57BD3E4D6FDA188CFA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include a commercial motor vehicle (as defined in section 31101 of title 49, United States Code);</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4228FF2F7944364B54127BFBEEEB94A"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>vehicle that performs partial driving automation</quote> does not include a commercial motor vehicle (as defined in section 31101 of title 49, United States Code); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H54EAD5878F8549F1B44B129B399A53A2"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>operational design domain</quote> means the specific conditions under which a given driving automation system or feature thereof is designed to function.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D794784C9D44F418BCFD8D72960854B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Revisions to certain definitions</header>
 <subparagraph id="HE7637DF8CE434AE79F3D7115C52DC887"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If SAE International (or its successor organization) revises the definition of any of the terms defined in subparagraph (A), (B), or (E) of paragraph (1) in Recommended Practice Report J3016, it shall notify the Secretary of the revision. The Secretary shall publish a notice in the Federal Register to inform the public of the new definition unless, within 90 days after receiving notice of the new definition and after opening a period for public comment on the new definition, the Secretary notifies SAE International (or its successor organization) that the Secretary has determined that the new definition does not meet the need for motor vehicle safety, or is otherwise inconsistent with the purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/301">chapter 301</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code. If the Secretary so notifies SAE International (or its successor organization), the existing definition in paragraph (1) shall remain in effect.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4B144A78A354D52941FEF1E0DB03B39"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary does not reject a <italic></italic>definition revised by SAE International (or its successor organization) as described in subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall promptly make any conforming amendments to the regulations and standards of the Secretary that are necessary. The revised definition shall apply for purposes of this section. The requirements of section 553 of title 5, United States Code, shall not apply to the making of any such conforming amendments.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF47D2DC2AB1348F3B436B0915F5CDD27"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pursuant to section 553 of title 5, United States Code, the Secretary may update any of the definitions in subparagraph (A), (B), or (E) of paragraph (1) if <italic></italic>the Secretary determines that materially changed circumstances regarding highly automated vehicles have impacted motor vehicle safety such that the definitions need to be updated to reflect such circumstances.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


