<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H46167737226C4D12B598389B6B42868B" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2003 IH: Pre-K for USA Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2003</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170406">April 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Every Student Succeeds Act to provide grants for high-quality, local prekindergarten
			 programs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H285B700C9D6B4122B9CE4C66B4EA2C93" style="OLC">
 <section id="H88F84D2449674223860951493BC0536D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pre-K for USA Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HB876509CA89E4AF78A454A653C263D9C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Local prekindergarten development grants</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title IX of the Every Student Succeeds Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/95">Public Law 114–95</external-xref>; 129 Stat. 2124) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H345FC763A6B14B9E85E600D53CFB7B3D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 9212, in the section heading by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Preschool</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">State preschool</header-in-text></quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBCB074BB57ED46F0B4473706DD1DFFBF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after section 9212 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1AA6B678491247939FBA1C16B07BA380" style="OLC">
					<section id="H967A7F449AFB41999437EB74B6F7E857"><enum>9212A.</enum><header>Local prekindergarten development grants</header>
						<subsection id="H9942593074EE4B8394A71AD036881CBD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prekindergarten development grants</header>
 <paragraph id="HC382B8C717CE47B2B133DFDF14ACB776"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, jointly with the Secretary of Education (referred to in this section jointly as the <quote>Secretaries</quote>), shall award competitive grants to eligible local entities to assist such entities in establishing high-quality prekindergarten programs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2259F561BEB0437A973CCED2D3509A37"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grant duration</header><text>The Secretaries shall award grants under this section for a period of not more than 3 years. Such grants shall not be renewed.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE35F3C2FB3B14E9787D285C4FD7B2DC1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be considered for a grant under this section, an eligible local entity shall submit an application to the Secretaries at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Secretaries may reasonably require.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H21E671A6CE994A92A307638C013BAC6C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Matching requirement</header>
 <subparagraph id="H90CCBD8129F242EA972D8AC4357ACDC7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section an eligible local entity shall contribute, for the activities for which the grant was awarded, non-Federal matching funds in an amount equal to not less than 20 percent of the amount of the grant.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42B4FE2F4450496DBDB15942EEACFF90"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Non-Federal funds</header><text>To satisfy the requirement of subparagraph (A) an eligible local entity may use—</text> <clause id="HE4D80B84D4F940C491013EBE1E91FC57"><enum>(i)</enum><text>non-Federal resources in the form of State funding, local funding, or contributions from philanthropy or other private sources, or a combination of such resources; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H201683CCBFBA44A183F7A12ED9BCEEB8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in-kind contributions.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H057E983E34244925BE5F8DF89C9477B4"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Financial hardship waiver</header><text>The Secretaries may waive the requirement of subparagraph (A) or reduce the amount of matching funds required under such subparagraph for an eligible local entity that has submitted an application for a grant under this section if the entity demonstrates, in the application, a need for such a waiver or reduction due to extreme financial hardship, as determined by the Secretaries.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2F34616CCB2446D3A5A0446656E0DDEB"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Double-Dipping prevention</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretaries may not award a grant under this section to an eligible local entity for a fiscal year if the State in which the entity is located has applied for, or has been awarded, a grant under section 9212 for such fiscal year.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCD72F751B1974BBAAA46F93FD16BB4E9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H5312AEE09AF04D47BCAA0A01B8E651B5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Early childhood education program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>early childhood education program</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 103 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1003">20 U.S.C. 1003</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC8E522A3E78F47758F906733A6136CD4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible local entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible local entity</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H49C1BBEF8A3B4B5DB271350523BEDF1A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a local educational agency, including a charter school or a charter management organization that acts as a local educational agency, or an educational service agency in partnership with a local educational agency;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC257CD3FAFA47F78A2FAB7C4B85DA5F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity (including a Head Start program or licensed child care setting) that carries out, administers, or supports an early childhood education program; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3EE2567E49C24A8A881962154550ECF6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a consortium of entities described in subparagraph (A) or (B).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD79A4585F52448EB80C960A18260C821"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Full-day</header><text>The term <term>full-day</term> means a day that is—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HED0B929C858148CEB475D4AC966DA8CE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>equivalent to a full school day at the public elementary schools in the State; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66D90A5DBE224F59A7EB14E7E1C1BD2C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not less than 5 hours.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C51BACD351E479AA425330516575993"><enum>(4)</enum><header>High-quality prekindergarten program</header><text>The term <term>high-quality prekindergarten program</term> means a prekindergarten program supported by an eligible local entity that includes, at a minimum, the following elements based on nationally recognized standards:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6474FE796EC945C0AAA06E7A7F9F925E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Serves children who—</text> <clause id="H654DA324FAE049B6912973BF3A0AFB5A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are age 4 or children who are age 3 or 4, by the eligibility determination date (including children who turn age 5 while attending the program); or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB77074279D9C4D5B83872136EC79994A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>have attained the legal age for State-funded prekindergarten.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2808C0EE97D54B7F930934294BD54758"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Requires high staff qualifications, including that teachers meet the requirements of one of the following clauses:</text>
 <clause id="H2C2569D13BB84107A374551C15B7F56B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The teacher has a bachelor’s degree in early childhood education or a related field with coursework that demonstrates competence in early childhood education.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H87AAA4D33E464D8096D4B20880860A9B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The teacher—</text> <subclause id="HC879006B54064C18A4565929F1187504"><enum>(I)</enum><text>has a bachelor’s degree in any field;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H37B10C2B757F42CEB935C94C5922C1D7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>has demonstrated knowledge of early childhood education through passage of a State-approved assessment in early childhood education;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB676B5BA8774443CAC9DC9FAA2745FA4"><enum>(III)</enum><text>engages in ongoing professional development in early childhood education for not less than 2 years; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H424AC68F30CB471C92741F21A2CA8A5C"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>is enrolled in a State-approved educator preparation program in which the teacher receives ongoing training and support in early childhood education and is making progress toward the completion of the program in not more than 3 years.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H3F07F73B74F344BB87B1E4EB46DC2AB5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The teacher has a bachelor’s degree in any field with a credential, license, or endorsement that demonstrates competence in early childhood education.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD1E2B03030E43FFB63684FC55742864"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Maintains a maximum class size of 20 children.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H654DF70B982E486CBB91E0B4A0FC368B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Maintains a child to instructional staff ratio that does not exceed 10 to 1.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF3A2D7B7F074676B538D999D07D3107"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Offers a full-day program.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B7417F576F546F5A3F3FA68FB111856"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Provides developmentally appropriate learning environments and evidence-based curricula that are aligned with the State’s early learning and development standards.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97140A2636C449388D1F080F0568923C"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Offers instructional staff salaries comparable to kindergarten through grade 12 teaching staff.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H385E383B90664E06B187B25B1CCE1075"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Provides for ongoing monitoring and program evaluation to ensure continuous improvement.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09488822A72F4336B891327351306FB3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Offers accessible comprehensive services for children that—</text> <clause id="HF8B0DBDCC5494BE2A9F0783F5108AA91"><enum>(i)</enum><text>include, at a minimum—</text>
 <subclause id="H9B53200DF8CF48FBB2BD1F85E7DE557F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>screenings for vision, dental, health (including mental health), and development and referrals, and assistance obtaining services, when appropriate;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H5054588663204A1788BF35B9F296033B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>family engagement opportunities (taking into account home language), such as parent conferences (including parent input about their child’s development) and support services, such as parent education and family literacy services;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA1B7C25791774EF99D1B4973662ED3A2"><enum>(III)</enum><text>nutrition services, including nutritious meals and snack options aligned with requirements set by the most recent Child and Adult Care Food Program guidelines promulgated by the Department of Agriculture as well as regular, age-appropriate, nutrition education for children and their families;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H2EDA25F5D8424751BEEA21C8985285CF"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>programs coordinated with local educational agencies and entities providing programs authorized under section 619 and part C of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1419">20 U.S.C. 1419</external-xref> and 1431 et seq.);</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HEE2DB61DA434427CAF67FA0CDB1B4974"><enum>(V)</enum><text>physical activity programs aligned with evidence-based guidelines, such as those recommended by the Institute of Medicine, and that take into account and accommodate children with disabilities; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H029BD504954E4E2D873EBF1A63ED6A2D"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>additional support services, as appropriate, based on the findings of a needs analysis; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H53F52FADA3B2485A829A358CAC18CCC1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are provided on-site, to the maximum extent feasible.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H52ED664B172846808958EBCBFD5EF676"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Provides high-quality professional development for staff, including regular in-class observation for teachers and teacher assistants by individuals trained in observation and which may include evidence-based coaching.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2AFD08042CCE4434AAC74BD338E0A402"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Meets the education performance standards in effect under section 641A(a)(1)(B) of the Head Start Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9836a">42 U.S.C. 9836a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6401271A10C548078F7F6850142E26AF"><enum>(L)</enum><text>Maintains evidence-based health and safety standards.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF20220BE0AA846628BE31C057A1B9921"><enum>(5)</enum><header>ESEA terms</header><text>The terms <term>local educational agency</term> and <term>State</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H306CD9462DBE490DA872D2CB8B794ED2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section—</text> <paragraph id="HF75F7648DA4B4FDAB90762CFD07B4025"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$250,000,000 for fiscal year 2018; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H61D7F1976EF84BD4992926CF28F05437"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2027.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></section><section id="H8E44D220311A42D7A383ACA2926C7CD1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents in section 2 of the Every Student Succeeds Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/95">Public Law 114–95</external-xref>; 129 Stat. 1802) is amended by striking the item relating to section 9212 and inserting the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE40AFBF6B4D84598AC04C828C639EF53" style="OLC">
				<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
					<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 9212. State preschool development grants.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 9212A. Local prekindergarten development grants.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


