<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H9BD6D2CBDF1E4157ABD68DD27B59EEAF" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3236 IH: Ambulance Medicare Budget and Operations Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3236</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170713">July 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000181">Mr. Nunes</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="U000031">Mr. Upton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend titles XI and XVIII of the Social Security Act to improve provider and supplier cost
			 reporting of ambulance services under the Medicare program, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H0FBBA521E9084A6D9061DB463665F5CF" style="OLC">
 <section id="H2B40C91D92EF4CDEA173059965258EF9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ambulance Medicare Budget and Operations Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H8B93B0198ACE4BE48745A70F7B415C24"><enum>2.</enum><header>Ground ambulance services cost reporting requirement</header> <subsection id="H81C938E84D6145F58A5794D9AEC76685"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1121 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320a">42 U.S.C. 1320a</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H87C7EF260F8A44769A91A1D32A8DAA26"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="H5D77A4D0F16D4D68ACFA63D42A896BB1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>For the purposes of</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to subsection (d), for the purposes of</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53157DEDE0E34A819B5A90331432C8C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>providers and suppliers of ground ambulance services,</quote> after <quote>health maintenance organizations,</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C2815037E8C461FB93AE0445F539A18"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H986FB2682118440FBC4FAED26F5479AF" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HF3088FBD915C4F65A60808E292C7BA47"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a provider or supplier of ground ambulance services that furnishes such services for fewer than 20 individuals entitled to benefits under part A and enrolled under part B in a reporting period (as defined by the Secretary), the Secretary may modify the requirements for inclusion of any information specified in subsection (a) in reports made in accordance with the uniform reporting system established under this section with respect to such services.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA58ED06AE84D4B818CB9C7A253025694"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Hospital provider agreements</header><text>Section 1866(a)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395cc">42 U.S.C. 1395cc(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H726C7795AE024C2D8C01AA11B4A2020C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (X), by striking <quote>Secretary, and</quote> and inserting <quote>Secretary,</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8C0CC1FF0125466DAD72C4322D44118B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (Y)(ii)(V), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>, and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEAAA69CF18534892ACB27DB342C7FA90"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (Y) the following new subparagraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE84F4B1DB7BF49AEA6781371D9E3EEDF" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="HE32454BEBC8C4E44AC9177B47F60A837" indent="up1"><enum>(Z)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a hospital that is a provider of ground ambulance services, with respect to such services furnished for reporting periods (as defined by the Secretary) on or after January 1, 2022, to make reports to the Secretary of information described in section 1121(a) in accordance with the uniform reporting system established under such section for providers and suppliers of ground ambulance services.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF64E6145C63F439185564A479A4E7029"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Skilled nursing facility provider agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1819(d) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395i-3">42 U.S.C. 1395i–3(d)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H99A1D8A3697E433A80258C7E71F4EE41" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H8E5AC164F8B64C18ACD13B1C878F2900"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Ambulance services cost reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A skilled nursing facility that furnishes ground ambulance services, with respect to such services furnished on or after January 1, 2022, shall make reports to the Secretary of information described in section 1121(a) in accordance with the uniform reporting system established under such section for providers and suppliers of ground ambulance services.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9565E7EF77D64BD7B2137EF65D8553E4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Home health agency provider agreements</header><text>Section 1891(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395bbb">42 U.S.C. 1395bbb(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8C36DF104A694954833C708E1E9A19E4" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HB8E5CC52ED634CCE9C7DB5D7E12B9771"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an agency that furnishes ground ambulance services, with respect to such services furnished on or after January 1, 2022, the agency makes reports to the Secretary of information described in section 1121(a) in accordance with the uniform reporting system established under such section for providers and suppliers of ground ambulance services.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8FA41F4107D041B59DAB11DBAB81DF36"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Suspension of payment for ground ambulance services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1834(l) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(l)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAACAF088F3AA4E74BB5AE0C18316F78A" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="H2901F7173AAC4C9498884A4DCF4E89B6"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Authority to suspend payments for ground ambulance services</header>
 <subparagraph id="HB860738CF085466FAD20E242189081D9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subparagraphs (C) and (D), in the case that the Secretary determines that a supplier of ground ambulance services has not made to the Secretary complete, accurate, and timely reports of such services for reporting periods (as defined by the Secretary) with respect to a year beginning with 2020 of information described in section 1121(a) in accordance with the uniform reporting system established under such section for providers and suppliers of ground ambulance services and, as determined appropriate by the Secretary, of any of the information described in subparagraph (B), the Secretary may suspend payments made under this subsection, in whole or in part, to such supplier until the Secretary determines that such supplier has submitted such reports with respect to such reporting period.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2AED329B72B7440E8B56951D0E9B87E2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may, with respect to a supplier of ground ambulance services, require the following information (to be reported to the extent practicable under the uniform reporting system established under section 1121(a)):</text>
 <clause id="HEE4466E4DDC4417CB4B6C598D3512E83"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Whether the supplier is part of an emergency services department, a governmental organization, or another type of entity (as described by the Secretary).</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE795073786E2487296B0AC99C9F5D296"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The number of hours in a week during which the supplier is available for furnishing ground ambulance services.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4B1A663B00534520BE00F912E8E7C12E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Any State regulations regarding requirements relating to the stocking of ambulances with certain equipment or drugs.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3ED3ADC17A904A49A8DF494E44BC5D89"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The average number of volunteer hours a week used by the supplier.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBFB7002309664C809CE5BD967C89CC03"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Hardship delay</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a process whereby a supplier of ground ambulance services may request a delay in reporting information described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) with respect to a reporting period for reason of significant hardship (as determined by the Secretary).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28314DFEBD754EC0B3459C2FD3CBA41C"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Authority to modify cost reporting elements and enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not earlier than January 1, 2023, the Secretary may, after taking into account the recommendation of the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission in the most recent report available to the Secretary submitted under section 3 of the Ambulance Medicare Budget and Operations Act of 2017 regarding whether cost reporting of ground ambulance services by a supplier or category of suppliers (as specified for purposes of the report submitted under such section) should be required or modified, and through notice and comment rulemaking, provide that subparagraph (A) no longer applies to ground ambulance services suppliers or such a category of such suppliers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="HFEA1B76382EE48DA9942D4D8320080FB"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Stakeholder feedback</header>
 <paragraph id="H93E81E779A7B4988A1F8BEA80306296E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall implement the provisions of this section, including the amendments made by this section, through notice and comment rulemaking and seek input from stakeholders.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2236CC44E7A04747BAFC0728A46DE934"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nonapplication of Paperwork Reduction Act</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">Chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code, shall not apply with respect to notice and comment rulemaking carried out under paragraph (1).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H5C2C9E6FAE7D48C7B3B105A01B871849"><enum>3.</enum><header>Ground ambulance services cost reporting study</header>
 <subsection id="H598510C254DF43389F47911F1017D075"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than March 15, 2022, and as determined necessary by the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission thereafter, such Commission shall assess and submit to Congress a report on ambulance services cost reporting carried out in accordance with sections 1121(a) and 1834(l) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320a">42 U.S.C. 1320a(a)</external-xref>, 1395m(l)) and the adequacy of payments for such services made under section 1834(l) of such Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD4D7AAF6ADEF4A589FEBB07A2E8AACE9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report described in subsection (a) shall contain the following:</text> <paragraph id="HF437868FB2D541088CEF3717C5F7B2AF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An analysis of the accuracy of cost report data submitted in accordance with such sections.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H59012946A2C84D399456D35B74964E9E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An analysis of any burden on providers and suppliers of such services associated with reporting such data.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H67019853794B4ACD975E7A8A040ED2FC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A recommendation on whether or not cost reporting of ambulance services by providers, suppliers, or a category of suppliers (as specified by the Secretary) of such services should be required or modified, taking into account the analyses described in paragraphs (1) and (2).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H97B183AD18A1435DAD7F3FD41F3E5783"><enum>4.</enum><header>Extension of ground ambulance services extenders</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1834(l) of the Social Security Act (42. U.S.C. 1395m(l)) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HDDCCD1A3C7B741B1ABF5179EF2E41DCB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (12)(A), by striking <quote>2018</quote> and inserting <quote>2023</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0C3357B25F334E4AA7AE41BA13EEBD6A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (13)(A), by striking <quote>2018</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>2023</quote>.</text> </paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

