<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF5B6A0944F274E14A144335F95140A96" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2281 IH: Border Enforcement Security Task Force Reauthorization Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2281</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170502">May 2, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000132">Mr. Vela</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000588">Mr. Richmond</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001197">Ms. McSally</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barrag&#225;n</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to reauthorize the Border Enforcement Security Task Force program within the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H49C6EB9E7D2343F08E3D1F192C5E365C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6B87EBF67BDE45859D4CF80085D5BDF0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Border Enforcement Security Task Force Reauthorization Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB6C320F039B84784828E98BD1A20199E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Modified instructions</header> <subsection id="HDF7EEEF030B046089297A68D710EADF4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Updated considerations for the establishment of units</header><text>Paragraph (2) of section 432(c) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/240">6 U.S.C. 240(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H274EDCFEAD43438E9FD631F22622C451"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>the Secretary shall consider</quote> and inserting <quote>the Secretary shall apply risk-based criteria that takes into consideration</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H84B921E8CEB446D69AD3D97DD592DEC2" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by inserting before the semicolon the following: <quote>, including threats posed by transnational criminal organizations</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H372DEB42B24748B9924EC9825137986B" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0015B8D448A2454BB6DC304453AB1CCE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE1767EAD2CD341678DF97AF52832C3A2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraphs:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H79619CA186F345E9870B78675F74E2BA" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H118DA685E27748A197E24AFBE6F9DCE3"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the extent to which the BEST unit would advance the Department’s homeland and border security strategic priorities and related objectives; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1474C47CC43B4843B6F75E15D8972E39"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether departmental Joint Task Force operations as established pursuant to section 708 and other joint cross-border initiatives would be enhanced, improved, or otherwise assisted by the BEST unit to be established.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA0AD57E19C5242589E62CE8C766A19FE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Updated report elements</header><text>Subsection (e) of section 432 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/240">6 U.S.C. 240</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HE9B90B276339414EB4A65A3FF363278C" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H13F1D9F2D3854D298F865641A7A708F0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section and annually thereafter for the following five years, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that includes the following:</text> <paragraph id="HC2A6684FC9E445C59A32C2C0D13E2B84" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of the effectiveness of BEST in enhancing border security, disrupting and dismantling transnational criminal organizations, and reducing drug trafficking, arms smuggling, illegal alien trafficking and smuggling, violence, and kidnapping along and across the international borders of the United States, as measured by crime statistics, including violent deaths, incidents of violence, and drug-related arrests.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD344EADF0FED4951AD262D59A5CC82EC" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of how BEST enhances information-sharing, including the dissemination of homeland security information, among Federal, State, local, tribal, and foreign law enforcement agencies.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H58E7FFED81214BC7B76F72BEA7AF5CB6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of how BEST advances the Department’s homeland and border security strategic priorities and effectiveness of BEST in achieving related objectives.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB0190F7BB8704A858BA18FC37BA5079B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An assessment of BEST’s joint operational efforts with departmental Joint Task Force operations established pursuant to section 708 and other joint cross-border initiatives.</text></paragraph> </subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

