<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1BB8823B6FF74DC0A147F767AE89FD42" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><form><distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 871</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170206">February 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001195">Mr. Smith of Missouri</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000487">Mr. Royce of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to exempt premiums paid on non-cash-value property and casualty insurance from the taxes to enforce reporting on certain foreign accounts.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H00CB0C034B994FBE83BF216690713795" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H077FEAB34BB24A2B978CFD8981248B8C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Exemption for premiums paid on non-cash-value property and casualty insurance from taxes to enforce reporting on certain foreign accounts</header> 
<subsection id="H4EF1ED5A705A4C1F982147656D2B8DFC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1473">Section 1473(1)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by redesignating subparagraph (C) as subparagraph (D) and by inserting after subparagraph (B) the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H75E2404B72B94DEBB153684C7C7C15C3" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HC6B5BA0473104DBABB27B7A993A59709"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exception for premiums paid on non-cash-value property and casualty insurance</header> <clause id="HA5F3DFDFACE24F7CB66343FD0980F0E8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Such term shall not include any premium paid for any insurance contract if—</text> 
<subclause id="HC9E18AE2F7C447008A478C1A235D1612"><enum>(I)</enum><text>such insurance contract does not have an aggregate cash value greater than zero, and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HAAD89F1992F54D1FA2D019F1891FBC17"><enum>(II)</enum><text>no portion of the reserves, unearned premiums, or unpaid losses, with respect to such contract are taken into account under paragraph (1) or (2) of section 816(a).</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H3AD91ADFA440413B9545391A25BAFEFC"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Cash value</header><text>The term <quote>cash value</quote> means any amount (determined without reduction for any charge or policy loan) that—</text> <subclause id="H1031BC8B6BAE4BDF84F673EA392CA8EC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is payable under the contract to any person upon surrender, termination, cancellation, or withdrawal, or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H28C78B7CEEB64EFF866B1651AEE4E773"><enum>(II)</enum><text>can be borrowed by any person under, or with regard to, the contract (including by pledging as collateral).</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H80F728BAC99740058C5391E45BDA82B2"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>Notwithstanding clause (ii), the term <quote>cash value</quote> shall not include any amount payable—</text> 
<subclause id="HA0730C51D15741EF9C96384BB1EF9FB0"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">solely by reason of the death of an individual insured under a life insurance contract,</text></subclause> <subclause id="HF906CF6FCC734F4286369667CDD312BD"><enum>(II)</enum><text>as a personal injury or sickness benefit or a benefit providing indemnification of an economic loss incurred upon the occurrence of the event insured against,</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H87CE51BBC0AF4FB2B59339E6C8E0B0B9"><enum>(III)</enum><text>as a refund of a previously paid premium (less cost of insurance charges whether or not actually imposed) under an insurance contract (other than a life insurance contract) due to cancellation or termination of the contract, decrease in risk exposure during the effective period of the contract, or arising from the correction of a posting or similar error with regard to the premium for the contract,</text></subclause> <subclause id="HD1F30816973F49DBBF28E94EF32D1209"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>as a policyholder dividend (other than a termination dividend) provided that the dividend relates to an insurance contract under which the only benefits payable are described in subclause (II), or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H2B3D15F134A24B0D9A9A6F8BF096DFC0"><enum>(V)</enum><text>as a return of an advance premium or premium deposit for an insurance contract for which the premium is payable at least annually if the amount of the advance premium or premium deposit does not exceed the next annual premium that will be payable under the contract.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H5D5602E8906C4B89A06E2181BEB277E2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to payments made after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

