<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H80A81E688F384E27901C15EC88F9F6F4" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1910 IH: Support Our Military Caregivers Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1910</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170405">April 5, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001051">Mr. Carter of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001094">Mr. Cook</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001096">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000464">Mr. Faso</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000168">Mr. Olson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000586">Mr. Renacci</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000487">Mr. Royce of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000806">Mr. Webster of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000066">Mr. Young of Iowa</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="Z000017">Mr. Zeldin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the process for determining the eligibility of
			 caregivers of veterans to certain benefits administered by the Secretary
			 of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H94D30BD45C0F4C4F8C910022A56F8046" style="OLC">
 <section id="H6A0BED225132453685DD844507E8133E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Support Our Military Caregivers Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H6E488BE522504F129256F8813CF81687" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>External clinical review of denied applications by caregivers of veterans</header> <subsection id="HFF3CCE304BE74FF38BE239B7721EED1C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1720G of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8BA39816CC0B463788F3C08D6AFA72BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (d) and (e) as subsections (e) and (f), respectively; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE2162A949B724A8B962D24D71C1320CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (c) the following new subsection (d):</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA9BBA551251648F68428E887ADE2EFE1" style="USC">
						<subsection commented="no" id="H6414BA05DD004339999E07E34AA7C949"><enum>(d)</enum><header>External clinical review of applications</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB6ED225F74D34719B0E0B103A51A93A5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Using amounts otherwise appropriated to carry out this section, an individual may elect to have an independent contractor described in paragraph (2) perform an external clinical review of any of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFBAF4E2F0AE243F09688CFB4F1705875" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The denial by the Secretary of an application by an individual to be a caregiver or family caregiver eligible for the program of comprehensive assistance administered by the Secretary pursuant to this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9C905E4300FE4C20AE88DB14F662196D" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to such an application that the Secretary has granted, a determination by the Secretary of the level or amount of personal care services that a veteran requires.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB95DE94B85DF41B5A587754FA6C8D3F0" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A request by a caregiver or family caregiver for a reconsideration of the level or amount of personal care services that a veteran requires based on changes to the health or abilities of the veteran occurring since the Secretary granted such an application.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA98FF48420C04B31A316B1AF33C95F00" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The revocation by the Secretary of assistance administered by the Secretary pursuant to this section.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H34B5DBEB94F84B67AC29C9EC6906A4BC" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An independent contractor described in this paragraph is an independent contractor that—</text> <subparagraph id="HA286A3B994A44E678134DB92C39CC40D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is awarded a contract by the Secretary to carry out this section pursuant to full and open competition under the Federal Acquisition Regulation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H72F874DD9C9D49F98C6F6D9245A69531"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has no direct or indirect financial relationship with any non-Department provider of services to caregivers and family caregivers pursuant to this title;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2FAA9C096F6A423280B9A471D54E623A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has not otherwise conducted an external clinical review of benefits administered by the Secretary pursuant to this title other than this section;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H12F114E6DA7946F2BB1A6526C9E982FD"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has sufficient training and expertise in medical science and other appropriate health, educational, and vocational training and legal matters to perform the reviews described in paragraph (1); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H212CDE930F8949E9BFFF43C44E1900D4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>employs a panel of physicians or other appropriate health care professionals who do not provide health care to the individual who makes an election under paragraph (1).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFC997C81BA94BF184E2F3A24FD2C496" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Each external clinical review conducted pursuant to paragraph (1) shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H5AEB419AECDD4B72ADFC1FD67D2D68F5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be based on applicable information included in the application for assistance described in such paragraph, including clinical expertise, medical, technical, and scientific evidence;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A004A29BB50431890E1DA51F745C792"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include an opportunity for both the individual who elects for such review and, to the extent possible, the veteran for whom care is being provided to offer opinions and supporting data as to the level of care required; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE140CC431D44355A6E4343CD80FFD20"><enum>(C)</enum><text>include a review of the initial clinical review of such veteran and any other review made by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2751C276DC994A529F12D93A400C40B9" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In carrying out the external clinical reviews pursuant to paragraph (1), the independent contractor shall, as determined appropriate by the Secretary—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H812E29D57299438FA0E3E9A8056135A3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>collect and maintain information required; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8EE6234D781342209DAE11C431DDEA2D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>share such information with the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F79CDE9232842A6AAABDD8558797D94" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall take into account, but is not bound by, any determination made by the independent contractor pursuant to paragraph (1) in determining the final decision with respect to the application for assistance. The Secretary may make a final decision that is contrary to such a determination if the Secretary includes clinically supported documentation with the decision.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H5D57A7E4E95448DEAC32F7204B4078F9" indent="up1"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that each external clinical review conducted by the independent contractor pursuant to paragraph (1) is completed and the Department is notified in writing of the results of the review by not later than 120 days after the date on which the individual makes the election under such paragraph. Not later than 30 days after the delivery of the determination recommended by the independent contractors, the Secretary shall ensure that the veteran and the individual making the election under such paragraph is notified in writing of the final decision of the Secretary. In accordance with paragraph (5), such notification shall include an explanation of the recommended decision, a discussion of the facts and applicable regulations, and an explanation of the clinical rationale for the final decision.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFB46994718444F0890C122873223FA98" indent="up1"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall notify individuals who submit an application to be a caregiver or family caregiver eligible for the program of comprehensive assistance administered by the Secretary pursuant to this section of the ability of the individual to make an election under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6656C3335ED4471D9C77A025D17E7ECF" indent="up1"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection may be construed to affect claims made by veterans for disability compensation under chapter 11 of this title.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H08C8F5DCE0464982BFDDE23D6A4E5001"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to elections under subsection (d) of section 1720G of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a)(2), that are for applications or revocations for assistance for caregivers and family caregivers pursuant to such section for which the Secretary of Veterans Affairs has not made a final decision as of the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H91805CA794194E37AF4B79CC727A2E7B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Process to determine eligibility for caregivers of veterans</header>
 <subsection id="H476EE376E62D496B992161B26EA836C6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Directives</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall issue directives regarding the policies, procedures, and operational requirements for the Family Caregiver Program, including with respect to determining the eligibility of an individual to participate in the Family Caregiver Program.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8E80493A74D64A6BA5920B20B2D0E0B0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>GAO Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report on the processes of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs with respect to—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA32D79D7A7B048BAB165AE86475FFE00"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determining the eligibility of an individual to participate in the Family Caregiver Program;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H522C30D8F3F744A0917644212BBBB75E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>adjudicating appeals to such determinations; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEA7F434ACBFF44739F4A9682C26BDF40"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the periodic eligibility reevaluation of an individual participating in such program and the communication of any changes as a result of such reevaluations to the veteran and caregiver.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7234720D39B740C2A02FEEE144591BF1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Family Caregiver Program defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>Family Caregiver Program</term> either the program of comprehensive assistance for family caregivers or the program of general caregiver support services established by section 1720G of title 38, United States Code.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


