<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H8A5974D9D3D04C778EBB78E866CDA572" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2135 IH: Northern Rockies Ecosystem Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2135</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170425">April 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000465">Ms. Tsongas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001038">Mr. Crowley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To designate certain National Forest System lands and certain public lands under the jurisdiction
			 of the Secretary of the Interior in the States of Idaho, Montana, Oregon,
			 Washington, and Wyoming as wilderness, wild and scenic rivers, wildland
			 recovery areas, and biological connecting corridors, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HEE2C5BC520C648A19D4850EEEE438943" style="OLC">
		<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9BF3AC6D6E9B410984C85D30AF3848BE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="H140E95D1B46A473294F57C75380A2142"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short Title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Northern Rockies Ecosystem Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H254AE91F67B743FA98A92F6CCE0D4EAF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of Contents</header><text>The table of contents of this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
					<toc-entry idref="H9BF3AC6D6E9B410984C85D30AF3848BE" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H4352C2351B124AAE8DF88E6B5764D163" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HE596F11FE1E948D3B616126AB7C3AFD9" level="section">Sec. 3. Purposes.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H680CDECE0E2C4CA4A349151AFAE521D5" level="section">Sec. 4. Definitions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H24444941791D466584DFA8AC79A64144" level="title">Title I—DESIGNATION OF WILDERNESS</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H03B08F70FB1B4400A2356AA500AF5F32" level="section">Sec. 101. Designation of certain National Forest System lands, National Park System lands, and
			 Bureau of Land Management lands as wilderness.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HC7DD35483D9F4502925BE8F8CB2C16C5" level="section">Sec. 102. Greater Glacier/Northern Continental Divide ecosystem.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HD7318AD077A44CC590D8ADBE1DB205B5" level="section">Sec. 103. Greater Yellowstone ecosystem.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H999D6F0628694A309C38BA81D88B8FC1" level="section">Sec. 104. Greater Salmon/Selway ecosystem.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HB458327308084953B36FD45A9EA4E0C8" level="section">Sec. 105. Greater Cabinet/Yaak/Selkirk ecosystem.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HD16D4D76214F492B9B651F0D637D9B59" level="section">Sec. 106. Greater Hells Canyon ecosystem.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H174F0B0BE89D4432B214D4C85FCDF91D" level="section">Sec. 107. Islands in the Sky Wilderness.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H9EB6FF1A03CF4EAB9E1B135E4DFC582D" level="section">Sec. 108. Wilderness in biological connecting corridors.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HBC9E649B03564D90A9DD337777F166A9" level="section">Sec. 109. Administration.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H804AF48DDDED40B8A77296FE5B583D71" level="section">Sec. 110. Water.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H37C0D2B5B17848A885B42CFB253A75B1" level="title">Title II—BIOLOGICAL CONNECTING CORRIDORS</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HD51513420C8B4DB485DBDEBF211A64EE" level="section">Sec. 201. Findings.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H76453BD3B5CA47E6AB1B8EA15E54A5A0" level="section">Sec. 202. Designation of biological connecting corridors.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HEFEDAE100C1E4FC4B84E264B40E61947" level="section">Sec. 203. Treatment of biological connecting corridors.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H730348DEFDCA4FC69F07E7D126B0FB9B" level="section">Sec. 204. Applicability of title.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HE3EE08174BF442F3BF6709921001A3A9" level="section">Sec. 205. Cooperative agreements and land trades and acquisitions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H4CB4F3C98AE5476B8641EF6090D2A6F3" level="section">Sec. 206. Exemption of certain roads and highways.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H7BB8DA0D97044531A200C127071C72E4" level="title">Title III—WILD AND SCENIC RIVERS DESIGNATIONS</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HB318337BE7F841E1867AE9F881BECC9D" level="section">Sec. 301. Designation of wild and scenic rivers in Idaho, Montana, and Wyoming.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H91DE823B09844A2FB6EDB741E0E23F8C" level="title">Title IV—WILDLAND RESTORATION AND RECOVERY </toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HCB0AA87C50A8492A9675C91B85F25D16" level="section">Sec. 401. Definitions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HC9C3CC0476304AAF8E09F5A8DC056BE5" level="section">Sec. 402. Restoration and recovery.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H6B9AC1644BC141E69F79DFAECD87A97F" level="section">Sec. 403. Management.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H43A92FD53D784F3ABB72EBB4D91ADA1F" level="title">Title V—IMPLEMENTATION AND MONITORING</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H0FCBC381902D441489CEF3E8034C503B" level="section">Sec. 501. Implementation report.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HE3832A30F32A48F3ABA39947EA4F52F9" level="section">Sec. 502. Interagency team.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HFDBC28A5B481429CB0D560480583DA26" level="section">Sec. 503. Roadless lands evaluation.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H0728BFCFC47D43FFBA79BE5BA4529F9C" level="title">Title VI—Additional Provisions Regarding Indian Tribes</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H1160B0BA1E86493FA410B68EF497A3FE" level="section">Sec. 601. Indian tribes.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H50A5DBE38FDB465FB6D5E387F044B3F8" level="section">Sec. 602. Federal trust responsibility.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H6405205F819245B7B1F34C5B2BF61061" level="section">Sec. 603. Exemption from freedom of information act.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H042DBEED3C5C44258805B079438761DF" level="section">Sec. 604. Application of Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H28EC832316734F34BC2C5DA451BB0BEF" level="section">Sec. 605. Native American uses.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H27EE715CB49540328BE2CAC071834CD0" level="title">Title VII—RULES OF CONSTRUCTION</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HA11783DAB3DA48C0AF27DF1E51E90929" level="section">Sec. 701. Water rights.</toc-entry></toc>
 </subsection></section><section id="H4352C2351B124AAE8DF88E6B5764D163"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress makes the following findings:</text> <paragraph id="HCDCAFEC62A7A4724A07428ABFA2917AF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Many areas of undeveloped National Forest System lands, National Park System lands, and public lands administered by the Bureau of Land Management in the States of Idaho, Montana, Oregon, Washington, and Wyoming possess outstanding natural characteristics which give them high values as wilderness, parks, and wild and scenic rivers and will, if properly preserved, be an enduring resource of wilderness, wild land areas, and biodiversity for the benefit of the American people.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H801D6DEC981D4F7E8409582B75F74D2B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Northern Rockies Bioregion contains the most diverse array of wild lands remaining south of Canada, providing sanctuary for a host of species listed as threatened or endangered under section 4(c) of the <act-name parsable-cite="ESA">Endangered Species Act of 1973</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1533">16 U.S.C. 1533(c)</external-xref>). These national interest public lands are among the most popular wild lands in the United States, embracing greater ecosystems and national treasures such as the Greater Yellowstone, Greater Glacier/Northern Continental Divide, Greater Hells Canyon/Wallowa, Greater Salmon/Selway, and Greater Cabinet/Yaak/Selkirk ecosystems.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0BDAB153E4E54550953476F03A109289"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The natural ecosystems in the Northern Rockies Bioregion are largely dependent on National Forest System lands, National Park System lands, and public lands administered by the Bureau of Land Management, and the ecological productivity and diversity of resources these Federal public lands provide. Conservation of roadless areas on these public lands, which produces clean water, protects native fisheries and native flora and fauna, and provides scenic and recreational qualities, also preserves options for sustainable economics through activities such as hunting, fishing, and wilderness-based recreation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H83AB3AD533794692860DD0B6D4A585E1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The headwaters of several major river systems, including the Columbia, Snake, Green, Missouri and Saskatchewan Rivers, originate in the Northern Rockies Bioregion, and these rivers send their waters to three different oceans. These waters are of tremendous economic importance to farming and ranching operations, municipal water supplies, and water-based recreation, including fishing and boating. Protection of this world class water resource will enhance these uses, reduce costs for water treatment and irrigation, and increase native fish populations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB45BE55804164451A33D30862BD6175D"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The wildlife treasures of the Northern Rockies are of international significance and contain remarkably intact large mammalian fauna and rare and unique plant life. Wildlife habitat fragmentation due to roadbuilding, timber harvest, mining, oil and gas exploration, lack of interagency cooperation, and other activities has severe effects on the wildlife populations (including those listed as threatened or endangered under section 4(c) of the <act-name parsable-cite="ESA">Endangered Species Act of 1973</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1533">16 U.S.C. 1533(c)</external-xref>)) and their habitat, the water quality, the ancient forests, and the greater ecosystems of the Northern Rockies Bioregion. The overemphasis on resource extraction from National Forest System lands and public lands administered by the Bureau of Land Management has compromised ecosystem integrity and detracted from economic diversification opportunities. Economic instability and high unemployment in rural, resource-dependent communities is a common result of overexploitation of these lands.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFBC2F914B7754F928A0E4F84B935F60A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Continued fragmentation and development of the remaining roadless and essentially roadless ecosystems and biological connectors of the Northern Rockies would cause a loss to the Nation of an entire wild land region and of the only remaining areas south of Canada still pristine enough to support populations of caribou, gray wolves, grizzly bears, anadromous fish, and numerous other rare and endangered plant and animal life all in one intact bioregion.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1C644235D44C4FB0ACD2155452E52704"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Since the 1936 roadless area inventory completed by Bob Marshall, millions of acres of roadless wild lands have been developed in the Northern Rockies. Extensive fragmentation of wild lands and wildlife habitat has resulted in the listing of several species as threatened or endangered and reduced the numbers and range of many others, including anadromous fish.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCF1A5531952C4A5A8DABB979D4391F3F"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The natural ecosystems of the Northern Rockies Bioregion also serve as educational and research centers for on-site studies in biology, geology, astronomy and other sciences. The pristine nature of the National Forest System lands, National Park System lands, and public lands administered by the Bureau of Land Management in the Northern Rockies Bioregion helps local communities attract new residents and businesses based on local quality of life.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8D231B5B8DE2479C911F5D879C50F6C6"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A review of the current situation in the Northern Rockies has revealed the urgent need for an ecological reserve system for the Northern Rockies Bioregion, which includes core ecosystem reserve areas and biological connecting corridors necessary to ensure wildlife movements and genetic interchange between the core reserve areas. Wildlife freedom of movement has always been essential to the survival of wildlife species, and an increasing number of scientific studies have identified movement corridors as a necessity for wildlife conservation in a changing climate. Several foreign governments, including the governments of Australia and Scotland, have announced plans for corridors that would make wildlife movement possible as climate pressures increase. The concept of connective corridors for wildlife movement has been endorsed by governors of States in the western United States, and is now widely recognized by conservation and scientific organizations. For example, freedom of movement for wildlife is basic to the emerging new science of <quote>Movement Ecology</quote> described in a December 2008 Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences. This freedom of wildlife movement was a fundamental reason for the Act's development and introduction, and has become an increasingly high profile issue in the climate and biological sciences.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H368FDA9815D24AA78C01BB88507832AE"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The economic value to the Nation of most of these undeveloped areas, left in their natural state, greatly exceeds any potential return to the Treasury of the United States from timber harvest and development. If current Federal land management in the Northern Rockies continues to result in the development of roadless areas, the American public will be using its tax dollars to fund permanent reductions in wilderness, water quality, fish and wildlife habitat, and species and biological diversity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H02E2C0FCE2D1481B8F640F1CED575EF3"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Instead, this Act provides opportunities for employment in outdoor trades by establishing rehabilitation zones on specific tracts of damaged Federal land where active restoration work will occur. This Act will provide contracts for local businesses and renew the intrinsic economic, social and cultural benefits that result from productive land. Federal land rehabilitation projects represent a direct benefit to the local economy and reduce the loss to American taxpayers caused by below-cost timber sales and other subsidized resource extraction.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDF1E012A21EB45FD8D2A69817921A32A"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The congressional review of roadless areas within the National Forest System, National Park System, and public lands administered by the Bureau of Land Management in the States of Idaho, Montana, Oregon, Washington, and Wyoming has identified areas which, on the basis of their land form, ecosystem, associated fish and wildlife, economic value, and location will help to fulfill the role of the United States Forest Service, National Park Service, and Bureau of Land Management to ensure a quality National Wilderness Preservation System. The review has identified other areas which may have outstanding values as wild and scenic rivers. The review has also identified areas which may not possess outstanding wilderness attributes and should not now be designated as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System, but which should be studied to determine their role in maintaining biological diversity in the Northern Rockies.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H944FF41BBD7245C0B8689C675171A0CE"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Many areas of National Forest System lands and public lands administered by the Bureau of Land Management have been damaged and their productivity reduced by unwise development practices, which have also impaired ecosystem function and biological diversity. The Island Park area adjacent to Yellowstone National Park contains large clear-cut areas right up to the park boundary. Efforts should be made to return these areas to their former ecological health and native diversity. These efforts should seek to ensure that vital ecosystem components are restored, especially in areas where wildlife travel corridors and native fish and wildlife populations have been damaged or eliminated. Restoration efforts should seek to ensure and maintain genetic interchange, biological diversity, and restoration of native species diversity throughout the Northern Rockies Bioregion.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9F1311B8B731425E8DD94BC3DD4D2316"><enum>(14)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Backcountry areas of the National Park System have been damaged by inappropriate management, despite policies that require that recommended wilderness be administered as wilderness. An emphasis on structures and motorized equipment, and in some instances developed <quote>backcountry</quote> campsites, have all detracted from and degraded the wilderness character of these backcountry areas.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAA260FA63FF740EDB0C2BEB21316C275"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Federal agencies entrusted with managing the natural resources of the Northern Rockies Bioregion operate under contradictory congressional mandates, and thus are in dissension over management policies which involve common resources and greater ecosystems. Existing agency structures and regulatory mechanisms have proven unsatisfactory for responsible management of nationally important ecosystems on public lands. Existing laws and regulations have not been sufficient to establish and maintain agency accountability for public resources.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEC06E718D0E24D5BA42D2208146D81D9"><enum>(16)</enum><text>This Act does not affect private existing rights.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="HE596F11FE1E948D3B616126AB7C3AFD9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Purposes</header> <subsection id="H1F56AC0AED514C7AB2A2A3ABCA4AC68A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The purposes of this Act are—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFAF3065B996342398E79684A3ADFC915"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to designate certain National Forest System lands, certain National Park System lands, and certain public lands administered by the Bureau of Land Management in the States of Idaho, Montana, Oregon, Washington, and Wyoming as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDD8520458E28400BB99CEB28A46CD38E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to designate certain National Forest System lands, public lands administered by the Bureau of Land Management, and watercourses on these lands in the States of Montana, Idaho, and Wyoming as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H956FDB581D624D149EADBBAE085DD586"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to prioritize areas for wildland recovery to help restore biological diversity and native species; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H508BA7AC955C4665A71D783AF1EBCDE1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to establish a system of biological connecting corridors between the core ecosystems in the Northern Rockies Bioregion.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H071286A470754FD1BBB99B4A09B6FC73"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose of Designations</header><text>The designations made by this Act are made in order to—</text> <paragraph id="HCF4D1ADD70224D4C9818A67C274E39D1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promote, perpetuate, and preserve the wilderness character of the area so designated;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF90422D4ECD9449CA247C741C4E41AA6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>protect water quality, watersheds, and wildlife habitat, including that of species listed as threatened or endangered under section 4(c) of the <act-name parsable-cite="ESA">Endangered Species Act of 1973</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1533">16 U.S.C. 1533(c)</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9BE5DA382F1C4C489484855A423A336F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>protect the ecological integrity and contiguity of major wild land ecosystems and their interconnecting corridors identified by the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, and other sources;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD6BA5A8182D74E4C849D5D2FA0AD4E0B"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">protect and maintain biological and native species diversity and dispersal throughout the Northern Rockies Bioregion;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCF243BBE33FE404EB171C541BC7939E9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>promote and ensure interagency cooperation in the implementation of integrated, holistic ecosystem management and protection of the ecosystems and corridors covered by this Act based upon principles from conservation biology;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB531A7B1F8384EAA8115163543E37982"><enum>(6)</enum><text>preserve scenic, historic, and cultural resources;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE5E0C1868A1B47B2AA2D80E9FBAFB671"><enum>(7)</enum><text>promote scientific research, primitive recreation, solitude, physical and mental challenge, and inspiration for the benefit of all of the American people;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA2A2E82173F8482587D4FB9B7C7F4A40"><enum>(8)</enum><text>avoid the misinvestment of scarce capital in lands of marginal timber value; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC838BF3E8F854BD589604B5F25E22013"><enum>(9)</enum><text>promote ecologically and economically sustainable management in the Northern Rockies Bioregion.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H680CDECE0E2C4CA4A349151AFAE521D5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H48065A8C86554616AE18705F571F09E1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Development</header><text>The term <term>development</term> means activities that eliminate the roadless and wilderness characteristics of the land and includes ski resort facilities and such activities as roadbuilding, timber harvest, mining, and oil and gas drilling.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCD740955C4794388BE5D1DB095F1AF04"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Greater ecosystem</header><text>The term <term>greater ecosystem</term>, when used in conjunction with the specific ecosystems protected under this Act, means the ecological land units of sufficient scale to support and maintain populations of large vertebrate species and the other native plant and animal species of the units. These units are comprised of lands which are similar in regards to topography, climate, and plant and animal species. The ecosystems in the Northern Rockies are also defined in terms of the habitat of wildlife indicator species listed as threatened or endangered under section 4(c) of the <act-name parsable-cite="ESA">Endangered Species Act of 1973</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1533">16 U.S.C. 1533(c)</external-xref>), including grizzly bear, gray wolf, bald eagle, and caribou, and have been depicted on maps published by Federal agencies.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAACCBF1FAEE44B299F61BE7C0C777E2C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Northern rockies bioregion</header><text>The term <term>Northern Rockies Bioregion</term> means the portion of the Northern Rocky Mountains in the States of Montana, Idaho, Wyoming, Oregon, and Washington, so referred to on maps referred to in this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5E7B353862464D31A40467AF7CA61832"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Corridors</header><text>The term <quote>corridors</quote> means areas that provide connectivity of habitat or potential habitat and that facilitate the ability of terrestrial, estuarine, and freshwater fish, or wildlife to move within a landscape as needed for migration, gene flow, or dispersal, or in response to the impacts of climate change or other impacts.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3C9A343B1E9A4EA4A84E4D80DE776915"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Habitat</header><text>The term <quote>habitat</quote> means the physical, chemical, and biological properties that are used by fish, wildlife, or plants for growth, reproduction, survival, food, water, and cover, on a tract of land, in a body of water, or in an area or region.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8D64636C56314A2CB80EFD31DB788236"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Indian tribe</header><text>The term <quote>Indian tribe</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1F10E2494E8B4B97950D9DDDE22B7B47"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Natural resources</header><text>The term <quote>natural resources</quote> means the terrestrial, freshwater, estuarine, and marine fish, wildlife, plants, land, water, habitats, and ecosystems of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2669651BD913461CBC86E77332B1B31C"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Public land</header><text>The term <quote>public land</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 103(e) of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1702">43 U.S.C. 1702(e)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8206ED82122647779C25AEB314F2FD83"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Resilience</header><text>The terms <quote>resilience</quote> and <quote>resilient</quote> means the ability to resist or recover from disturbance and preserve diversity, productivity, and sustainability.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6391CBF911244EA3B8BABFDE666B5280"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Secretary concerned</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary concerned</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H7CADC9D87B604EFD8384A89218279522"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to National Forest System lands; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70CC61E9F19F4BD8A8CFDF7E1F05B2C0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior, with respect to National Park System lands and public land.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></section><title id="H24444941791D466584DFA8AC79A64144"><enum>I</enum><header>DESIGNATION OF WILDERNESS</header> <section id="H03B08F70FB1B4400A2356AA500AF5F32"><enum>101.</enum><header>Designation of certain National Forest System lands, National Park System lands, and Bureau of Land Management lands as wilderness</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In furtherance of the purpose of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</external-xref> et seq.), certain National Forest System lands, National Park System lands, and public lands administered by the Bureau of Land Management, as described in this title, in the States of Idaho, Montana, Oregon, Washington, and Wyoming are designated as wilderness and, therefore, as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System.</text>
			</section><section id="HC7DD35483D9F4502925BE8F8CB2C16C5"><enum>102.</enum><header>Greater Glacier/Northern Continental Divide ecosystem</header>
 <subsection id="H6E824FE9276D4126812A3EEDB9BB2F65"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>In order to protect the unique ecosystem of the greater Glacier/Northern Continental Divide region, the areas described in this section are hereby designated as wilderness.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFDEC352787FF449E89BEA565652A0401"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Bob Marshall Wilderness Additions</header><text>The following areas are incorporated into the Bob Marshall Wilderness:</text> <paragraph id="H53E1C4F643E14F9B81FC50B698D8FC61"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Choteau Mountain/Teton High Peaks/Deep Creek Addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lewis and Clark National Forest and land administered by the Lewistown Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 73,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>__</quote> and dated ___, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Bob Marshall Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE8A479661DDC4DDAB4E4A1A37C73BD12"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Renshaw Addition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain Federal land within the Lewis and Clark National Forest and land administered by the Lewistown Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 30,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>___</quote> and dated ___, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Bob Marshall Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H80820218C2E34BF5A1727873F9458C7A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Swan Front Addition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain Federal land within the Flathead National Forest and Lolo National Forest comprising approximately 169,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>___</quote> and dated ___, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Bob Marshall Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA5C432BF7C9A453FAA0D9325E679EBF4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Hungry Horse Reservoir West</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Flathead National Forest comprising approximately 179,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>___</quote> and dated ___, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Bob Marshall Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H21F492BA01474FB69D5CC25882F22191"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Bob North Addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Flathead National Forest comprising approximately 88,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>___</quote> and dated ___, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Bob Marshall Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF450C597DF574247929C728EE264ECC3"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Monture creek addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lolo National Forest comprising approximately 99,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>___</quote> and dated ___, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Bob Marshall Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H747399C921F74DED89D6658CE1A64816"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Great Bear Wilderness Additions</header><text>The following areas are incorporated into the Great Bear Wilderness:</text> <paragraph id="HF7B8DAA822AA4B8BA1DE3BA9B42177D5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Hungry Horse Reservoir East Addition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain Federal land within the Flathead National Forest comprising approximately 37,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Great Bear Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H48F9C015651445A3ACC6EA1E36DD3107"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Middle fork additions</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Flathead National Forest comprising approximately 53,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Great Bear Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB6A49CF9D00D4E8A91CCAEDBDC848151"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Scapegoat Wilderness Additions</header><text>The following areas, consisting of a total of approximately 125,000 acres, are incorporated into the Scapegoat Wilderness:</text>
 <paragraph id="H52CEE2B907AC43FEBB42A0F6D972176C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Stonewall Mountain Addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Helena National Forest comprising approximately 55,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Scapegoat Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB5FDDAAA75BB41F7BF55487E042EB140"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Silver King/Falls Creek Addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lewis and Clark National Forest and Helena National Forest comprising approximately 25,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Scapegoat Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H990FF1F62411403EBED1968ECD72C75C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Benchmark/elk Creek Addition</header><text>Certain Federal lands within the Lewis and Clark National Forest, comprising approximately 28,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Scapegoat Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF94E119E540044EC98A280239FF6480C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Mission Mountains Wilderness Additions</header><text>The following areas, consisting of a total of approximately 16,000 acres, are incorporated into the Mission Mountains Wilderness:</text>
 <paragraph id="HF46B884E0E37428D9948D097040A4BA8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Mission Mountain Wilderness Addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Flathead National Forest comprising approximately 20,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Mission Mountains Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA7C7E2BADBBD438C93AF886FDC89780D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Marshall Peak Addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lolo National Forest comprising approximately 9,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Mission Mountains Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF8FD2604B30F4069A382CD2DCEDF53B8"><enum>(f)</enum><header>New National Wilderness Preservation System Components</header><text>The following areas are designated as new components of the National Wilderness Preservation System:</text>
 <paragraph id="H8BE8591F8699472F826F8A4364BFE0B4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Glacier wilderness, glacier national park</header><text>Certain Federal land within Glacier National Park comprising approximately 925,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Glacier Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAF913012E78A45818468549EB87B1453"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sawtooth ridge wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lewis and Clark National Forest comprising approximately 14,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated _______, which shall be known as the Sawtooth Ridge Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCC4232D41FF64BEEAECD96AFA6030485"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Tuchuck wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Flathead National Forest and the Kootenai National Forest comprising approximately 142,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Tuchuck Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF4A22E71CE0E44D3AE87469F2EF7F429"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Le beau wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Flathead National Forest and the Kootenai National Forest comprising approximately 8,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Le Beau Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H16233CB020DF4C4694015D37A4E7791B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Ten lakes wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Kootenai National Forest comprising approximately 49,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Ten Lakes Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6939240CD6EA49AD9CB6F2C7B9E1BA01"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Coal ridge wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Flathead National Forest comprising approximately 24,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as Coal Ridge Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC3F8ED2B5CC94EA98C185B9C9DF09A47"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Standard peak wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Flathead National Forest comprising approximately 19,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as Standard Peak Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4C544BDF607049FB910B65F425950ED7"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Demers wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Flathead National Forest comprising approximately 7,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as Coal Ridge Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE87765908D7F4CD5B766B93223DDD25A"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Lincoln gulch wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Helena National Forest comprising approximately 9,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as Lincoln Gulch Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA4486F5939404E3999DA8E2644D62589"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Anaconda hill wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Helena National Forest comprising approximately 20,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as Anaconda Hill Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H61CABBDD884A428D823778F0D0AE87AF"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Specimen creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Helena National Forest comprising approximately 13,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as Specimen Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HED0B45547CC746BF8086A282245BB829"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Crater mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Helena National Forest comprising approximately 10,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as Crater Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFA6235467E3E4DEE9A748A043EEED8DF"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Ogden mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Helena National Forest comprising approximately 8,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as Ogden Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6810653E9CAA4C5DB0751B940620EA09"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Nevada mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Helena National Forest comprising approximately 54,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as Nevada Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H015B24970341478CAE2EDEE83025E4B2"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Blackfeet wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lewis and Clark National Forest comprising approximately 129,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>____</quote> and dated ____, which shall be known as the Blackfeet Wilderness.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD7318AD077A44CC590D8ADBE1DB205B5" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>103.</enum><header>Greater Yellowstone ecosystem</header>
 <subsection id="HCB5AE137F66242F6815C485BECCDE926"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to protect the unique ecosystem of the greater Yellowstone region, the areas described in this section are hereby designated as wilderness.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9F7497151710473E9202CEC6ACA3FC23"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Absaroka-Beartooth wilderness additions</header><text>Certain Federal lands within the Custer Gallatin National Forest and Shoshone National Forest comprising approximately 265,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Absaroka-Beartooth Wilderness.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE41539728D51401E94992B5838D8A426"><enum>(c)</enum><header>North absaroka wilderness additions</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Shoshone National Forest and the Custer Gallatin National Forest comprising approximately 173,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the North Absaroka Wilderness.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H56996880CF0A4CD89BC0E662BAE35048"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Washakie wilderness additions</header><text>Certain Federal land with the Shoshone National Forest and land administered by Lander Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 339,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Washakie Wilderness.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2A304ED9DC2C44E98465896525594111"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Fitzpatrick Wilderness Additions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following areas are incorporated into the Fitzpatrick Wilderness:</text> <paragraph id="HE02398C450484F989755F89A6B5C29CA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Fitzpatrick wilderness addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Shoshone National Forest and land administered by the Lander Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 14,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Fitzpatrick Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAE512CE1F3CF49FF82CC186F8586CD25"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Bench mark/warm springs addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Shoshone National Forest comprising approximately 15,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Fitzpatrick Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD3994A68DC4C44CEA0F6AB027ED5EDC6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Teton Wilderness Additions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain Federal lands within the Bridger-Teton National Forest comprising approximately 24,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Teton Wilderness.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4BB7BDA731E54A10A72F165425E5C27D"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Gros Ventre Wilderness Additions</header><text>The following areas are incorporated into the Gros Ventre Wilderness:</text> <paragraph id="HD0BD0793DC82435FA350D908F43F7E47"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Shoal creek addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Bridger-Teton National Forest comprising approximately 32,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Gros Ventre Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC3B6F8F450BB4AD886561379218D78E7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Gros ventre additions</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Bridger Teton National Forest comprising approximately 124,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Gros Ventre Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H59E8CE561A494369A9840FD808848608"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Bridger Wilderness Additions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain Federal land within the Bridger-Teton National Forest and land administered by the Pinedale Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 230,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Bridger Wilderness.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H835DC1CF21774685AB2E3C700645AEC9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Popo Agie Wilderness Additions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain Federal land within the Shoshone National Forest comprising approximately 60,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Popo Agie Wilderness.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDB8EB06901E54859BCF3429B4C8963E4"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Winegar Hole Wilderness Additions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain Federal land within the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 5,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Winegar Hole Wilderness.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3E71B8E98BDA47A9931019FC1DD06DD3"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Jedediah Smith Wilderness Additions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain Federal lands within the Bridger-Teton and Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 51,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Jedediah Smith Wilderness.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9816E85709824E10A739C062DD05B7EB"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Lee Metcalf Wilderness Additions</header><text>The following areas are incorporated into the Lee Metcalf Wilderness:</text> <paragraph id="HEC8D91282F2E4F7DB0CC6E559A7A1AAC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Cowboys heaven addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Custer Gallatin National Forest and the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest comprising approximately 40,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Lee Metcalf Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H474F9C5F946342A98EAD4607B60993EE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Lee metcalf addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Custer Gallatin National Forest and the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest comprising approximately 143,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Lee Metcalf Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7B24EA3AE02D46E88E2424B660399E48"><enum>(m)</enum><header>New National Wilderness Preservation System Components</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following areas are designated as new components of the National Wilderness Preservation System:</text>
 <paragraph id="H3977B60F80344C62BFFD1E78A6654EE5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Yellowstone wilderness, yellowstone national park</header><text>Certain Federal land within Yellowstone National Park comprising approximately 2,030,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Yellowstone Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H69C273F9231B42C89A2ABCD05464FCEF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grand teton wilderness, grand teton national park</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Grand Teton National Park comprising approximately 123,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Grand Teton Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H007CF1040E2746239951E4CBD1F3923B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Snowcrest wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest and land administered by the Dillon Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 105,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Snowcrest Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H05929B5F53B34AEABE0B13687EBEE766"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Antelope basin wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest comprising approximately 70,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as Antelope Basin Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5E4F529502ED4522A3AA787D68F0EFFC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Lone butte wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest comprising approximately 14,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as Lone Butte Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0B7BE2BE73FA4E2AADEB05A2A1BC2DC2"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Black butte</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest comprising approximately 39,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known Black Butte Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H52F770B5EEBC4F18A3D49C12AF90DCD7"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Gravelly mountains wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest comprising of approximately 53,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as Gravelly Mountains Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H320775C3706F4898B2549F9B8F332D51"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Vigilante wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest comprising approximately 16,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as Vigilante Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H59702AC8DA6C46688AA8CFFC0A774238"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Cherry lakes wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest comprising approximately 13,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as Cherry Lakes Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H19EF3AE7DF4942FE815E754B2ECB2A8E"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Axolotl wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest and land administered by the Dillon Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management consisting of approximately 35,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Axolotl Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8C86F283DE1F4165A1BA2CB0B12AC716"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Crockett lake wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest comprising approximately 7,000 acres administered as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as Crockett Lake Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBBFF6005C1A94CDE8E9AFF1E04DF96FA"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Gallatin range wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Custer Gallatin National Forest comprising approximately 221,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Gallatin Range Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H053F9AA9EF9D4542BA79B52DEF916A40"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Chico peak wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Custer Gallatin National Forest comprising approximately 12,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Chico Peak Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA7E440930112431280FF8763BA738737"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Madison wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Custer Gallatin National Forest comprising approximately 15,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Madison Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H840EB748583D421D844A5C13CE05A8B6"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Lionhead wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Custer Gallatin National Forest and the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 48,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Lionhead Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAEEB1EE730954032990130ADBE543EFB"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Deep lake wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Custer Gallatin National Forest and the Shoshone National Forest comprising approximately 90,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Deep Lake Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H532EE7E89D9746819FF5C51524F31003"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Monument ridge wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Bridger-Teton National Forest comprising approximately 18,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Monument Ridge Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE8BD63FD69B04D4391FBFF2F2C2AFBEE"><enum>(18)</enum><header>Munger mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Bridger-Teton National Forest comprising approximately 10,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Munger Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA2D98EE4D2E54A09B4938A2B3F59AD82"><enum>(19)</enum><header>Little sheep mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Bridger-Teton National Forest comprising approximately 14,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Little Sheep Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5202D91109CE49F6937B77DCB618B76E"><enum>(20)</enum><header>Mt. leidy highlands wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Bridger-Teton National Forest comprising approximately 205,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Mt. Leidy Highlands Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H88FB45190EF54FA191A3F56B5887E5DC"><enum>(21)</enum><header>Salt river range wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Bridger-Teton National Forest comprising approximately 245,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Salt River Range Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAF02FF6D73224FD1B179C851EC76A730"><enum>(22)</enum><header>Grayback ridge wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Bridger-Teton National Forest comprising approximately 314,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Grayback Ridge Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDBB16D23366C4EB09733BB4ECBF4BDE0"><enum>(23)</enum><header>Commissary ridge wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Bridger-Teton National Forest comprising approximately 143,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Commissary Ridge Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB57FDA7208FC482EA3D0B7EEBD8C4271"><enum>(24)</enum><header>South wyoming range wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Bridger-Teton National Forest comprising approximately 98,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the South Wyoming Range Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H49B5A04A0B154D1DB9506A23EF4BC5BF"><enum>(25)</enum><header>North mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Bridger-Teton National Forest comprising approximately 5,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the North Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H41553CF689DF4BB7B04EDD394DCE50B5"><enum>(26)</enum><header>Grayback ridge east wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Bridger-Teton National Forest consisting of approximately 18,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Grayback Ridge East Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF1214C96F90C46AD8E8FE77A4AB3BEAF"><enum>(27)</enum><header>Palisades wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Bridger-Teton National Forest and the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 224,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Palisades Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H18C17475CB9D4612BBD0DAA50F56EC39"><enum>(28)</enum><header>Gannett hills wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Bridger-Teton National Forest, and the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 63,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Gannett Hills Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H41BAFD99EE4C4C148F5F2BF51D86C1F5"><enum>(29)</enum><header>Raymond mountain north wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Bridger-Teton National Forest and land administered by the Kemmerer Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 19,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>____</quote> and dated ____, which shall be known as the Raymond Mountain North Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H534BD0358C0C4B4B92A73C994934DB3D"><enum>(30)</enum><header>Raymond mountain south wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land administered by the Kemmerer Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 24,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>____</quote> and dated ____, which shall be known as the Raymond Mountain South Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD91F31EDEDD44101B4E6EBC93365DE2F"><enum>(31)</enum><header>Lake mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Bridger-Teton National Forest and land administered by the Pinedale Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 17,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Lake Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAFF274BBD60C4E268AAC4EF388E5765B"><enum>(32)</enum><header>Garns mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 104,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Garns Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD989928977B04AC0AC35B23DE4423CB6"><enum>(33)</enum><header>Antelope creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 17,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Bald Mountain Antelope Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA67402A0345C4366B3FAFB0B219A2B4E"><enum>(34)</enum><header>Bear creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 98,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Bear Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H69597E12C5E6430AB4E9FD15B2D320B1"><enum>(35)</enum><header>Stump creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 97,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Stump Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEBCDFA34D95D4EF0BA50DAB3D0A2DEA8"><enum>(36)</enum><header>Caribou-targhee wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 94,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Caribou-Targhee Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9CB08B9221194C0BAA508B642E04A438"><enum>(37)</enum><header>Poker peak wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 20,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Poker Peak Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAD5767490C194BBDB3D2BCAB1C23C3A1"><enum>(38)</enum><header>Tincup wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 7,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Tincup Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H465B59F5BF1143BF8B92B8272E4566E3"><enum>(39)</enum><header>Schmid peak wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 20,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Schmid Peak Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1014779622CE45D2A97622A6AF2E9104"><enum>(40)</enum><header>Sage creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 11,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Sage Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H26C639DDC84842499900D8E111C625D6"><enum>(41)</enum><header>Preuss creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 14,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Preuss Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC89BEECE00AE42F7969CFC9085A37317"><enum>(42)</enum><header>Dry ridge wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 23,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Dry Ridge Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8B22620E99CE4B82B03A303896A0F5AA"><enum>(43)</enum><header>Meade peak wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 45,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Meade Peak Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4093D7DCC06F484196822FC8111D8725"><enum>(44)</enum><header>Tobacco root mountains wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest and land administered by the Dillon Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 97,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Tobacco Root Mountains Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2E32581788284A1FB4EA4385EDC0A173"><enum>(45)</enum><header>Potosi wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest comprising approximately 5,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as Potosi Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H82BBE3B4B173480E8F8FBF97549E84EC"><enum>(46)</enum><header>Bayer mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Shoshone National Forest comprising approximately 9,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Bayer Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBCCFE726902B48E49538DB25D61E0D0E"><enum>(47)</enum><header>Little popo agie canyon wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Shoshone National Forest comprising approximately 11,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Little Popo Agie Canyon Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H03BA8B3FDAA744CEBAD9DECA9F1CF8B5"><enum>(48)</enum><header>Clark fork wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Shoshone National Forest comprising approximately 42,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Clark Fork Wilderness.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H999D6F0628694A309C38BA81D88B8FC1" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>104.</enum><header>Greater Salmon/Selway ecosystem</header>
 <subsection id="H8F8AF959CFBC4EE7B63CB77F87136A7C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to protect the unique ecosystem of the Greater Yellowstone region, the areas described in this section are hereby designated as wilderness.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H34FE094C7E1C4FA5A97BA8BD25FBFA87"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Frank Church-River of No Return Wilderness Additions</header><text>The following areas are incorporated into the Frank Church-River of No Return Wilderness:</text> <paragraph id="HF2A6D655B2CC4FCBA8D671051D691E31"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Pinnacle peak (sugar mountain) addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Payette National Forest comprising approximately 10,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Frank Church-River of No Return Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC04D987E69464CAABB6F58A3F0F124F8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Placer creek addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Payette National Forest comprising approximately 7,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Frank Church-River of No Return Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE2489D4160934BCE81988DC14FF4E8DA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Smith creek addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Payette National Forest comprising approximately 2,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Frank Church-River of No Return Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF4215B4525784304B3D056AF4A45D606"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Cottontail point-pilot creek addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Payette National Forest and land administered by the Cottonwood Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 99,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Frank Church-River of No Return Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD50602A8BCEB48489212E8B6BDD33292"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Jersey-jack addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests comprising approximately 64,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Frank Church-River of No Return Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H666632B5934842F29433C1A40DE86846"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Mallard addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests comprising approximately 20,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Frank Church-River of No Return Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDC255F6ED8C24B0598C0F3D10BA20769"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Bluejoint addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Salmon-Challis National Forest and the Bitterroot National Forest comprising approximately 70,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Frank Church-River of No Return Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8BDA1619216544E59039FD74181B1A84"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Blue bunch addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Salmon-Challis National Forest and the Boise National Forest comprising approximately 11,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Frank Church-River of No Return Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2C98261264E049DD9E73B882F92CA26A"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Loon creek addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Salmon-Challis National Forest and the Sawtooth National Forest comprising approximately 109,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Frank Church-River of No Return Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7E80143C804E4091AAB3F7B456F1CEDB"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Salmon-challis additions</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 303,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Frank Church-River of No Return Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5765104F895145D9AB41D84DCF13599E"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Boise additions</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Boise National Forest comprising approximately 59,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Frank Church-River of No Return Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H86117750229241559EBF096C6BCEC7DC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Gospel Hump Wilderness Additions</header><text>The Gospel Hump additions consisting of approximately 55,000 acres administered by the Nez Perce National Forest are incorporated into the Gospel Hump Wilderness.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5EC8764EB299480186FBB22F2E540E61"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Selway-Bitterroot Wilderness Additions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following areas are incorporated into the Selway-Bitterroot Wilderness:</text> <paragraph id="HB6B87605BB994FE2BB48472C990917F0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Lochsa face addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests comprising approximately 75,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Selway-Bitterroot Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3648F248BCD8483C9EB2C08DB05218A3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elk summit/sneakfoot/north fork spruce addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests comprising approximately 59,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Selway-Bitterroot Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA967348CB65A4C5B87DCF06D52AE4F57"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rackliff-gedney addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests comprising approximately 90,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Selway-Bitterroot Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H102391985D5649FE871E9239EE683CD1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Meadow creek addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests and on land administered by the Cottonwood Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 215,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Selway-Bitterroot Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD9F8D62DF39F4AE0A605FE2D5B97BEB4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Lolo creek addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests and the Lolo National Forest comprising approximately 18,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Selway-Bitterroot Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBCD41CE5127D4FB89159118E5A6347C1"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Bitterroot addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Bitterroot National Forest and the Nez-Perce National Forest comprising approximately 123,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Selway-Bitterroot Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE9DA65CA2E5C48D594889634B29A279F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Sawtooth Wilderness Additions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain Federal land within the Boise National Forest, Sawtooth National Forest and the Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 540,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Sawtooth Wilderness.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA89C0FD2D3694B0DA00906EDADA05095"><enum>(f)</enum><header>New National Wilderness Preservation System Components of the Great Burn Wildlands Complex</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following areas within the Great Burn Wildlands Complex are designated as new components of the National Wilderness Preservation System:</text>
 <paragraph id="H2BC6DBD0C57D42F2BD22A90C99C2A860"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Great burn (hoodoo) wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests and the Lolo National Forest comprising approximately 255,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Great Burn (Hoodoo) Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0BC899549DC240208A6A515BFA912ED6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Upper north fork wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forest, the Idaho Panhandle National Forest, and the Lolo National Forest comprising approximately 62,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Upper North Fork Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB0EA047FAA0A4556A737060DA7A10FFD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Sheep mountain/state line wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests, the Idaho Panhandle National Forest, and the Lolo National Forest comprising approximately 68,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Sheep Mountain/State Line Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD3C1E89AFCB144DE9AB05B9CD7F462F3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Mallard-larkins wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests and the Idaho Panhandle National Forest comprising approximately 260,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Mallard-Larkins Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H064472A07F494E43811840E6263C897C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Bighorn-weitas wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests comprising approximately 260,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Bighorn-Weitas Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H70433B8276B344A7A1106BD9331A1A29"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Eldorado wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests comprising approximately 7,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Eldorado Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5AD4C7443D9A4F29AF737C7EFEB2FEDD"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Moose mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests comprising approximately 22,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Moose Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H34C1D1DCCDC34504AFCE9E48581065D9"><enum>(8)</enum><header>North lochsa slope wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests approximately 118,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the North Lochsa Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0E960F2AAF3842E7980DF77232763498"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Pot mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests approximately 51,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Pot Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB2C83D2356C34209A2634A2F272992F7"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Siwash wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests comprising approximately 9,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Siwash Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3B029B507E3F4BDF941E07D744AE8290"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Weir-post office wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests comprising approximately 22,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Weir-Post Office Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF172FF168D724E8C9ED59DAA35875E4C"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Mosquito fly wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Idaho Panhandle National Forest comprising approximately 19,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Mosquito Fly Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2C1BE62D65F34566B1C3765374EF0829"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Midget peak wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Idaho Panhandle National Forest comprising approximately 7,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Midget Peak Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD80902D354FA4BF39BF9DD2EB7A2BA5D"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Stark mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lolo National Forest comprising approximately 13,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated _____, which shall be known as Stark Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H038AFD126FBA4A578EBD96298EBB6C14"><enum>(g)</enum><header>New National Wilderness Preservation System Components of the Little Slate Creek Wildlands Complex</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following areas within the Little Slate Creek Wildlands Complex are designated as new components of the National Wilderness Preservation System:</text>
 <paragraph id="HFEDD9BE667ED4A04A73C677F82F692C0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Little slate creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests comprising approximately 12,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Little Slate Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF737EBB444EA421BA05B8FA83CA01354"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Little slate creek north wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests comprising approximately 6,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Little Slate Creek North Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6FC867DC64AF414895F35A13FE203792"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Other New National Wilderness Preservation System Components</header><text>The following areas are designated as new components of the National Wilderness Preservation System:</text>
 <paragraph id="H48D8DEB8E2ED4F1CB8EBFB4AE539CE29"><enum>(1)</enum><header>French creek/patrick butte wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Payette National Forest comprising approximately 170,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the French Creek/Patrick Butte Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0840E643706447BB923E9EAA9FEB843D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Crystal mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Payette National Forest comprising approximately 13,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Crystal Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H48A060A0DD05462C8F8F77CBD341E60A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secesh wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Payette National Forest comprising approximately 248,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Secesh Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H06AA0307788F460F856C40036A23DB1E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Needles wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Payette National Forest and the Boise National Forest comprising approximately 161,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Needles Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA18D0AA5CDF340F8BA35CD76647B5327"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Caton lake wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Payette National Forest and the Boise National Forest comprising approximately 85,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Caton Lake Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDE26CF15EEE94558BC1226B2BDE58EAC"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Poison creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Payette National Forest and the Boise National Forest comprising approximately 5,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Poison Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6258362ECDB24862842E9DB7D32CFAC3"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Meadow creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Payette National Forest and the Boise National Forest comprising approximately 29,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Meadow Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1573B6D6A72647288703E701F20F8406"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Mount heinen wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Boise National Forest comprising approximately 13,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Mount Heinen Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2855B8EF5EBC491CA6E4B1B1A14F3C28"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Reeves creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Boise National Forest comprising approximately 11,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Reeves Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDEC35ED41D454CBC887297453AA1098B"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Peace rock wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Boise National Forest comprising approximately 192,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Peace Rock Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA67201C997FE41FC8D84CE80139BF49C"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Deadwood wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Boise National Forest comprising approximately 52,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Deadwood Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2D4D3BCF808B4C78A6F5E003E861F94B"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Whitehawk mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Boise National Forest comprising approximately 9,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Whitehawk Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H117F81A674DB4683A5FB716E69B063FF"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Stony meadows wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Boise National Forest comprising approximately 13,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Stony Meadows Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD9263D3F2E264A69A4FABB9D662DF362"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Scriver creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Boise National Forest comprising approximately 8,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Scriver Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCFDBD0A650E5456BA30056579C546173"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Grimes pass wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Boise National Forest comprising approximately 13,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Grimes Pass Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H827293DCAF5141C09C1DD3626DC3F700"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Gallagher wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Boise National Forest comprising approximately 6,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Gallagher Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBF1C02A7A0E6461882811B1D9A8B55E3"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Corski creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Boise National Forest comprising approximately 8,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Corski Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6CE5E288C88447CAA9E71C1C1647D0B9"><enum>(18)</enum><header>Bull trout wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Boise National Forest and the Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 115,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Bull Trout Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD20E941CA80C4AA1A8153CA011C78C13"><enum>(19)</enum><header>Breadwinner wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Boise National Forest comprising approximately 20,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Breadwinner Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H95F74407967E43F5A00A4FCD26543C51"><enum>(20)</enum><header>Elk creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Boise National Forest comprising approximately 15,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Elk Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H46C183FA27CD46438752F812FB6072B7"><enum>(21)</enum><header>Steel mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Boise National Forest comprising approximately 23,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Steel Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAA0C9FF7CE634FA4B02B5A571B2914DA"><enum>(22)</enum><header>Rainbow wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Boise National Forest comprising approximately 31,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Rainbow Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H545B59218CBF473693AA73D46AEEE94C"><enum>(23)</enum><header>Grand mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Boise National Forest comprising approximately 14,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Grand Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5D0FCD8AD43344CDA2E62AC686AC7ABC"><enum>(24)</enum><header>Sheep creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Boise National Forest comprising approximately 70,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Sheep Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0E4A46A8F9CA4859A3D95D29274A4A53"><enum>(25)</enum><header>Snowbank wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Boise National Forest comprising approximately 34,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Snowbank Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6545BB5C81D74D0EBFB2837D571CCDE7"><enum>(26)</enum><header>House mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Boise National Forest comprising approximately 26,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the House Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5D77E91293074711B5E8AC84A06F8E41"><enum>(27)</enum><header>Danskin wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Boise National Forest comprising approximately 30,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Danskin Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB18C5606A33142368305DED5D757EC0D"><enum>(28)</enum><header>Cow creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Boise National Forest comprising approximately 15,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Cow Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H22D1B2B4FD3D4CD69AEBBE4B4E16EB4D"><enum>(29)</enum><header>Wilson peak wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Boise National Forest comprising approximately 8,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Wilson Peak Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4BC9FC6F5E0445019133E69A242F83CA"><enum>(30)</enum><header>Lost man creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Boise National Forest comprising approximately 13,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Lost Man Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8212F047060C4DACA30C719167A4B6E5"><enum>(31)</enum><header>Whiskey jack wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Boise National Forest comprising approximately 7,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Whiskey Jack Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDF60738894C047FBBA45DACD95235C90"><enum>(32)</enum><header>Cathedral rocks wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Boise National Forest comprising approximately 8,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Cathedral Rocks Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAB17EACFB42144DD86B6E508D907723E"><enum>(33)</enum><header>Lime creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Sawtooth National Forest and the Boise National Forest comprising approximately 97,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Lime Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4E3E692FDC6D49CF8C22DF32EEA389D6"><enum>(34)</enum><header>O’<enum-in-header>H</enum-in-header>ara falls creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests comprising approximately 33,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the O’Hara Falls Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8DEDF8D5D7DD4673842EB2B97092BFBF"><enum>(35)</enum><header>Lick point wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests comprising approximately 7,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Lick Point Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1E29C6CA119D466EABF77EC90409FDB4"><enum>(36)</enum><header>Clear creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests comprising approximately 9,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Clear Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H113CCA8D403744DEBDB4D38C955F0BAF"><enum>(37)</enum><header>Silver creek-pilot knob wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests comprising approximately 21,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Silver Creek-Pilot Knob Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA8B76242182B4E03B82140387EC68103"><enum>(38)</enum><header>Dixie summit-nut hill wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests comprising approximately 13,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Dixie Summit-Nut Hill Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD2C0633B2EF3462694053008E9A212CF"><enum>(39)</enum><header>North fork slate creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests comprising approximately 11,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the North Fork Slate Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3005310351724FF68A13BF7903DEF161"><enum>(40)</enum><header>John day wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests comprising approximately 10,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the John Day Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HADFB423299CB4EF083146CCACB29CCBB"><enum>(41)</enum><header>Perreau creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 8,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Perreau Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6155373B2780468E93BCF60772BF8837"><enum>(42)</enum><header>Napias wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 9,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Napias Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5EABB2EAC0F54ED6BDCB6A2DF2EA2C49"><enum>(43)</enum><header>Napolean ridge wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 51,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Napolean Ridge Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCCE7C0F26A0D418CB09995A1A90981C7"><enum>(44)</enum><header>Jesse creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 14,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Jesse Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H26BF8FC2A5DF432E953026E95C90086A"><enum>(45)</enum><header>Haystack mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 12,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Haystack Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6F7F3CFC976F4B8D80E215388A021AD2"><enum>(46)</enum><header>Phelan wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 13,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Phelan Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAD38AA9C051E420E81E88EC039560E53"><enum>(47)</enum><header>Sheepeater wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 35,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Sheepeater Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H390F7F0D4268473F9977560FA959DAF5"><enum>(48)</enum><header>South fork deep creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 13,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the South Fork Deep Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDA900481F2324E55B534E29AC46F7BF0"><enum>(49)</enum><header>Cobalt wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 7,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Cobalt Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1307D09CF9A44B0D8E7B4FDC5041154C"><enum>(50)</enum><header>Jureano wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 25,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Jureano Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H578D5A4A7A864FFCBADE377E47A6978F"><enum>(51)</enum><header>South panther wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 6,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the South Panther Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H72B73960F3284F1FA10680C84B1318F9"><enum>(52)</enum><header>Musgrove wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 8,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Musgrove Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB770651B92484664B9C5A09E680DC759"><enum>(53)</enum><header>Taylor mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 63,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Taylor Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HABB12062EC8949BAB493A5D4C1660C7E"><enum>(54)</enum><header>Martin creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 99,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Martin Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2A13BFFDE49748D08029FEA9C16EE5EB"><enum>(55)</enum><header>White knob wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 65,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the White Knob Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8D9D74AC75254478A7906B97BD4070F5"><enum>(56)</enum><header>Porphyry peak wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 47,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Porphyry Peak Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3AA2E4B14D4F4D74A688259C0F1FE76B"><enum>(57)</enum><header>Greylock wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 12,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Greylock Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD192EA3152DC4082B96010B69A3B66B9"><enum>(58)</enum><header>Copper basin wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 11,000 as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Copper Basin Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF3950D00337544AC9DAECF43563A044F"><enum>(59)</enum><header>Cold springs wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 9,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Cold Springs Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1C445017B42D43EFB245509E3EDEE1FC"><enum>(60)</enum><header>Pioneer mountains wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Sawtooth National Forest and the Salmon-Challis National Forest and on land administered by the Shoshone Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 308,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Pioneer Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCE10DA45C95C449894D126CF5F2B692F"><enum>(61)</enum><header>Railroad ridge wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Sawtooth National Forest and the Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 51,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Railroad Ridge Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H84AD9BF5038F4B9C8AB2069E1AEE0229"><enum>(62)</enum><header>Buttercup mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Sawtooth National Forest comprising approximately 57,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Buttercup Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7EBE9181AB2B48FEBAE19013A4C64A2F"><enum>(63)</enum><header>Elk ridge wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Sawtooth National Forest comprising approximately 9,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Elk Ridge Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7EB01827684345B4B877CDADB9B7227A"><enum>(64)</enum><header>Grandmother mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Idaho Panhandle National Forest and on land administered by the Coeur d’Alene Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 35,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled _____ and dated ______, which shall be known as the Grandmother Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6F283F72F2E84E0C90DB0CC64D55C14F"><enum>(65)</enum><header>Pinchot butte wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Idaho Panhandle National Forest and on land administered by the Coeur d’Alene Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 9,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled _____ and dated ______, which shall be known as the Pinchot Butte Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2EF871F3CC3D43B4B20BACE795DC5D3C"><enum>(66)</enum><header>Liberal mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Sawtooth National Forest comprising approximately 11,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Liberal Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2D6FB9FE419F4B19B866B0B93EA18EC9"><enum>(67)</enum><header>Horse heaven wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Payette National Forest and the Boise National Forest comprising approximately 18,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Horse Heaven Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H31238797EC2344EAB06E1312D310271F"><enum>(68)</enum><header>Chimney rock wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Payette National Forest comprising approximately 9,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Chimney Rock Wilderness.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB458327308084953B36FD45A9EA4E0C8" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>105.</enum><header>Greater Cabinet/Yaak/Selkirk ecosystem</header>
 <subsection id="H0E6056DAC0C749CD915E8CB965E54F9F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to protect the unique, heavily fragmented, and endangered Greater Cabinet/Yaak/Selkirk ecosystem, the areas described in this section, are hereby designated as wilderness.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBB965AEB43D24F28A7EEBAC415E9C805"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Cabinet Mountains Wilderness Additions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain Federal land within the Kootenai National Forest comprising approximately 100,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Cabinet Mountains Wilderness.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC9AC5492EDA947A2A810CE6B92645F62"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Salmo-Priest Wilderness Additions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain Federal land within the Idaho Panhandle National Forest and the Colville National Forest comprising approximately 47,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Salmo-Priest Wilderness.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H554012F57F5C44E1B31961B12BE84389"><enum>(d)</enum><header>New National Wilderness Preservation System Components</header><text>The following areas are designated as new components of the National Wilderness Preservation System:</text>
 <paragraph id="HE6A4CBFF953A4211BF253D205A380D4C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Skyline mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Kootenai National Forest comprising approximately 15,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as Skyline Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD81F41DACB4340A0A5AF33BD98B224F9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Galena creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Kootenai National Forest comprising approximately 20,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as Galena Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H65E6AD898EC1447195F1C291B38D06A0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Berray mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Kootenai National Forest comprising approximately 9,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as Berray Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H00CA6CCB021B4EF3AA953FAD8D2E288A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Lone cliff-smeads wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Kootenai National Forest comprising approximately 10,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as Lone Cliff-Smeads Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H451E0A419C4249A98F25B4E839334F58"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Mcneeley wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Kootenai National Forest comprising approximately 7,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as McNeeley Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA4E56A96288942EF956ADAD87110B8C6"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Northwest peaks wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Kootenai National Forest comprising approximately 15,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as Northwest Peaks Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H43B85DE589734BE7B17E496C9422B10F"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Roderick wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Kootenai National Forest comprising approximately 30,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as Roderick Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H58875C1690714E8D837A9D35A0378838"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Grizzly peak wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Kootenai National Forest comprising approximately 7,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as Grizzly Peak Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H91DD42D1878C41E99CFECB8279B8FB4C"><enum>(9)</enum><header>West fork yaak wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Kootenai National Forest comprising approximately 9,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as West Fork Yaak Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H289D1C698E4B489BA802E95710382D61"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Mt. henry wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Kootenai National Forest comprising approximately 14,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as Mt. Henry Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H03101E9961E34774BA4232C16676B461"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Alexander creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Kootenai National Forest comprising approximately 7,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as Alexander Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2345C15978B644C5AAC3F00399894B31"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Robinson mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Kootenai National Forest comprising approximately 7,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as Robinson Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC3770E95D5974EAA837E7D075E906748"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Devil’s gap wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Kootenai National Forest comprising approximately 5,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as Devil’s Gap Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H24E9C1F93AFE41B0A6EE6C57C98CB6AE"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Lone cliff west wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Kootenai National Forest comprising approximately 5,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as Lone Cliff West Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H047997C55C0640958A7FD2281D46A285"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Allen peak wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Kootenai National Forest comprising approximately 30,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as Allen Peak Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6783D806142C4C218264095541678A7E"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Huckleberry mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Kootenai National Forest comprising approximately 9,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as Huckleberry Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8355B3512BAB495CA2671E1730EE1335"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Cataract peak wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Kootenai National Forest and the Lolo National Forest comprising approximately 39,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Cataract Peak Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5A7C527D21A1447380035E9E46201DF6"><enum>(18)</enum><header>Cube iron-silcox wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Kootenai National Forest and the Lolo National Forest comprising approximately 39,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Cube Iron-Silcox Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDF45811B65F54B60B28FFB1079057D27"><enum>(19)</enum><header>Sundance ridge wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lolo National Forest comprising approximately 8,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as Sundance Ridge Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0BAA54240D99423CB51867D9A04FD021"><enum>(20)</enum><header>Teepee-spring creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lolo National Forest comprising approximately 14,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated _____, which shall be known as Teepee-Spring Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8B0A7090E3D3408FB8BBB1D18571FF73"><enum>(21)</enum><header>Baldy mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lolo National Forest and comprising approximately 6,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as Baldy Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFC292925A13B4F778D4C027BEB415BF2"><enum>(22)</enum><header>Scotchman’s peak wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Kootenai National Forest and the Idaho Panhandle National Forest comprising approximately 88,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Scotchman’s Peak Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB2933B74D91D4EDD9B1EED205B677482"><enum>(23)</enum><header>Buckhorn ridge wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Kootenai National Forest and the Idaho Panhandle National Forest comprising approximately 36,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Buckhorn Ridge Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF0EB50D9601B45F7A0236968875B755E"><enum>(24)</enum><header>Grassy top/hall mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Idaho Panhandle National Forest and the Colville National Forest comprising approximately 24,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Grassy Top/Hall Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6BCE3DA05FA041E088F633D4E82A7BAB"><enum>(25)</enum><header>Abercrombie-hooknose wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Colville National Forest comprising approximately 38,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Abercrombie-Hooknose Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H230DA94F4F6C42AFBF6D9202A17D67B2"><enum>(26)</enum><header>Harvey creek/bunchgrass wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Colville National Forest comprising approximately 6,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Harvey Creek/Bunchgrass Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4DD9B889C9C64201A378F27941B0B94C"><enum>(27)</enum><header>South fork mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Idaho Panhandle National Forest and the Colville National Forest comprising approximately 6,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the South Fork Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H52C911FAE56A49ADA4412D36B3BFC041"><enum>(28)</enum><header>Quartzite wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Colville National Forest comprising approximately 5,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Quartzite Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H23A1B950CFE9415E86FE8A86CC5C74A3"><enum>(29)</enum><header>South fork hungry mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Idaho Panhandle National Forest and the Colville National Forest comprising approximately 9,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the South Fork Hungry Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA908EBFACD0A4FC29712F54C03374D52"><enum>(30)</enum><header>Continental mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Idaho Panhandle National Forest comprising approximately 8,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Continental Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB0C5A67292A14D04B7CC3EF095342954"><enum>(31)</enum><header>Deep white wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Idaho Panhandle National Forest comprising approximately 8,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Deep White Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H80A80CBBE16E474284547CECE3B85D61"><enum>(32)</enum><header>Schafer peak wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Idaho Panhandle National Forest comprising approximately 6,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Schafer Peak Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0A58E59DBC8445E096557D2B10354451"><enum>(33)</enum><header>Upper priest lake wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Idaho Panhandle National Forest comprising approximately 13,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Upper Priest Lake Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9D88BAE0D2AC422686131E0BB6EF2FF3"><enum>(34)</enum><header>Long canyon/selkirk crest wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Idaho Panhandle National Forest and on land administered by the Coeur d’Alene Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 99,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Long Canyon/Selkirk Crest Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H97D20F2C99094661ABAA61D7D993FD31"><enum>(35)</enum><header>Lake estelle roberts wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Idaho Panhandle National Forest and the Kootenai National Forest comprising approximately 79,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Lake Estelle Roberts Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3E565DA0D35A4278ADBFBFCB3007A9E1"><enum>(36)</enum><header>Trestle peak wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Idaho Panhandle National Forest and the Kootenai National Forest comprising approximately 7,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Trestle Peak Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB52BEC46D99A4D09BEA8CB2A746217A3"><enum>(37)</enum><header>Beetop wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Idaho Panhandle National Forest comprising approximately 12,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Beetop Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDFB86B6BC3774316B8105272AA108DFC"><enum>(38)</enum><header>Packsaddle wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Idaho Panhandle National Forest comprising approximately 19,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Packsaddle Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2B17A5954E6C4EF59B207D63EB8B39FB"><enum>(39)</enum><header>Blacktail pend oreille wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Idaho Panhandle National Forest comprising approximately 5,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Blacktail Pend Oreille Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H238A4ECF2FB74168AAB8979176BB8F4F"><enum>(40)</enum><header>Magee wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Idaho Panhandle National Forest comprising approximately 35,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Magee Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2BF13C9A761E4F948041866E3448B3BD"><enum>(41)</enum><header>Tepee creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Idaho Panhandle National Forest comprising approximately 5,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Tepee Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3E5AFC474633439392966AA6F21BC800"><enum>(42)</enum><header>Trouble creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Idaho Panhandle National Forest comprising approximately 6,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Trouble Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB914BF640CF0433EB3ADB5A88375C056"><enum>(43)</enum><header>Graham coal wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Idaho Panhandle National Forest comprising approximately 10,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Graham Coal Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD2541B395D884FBA8937F28C4EC55828"><enum>(44)</enum><header>Kootenai peak wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Idaho Panhandle National Forest comprising approximately 5,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Kootenai Peak Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE41E657542A34BBBBD20121EF24B9E2D"><enum>(45)</enum><header>Katka wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Idaho Panhandle National Forest comprising approximately 10,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Katka Wilderness.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD16D4D76214F492B9B651F0D637D9B59"><enum>106.</enum><header>Greater Hells Canyon ecosystem</header>
 <subsection id="H13AD7921A80C4C64A8E18130FDF4E5A3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to protect the unique and endangered Greater Hells Canyon ecosystem, the areas described in this section are hereby designated as wilderness.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEF642BBF1D5D4FF8A10856B76077D17D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Hells Canyon Wilderness Additions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following areas, consisting of a total of approximately 394,000 acres, are incorporated into the Hells Canyon Wilderness:</text>
 <paragraph id="HFB52A0DD8A33436EA2F082870020632A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rapid river addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Payette National Forest and the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests comprising approximately 76,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Hells Canyon Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H92A8432A2F28458FB0EF3DB02475236A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Salmon face addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests comprising approximately 9,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Hells Canyon Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7ABBE8B829F141FA9243D17FB49DC6DF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Klopton creek/corral creek addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests comprising approximately 21,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Hells Canyon Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H04163FF9097B4C99B8DC57595805500A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Big canyon addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests comprising approximately 14,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Hells Canyon Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6C2C13665672444CB312221B40CAE11E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Other hells canyon wilderness addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Wallowa-Whitman National Forest comprising approximately 264,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Hells Canyon Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8F78DF885F8E40A3B909E51677867C8C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eagle Cap Wilderness Additions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain Federal land within the Wallowa-Whitman National Forest comprising approximately 100,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Eagle Cap Wilderness.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2F4C0D0AA1C34D219FAAD1BC127CC389"><enum>(d)</enum><header>New National Wilderness Preservation System Components</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following areas are designated as new components of the National Wilderness Preservation System:</text>
 <paragraph id="HB6842F58BEA34EE8AB300364223CCEC6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Lake fork wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Wallowa-Whitman National Forest comprising approximately 12,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Lake Fork Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2CCEF01C22F5453FA6202619EA2CF277"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Castle ridge wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Wallowa-Whitman National Forest comprising approximately 7,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Castle Ridge Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H359E4A0E99A54AF4AF84995B3828E018"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Homestead wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Wallowa-Whitman National Forest comprising approximately 6,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Homestead Wilderness.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H174F0B0BE89D4432B214D4C85FCDF91D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>107.</enum><header>Islands in the Sky Wilderness</header>
 <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H09CD95D8FD5240E1B11C61AC8A884D43"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to protect the unique and increasingly isolated ecological treasure of island mountain ranges in the Northern Rockies Bioregion, the areas described in this section are hereby designated as wilderness.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA6479836D2494CDD95D0DB92ECA9A3D0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Wenaha-Tucannon Wilderness Additions</header><text>The following areas are incorporated into the Wenaha-Tucannon Wilderness:</text> <paragraph id="H2421287D032D411D8B41FED5A9287671"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Upper tucannon addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Umatilla National Forest comprising approximately 13,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Wenaha-Tucannon Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3EF3B720610444928F6B2362D8A82293"><enum>(2)</enum><header>W-<enum-in-header>T</enum-in-header> addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Umatilla National Forest comprising approximately 2,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Wenaha-Tucannon Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEC442F13396C443AA691F0C2115A0FCF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Meadow creek addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Umatilla National Forest comprising approximately 2,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Wenaha-Tucannon Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1D7DA640F0754AE3BB7C6CDC588EA654"><enum>(c)</enum><header>North Fork John Day Wilderness Additions</header><text>The following areas are incorporated into the Wenaha-Tucannon Wilderness:</text> <paragraph id="H5360903C64524EFDB95FF087B558CC84"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Greenhorn mountain addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Malheur National Forest and the Wallowa-Whitman National Forest comprising approximately 24,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the North Fork John Day Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HECB96DB7A5EE4D1A939626629AFD7589"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Jumpoff joe addition to north fork john day wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Malheur National Forest and the Umatilla National Forest comprising approximately 7,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the North Fork John Day Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBB24B563773749F583DCC197A9C55CCB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Twin mountain addition to north fork john day wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Wallowa-Whitman National Forest comprising approximately 20,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the North Fork John Day Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA35F405C57C845EAADA39F71EDD9B637"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Cloud Peak Wilderness Additions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain Federal land within the Bighorn National Forest and land administered by the Worland Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 203,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Cloud Peak Wilderness.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4621D302304F4702B97826AB471C3E29"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Monument rock wilderness addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Malheur National Forest comprising approximately 5,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Monument Rock Wilderness.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H54ED32A47FBE4069A1791F98BEFB75E6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Mount naomi wilderness addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 28,000 as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Mount Naomi Wilderness.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD88B8299F8804498913F8721E8C67D5A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>New National Wilderness Preservation System Components in the Kettle Mountains</header><text>The following areas within the Kettle Mountains are designated as new components of the National Wilderness Preservation System:</text>
 <paragraph id="HD80A4DF37BD344F39BF4FF894A2B4C71"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Thirteen mile wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Colville National Forest comprising approximately 12,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Thirteen Mile Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA5C5C4B411EE4CD4B682AC697AE59055"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Bald snow wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Colville National Forest comprising approximately 20,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Bald Snow Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H70F3B7A4C18148E49AAC09A850661480"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Copper/kettle wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Colville National Forest comprising approximately 81,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Copper/Kettle Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC86804F38C214C608A528D16973D4835"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Huckleberry south wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Colville National Forest comprising approximately 10,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Huckleberry South Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H72285343755F4543ACD867D9FB5E5942"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Cougar mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Colville National Forest comprising approximately 6,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Cougar Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCAF4CC9AD0F841BDA776424E1B3851B8"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Owl mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Colville National Forest comprising approximately 15,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Owl Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H92BCBFDF895D478895CEAAFAC37923AC"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Deer kettle wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Colville National Forest comprising approximately 6,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Deer Kettle Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCE3146B4AB5D4FFCBAA0E6DB17263019"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Jackknife wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Colville National Forest comprising approximately 9,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Jackknife Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCB48781D7C1E4B66A8947CAB21FAF7F1"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Paradise wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Colville National Forest comprising approximately 9,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Paradise Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD80246E5A2A84362B349A79E1EF35002"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Bulldog mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Colville National Forest comprising approximately 7,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Bulldog Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB317341308AD49B2B42555EF60AC4163"><enum>(h)</enum><header>New National Wilderness Preservation System Components in the Big Horn Mountains</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following areas within the Big Horn Mountains are designated as new components of the National Wilderness Preservation System:</text>
 <paragraph id="H8D60E0FAEFA247409EDE6568CC0B84CC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Little bighorn wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Bighorn National Forest comprising approximately 120,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Little Bighorn Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H240472A46F23410D87164DFAF03A6B6D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Walker prairie wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Bighorn National Forest comprising approximately 51,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Walker Prairie Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5495795B76524E65B4DADC514DD71112"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Devil’s canyon wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Bighorn National Forest comprising approximately 32,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Devil’s Canyon Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H36FCD658EEFD419F81165E29DBB951FD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Hideout creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Bighorn National Forest comprising approximately 9,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Hideout Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA7C1B2AE56FD4F2DBDE8CE66529B5E5E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Bear rocks wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land comprising approximately 25,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Bear Rocks Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H252A9D8A1020421AA11506D14D0EF96C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Horse creek mesa wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Bighorn National Forest comprising approximately 42,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Horse Creek Mesa Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H019B1A9FB52E4654899013D433FDA0FD"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Petes hole wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Bighorn National Forest comprising approximately 20,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Petes Hole Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD4A7D49256A746C09A462FA6A5D8FA43"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Grommund creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Bighorn National Forest comprising approximately 6,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Grommund Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAF9B430CDBD44FD59DD56D53AE1CDDAE"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Hazelton peaks wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Bighorn National Forest comprising approximately 9,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Hazelton Peaks Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H35EE9543ED3448259D959913F7543039"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Leigh creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Bighorn National Forest comprising approximately 7,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Leigh Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC3D8FE7143634A4B832027D0038334B7"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Medicine lodge wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Bighorn National Forest and land administered by the Worland Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 23,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Medicine Lodge Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8865F6C4023D4EC7B591274F02A0E82E"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Alkali creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land administered by the Worland Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 17,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Alkali Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAA3150D3930049239F43719810743D93"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Trapper creek canyon wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land administered by the Worland Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 17,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Trapper Creek Canyon Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCEA9F0D147BA4EC3AA426AF723241F01"><enum>(14)</enum><header>North fork powder river wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land administered by the Buffalo Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 15,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the North Fork Powder River Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4EC063F722F94AC3962B5BA2C5BBD459"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Gardner mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land administered by the Buffalo Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 18,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Gardner Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H89317E70917D4B7D957E2CADFC1E07A6"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Honeycombs wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land administered by the Worland Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 53,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Honeycombs Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6D87D4ED142C4AE390CC015C5511BCF9"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Buffalo creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land administered by the Worland Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 27,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Buffalo Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF2833E0050DC432AB830042A274B534C"><enum>(18)</enum><header>Lysite mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land administered by the Worland Lander Field Offices of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 10,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Lysite Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H821FC539388B496D98B84E7E6262155B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>New National Wilderness Preservation System Components in the Pryor Mountains</header><text>The following areas within the Pryor Mountains are designated as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System:</text>
 <paragraph id="H43CE83A2A49C426CB45A9134772F2D30"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Lost water canyon wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Custer Gallatin National Forest, the Bighorn National Recreation Area, and land administered by the Billings Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 63,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Lost Water Canyon Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF7928439A6DD44509A599BDCA168FCB2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Big pryor mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Custer Gallatin National Forest comprising approximately 39,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Big Pryor Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6ADE9212E6C44826A512B63148E17CDF"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Other New National Wilderness Preservation System Components</header><text>The following areas are designated as new components of the National Wilderness Preservation System:</text>
 <paragraph id="HDD2F7B32E589450CB81071653AEF8907"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Willow springs wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Umatilla National Forest comprising approximately 9,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Willow Springs Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9367E809758948919450B61F99907398"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Asotin creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Umatilla National Forest comprising approximately 16,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Asotin Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDA95AA410B4B4084B9314CE90AEFB8D5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Spangler wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Umatilla National Forest comprising approximately 6,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Spangler Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0F9E50C0848E4CE6B1FDD715A9374B9B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Wenatchee creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Umatilla National Forest comprising approximately 19,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Wenatchee Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H93AA646284504978A300E63D6B3DA641"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Walla walla wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Umatilla National Forest comprising approximately 35,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Walla Walla Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H022F5640476C4230B1363BB8CA1AD9AD"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Grand ronde wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Umatilla National Forest and the Wallowa-Whitman National Forest comprising approximately 19,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Grande Ronde Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC2D30CFB495148878C73DFE2C5446388"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Texas butte wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Umatilla National Forest comprising approximately 8,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Texas Butte Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H00BA9C826078424E879B2A825EB66046"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Skookum wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Umatilla National Forest comprising approximately 9,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Skookum Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5CD55BAAC9B542DFB985179EF6EE5459"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Potamus wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Umatilla National Forest comprising approximately 6,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Potamus Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H88A4A555352C4ADF8B46EABD7A0E7B08"><enum>(10)</enum><header>South fork-tower wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Umatilla National Forest comprising approximately 16,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the South Fork-Tower Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H783885D535BC42AB9FD4EC1AA4B1B8D5"><enum>(11)</enum><header>East john day wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Umatilla National Forest and the Wallowa-Whitman National Forest comprising approximately 6,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the East John Day Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEC000E8B8AC641FDBDA4D6DAAA3C4473"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Horseshoe ridge wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Umatilla National Forest comprising approximately 6,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Horseshoe Ridge Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H174098FFBBEC4F8FA5AEC705C16EAA80"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Hellhole wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Umatilla National Forest comprising approximately 67,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Hellhole Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4010D9E535E740D99D824C96253669D1"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Mount emily wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Wallowa-Whitman National Forest comprising approximately 9,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Mount Emily Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDDE889F4CAB84694B39C37C604572A71"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Upper grande ronde wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Wallowa-Whitman National Forest comprising approximately 12,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Upper Grande Ronde Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEBDE68A603B3406E920F0E2FE3B37C4C"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Joseph canyon wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Wallowa-Whitman National Forest comprising approximately 24,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Joseph Canyon Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD69E0C6A11444614B23DAD1F4E54FDDF"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Tope creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Wallowa-Whitman National Forest comprising approximately 9,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Tope Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H54BF2AC1108444D69AE8648D2D4704EF"><enum>(18)</enum><header>Baldy mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Malheur National Forest comprising approximately 6,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Baldy Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5274381F4AC942C491039FBB6B280CE0"><enum>(19)</enum><header>Dixie butte wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Malheur National Forest comprising approximately 8,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Dixie Butte Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE159BAE7F8344855BBE0F035F3D2D257"><enum>(20)</enum><header>Murderers creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Malheur National Forest comprising approximately 21,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Murderers Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H01CA90E963864CF6B57C1E0ED9914F12"><enum>(21)</enum><header>Glacier mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Malheur National Forest comprising approximately 16,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Glacier Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H54006DD99BD94987B3F301F20AC6BE55"><enum>(22)</enum><header>Malheur river wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Malheur National Forest comprising approximately 6,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Malheur River Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB4D87E3A8C814112879F9EA12BF08068"><enum>(23)</enum><header>Mcclellan mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Malheur National Forest comprising approximately 23,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the McClellan Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7A73151DB0CF43618B52C5AC97A02C55"><enum>(24)</enum><header>Myrtle-silvies wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Malheur National Forest comprising approximately 11,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Myrtle-Silvies Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H01157494BD2241E2B8216B9E999070D3"><enum>(25)</enum><header>Nipple butte wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Malheur National Forest comprising approximately 13,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Nipple Butte Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H58E11A999AB94BC9A798809933EFD9E6"><enum>(26)</enum><header>West malheur wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Malheur National Forest comprising approximately 5,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the West Malheur Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HECEEC52EF8F8434E87BF43C3D691D0FB"><enum>(27)</enum><header>Shaketable wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Malheur National Forest comprising approximately 8,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Shaketable Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4450F2B2EBB0471FB37EFF60BFC8C090"><enum>(28)</enum><header>Utley butte wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Malheur National Forest comprising approximately 11,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Utley Butte Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7EB9E1C961014154B15F6C9C58AAB2F7"><enum>(29)</enum><header>Flint range wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest comprising approximately 73,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as Flint Range Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD598E143150F438BB67F88E8E53FF33C"><enum>(30)</enum><header>Fred burr wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest comprising approximate 6,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as Fred Burr Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H72813579E61E4295A34D68C476DD2267"><enum>(31)</enum><header>Elkhorn mountains wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Helena National Forest and land administered by the Butte Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 88,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as Elkhorn Mountains Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HABACD06CF34B4FB9A59D73B9FA371580"><enum>(32)</enum><header>Cache peak wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Sawtooth National Forest comprising approximately 27,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Cache Peak Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC993041DA11145219A4114CCA04F23FE"><enum>(33)</enum><header>Sublett wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Sawtooth National Forest comprising approximately 7,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Sublett Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H225EA145635D43CA867AE74FAA34857F"><enum>(34)</enum><header>Burnt basin/black pine wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Sawtooth National Forest comprising approximately 44,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Burnt Basin/Black Pine Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC5FACFCF4863414FBB75EA353C773554"><enum>(35)</enum><header>Mount harrison wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Sawtooth National Forest comprising approximately 30,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Mount Harrison Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE316F52945A94CA79F66355E92B8DAED"><enum>(36)</enum><header>Fifth fork rock creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Sawtooth National Forest comprising approximately 17,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Fifth Fork Rock Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6AC1281EDC414CC3AF0FDAB004556A2C"><enum>(37)</enum><header>Third fork rock creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Sawtooth National Forest comprising approximately 14,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Third Fork Rock Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5979D9400FFD4EF296C2E798AEBED931"><enum>(38)</enum><header>Cottonwood wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Sawtooth National Forest comprising approximately 11,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Cottonwood Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4F565C7EAFEF4A82A830B265425F0EA1"><enum>(39)</enum><header>Mahogany butte wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Sawtooth National Forest comprising approximately 21,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Mahogany Butte Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H11DAB15740AC4629BAAD89F8C60D8215"><enum>(40)</enum><header>Thorobred wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Sawtooth National Forest comprising approximately 6,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Thorobred Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE7EBB6C707B14841868726DA85799CA4"><enum>(41)</enum><header>Worm creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 42,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Worm Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0AE3A75AB9CF4D70A296C2A16C22E69E"><enum>(42)</enum><header>Swan creek mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 7,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Swan Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8FA4C1C7247347E9A6477F9F047C2146"><enum>(43)</enum><header>Gibson wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 8,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Gibson Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H088061AA2B424FE3A93CFC663D16601F"><enum>(44)</enum><header>Paris peak wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 9,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Paris Peak Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB936D332F128467EB1187365AAA9321C"><enum>(45)</enum><header>Station creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 9,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Station Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5F6002D97D8E40448014DB5E13873B82"><enum>(46)</enum><header>Mink creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 16,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Mink Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H46CCF301FA8641698394324DD7341D31"><enum>(47)</enum><header>Liberty creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 15,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Liberty Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB97D3292BBD84699A7956C72ADD72EA7"><enum>(48)</enum><header>Williams creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 10,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Williams Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H51922B6C8AA2456BAB2E68C91D5C5418"><enum>(49)</enum><header>Stauffer creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 6,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Stauffer Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8F7B0376C92B4AEE88C023C9F6E2C046"><enum>(50)</enum><header>Sherman peak wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 8,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Sherman Peak Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H92E77DA7D1204A99B24FA50361EEC5F0"><enum>(51)</enum><header>Soda point wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 23,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Soda Point Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H610C4410D63D443F9A2D5179B2445708"><enum>(52)</enum><header>Clarkston mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 16,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Clarkston Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB4A18A1411C940CC9D3AE2F6208AB73F"><enum>(53)</enum><header>Malad wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 7,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Malad Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H931D1A8EC9B842579F1D5F618400C0F2"><enum>(54)</enum><header>Oxford mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 41,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Oxford Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBA548EAB3411476FB563996EF943FAF4"><enum>(55)</enum><header>Elkhorn mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 42,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Elkhorn Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBA8E22D4AB5D4D61B94110EE638B5E99"><enum>(56)</enum><header>Bonneville peak wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 32,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Bonneville Peak Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5756650037244EA581EB37545B50DABB"><enum>(57)</enum><header>North pebble wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 5,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the North Pebble Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H82791C1546D544C8AB0FC9B7D9EF708D"><enum>(58)</enum><header>Toponce wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 18,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Toponce Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB33C8B372D604878BFED58419C38A157"><enum>(59)</enum><header>Scout mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 25,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Scout Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDC2AEF6679AF4071936AD0BEBCFBFD0E"><enum>(60)</enum><header>West mink area</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 20,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the West Mink Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H80BAF0DAB6D4475DBE7DF3D7685323A9"><enum>(61)</enum><header>Cuddy mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Payette National Forest comprising approximately 41,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Cuddy Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H702FFA52C6A2460BB7E27E4B082018B2"><enum>(62)</enum><header>Council mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Payette National Forest comprising approximately 17,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Council Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H24B6E02D66E044E79248956FCBDE5026"><enum>(63)</enum><header>Mccullough peaks wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land administered by the Cody Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 38,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the McCullough Peaks Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H86D34B36FD63423D9345AADD175684F2"><enum>(64)</enum><header>Tatman mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land administered by the Worland Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 25,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Tatman Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2B6E0CE76516464AA70AC3C632B1DF70"><enum>(65)</enum><header>Fivemile creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land administered by the Worland Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 24,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Fivemile Creek Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4F01F44672CA407997055DC5A51C5F9A"><enum>(66)</enum><header>Bobcat draw badlands wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land administered by the Worland Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 30,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Bobcat Draw Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC9280645D7514CDE9153CEDEAF1C21A8"><enum>(67)</enum><header>Cedar bighorn wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land administered by the Worland Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 39,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Cedar Bighorn Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H80E015704E3049CD8F49E90CB7DD877F"><enum>(68)</enum><header>Copper mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land administered by the Lander Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 7,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Copper Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H72C269B09EFB49698CCD16AB6A2AFB5A"><enum>(69)</enum><header>Fuller peak wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land administered by the Lander Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 10,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Fuller Peak Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H55E86F1736104010A8EA77209C3D1FB7"><enum>(70)</enum><header>Lysite badlands wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land administered by the Lander Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 14,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Lysite Badlands Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0AEF90EC83AC48CAB0131EA138B3CEEB"><enum>(71)</enum><header>Hoodoo mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the public lands administered by the Missoula Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 11,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Hoodoo Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H21611BD1117448D3B2F8061F83672BD4"><enum>(72)</enum><header>Wales creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal lands within the public lands administered by the Missoula Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 12,000 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Wales Creek Wilderness.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H9EB6FF1A03CF4EAB9E1B135E4DFC582D"><enum>108.</enum><header>Wilderness in biological connecting corridors</header>
 <subsection id="H34AC3D21463F41B2BD71B9372EFC4C77"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to protect the unique and increasingly isolated ecological treasure of island mountain ranges in biological connecting corridors, the areas described in this section, are hereby designated as wilderness.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3D2B5FC97204492A9ACA05325AB013D3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sapphire Mountains/Continental Divide Corridor</header><text>The following areas in this corridor, designated in title II, are hereby designated as wilderness:</text> <paragraph id="HE2930B54C52C4BDF9A570AFE0BEDB5E0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Welcome creek wilderness addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lolo National Forest comprising approximately 1,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated _____, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Welcome Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD8E2D09270084489A4FD6A3B0FC582F5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Anaconda-pintler wilderness addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Bitterroot and Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest comprising approximately 194,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Anaconda-Pintler Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF4B778C6AD3E4D45BA239EE1AFB02CB8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Stony mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Bitterroot, Lolo and Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest comprising approximately 120,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Stony Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H469727EA0D33420F95E37658FFCC9ABB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Quigg peak wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lolo and Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forests and land administered by the Missoula Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 77,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Quigg Peak Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5CCFEB913CA147479BF4AD04BDB95F34"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Silver king wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lolo and Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest comprising approximately 50,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Silver King Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H716B7C7CF02349BB9DBDA5C628FD3D7C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Emerine wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest comprising approximately 15,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Emerine Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE8112363BA9F4D26BC542176EAEC8E62"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Sleeping child wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Bitterroot National Forest comprising approximately 21,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Sleeping Child Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA50BC8A7DB1744FFBB7C75AEA17525F4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Jocko Mountains/Cabinet Mountains Corridor</header><text>The following areas in this corridor, designated in title II, are hereby designated as wilderness:</text> <paragraph id="HF93092BE96B446A8AFE37DAE373311C2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Mount bushnell wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lolo National Forest comprising approximately 42,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Mount Bushnell Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEB0180DDE2E4482BBAF0DC0CB241207F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cherry peak wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lolo National Forest comprising approximately 38,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated _____, which shall be known as the Cherry Peak Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0F76C9F5924D495E887E3F408ACAD3A6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Patrick’s knob/north cutoff</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lolo National Forest comprising approximately 17,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Patrick’s Knob/North Cutoff Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFA90DE920DC345A685E27C18F627301A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>South siegel/south cutoff wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lolo National Forest comprising approximately 13,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the South Siegel Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6B67B3C537B14E77ABDBFF15ABB9EF7A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>North siegel wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lolo National Forest comprising approximately 9,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the North Siegel Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1C437CF9A9B64549A393B70C1E86EA50"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Reservation divide wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lolo National Forest comprising approximately 19,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Reservation Divide Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1998A12B8BE44481B55252142E896D6E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Nine mile/Great burn corridor</header><text>The following areas in this corridor, designated in title II, are hereby designated as wilderness:</text> <paragraph id="HDF03AE33DB144565B744D8F9D3D27581"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Burdette wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lolo National Forest comprising approximately 16,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Burdette Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H96F3D123393946D5A9AE76BC40F3855C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Petty mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lolo National Forest comprising approximately 16,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Petty Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H248D339DA2514D569A8CBEF5F77DFFD5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Gillman creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lolo National Forest comprising approximately 8,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Gillman Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H38A974945E9A46B69888DFE73C63DDDA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Anaconda-Pintler-Divide corridor</header><text>The following areas in this corridor, designated in title II, are hereby designated as wilderness:</text> <paragraph id="H84A5383AC1D542528B3E68EAB0B6B1B1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Fleecer wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest comprising approximately 36,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Fleecer Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD7BDD07A484649659F3FFAC6FFFB9088"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Highlands wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest comprising approximately 21,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Highlands Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEB1CD12179344BDC86D369D376FB8891"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Basin creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest comprising approximately 9,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Basin Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2868D1ED10E847789BFD75B9B670CE37"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Granulated mountains wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest comprising approximately 14,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Granulated Mountains Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H005409D75DF84C77996CE3E393DE78F1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Lower boulder wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land administered by the Butte Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 6,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Lower Boulder Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9C901F5523C64E7A9EC16EF584DBAD70"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Ruby range wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land administered by the Dillon Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 27,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ___________, which shall be known as the Ruby Range Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1AC3CE3B6C124CB38B0261A452934EB4"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Humbug spires wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land administered by the Butte Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 12,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated _________, which shall be known as the Humbug Spires Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7AADFACB6C384CA29A33EEAFC62859A6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Ten lakes/Cabinet/Yaak corridor</header><text>The following areas in this corridor, designated in title II, are hereby designated as wilderness:</text> <paragraph id="H12275B81960E436390E97D3FAF35EAC5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Gold hill wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Kootenai National Forest comprising approximately 6,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Gold Hill Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H15E25628E7144A01B1380656148F3A89"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Gold hill west wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Kootenai National Forest comprising approximately 16,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Gold Hill West Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4F2919C37AF94A8780B8F981D1D639E9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Zulu creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Kootenai National Forest comprising approximately 6,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Zulu Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9235D9E022E24321A09DDAB1027C7BCE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Good creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Kootenai National Forest comprising approximately 8,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Good Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDA76B4CFA99D431D84EBEF1F1B2960B5"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Cabinet/Yaak/Great burn complex corridor</header><text>The following areas in this corridor, designated in title II, are hereby designated as wilderness:</text> <paragraph id="H091A007C2A004BC08B1DBA21ADF5644C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Maple peak wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lolo, Idaho Panhandle, and Kootenai National Forests comprising approximately 19,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Maple Peak Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9D61FB9B40294D1D808A838B2AB177FA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Storm creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Idaho Panhandle and Kootenai National Forest comprising approximately 8,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Storm Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H275A6DD36D6B4792BEFD66FCD9E27DC5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Hammond creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Idaho Panhandle National Forest comprising approximately 17,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Hammond Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2E22E6F75AB646BFB290C55A648FD304"><enum>(4)</enum><header>North fork wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Idaho Panhandle National Forest comprising approximately 31,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the North Fork Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE1948DFFD4A84A8D9B751F7A515F6E16"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Big creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Idaho Panhandle National Forest comprising approximately 76,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Big Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6DB22B21041143F3B1971B674E3DF4B0"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Bobtail peak wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Idaho Panhandle National Forest comprising approximately 12,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Bobtail Peak Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFCC1268F87C74CD4B3AF8B41191F8719"><enum>(7)</enum><header>East cathedral peak wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Idaho Panhandle National Forest comprising approximately 22,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the East Cathedral Peak Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8D047739157F4E6E9FC883F8A6B19743"><enum>(8)</enum><header>East fork elk wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Kootenai National Forest comprising approximately 7,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the East Fork Elk Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H31D318CF2A584781B7AB8229565B0DA1"><enum>(9)</enum><header>West fork elk wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Kootenai National Forest comprising approximately 5,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated _____, which shall be known as the West Fork Elk Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H631F2E4F9239498888CE04FC8E699749"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Spion kop wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Idaho Panhandle National Forest comprising approximately 22,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Spion Kop Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD88392A1DAC24778AC136ABB11D52DF7"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Roland point wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Idaho Panhandle National Forest comprising approximately 6,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Roland Point Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDEF285DE46D349B3BC77F3472714A9F0"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Trout creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Idaho Panhandle and Kootenai National Forests comprising approximately 39,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Trout Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H630FC43E313544308147FB527E3C1066"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Wonderful peak wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Idaho Panhandle and Lolo National Forest comprising approximately 6,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Wonderful Peak Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H63DAB036FB444B61B1B371976BB642D6"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Stevens peak wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Idaho Panhandle and Lolo National Forest comprising approximately 5,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Stevens Peak Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H31D36E45747E43DE8B53E5B13B27D149"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Evans gulch wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lolo National Forest comprising approximately 8,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Evans Gulch Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HED98156A0F224125AEC8875E1EB76D99"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Gilt edge-silver creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lolo National Forest comprising approximately 10,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Gilt Edge-Silver Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC1F3A5BAF2B0463CB475102613242993"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Ward eagle wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lolo National Forest comprising approximately 9,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Ward Eagle Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCA1FB35F33BB48CB91EB8DA422A19D72"><enum>(18)</enum><header>Marble point wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lolo National Forest comprising approximately 13,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Marble Point Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0F18EA3DD00E49F694AF331E127F68B9"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Anaconda-Pintler/Bitterroot mountains corridor</header><text>The following areas in this corridor, designated in title II, are hereby designated as wilderness:</text> <paragraph id="HE251CE88371C4CCD8F1564FF532A01C5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>West pioneers wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest comprising approximately 230,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the West Pioneers Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H195B7BDD4A7F40B99A89BCDF17AEFCBB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cattle gulch ridge wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest comprising approximately 19,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Cattle Gulch Ridge Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H52CF49C7173F4843B49D00005EFFA252"><enum>(3)</enum><header>East pioneers/call mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forests and land administered by the Dillon Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 160,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the East Pioneers/Call Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8A466DF5D11A4F2CBD9252AF8E05A3EF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Frank church/Greater yellowstone corridor</header><text>The following areas in this corridor, designated in title II, are hereby designated as wilderness:</text> <paragraph id="H7F624C6152864E22B47CBE28707D470D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Tolan creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Bitterroot National Forest comprising approximately 7,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Tolan Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA42AEF7A096B4936B9C16686E7323013"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Allan mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Bitterroot and Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 151,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Allan Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H24F917485198427BB8C7397E4DBEF6C8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Anderson mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge and Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 49,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Anderson Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H83298419671D41519D7B2B1162C140AA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>West big hole wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge and Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 210,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the West Big Hole Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBFFBB0E24A9D41E18FAD684295551201"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Goat mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge and Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 45,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Goat Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1638184BF5C74CD983AD60BE4BF41EA6"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Italian peaks wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge, Salmon-Challis, and Caribou-Targhee National Forest and land administered by the Salmon Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 305,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Italian Peaks Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9E0E1674F1FD402799A45014BC603686"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Garfield mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge and Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 92,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Garfield Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB916CBEA81214315856E080384A92B48"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Four eyes canyon wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest comprising approximately 8,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Four Eyes Canyon Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB3C5BAAB2BF2422EBA5010FD191C1C4C"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Tendoy mountains wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forests and land administered by the Dillon Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 83,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Tendoy Mountains Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD00AD60724E04C388D85672A48E22ED5"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Henneberry ridge wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land administered by the Dillon Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 12,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ___________, which shall be known as the Henneberry Ridge Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB073982A0AC94EA5ACF2FB562EC00182"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Black tail mountains wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land administered by the Dillon Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 15,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated _________, which shall be known as the Black Tail Mountains Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H398AFCD53C3A47FAB5A64AE74BB31146"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Saginaw creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest comprising approximately 9,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Saginaw Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7A5778D0568246DEB8D60516758F6633"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Tash peak wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest comprising approximately 53,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Tash Peak Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H53FAF97AC6194B7BAEF0F410C71D7799"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Beaver lakes wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest comprising approximately 7,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Beaver Lakes Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0E631E4293F940A6B263F4E6A380F9DA"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Agency creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 6,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Agency Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD7B6D9FB7EFE434EAD25CBA351DCFD45"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Freezeout wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Caribou-Targhee and Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forests comprising approximately 37,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Freezeout Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF5227FCB180F4D5A8F6EFBD29CABC84F"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Two top wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Caribou-Targhee National Forest comprising approximately 7,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Two Top Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF947F6972C554626A805065867C17302"><enum>(18)</enum><header>Centennials wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Caribou-Targhee and Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forests and land administered by the Dillon Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 88,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Centennials Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA483334F76624B9E8CE4F57A5131EF67"><enum>(19)</enum><header>Little bear creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest comprising approximately 7,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Little Bear Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0AADCE4054754076A301EA5B457632EF"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Lemhi mountains corridor</header><text>The following areas in this corridor, designated in title II, are hereby designated as wilderness:</text> <paragraph id="H20EE5C98D09C4F5298F3450C75641070"><enum>(1)</enum><header>North lemhi mountains wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Salmon-Challis National Forest and land administered by the Challis Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 309,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the North Lemhi Mountains Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC77CFC46CD794059AE83E1460411582E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>South lemhi wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Salmon-Challis, and Caribou-Targhee National Forests and land administered by the Upper Snake Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 173,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the South Lemhi Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBCC7D9E06201414AA3B96C8A7A0671AF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Warm canyon wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 7,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Warm Canyon Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4241E42F9D8A48C085597DC9F7DA9D3E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Goldbug ridge wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 13,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Goldbug Ridge Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF238CFA4240748B6BF5A1ED6C16E43BD"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Sal mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 14,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Sal Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6F216F110D5647DB9EF76B49BD44D69C"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Lost river range corridor</header><text>The following areas in this corridor, designated in title II, are hereby designated as wilderness:</text> <paragraph id="HFFE8A6F74D374633ABDC24722FE1EFC5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Borah peak wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Salmon-Challis National Forest and land administered by the Challis Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 155,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Borah Peak Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H576D65C478714283905090AAB56348CF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>King mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 87,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the King Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H33187FE83EC5408F9DA38B224FF0ADAC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Grouse peak wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 9,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Grouse Peak Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC54CBE54D34D4F7EBDB12F2F33264B08"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Red hill wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 15,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Red Hill Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2890DD83DB5948C8996034BE0F764865"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Jumpoff mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 14,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Jumpoff Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBF1177725F59430E985F66E1606E86F6"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Wood canyon wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 8,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Wood Canyon Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H80AC24E4D2C946588666811056BDE8BA"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Pahsimeroi wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Salmon-Challis National Forest comprising approximately 73,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Pahsimeroi Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7413B48FA0B7474E9251E1C868904DE7"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Burnt creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land administered by the Upper Snake and Challis Field Offices of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 22,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Burnt Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H102B66A3E97C4C1C8D121958952A0DF3"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Hawley mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land administered by the Upper Snake Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 17,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Hawley Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF36D44AF07144EB5BB5A9D67C0E20D9C"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Boulder/White clouds/Lost river range corridor</header><text>The following areas in this corridor, designated in title II, are hereby designated as wilderness:</text> <paragraph id="HB63D97E6CFB84D9FAFFAED01A240E942"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Jerry peak wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land administered by the Challis Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 28,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Jerry Peak Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA499C6C20AB64A479C7856FA7ED1FE5C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Jerry peak west wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land administered by the Challis Field Office of Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 12,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Jerry Peak West Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5EA17CEA82C7499384AE039FE0CCA03E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Corral-horse basin wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land administered by the Challis Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 47,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Corral-Horse Basin Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6EBD6BDA7F2C48CFBD322F76BE60C883"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Appendicitis hill wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land administered by the Upper Snake Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 22,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Appendicitis Hill Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8CF93EC6F3364646931BB7F5E3FFC0E3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>White-knob mountains wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land administered by the Upper Snake Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 10,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the White-Knob Mountains Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H25D61F7EEE7242609C494CFF6546C970"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Greater glacier/Greater yellowstone corridor</header><text>The following areas in this corridor, designated in title II, are hereby designated as wilderness:</text> <paragraph id="H18B083FC13A84D65A61EA8479F94C15F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Tenderfoot wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lewis and Clark National Forest comprising approximately 105,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated _____, which shall be known as the Tenderfoot Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5401E10C382F465D99ACD83082BDC6FE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Middle fork judith wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lewis and Clark National Forest comprising approximately 84,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated _____, which shall be known as the Middle Fork Judith Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6415A106A4944D3888D1ED927CBE987C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Pilgrim creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lewis and Clark National Forest comprising approximately 47,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated _____, which shall be known as the Pilgrim Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H73D4349A05DE449E8EFE11F1084905CE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Paine gulch wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lewis and Clark National Forest comprising approximately 8,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated _____, which shall be known as the Paine Gulch Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAFFDE8F49992449FAE9F0B4AC636718A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Sawmill gulch wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lewis and Clark National Forest comprising approximately 12,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated _____, which shall be known as the Sawmill Gulch Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0C15E9C24FC14B5CA740C15ACED5C9C0"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Spring creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lewis and Clark National Forest comprising approximately 18,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated _____, which shall be known as the Spring Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7D797DCA404441E6A035F2F59EE58ED5"><enum>(7)</enum><header>TW mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lewis and Clark National Forest comprising approximately 8,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated _____, which shall be known as the TW Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE0D5AA1ED7504CD4BBD550DBB45D42AD"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Big baldy wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lewis and Clark National Forest comprising approximately 43,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated _____, which shall be known as the Big Baldy Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6C28154C816141A28E9AE21E865BB051"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Stanford wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lewis and Clark National Forest comprising approximately 10,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated _____, which shall be known as the Stanford Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAFA8D0D4E2444AA59E84D79CD44966D1"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Tollgate-sheep wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lewis and Clark National Forest comprising approximately 25,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated _____, which shall be known as the Tollgate-Sheep Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1853A2F9325D493FB65A466BA62B2D74"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Mount high wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lewis and Clark National Forest comprising approximately 33,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated _____, which shall be known as the Mount High Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1E8698C9854944D88762FEA9091C46D8"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Bluff mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lewis and Clark National Forest comprising approximately 37,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated _____, which shall be known as the Bluff Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6189B21B6F4242F5ACD9985EEFB83CA0"><enum>(13)</enum><header>North fork smith wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lewis and Clark National Forest comprising approximately 9,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated _____, which shall be known as the North Fork Smith Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7729009AC96F458084F000727883D3D1"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Big snowies wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lewis and Clark National Forest and land administered by the Lewistown Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 105,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated _____, which shall be known as the Big Snowies Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H746E5322DCBD47048DE169BE6F8AF4E9"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Highwoods wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lewis and Clark National Forest comprising approximately 25,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated _____, which shall be known as the Highwoods Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H73F6512587F1400D95841BFB323B61A2"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Highwood baldy wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lewis and Clark National Forest comprising approximately 16,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated _____, which shall be known as the Highwood Baldy Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8FF9E99543ED4C9AB896F61D670E4BAF"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Calf creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lewis and Clark National Forest comprising approximately 10,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated _____, which shall be known as the Calf Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA472DD3C22BB4BB0A791B4D6714479BA"><enum>(18)</enum><header>Eagle creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lewis and Clark National Forest comprising approximately 6,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated _____, which shall be known as the Eagle Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4588A282E608437CA58097F5570EA6B4"><enum>(19)</enum><header>Castle mountains wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lewis and Clark National Forest comprising approximately 28,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated _____, which shall be known as the Castle Mountains Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD7CE836B8F274B8AA804D3EA96F8A60A"><enum>(20)</enum><header>Box canyon wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lewis and Clark National Forest comprising approximately 15,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated _____, which shall be known as the Box Canyon Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H88B5EDEB60B945BE8179D0C6B3EC23D7"><enum>(21)</enum><header>Crazy mountains wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Lewis and Clark National Forest and the Custer Gallatin National Forest comprising approximately 159,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Crazy Mountains Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H62C4108510AA4F5A8FA49D618B1B363F"><enum>(22)</enum><header>Gates of the mountain wilderness addition</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Helena National Forest comprising approximately 20,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be added to and administered as part of the Gates of the Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H082A30E877C548FAA4B2C79B62D33131"><enum>(23)</enum><header>Lazyman gulch wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Helena National Forest comprising approximately 11,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated _____, which shall be known as the Lazyman Gulch Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCDA5C5AB1CCA4B04B5988CCE417285F3"><enum>(24)</enum><header>Big birch pond wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Helena National Forest comprising approximately 19,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated _____, which shall be known as the Big Birch Pond Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE457D36561BD4B5A81A917046A1826A2"><enum>(25)</enum><header>Camas creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Helena National Forest comprising approximately 27,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Camas Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6F50F6A7FEAB49F4A1AF924685C40954"><enum>(26)</enum><header>Jericho mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Helena National Forest comprising approximately 12,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Jericho Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3097FA430065467E8456AB9633552779"><enum>(27)</enum><header>Irish gulch wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Helena National Forest comprising approximately 7,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Irish Gulch Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE0A24D0E0EDD466DB3F9FD128D7EAF17"><enum>(28)</enum><header>Grassy mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Helena National Forest comprising approximately 7,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Grassy Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7A16ED2FE84D4562ABE8C49598501690"><enum>(29)</enum><header>Middleman/hedges wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Helena National Forest comprising approximately 34,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Middleman/Hedges Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H603AE2FEB5444D8D8DA61B88293BD896"><enum>(30)</enum><header>Hellgate gulch wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Helena National Forest comprising approximately 17,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Hellgate Gulch Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7C683B6491BB4DD58CEED7DE80E60AE4"><enum>(31)</enum><header>Cayuse mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Helena National Forest comprising approximately 22,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Cayuse Mountain Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4B098BA6B940461EA3077BFF781771C9"><enum>(32)</enum><header>Electric peak/little blackfoot meadows wilderness, beaverhead-deerlodge and helena national forests</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Helena and Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest comprising approximately 53,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Electric Peak/Little Blackfoot Meadows Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2733982CD3FA45E49B6536C591DA82E7"><enum>(33)</enum><header>Whitetail-haystack wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest comprising approximately 73,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Whitetail-Haystack Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8BC012ACAB154DA083173C11CB38EB31"><enum>(34)</enum><header>O’<enum-in-header>N</enum-in-header>eil creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest comprising approximately 7,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the O’Neil Creek Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4C965A4361714552B00D4D352680FE28"><enum>(35)</enum><header>Bangtail wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Custer Gallatin National Forest comprising approximately 51,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, which shall be known as the Bangtail Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H69515B1DC00E478AB2026BCD4746F229"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Mt. leidy highlands/Wind river range corridor</header><text>The following area in this corridor, designated in title II, is hereby designated as wilderness:</text> <paragraph id="H504A2C683AAD4CAFA9591313065DAF46"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Fish lake mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land within the Shoshone National Forest comprising approximately 7,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated _____, which shall be known as the Fish Lake Mountain Wilderness.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HBC9E649B03564D90A9DD337777F166A9"><enum>109.</enum><header>Administration</header>
 <subsection id="H5B9AC76535754DB1B628E1CE61D9328E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Management generally</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, land designated as wilderness by this title shall be administered in accordance with the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</external-xref> et seq.) by the Secretary concerned, except that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7D16B1ED248E4033B822939208E67A5B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any reference in the Wilderness Act to the effective date of the Wilderness Act or any similar reference shall be deemed to be a reference to the date of the enactment of this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA4CB812118A943998C5074CC46CCA487"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any reference in the Wilderness Act to the Secretary of Agriculture shall be considered to be a reference to Secretary concerned; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6B0C686763B843ADA1FA67D7DB71CCE1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Secretaries shall, to the greatest extent possible, coordinate the management of those wilderness areas containing land administered by more than one Federal land management agency.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H67E1AD8464FA43288DC882CCC48B8821"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Maps and description</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary concerned shall file a map and legal description of the land designated as wilderness by this title with—</text>
 <paragraph id="H027907B2532C4DB094F41EEDEADBE304"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCA237E03840E47189397B178E8048936"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1FF0F82DA7984727A79C329765DDEEC9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Force and effect</header><text>Each map and legal description shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act, except that the Secretary concerned may correct clerical and typographical errors in the maps and legal descriptions.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H122CB5C560AA4343B761D941563A846A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>Each map and legal description filed under subsection (a) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the Office of the Chief of the Forest Service, the Office of the Director of the Bureau of Land Management, or the Office of the Director of the National Park Service, as appropriate.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H804AF48DDDED40B8A77296FE5B583D71"><enum>110.</enum><header>Water</header>
 <subsection id="H5B01834BA44F4BDCBED3A85CAB994EF9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reservation</header><text>With respect to the lands designated as wilderness by this title, the Congress hereby reserves a quantity of water sufficient to fulfill the purposes for which the lands are designated as wilderness. The priority date of such reserved rights shall be the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEDFD7A6387DC4CC59591D9AA363C424B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of the Interior, and all other officers of the United States shall take all steps necessary to protect the rights reserved by subsection (a), including the filing of claims for quantification of such rights in any present or future appropriate stream adjudication, in a court of the State of Idaho, Montana, Wyoming, Oregon, or Washington, in which the United States has been or is properly joined in accordance with section 208 of the Act of July 10, 1952 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/666">43 U.S.C. 666</external-xref>; commonly referred to as the McCarran Amendment).</text>
				</subsection></section></title><title id="H37C0D2B5B17848A885B42CFB253A75B1"><enum>II</enum><header>BIOLOGICAL CONNECTING CORRIDORS</header>
 <section id="HD51513420C8B4DB485DBDEBF211A64EE"><enum>201.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress makes the following findings:</text> <paragraph id="HEDCBB44E144548A3B9C5A82D9DF5736B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The most recent scientific information on ecological reserve design and function, including recent scientific information on species dispersal in response to a changing climate, points out the critical need for biological connecting corridors between the larger core ecosystem areas.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H375C6F10A799493AB62D579AC9171E45"><enum>(2)</enum><text>While none of the remaining major wild land ecosystems of the Northern Rockies Bioregion appears to be of sufficient size to perpetuate the full complement of self-sustaining viable populations of native wildlife, biological diversity, and full range of ecological processes on its own, it appears that an effective reserve system can be achieved if biological connecting corridors between the ecosystems are identified and protected.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H33F780368B53464886EE835F2C3C85B3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The wild land areas addressed by this title are located between the major core ecosystems of the region and are essential for wildlife and plant migration and genetic interchange.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8F189103F58A4CDA9A4D1BDC22A4D428"><enum>(4)</enum><text>These areas are some of the most beautiful and wild mountain ranges in the United States, including the Bitterroot, Sapphire, Lost River, Lemhi, and Bridger mountain ranges.</text>
				</paragraph></section><section id="H76453BD3B5CA47E6AB1B8EA15E54A5A0"><enum>202.</enum><header>Designation of biological connecting corridors</header>
 <subsection id="HAF0571E2643E41B4B6C566A0C4680838"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To protect the life flow of the Northern Rockies Bioregion, the areas described in this section are hereby designated as biological connecting corridors. The designated biological connecting corridors are of two types, areas designated as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System in title I and areas subject to special corridor management requirements under section 203 in this title. Each biological connecting corridor shall be known by the name given it in the subsection establishing it. Each map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the Office of the Chief of the Forest Service and the Office of the Director of the Bureau of Land Management.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H63F896BF6F404E168B79750A690D9AB5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sapphire Mountains/Continental Divide Corridors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain Federal land comprising approximately 120,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, administered by the Bitterroot, Beaverhead-Deerlodge, or Lolo National Forest and land administered by the Missoula Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management are designated as Sapphire Mountains/Continental Divide Corridor and shall be subject to the special corridor management requirements under section 203.</text>
 </subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2ABCC47025F44673B1ED979219D061C0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Jocko Mountains/Cabinet Mountains Corridor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain Federal land comprising approximately 129,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, administered by the Lolo National Forest are designated as Jocko Mountains/Cabinet Mountains Corridor and shall be subject to the special corridor management requirements under section 203.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEAC6FDA2F2D448A1B97A0D2ECD44D92D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Nine Mile/Great Burn Corridors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain Federal land comprising approximately 73,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, administered by the Lolo National Forest are designated as Nine Mile/Great Burn Corridor and shall be subject to the special corridor management requirements under section 203.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6AF674AA4C6F44C4A89CB66AE5B68511"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Anaconda-Pintler-Divide Corridors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain Federal land comprising approximately 260,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest and land administered by the Dillon or Butte Field Offices of the Bureau of Land Management are designated as Anaconda-Pintler-Divide Corridor and shall be subject to the special corridor management requirements under section 203.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9786AB06DAA74766A0B68702D3146671"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Ten Lakes/Cabinet/Yaak Corridors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain Federal land comprising approximately 310,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, within the Kootenai National Forest are designated as Ten Lakes/Cabinet/Yaak Corridor and shall be subject to the special corridor management requirements under section 203.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6939E2BE599B4FD39B48BEED6352640B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Cabinet/Yaak/Great Burn Complex Corridor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain Federal land comprising approximately 205,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, within the Idaho Panhandle, Lolo or Kootenai National Forest are designated as Cabinet/Yaak/Great Burn Complex Corridor and shall be subject to the special corridor management requirements under section 203.</text>
 </subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H21507BEE4C084E91903322CC54105EC3"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Cabinet/Yaak/Selkirk Corridors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain Federal land comprising approximately 96,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, administered by the Idaho Panhandle, Kootenai, or Colville National Forest are designated as the Cabinet/Yaak/Selkirk Biological Connecting Corridor and shall be subject to the special corridor management requirements under section 203.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA2F21D66EFF647A4929591ED57F6FDC0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Cabinet/Yaak/Canada Corridors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain Federal land comprising approximately 41,000, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, within the Idaho Panhandle or Kootenai National Forest are designated as the Cabinet/Yaak/Canada Biological Connecting Corridor and shall be subject to the special corridor management requirements under section 203.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H478515AFD59C42859015C6BB8252BC72"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Anaconda-Pintlar/Bitterroot Mountains Corridors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain Federal land comprising approximately 147,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest and land administered by the Dillon Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management are designated as Anaconda-Pintler/Bitterroot Mountains Corridor and shall be subject to the special corridor management requirements under section 203.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEA7007D43D3C4394A8E9D0A808C491F6"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Frank Church/Greater Yellowstone Corridors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain Federal land comprising approximately 642,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge, Bitterroot, Caribou-Targhee, or Salmon-Challis National Forest and land administered by the Dillon or Salmon Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management are designated as the Frank Church/Greater Yellowstone Corridor and shall be subject to the special corridor management requirements under section 203.</text>
 </subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H520D425C680C4543B2C329DE74D8CBA3"><enum>(l)</enum><header>French Creek/Hells Canyon Corridors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain Federal land comprising approximately 3,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests or Payette National Forest and land administered by the Cottonwood Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management are designated as the French Creek/Hells Canyon Corridor and shall be subject to the special corridor management requirements under section 203.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2ADD6622002440ECA4F719005B463BA8"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Lemhi Mountains Corridors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain Federal land comprising approximately 88,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, within the Caribou-Targhee or Salmon-Challis National Forest and land administered by the Upper Snake or Challis Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management are designated as the Lemhi Mountains Corridor and shall be subject to the special corridor management requirements under section 203.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5C854A99564C4045AA6330FB6FAA7073"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Lost River Range Corridors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain Federal land comprising approximately 64,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, within the Salmon-Challis National Forest and land administered by the Upper Snake or Challis Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management are designated as the Lost River Range Corridor and shall be subject to the special corridor management requirements under section 203.</text>
 </subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2AFED74D581D434FA5D57865E9F1A9F7"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Frank Church Complex/Lemhi Range Corridors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain Federal land comprising approximately 3,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, within the Salmon-Challis National Forest and land administered by the Challis Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management are designated as the Frank Church Complex/Lemhi Range Corridor and shall be subject to the special corridor management requirements under section 203.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDDD2298BD0D84929972D78A84F2C6959"><enum>(p)</enum><header>Boulder/White Clouds/Lost River Range Corridors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain Federal land comprising approximately 88,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, within the Salmon-Challis National Forest and land administered by the Upper Snake or Challis Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management are designated as the Boulder/White Clouds/Lost River Range Corridor and shall be subject to the special corridor management requirements under section 203.</text>
 </subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HED1FD756D2D449D997B369A5829CEA14"><enum>(q)</enum><header>Bitterroot/Lemhi Corridors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain Federal land comprising approximately 20,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, within the Salmon-Challis National Forest and land administered by the Challis Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management are designated as the Frank Church Complex/Lemhi Range Corridor and shall be subject to the special corridor management requirements under section 203.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8A303FDFE34D472B930E3D61F3B66839"><enum>(r)</enum><header>Greater Glacier/Greater Yellowstone Corridors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain Federal land comprising approximately 542,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, within the Custer Gallatin, Helena or Lewis and Clark National Forest and land administered by the Lewistown Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management are designated as the Greater Glacier/Greater Yellowstone Corridor and shall be subject to the special corridor management requirements under section 203.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H05C7D23B19B64115A69CCE6DC583F59C"><enum>(s)</enum><header>Mt. Leidy Highlands/Wind River Range Corridors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain Federal land comprising approximately 69,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>_____</quote> and dated ______, within the Bridger-Teton or Shoshone National Forest and land administered by the Lewistown Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management are designated as the Mt. Leidy Highlands/Wind River Range Corridor and shall be subject to the special corridor management requirements under section 203.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HEFEDAE100C1E4FC4B84E264B40E61947"><enum>203.</enum><header>Treatment of biological connecting corridors</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Those portions of the biological connecting corridors designated by section 202 are hereby designated as special corridor management areas and shall be managed according to the Multiple-Use Sustained-Yield Act of 1960 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/528">16 U.S.C. 528</external-xref> et seq.) and other applicable laws, and in the following manner:</text>
 <paragraph id="H1936CAA650324610805C0C448868323C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The practice of even-aged silvicultural management and timber harvesting is prohibited within the special corridor management areas.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC0A80239427340529D6545B65018B557"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to valid existing rights, mining, oil, and gas exploration and development and new road construction or reconstruction is prohibited within the special corridor management areas.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6FBAFD332EFD4619BA00D0A0BB6073BB"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal land management agency responsible for the administration of a special corridor management area or portion thereof shall take immediate steps to ensure that road densities within the biological connecting corridor approach, as nearly as possible, zero miles of road per square mile of land area. Such road density shall not exceed 0.25 miles per square mile, using the method known as the <quote>moving window</quote> method.</text>
				</paragraph></section><section id="H730348DEFDCA4FC69F07E7D126B0FB9B"><enum>204.</enum><header>Applicability of title</header>
 <subsection id="H321FAEB484F34078B0DE69D0366DB913"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Federal Land Management Agencies</header><text>This title shall apply only to National Forest System lands and lands under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Land Management and the United States Fish and Wildlife Service.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H305A899CC2F24637BAB67CB8DFCB785A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Private Land and landowners</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Private lands are not affected by this title. No private landowner whose lands are adjacent to the designated connecting corridors shall be compelled, under any circumstances, to comply with this title. However, private landowners may enter into cooperative agreements with the Federal Government on a willing participant or willing seller basis to include their land in a biological connecting corridor.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="HE3EE08174BF442F3BF6709921001A3A9"><enum>205.</enum><header>Cooperative agreements and land trades and acquisitions</header>
 <subsection id="H4BB248A099E54F46B110F7D3F370AAB7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Cooperative Agreements</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall seek to enter into cooperative agreements with private, State, and corporate landowners and sovereign Indian tribes whose lands are adjacent to the designated connecting corridors, when such agreements would benefit the ecological integrity and function of the designated corridor.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFDD9764ADB494CE1A362EA193E07DC97"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Land Trades and Acquisitions</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior may undertake land trades or acquisitions in order to accomplish the purposes of this title when the Secretary concerned considers such action to be appropriate.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1DCD4C1FAB08452FA19ED763F44B11D1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>As part of the report required by section 501, the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior shall describe the progress of cooperative agreements, acquisitions, and proposed land exchanges sought pursuant to this section.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H4CB4F3C98AE5476B8641EF6090D2A6F3"><enum>206.</enum><header>Exemption of certain roads and highways</header>
 <subsection id="HF2DD155EA1DD41A683E8A64837159A09"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text>The roads and highways referred to in subsection (b) are expressly exempted from the provisions of this title. In the event that any county, State, Federal, or private road has been mistakenly omitted from this list, it is deemed to be incorporated by reference.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1EC12DA1ACA14B1088CB95FDD2C42C8C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Description</header><text>The roads and highways referred to in subsection (a) are the following:</text> <paragraph id="HF82D167C4C4C4755A690FDF2A8DF231D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>United States Highways 2, 10, 12, 20, 89, 91, 93, 95, and 287.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCCEEDE0A56614897AF1C057C8BA8381B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Interstate Highways 15 and 90.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE81AFE988DB645BC9E406516D9C9283C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Idaho State Highways 3, 28, 29, and 87.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5B94896C7CD1432AB5F7A23AABFBD74B"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Montana State Highways 2, 37, 38, 41, 43, 56, 58, 83, 87, 135, 200, 278, 287, 293, 294, 298, and 324.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H254DFF0E97FB4D15AE5754ECF0963C43"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Montana Secondary Roads 92, 278, 279, 294, 298, 324, 411, and 508.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF847EA2F90E347EA9882313628C231E6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Thompson Pass Road, Montana-Idaho.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC9456991EA042D8BF286AB8A1964303"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Moyie Springs to East Port Road, Idaho.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H73D5215B64474CE9B8E2C7B7A652D985"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The Red Rock Pass Road, Montana.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE5467012768D469E9070F357F6773CEC"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Boundary County, Idaho, Routes 3, 18, 34, and 47.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD12895CC8A2F4B1380937E2FB48605FD"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Lolo National Forest Route 102.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3AB9FF5E29E24D89941E1E2429701D8A"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Gallatin National Forest Route 259.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE770E4038E794C44A4A2AC8AB6B09DE8"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Kelly Canyon and Middle Fork Canyon Roads, Gallatin National Forest.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFD61DD6D3CD54361BC4123A6C7B2D12D"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Lewis and Clark County, Montana, Roads 4, 164, 280, 287, and 291.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5F2BDB6DCC6A40B7B20E4075696F903E"><enum>(14)</enum><text>The Beaverhead-Deerlodge to Basin Road, Montana.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H848C49D3F23A4029A1E353C2B530986B"><enum>(15)</enum><text>The Marysville to Avon Road, Montana.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCFDC2A3A113341AE84263499DC3FCFAA"><enum>(16)</enum><text>The Pahsimeroi Road, Butte County, Idaho.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="H7BB8DA0D97044531A200C127071C72E4"><enum>III</enum><header>WILD AND SCENIC RIVERS DESIGNATIONS</header>
 <section id="HB318337BE7F841E1867AE9F881BECC9D"><enum>301.</enum><header>Designation of wild and scenic rivers in Idaho, Montana, and Wyoming</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3(a) of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1274">16 U.S.C. 1274(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H5AF87C1605A6470D98CDA1A5D7990800" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="idEAB231AC4828482AACDDFF68E7F48B2F" indent="up1"><enum>(213)</enum><header>South Fork Payette, Idaho</header><text>The segment within the Boise and Sawtooth National Forests from the Sawtooth Wilderness Boundary downstream approximately 54 miles to confluence with the Middle Fork and then downstream on the main stem to the confluence with the North Fork, as generally depicted on the boundary map entitled <quote>South Fork Payette Wild River</quote> and dated January 2003, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id44232CA944BA4855ACF430824D6AB3D3" indent="up1"><enum>(214)</enum><header>Middle Fork Payette, Idaho</header><text>The segment within the Boise National Forest from Railroad Pass downstream approximately 33 miles to the national forest boundary, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4ED495F2E06C4AE19E41CF480F24FE81" indent="up1"><enum>(215)</enum><header>Deadwood, Idaho</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment within the Boise National Forest comprising from Threemile Creek downstream approximately 22 miles to the South Fork of the Payette, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id146A8681D9E14E739A6CA97AA81174E6" indent="up1"><enum>(216)</enum><header>Upper Priest, Idaho</header><text>The segment within the Panhandle National Forest from the Canadian border downstream approximately 19 miles to Upper Priest Lake, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idE7D6EF7A623843C2BDC36634096702BB" indent="up1"><enum>(217)</enum><header>Coeur d’Alene, Idaho</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment within the Panhandle National Forest from the headwaters downstream approximately 58 miles to the national forest boundary, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idE41EF77CA3D34D949EE7903D4C91F75E" indent="up1"><enum>(218)</enum><header>Little North Fork Clearwater, Idaho</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment within the Idaho Panhandle National Forest and the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests from the headwaters downstream approximately 37 miles to the National Forest boundary, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4218A544A3024F06B5AFC99704081D66" indent="up1"><enum>(219)</enum><header>Kelly Creek, Idaho</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests from its headwaters downstream approximately 31 miles to the North Fork of the Clearwater River, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0B9E06482B7C4BE5B48D9C11AE922252" indent="up1"><enum>(220)</enum><header>Cayuse Creek, Idaho</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests from its headwaters downstream approximately 39 miles to the confluence of Kelly Creek, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idAD252EC583EA4EAAA1CCE641C83D678A" indent="up1"><enum>(221)</enum><header>Bargamin Creek, Idaho</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests, comprising approximately 21 miles, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8BD0E7DA195D40F1913F9FDCD7B6E155" indent="up1"><enum>(222)</enum><header>Lake Creek, Idaho</header><text>The segment within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests from the wilderness boundary downstream approximately 10 miles to Crooked Creek, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idB305758EDDCE4E84A158CA47F0F57357" indent="up1"><enum>(223)</enum><header>Meadow Creek, Idaho</header><text>The segment within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests from its headwaters downstream approximately 34 miles to its confluence with the Selway River, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8BF7F1E21A2743179E6FAB19062A7973" indent="up1"><enum>(224)</enum><header>Running Creek, Idaho</header><text>The segment within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests comprising approximately 20 miles, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="id75E044768C474A80B60B7EDED6FEF57B" indent="up1"><enum>(225)</enum><header>Salmon, Idaho</header>
 <subparagraph id="id8293B5761F9440FF859C6135CBD71BBC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Vinegar creek</header><text>The segment within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests and Payette National Forest from Vinegar Creek downstream approximately 25 miles to the Little Salmon River, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC29C74F26D684C2694DA6526D0A09D46"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Salmon</header><text>The segment on public lands managed by the Bureau of Land Management from Hammer Creek downstream approximately 45 miles to the confluence with the Snake River, which shall be administered by the Secretary of the Interior.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA97EC1EDF1954C0580B5059ECBB9F9EA"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Salmon</header><text>The segment on public lands within the Sawtooth National Recreation Area from its headwaters downstream approximately 60 miles to the recreation area boundary, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3F24E0AEF9A84F4FA30BC87C9232A4A7" indent="up1"><enum>(226)</enum><header>East Fork Salmon, Idaho</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment within the Sawtooth National Recreation Area from the headwaters downstream approximately 42 miles to the recreation area boundary, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id23AFD79347884C678A45CDDE93017625" indent="up1"><enum>(227)</enum><header>North Fork Clearwater, Idaho</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests from the headwaters downstream to the Dworkshak Reservoir, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idECADA0BA185141A48135CCFBA6C4ADC1" indent="up1"><enum>(228)</enum><header>North Fork Coeur d’Alene, Idaho</header><text>The segment within the Panhandle National Forest from its headwaters south of Honey Mountain downstream to its confluence with the Coeur d’Alene River which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idF000E807B9D84A388587866937543213" indent="up1"><enum>(229)</enum><header>Pack, Idaho</header><text>The segment within the Panhandle National Forest from Harrison Lake downstream approximately 14 miles to the national forest boundary, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="idF0663E4D26204571B1672E04E0C03C05" indent="up1"><enum>(230)</enum><header>Henry’s Fork, Idaho</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment within the Caribou-Targhee National Forest from Big Springs downstream to the national forest boundary, except for Island Park Reservoir, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idC4CC7537D78744309FF39D542D1C4CA1" indent="up1"><enum>(231)</enum><header>Falls River, Idaho</header><text>The segment within the Caribou-Targhee National Forest from Yellowstone National Park downstream approximately 13 miles to the National Forest Boundary, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture as a wild river.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id809BC9F919744CB3AE6F7F5F49BB762C" indent="up1"><enum>(232)</enum><header>Lochsa River Watershed, Idaho</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests of the Lochsa River from the confluence of Colt Killed Creek and Crooked Fork downstream approximately 2 miles to the beginning of the Lochsa Recreational River, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5EE879060A484098BAA86E99C6515BAD" indent="up1"><enum>(233)</enum><header>Colt Killed Creek, Idaho</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests from its headwaters at Big Sand Lake downstream approximately 23 miles to its confluence with Crooked Fork, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id89A80E59E5D44092BA8979AAF14E26EE" indent="up1"><enum>(234)</enum><header>Moose Creek Complex, Idaho</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The main segment, including the North Fork segment, the East Fork segment, the West Moose segment, and the Rhoda Creek segment comprising approximately 86 miles within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id33E50B3E60FA44F8B828398302FEB805" indent="up1"><enum>(235)</enum><header>Bear Creek Complex, Idaho</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bear Creek segment, the Club Creek segment, the Paradise Creek segment, the Brushy Fork Creek segment, and the Wahoo Creek segment comprising approximately 70 miles within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id930C828D4E274D309D8AF5B11B5303AE" indent="up1"><enum>(236)</enum><header>Three Links Creek Complex, Idaho</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Three Links Creek segment and the West Fork Three Links Creek segment comprising approximately 23 miles within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idE9C46B83214944C780AC5E3B38137922" indent="up1"><enum>(237)</enum><header>Gedney Creek, Idaho</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests from its headwaters downstream approximately 14.5 to the confluence the Selway River, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9B5EF4A3699F4ABCA76669DA35659F36" indent="up1"><enum>(238)</enum><header>South Fork Clearwater, Idaho</header><text>The segment within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests from the confluence of the Red and American Rivers downstream to the Forest boundary, comprising approximately 40 miles, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id41CEACF3872A405287CFF99D94A0B882" indent="up1"><enum>(239)</enum><header>Johns Creek, Idaho</header><text>The segment within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests from the headwaters downstream to its confluence with the South Fork Clearwater, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7EB3ADD1A99D4322B16BE3A1E375AA65" indent="up1"><enum>(240)</enum><header>Slate Creek, Idaho</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment within the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests from the headwaters downstream the source approximately 15 miles to the forest boundary, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id691A4F6D11ED47E0935304AF3383F74A" indent="up1"><enum>(241)</enum><header>South Fork Two Medicine River, Montana</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment within the Lewis and Clark National Forest from its headwaters downstream approximately 10 miles to the Sawmill Flat Trailhead, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idEAFD266B9B92477BA782496ADC1BC155" indent="up1"><enum>(242)</enum><header>Badger Creek, Including the South and North Forks, Montana</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment within the Lewis and Clark National Forest from its headwaters downstream approximately 24 miles to the national forest boundary, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8F2AE8E6C0D94EF1B9B8B075D49442D3" indent="up1"><enum>(243)</enum><header>Dearborn, Montana</header><text>The segment within the Lewis and Clark National Forest downstream approximately 19 miles to the national forest boundary, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idACB03C8151444BCB8111D7B9B8EBBD00" indent="up1"><enum>(244)</enum><header>North Fork Birch Creek, Montana</header><text>The segment within the Lewis and Clark National Forest from its headwaters downstream approximately 7 miles to the national forest boundary, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id89634981E1384218AA1471394A64DCB4" indent="up1"><enum>(245)</enum><header>South Fork Sun, Montana</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment within the Lewis and Clark National Forest from its headwaters at Sun Lake downstream approximately 26 miles to its confluence with the North Fork, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id404CC9C8435B452090E9884F4192F8B3" indent="up1"><enum>(246)</enum><header>North Fork Sun, Montana</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment within the Lewis and Clark National Forest from the confluence of Open Creek and Fool Creek downstream approximately 27 miles, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idE2FD9371DF8849F99F3D3D2E0A2107AF" indent="up1"><enum>(247)</enum><header>Tenderfoot Creek, Montana</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment within the Lewis and Clark National Forest from the top of Tenderfoot Creek Falls downstream approximately 5 miles to the Smith River, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8B37BC2082A041A382EAF7A5E8268119" indent="up1"><enum>(248)</enum><header>Green Fork Straight Creek, Montana</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment within the Lewis and Clark National Forest from its headwaters downstream approximately 5 miles to Straight Creek, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idCE555EF1966E4877AEE0A0DA24EE3621" indent="up1"><enum>(249)</enum><header>Yaak River, Montana</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment within the Kootenai National Forest from the Yaak Falls downstream 46 miles to the mouth of the Yaak River at the junction of the Kootenai River, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1EB420403F2947028A040C90231F547E" indent="up1"><enum>(250)</enum><header>Kootenai River, Montana</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment within the Kootenai National Forest from the junction of the Fisher River downstream approximately 46 miles to the State line, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id556321F501B24AF6B18091FD45238067" indent="up1"><enum>(251)</enum><header>Bull River, Montana</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment within the Kootenai National Forest from the junction of the North and South Forks downstream 21 miles to the Cabinet Gorge Reservoir, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id858D9678F2E14D379D879889EDBD2069" indent="up1"><enum>(252)</enum><header>Vermillion River, Montana</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment within the Kootenai National Forest from the junction of Willow Creek, downstream 12 miles to the Noxon Reservoir, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id922195CA6BBD4B04B5E1903D2B0D3CB0" indent="up1"><enum>(253)</enum><header>West Fork Madison, Montana</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest from approximately the midpoint of Section 28, R. 2 W., T. 12 S., downstream approximately 21 miles to the West Fork Rest Area, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idCF1E4C1B97FB4F6E9ADF1364FBACB435" indent="up1"><enum>(254)</enum><header>Elk River, Montana</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest in the southeast corner of Section 16, R. 2 W., T. 11 S., downstream approximately 17 miles to the confluence with the West Fork of the Madison River, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4B35EFD0DBF341CDA5610E094F199DA1" indent="up1"><enum>(255)</enum><header>Browns Creek, Montana</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest from the west central part of Section 1, R. 14 W., T. 8 S., downstream approximately 4 miles to the forest boundary, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idF5CD751C93F341E283E5096F00C1CF1E" indent="up1"><enum>(256)</enum><header>Canyon Creek, Montana</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest from Canyon Lake downstream approximately 4 miles to the end of USFS road 7401, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id69EE8CB7B35943AB93C527377B229257" indent="up1"><enum>(257)</enum><header>Deadman Creek, Montana</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest from its headwater source downstream approximately 10 miles to the forest boundary, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id38EF474CF41F406E9BD68781C3B90332" indent="up1"><enum>(258)</enum><header>Smith River, Montana</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment within the Lewis and Clark National Forest from Tenderfoot Creek downstream approximately 12 miles to Deep Creek, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8E416757139A42B38FBE57F78CCF9EEA" indent="up1"><enum>(259)</enum><header>Middle Fork Judith River, Montana</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment within the Lewis and Clark National Forest from Arch Coulee Junction downstream approximately 5 miles to the national forest boundary, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idFE6973AB493A4F93943990F011A4A1B7" indent="up1"><enum>(260)</enum><header>Rock Creek Watershed, Montana</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segments within the Lolo and Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forests including the main fork of Rock Creek, the West Fork of Rock Creek, the East Fork of Rock Creek, the Ross Fork of Rock Creek, the Middle Fork of Rock Creek, the Carpp Creek segment, the Copper Creek segment, the Ranch Creek segment, the Welcome Creek segment, the Alder Creek segment, the Hogback Creek segment, the Wyman Gulch segment, the Stony Creek segment, the West Fork segment, and the Ross Fork segment, comprising approximately 134 miles, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2F2A283A74A94CF0A0D027DABCA3DC10" indent="up1"><enum>(261)</enum><header>Salt River, Wyoming</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment within the Bridger-Teton National Forest from the headwaters downstream approximately 12 miles to forest road 10072, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id59E8FE65755C4797AEE1CCED3B3CB733" indent="up1"><enum>(262)</enum><header>Swift Creek, Wyoming</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment within the Bridger-Teton National Forest from the source downstream approximately 8 miles to Periodic Spring, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0458820F93B5428AA2472B396A13352C" indent="up1"><enum>(263)</enum><header>Hoback River, Wyoming</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment within the Bridger-Teton National Forest from the source downstream approximately 10 miles to the end of forest road 30710, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idE5189A9A103D41DA9766E76000EA9FA9" indent="up1"><enum>(264)</enum><header>Thorofare, Wyoming</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment of the main stem within the Bridger-Teton National Forest from the headwaters downstream approximately 25 miles to the confluence with the Yellowstone River, and the headwaters of Open Creek downstream 10 miles to the confluence with the main stem, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idD80A7AE1967C41758969893301A4C437" indent="up1"><enum>(265)</enum><header>Atlantic Creek, Wyoming</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment within the Bridger-Teton National Forest from the Parting of the Waters downstream approximately 10 miles to the confluence with the Yellowstone River, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3C94A09CDCF4441D923AF0F78CB8868D" indent="up1"><enum>(266)</enum><header>Yellowstone, Wyoming</header><text>The segment within the Bridger-Teton National Forest from the headwater downstream approximately 28 miles to the boundary of Yellowstone National Park, which shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idAE4549D2A68941CB9432C5D176B55DCE" indent="up1"><enum>(267)</enum><header>Yellowstone River, Wyoming and Montana</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment within the Custer Gallatin National Forest and Yellowstone National Park from the southern boundary of Yellowstone National Park downstream approximately 102 miles to the mouth of Yankee Jim canyon, which shall be administered by the Secretaries of the Interior and Agriculture.</text>
					</paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</section></title><title id="H91DE823B09844A2FB6EDB741E0E23F8C"><enum>IV</enum><header>WILDLAND RESTORATION AND RECOVERY </header>
 <section id="HCB0AA87C50A8492A9675C91B85F25D16"><enum>401.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text> <paragraph id="H739D3838B1AA492FAC9E7EB56B4B7D51"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Recovery</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>recovery</term> means the restoration of lands damaged by land management activities to a natural untrammeled condition and the restoration of the undeveloped roadless character of such land.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8DA2FDB419264EF4A13712A493229DAA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recovery system</header><text>The term <term>Recovery System</term> means the National Wildland Restoration and Recovery System.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="HC9C3CC0476304AAF8E09F5A8DC056BE5"><enum>402.</enum><header>Restoration and recovery</header> <subsection id="H09642FB3B38C482A98B02AFA589FEC23"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Recovery areas</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following areas, consisting of a total of approximately 1,023,000 acres, as depicted on the maps dated ___ and entitled <quote>__</quote>, are designated as wildland recovery areas:</text>
 <paragraph id="HC3096DF777AA411ABD964F351A9399D0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Skyland area, consisting of approximately 10,000 acres administered by the Flathead National Forest.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H53FC086BE6364EB58AC34FF7C1E4AD4B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Hungry Horse area (except Hungry Horse Dam and Reservoir), consisting of approximately 205,000 acres administered by the Flathead National Forest.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3B687517C4BD44DEA3BF9A571E2CCF4C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Lolo Creek area, consisting of approximately 59,000 acres administered by the Lolo or Clearwater National Forest.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H21F54D599156482298E8B94A9698B0D1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Yellowstone West area, consisting of approximately 164,000 acres administered by the Caribou-Targhee National Forest.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H846CC2FD03CD400BBAFA76188EB9471F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Mt. Leidy area, consisting of approximately 70,000 acres administered by the Bridger-Teton National Forest.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5BB0C89CC0334BCA9A605F687FC6B40B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Cabinet/Yaak area, consisting of approximately 100,000 acres administered by the Kootenai National Forest.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4B6E90A97FCE495DB8BF51EEBD619A8B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Lightning Creek area, consisting of approximately 31,000 acres administered by the Panhandle National Forest.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA8C3F06736DE4DBD82602BA91ACA41E3"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Coeur d’Alene River area, consisting of approximately 372,000 acres administered by the Panhandle National Forest.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF22DDF4788E446C7BA79CE27B46EFFD3"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Magruder Corridor area, consisting of approximately 12,000 acres administered by the Nez Perce or Bitterroot National Forest.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HED7E19539307462BAD77376A6C7A9296"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text>The roads and highways and facilities referred to below are expressly exempted from the provisions of this title: All private, county, State, or Federal roads, including National Forest System roads, accessing existing authorized uses and any facilities such as a developed campground, ranger station, or other facilities deemed essential by the Forest Service.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2C8535C12E644527B13C925D0C5336C2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Magruder Corridor Area</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (b) of this section, the Secretary of Agriculture will recommend recovery and restoration on the part of the Magruder Corridor between Magruder Crossing and Dry Saddle under plans developed under section 403 of this title.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9DB71463841642189265EE6541217152"><enum>(d)</enum><text>Notwithstanding subsection (b) of this section, the Secretary of Agriculture may recommend recovery and restoration of any National Forest System road or Forest Service development or facility in any recovery area and the entire Magruder Corridor under plans developed under section 403 of this title.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H6B9AC1644BC141E69F79DFAECD87A97F"><enum>403.</enum><header>Management</header>
 <subsection id="H0CF38F66F02148FBAE58632DD7D0E1E6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Restoration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All lands within the Recovery Areas described in section 402(a) shall be managed so as to restore their native vegetative cover and reduce or eliminate invasive non-native species, facilitate native species diversity to the extent possible with climate change, stabilize slopes and soils to prevent or reduce further erosion, recontour slopes to their original contours, remove barriers to natural fish spawning runs, and generally restore such lands in their entirety to a natural roadless and wild condition.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H44C91E9078B14BCF9BF2D68DB47C8FD8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Water quality restoration</header><text>In the management of the Recovery Areas, special consideration shall be given to restoration of water quality in the Recovery Area.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5F3F9A00D16E4991BE5297AA20AAC35F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Recovery Plans</header><text>Not later than three years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall develop a wildland recovery plan for each Recovery Area. Each recovery plan shall detail necessary work and funding requirements needed to implement the management direction established under this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD46E6073A9A74A9AB887F7AA8A3C33E9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>The Secretary shall use measurable criteria to judge the success of recovery efforts taken pursuant to this section.</text>
				</subsection></section></title><title id="H43A92FD53D784F3ABB72EBB4D91ADA1F"><enum>V</enum><header>IMPLEMENTATION AND MONITORING</header>
			<section id="H0FCBC381902D441489CEF3E8034C503B"><enum>501.</enum><header>Implementation report</header>
 <subsection id="HF488797F68A04F07B90A92930FF8C3FD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report Required</header><text>Within three years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior shall jointly submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives a report that details the implementation of this Act. The report shall also detail any additional work and funding requirements necessary to achieve the purposes of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0FE8D2664F8F411DAD00D3D5F0106E57"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Preparation</header><text>The report shall be produced by a panel of independent scientists appointed by the National Academy of Sciences, in consultation with the Society for Conservation Biology.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="HE3832A30F32A48F3ABA39947EA4F52F9"><enum>502.</enum><header>Interagency team</header>
 <subsection id="H7EC1EF5F0F004B5B9DDEEB80530F52BE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior shall jointly establish an interagency team, containing equal numbers of participants from the public and private sectors, to monitor, evaluate, and make recommendations to ensure long-term results required by this Act.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="H7063755736854449B47EE6CD04718958"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Geographic Information System</header>
 <paragraph id="H75EE58D34F074ABDBA5DBDADDEEAD931"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Development</header><text>The interagency team shall develop a geographic information system for monitoring the Northern Rockies Bioregion. The geographic information system shall be based on satellite-gathered data and shall include comprehensive maps and databases to assist in the detection of changes in the Northern Rockies Bioregion.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB2E8DCE8A1764277AEA41C958C34BC1A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Types of information</header><text>The maps and databases included in the geographic information system shall be updated periodically to record the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE9D6DC40B4B14344A1D8FA5D0E891AE0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Vegetation cover (with species occurrence and densities).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7AAEEEEE09345248A55F71B44945BC5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Human impacts.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H27BAE586EE2341FBB6EBD5DF6A2B7C72"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Water and air quality.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5FF74DA0EB649CFA15F74254775A711"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Activities that bear on forest husbandry and restoration.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE750DED05C04411FA87B587BA9809643"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Status reports</header><text>The geographic information system shall include status reports on the progress of ecosystem protection, corridor consolidation, and forest recovery efforts and reports on the status of threatened and endangered species which are primary indicators of ecosystem health.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEB5212DFE91F4550BCE2B4F61B00CADF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Wildlife Movements</header><text>The interagency team shall assess the potential for facilitating wildlife movements across or under major highways and rail lines within the biological corridors established in title II. This assessment shall identify major crossing points and identify possible management actions to enhance the suitability of such crossing points as movement corridors, including underpasses, overpasses, and other methods for reducing the danger to native wildlife while facilitating movements within the Northern Rockies Bioregion.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="HFDBC28A5B481429CB0D560480583DA26"><enum>503.</enum><header>Roadless lands evaluation</header>
 <subsection id="H7DA85935FF884FED960C4A943DBBF006"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Evaluation Required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Roadless lands greater than 1,000 acres in size, that are located within the National Forest System in the Wild Rockies Bioregion in Idaho, Montana, Oregon, Washington, or Wyoming, and that are not designated as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System (under this Act or any other law) shall be identified and evaluated by the panel of independent scientists appointed under section 501. In identifying and evaluating these lands, the panel shall make use of existing satellite information and Geographic Information System data developed by the Forest Service, the Bureau of Land Management, and the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, in addition to other information sources. The panel shall study the role of such lands in maintaining biological diversity in the Northern Rockies and as part of the overall forest reserve system. The panel shall make recommendations regarding the management of the lands, and shall include the recommendations in the report required by section 501.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB01D5C6F88C848439EA03B19063F6DD0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After completion of the evaluation required by subsection (a), until Congress enacts a law stating otherwise, no new road construction or reconstruction, or timber harvest (except firewood gathering) shall be allowed in the lands described in subsection (a). In addition, subject to valid existing rights, no oil or gas leasing, mining, or other development which impairs the natural and roadless qualities of these lands shall be allowed on the lands.</text>
				</subsection></section></title><title id="H0728BFCFC47D43FFBA79BE5BA4529F9C"><enum>VI</enum><header>Additional Provisions Regarding Indian Tribes</header>
 <section id="H1160B0BA1E86493FA410B68EF497A3FE"><enum>601.</enum><header>Indian tribes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed to affect or modify any treaty or other right of an Indian tribe.</text>
 </section><section id="H50A5DBE38FDB465FB6D5E387F044B3F8"><enum>602.</enum><header>Federal trust responsibility</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act is intended to amend, alter, or give priority over the Federal trust responsibility to Indian tribes.</text>
 </section><section id="H6405205F819245B7B1F34C5B2BF61061"><enum>603.</enum><header>Exemption from freedom of information act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If a Federal department or agency receives any information related to sacred sites or cultural activities identified by an Indian tribe as confidential, such information shall be exempt from disclosure under section 552 of title 5, United States Code, popularly known as the Freedom of Information Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/552">5 U.S.C. 552</external-xref>).</text>
 </section><section id="H042DBEED3C5C44258805B079438761DF"><enum>604.</enum><header>Application of Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior may apply the provisions of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450">25 U.S.C. 450</external-xref> et seq.; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/93/638">Public Law 93–638</external-xref>) when appropriate in the implementation of this Act.</text>
			</section><section id="H28EC832316734F34BC2C5DA451BB0BEF"><enum>605.</enum><header>Native American uses</header>
 <subsection id="HBBDCC5359C3D4C939817D294F84FD44B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>For purposes of this section and section 505, the term <quote>protected areas</quote> means land designated by this Act as wilderness, wildland recovery areas, wild and scenic rivers, and biological corridors.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7A3B2EA8E14644A4BCFA35F08BDE78DC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Nonexclusive access</header><text>In recognition of the past use of portions of the protected areas by Native Americans for traditional cultural and religious purposes, the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior shall ensure nonexclusive access to these protected areas by native people for such traditional cultural and religious purposes. Such access shall be consistent with the purpose and intent of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/341">Public Law 95–341</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1996">42 U.S.C. 1996</external-xref>; commonly known as the American Indian Religious Freedom Act), and, in the case of land designated as wilderness by this Act, the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1121">16 U.S.C. 1121</external-xref> et seq.). The Secretaries, in accordance with such laws, upon request of an Indian tribe, may from time-to-time temporarily close to the general public use of one or more specific portions of these protected areas in order to protect the privacy of religious activities and cultural uses in such portions by an Indian people. As part of the preparation of general management plans for the protected areas, the Secretaries shall request that the chief executive officers of appropriate Indian tribes make recommendations with respect to assuring access to important sites, enhancing the privacy of traditional cultural and religious activities, and protecting cultural and religious sites.</text>
				</subsection></section></title><title id="H27EE715CB49540328BE2CAC071834CD0"><enum>VII</enum><header>RULES OF CONSTRUCTION</header>
 <section id="HA11783DAB3DA48C0AF27DF1E51E90929"><enum>701.</enum><header>Water rights</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed as a relinquishment or reduction of any water rights reserved, appropriated, or otherwise secured by the United States in the State of Idaho, Montana, Wyoming, Oregon, or Washington on or before the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
			</section></title></legis-body></bill>


