<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCA1115BC13B44BD69F96E506A73C6AB7" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3133 IH: Streamlining Environmental Approvals Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3133</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170629">June 29, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000299">Mr. Johnson of Louisiana</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000374">Mr. Abraham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000577">Mr. Graves of Louisiana</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001071">Mr. Jody B. Hice of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 to reduce unnecessary permitting delays by
			 clarifying associated procedures to increase economic development and
			 support coastal restoration programs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HCAD0E48642924F9F98AF7E4F5DCCBA50" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE17D2FCE6F72480D9570473776EF30FC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Streamlining Environmental Approvals Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SEA Act of 2017</short-title></quote> .</text> </section><section id="HBCAAE92609E34C85A6787CC9E25B97BD" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Addressing permits for taking of marine mammals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 101(a)(5)(D) of the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1371">16 U.S.C. 1371(a)(5)(D)</external-xref>) is amended as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="H60E792111F2B4F2292F3B0CFF785A6CE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In clause (i)—</text> <subparagraph id="HD257870598F34A85A2354702DD97A485"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>citizens of the United States</quote> and inserting <quote>persons</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H899CEBEB9EBD4B8F90BBFBFA42DB0F21"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>within a specific geographic region</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD1F5CAB09484B179EBB00E0CEEFF5C8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>of small numbers</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H223687B56FF54E6D9BAEAAED4CD768E6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by striking <quote>such citizens</quote> and inserting <quote>such persons</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H497ED402E257468588F1B98C8096EC6D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by striking <quote>within that region</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE63B204425F417593B1FDF7072B4E43"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In clause (ii)—</text> <subparagraph id="H7C3A864D611544CCA6B050DB637335FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subclause (I), by striking <quote>, and other means of effecting the least practicable impact on such species or stock and its habitat</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0402B02BD34A4E0F8BD860073A50C058"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subclause (III), by striking <quote>requirements pertaining to the monitoring and reporting of such taking by harassment, including</quote> and inserting <quote>efficient and practical requirements pertaining to the monitoring of such taking by harassment while the activity is being conducted and the reporting of such taking, including, as the Secretary determines necessary, </quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F5383B340CA4D5390DDBD26E032F3C9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1FC7C92D114E4B879AA662A878467C0F" style="OLC"> <quoted-block-continuation-text quoted-block-continuation-text-level="section">Any condition imposed pursuant to subclause (I), (II), or (III) may not result in more than a minor change to the specified activity and may not alter the basic design, location, scope, duration, or timing of the specified activity.</quoted-block-continuation-text><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7BACF0663E51447789A57F8AF95FF1E3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In clause (iii), by striking <quote>receiving an application under this subparagraph</quote> and inserting <quote>an application is accepted or required to be considered complete under subclause (I)(aa), (II)(aa), or (IV) of clause (viii), as applicable,</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBB11FA5B957542C98AD2C1FF071AEF94"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In clause (vi), by striking <quote>a determination of least practicable adverse impact on such species or stock under clause (i)(I)</quote> and inserting <quote>conditions imposed under subclause (I), (II), or (III) of clause (ii)</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB554C80CFB06412AAE2A22BF1015A6B3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>By adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9043D7130E45453CA03614B69F4B8E10" style="OLC">
					<clause id="HBC9BC3EDFAA14D48ADED56E19192882A" indent="up3"><enum>(viii)</enum>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H5C34CDAA0D364DC4B45B48EB06EC8F58"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall—</text> <item id="H8DCE89161BEA4745885C6F22750D1253" indent="up1"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>accept as complete a written request for authorization under this subparagraph for incidental taking described in clause (i), by not later than 45 days after the date of submission of the request; or</text>
 </item><item id="H8903095A5E094EBFA3B307BC37059961" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>provide to the requester, by not later than 15 days after the date of submission of the request, a written notice describing any additional information required to complete the request.</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H3B714A093031449C9C19CEAC3753FE93" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>If the Secretary provides notice under subclause (I)(bb), the Secretary shall, by not later than 30 days after the date of submission of the additional information described in the notice—</text>
 <item id="H0EC22B45E7204183A43365BB6D95649F"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">accept the written request for authorization under this subparagraph for incidental taking described in clause (i); or</text>
 </item><item id="H01ABEDD1207A4DADA8CD2F1C2A9A1092"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>deny the request and provide the requester a written explanation of the reasons for the denial.</text> </item></subclause><subclause id="HB5F0FDD44FC94339A0CD638A59C70386" indent="up1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>The Secretary may not make a second request for information, request that the requester withdraw and resubmit the request, or otherwise delay a decision on the request.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB4EE787CE93A4092BA83D3FDBF13B3CA" indent="up1"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>If the Secretary fails to respond to a request for authorization under this subparagraph in the manner provided in subclause (I) or (II), the request shall be considered to be complete.</text>
						</subclause></clause><clause id="H40B9987C2D0940D1B799D001C417187B" indent="up3"><enum>(ix)</enum>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HFE624897FE9A46E3B7BA86F9378F5397"><enum>(I)</enum><text>At least 90 days before the expiration of any authorization issued under this subparagraph, the holder of such authorization may apply for a one-year extension of such authorization. The Secretary shall grant such extension within 14 days after the date of such request on the same terms and without further review if there has been no substantial change in the activity carried out under such authorization nor in the status of the marine mammal species or stock, as applicable, as reported in the final annual stock assessment reports for such species or stock.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H89C3705702434C8986B1E77F963A6927" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In subclause (I) the term <quote>substantial change</quote> means a change that prevents the Secretary from making the required findings to issue an authorization under clause (i) with respect to such species or stock.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB81F561CE46C47B1BCFCDED12822CA5A" indent="up1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>The Secretary shall notify the applicant of such substantial changes with specificity and in writing within 14 days after the applicant’s submittal of the extension request.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="H91AB0F372194445DB598A4D09EC55E2A" indent="up3"><enum>(x)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary fails to make the required findings and, as appropriate, issue the authorization within 120 days after the application is accepted or required to be considered complete under subclause (I)(aa), (II)(aa), or (III) of clause (viii), as applicable, the authorization is deemed to have been issued on the terms stated in the application and without further process or restrictions under this Act.</text>
					</clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HE822180E511A44F5AB5BECB1D03BDCA9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Removing duplications</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 101(a)(5)(D) of the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1371">16 U.S.C. 1371(a)(5)(D)</external-xref>), as amended by section 2 of this Act, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8A1774B15BDF47B2B5A06265908C5218" style="OLC">
 <clause id="HF0A5244B6FA64EC3ACB9CE33E2988925" indent="up3"><enum>(xi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any taking of a marine mammal in compliance with an authorization under this subparagraph is exempt from the prohibition on taking in section 9 of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1538">16 U.S.C. 1538</external-xref>). Any Federal agency authorizing, funding, or carrying out an action that results in such taking, and any agency action authorizing such taking, is exempt from the requirement to consult regarding potential impacts to marine mammal species or designated critical habitat under section 7(a)(2) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1536">16 U.S.C. 1536(a)(2)</external-xref>).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


