<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H4A55712B7A974B7597E4F22F066EEC0D" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4140 IH: No Unconstitutional Strike against North Korea Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4140</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171026">October 26, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001184">Mr. Massie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000127">Mr. Nolan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001050">Ms. Hanabusa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000571">Ms. Gabbard</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000535">Mr. Gutiérrez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001037">Mr. Capuano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000287">Mr. Lewis of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000248">Mr. Serrano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000465">Ms. Tsongas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Maxine Waters of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the introduction of the Armed Forces into hostilities in North Korea without a
			 declaration of war or explicit statutory authorization, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H48B4609F1A05409DBAE60382DC843E96" style="OLC">
 <section id="H107E8EE1E668428496AD73F00990C6AA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Unconstitutional Strike against North Korea Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HCAE33EBE0EA346348EDF5301550F41E5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HE46119ABFC604737A4FEF98118907DE0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President is currently prohibited from initiating a war or launching a first strike without congressional approval under the Constitution and Federal law.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6C0DE50EA56543C58E93A790DE58DBAA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Constitution, in article I, section 8, grants Congress the sole power to declare war.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB7EF1915EE6347519117C8EF7BE76DC2"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">George Washington wrote that <quote>The constitution vests the power of declaring war in Congress; therefore no offensive expedition of importance can be undertaken until after they shall have deliberated upon the subject and authorized such a measure</quote> (Letter from George Washington to William Moultrie, August 28, 1793).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H63DBC629CDB44D73A4E6404B310DFF22"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Alexander Hamilton wrote that <quote><quote>The Congress shall have the power to declare war</quote>; the plain meaning of which is, that it is the peculiar and exclusive duty of Congress, when the nation is at peace, to change that state into a state of war</quote> (Hamilton Papers, Examination Number I, December 17, 1801).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5E300F0C734E4BB49130D2BE0E991D74"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">James Madison wrote that <quote>The power to declare war, including the power of judging the causes of war, is fully and exclusively vested in the legislature … the executive has no right, in any case, to decide the question, whether there is or is not cause for declaring war</quote> (Madison Papers, <quote>Helvidius</quote>, Number 4, September 14, 1793).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF6111196F8FB48279CD97E3978320BE8"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2(c) of the War Powers Resolution (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/93/148">Public Law 93–148</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1541">50 U.S.C. 1541</external-xref>) states that <quote>the constitutional powers of the President as Commander-in-Chief to introduce United States Armed Forces into hostilities, or into situations where imminent involvement in hostilities is clearly indicated by the circumstances, are exercised only pursuant to (1) a declaration of war, (2) specific statutory authorization, or (3) a national emergency created by attack upon the United States, its territories or possessions, or its armed forces</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC7D18E8C7F194EC79CBA5F8D4D23468B"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The American people, America’s allies in Asia, and the entire world have been deeply troubled by escalating tensions on the Korean peninsula.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8961BA4C8A9747379C56D6DF553227F3"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recent polling demonstrates that more than two-thirds of the American people believe that the United States should attack North Korea only if North Korea attacks first.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB55AE61374BF474687F969495889D945"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States has approximately 28,500 servicemembers stationed in South Korea, who would be placed in grave danger if an active military conflict were to erupt.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2AB1FD1B86424AEA8EA9ACA6CF73B854"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On August 14, 2017, Chairman of the U.S. Joint Chiefs of Staff, Marine Corps General Joseph Dunford stated that <quote>the United States military’s priority is to support our government’s efforts to achieve the denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula through diplomatic and economic pressure</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2392FADD165949269F075F8BCCE6259B"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On August 10, 2017, Defense Secretary James Mattis stated that armed conflict with North Korea <quote>would be catastrophic</quote>.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H9AD6CE3480BB404C867F91768179C46A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress in support of a diplomatic resolution to growing tensions with North Korea</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HCF01002F472C4520801BDE20320A4FB2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a conflict on the Korean peninsula would have catastrophic consequences for—</text> <subparagraph id="HA67C88654C574128AA59F74E92D8B43B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the American people;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84132B6B35354CAC897E1B5752793334"><enum>(B)</enum><text>members of the United States Armed Forces stationed in the region;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35242068BE0E43129BAE0010840075A9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>United States interests;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD27107AACF1941A59818CB2741F6CACF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>United States allies South Korea and Japan;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93DB37C0B19B456DA43A22D7F71E5FF6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the long-suffering people of North Korea; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A39E3FADA574447AF3DC5CC14CCB772"><enum>(F)</enum><text>global peace and security more broadly;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB987686AA2D94BCFB05B866C37056C58"><enum>(2)</enum><text>actions and statements that increase tensions and could lead to miscalculation should be avoided; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF8D2A9D3A714451FA78ABF87AF75C995"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the President, in coordination with United States allies, should explore and pursue every feasible opportunity to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBE7730DD070B43E4A637BD3048655103"><enum>(A)</enum><text>engage in talks with North Korea on concrete steps to reduce tensions and improve communication;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE901E53FF3C54775B202362C735AF71D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>initiate negotiations designed to achieve a diplomatic agreement to halt and eventually reverse North Korea’s nuclear and missile pursuits; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D37D6548CBF426E9ED0C8BCCBF55382"><enum>(C)</enum><text>move toward denuclearization and a permanent peace in the Korean peninsula.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HE20DFD76365A475BAF693CA34E613A2A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibition on unconstitutional military strikes against North Korea</header> <subsection id="H2A564F8755894207B622322E5FEBF143"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds appropriated or otherwise made available to the Department of Defense or to any other Federal department or agency may be used to launch a military strike against North Korea or otherwise introduce the Armed Forces into hostilities in North Korea before the earlier of—</text>
 <paragraph id="H936F0B9E087841AEBD7CD9BC3137FB85"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the date on which Congress declares war on North Korea; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBD412B35047E467C83D5CC1687651147"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the date of the enactment of an authorization described in subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBC4496BA709244D39330714A7AA46B0B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of military strikes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An authorization described in this subsection is an authorization that meets the requirements of the War Powers Resolution (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1541">50 U.S.C. 1541</external-xref> et seq.) and that is enacted after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA89E9C10A0E2438D99E8607A3327AEBF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The prohibition under subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to the introduction of the Armed Forces into hostilities—</text>
 <paragraph id="H396CAC7E88BB455F81AFBC2A367B9E4C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to repel a sudden attack on the United States, its territories or possessions, or its Armed Forces, or its allies; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H772426892FB54DF9BE0122BAA17EDFE7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to rescue or remove United States personnel.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H66CA6C517195498EA5CAF131280F969B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section may be construed to affect or alter the requirements of the War Powers Resolution (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1541">50 U.S.C. 1541</external-xref> et seq.) or to relieve the executive branch of the restrictions or reporting requirements therein.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


