<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF2FF00D0121A4F08BED593241A0B7957" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4116 IH: Transparent Drug Pricing Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4116</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171025">October 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001038">Mr. Higgins of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to require reporting by drug manufacturers to increase
			 transparency in drug pricing, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HC2494E4DBFBA4D368A212794474B7E74" style="OLC">
 <section id="H75EB04976A354763A587BDA012B16E52" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Transparent Drug Pricing Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H10F730D2C06541EF87887766AC654AC5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Drug manufacturer reporting</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part P of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280g">42 U.S.C. 280g</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5EA8CF3E3A9641AFAAE106502A0DF6DB" style="OLC">
				<section id="H14F6CC91A0A84C9E9E47F139A2C59602"><enum>399V–7.</enum><header>Drug manufacturer reporting</header>
 <subsection id="HDA6F5DAE874147E49E727041830876D3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Mandatory reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A drug manufacturer shall submit to the Secretary and to Congress an annual report specifying with respect to the previous calendar year (except as provided in subsection (d)(2))—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA72E0931ABC84289A7A33A24A5F25B0C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total expenditures of the manufacturer on—</text> <subparagraph id="HAA5455FA45E343F5867C4CCA99C5D609"><enum>(A)</enum><text>domestic and foreign drug research and development, including an itemized description of—</text>
 <clause id="HC516EBF380A44A79B499E77A35595D90"><enum>(i)</enum><text>basic and preclinical research;</text> </clause><clause id="H0D885F5E9F2547F4B8BB28E9AB2989DF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">clinical research, reported separately for each clinical trial;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5B6473F666884B54BF57C79FE0B4FD22"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>development of alternative dosage forms and strengths for the drug molecule or combinations, including the molecule;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC536C4DE9AA54C99A34E254EFDAD6637"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>other drug development activities, such as nonclinical laboratory studies and record and report maintenance;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1C7F5492075A4696B2FAF262B0CAC8A0"><enum>(v)</enum><text>pursuing new or expanded indications for such drug through supplemental applications under section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H169F0F36C6154D389B5C2DEDC6C9428D"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>carrying out postmarket requirements related to such drug, including under section 505(o)(3) of such Act;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4457069F00B044EEB7CB57D13961A1AB"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>carrying out risk evaluation and mitigation strategies in accordance with section 505–1 of such Act; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1E72DC0761D6426FB74AA7305BA1DBD5"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>marketing research;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1DBC147ED18342E1A7DB1584DB88E996"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the acquisition of drug components and packaging, in total and per unit sold, broken out by source and cost and identifying specific costs that reflect internal transfers within the manufacturer's company;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H607FF80D82FD4EB8AD8286DF93A6CAF2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>other acquisitions relating to drugs, including for the purchase of patents and licensing or the acquisition of any corporate entity owning any rights to a drug during or after development of the drug; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6927B130E083457AA4314D7AF3AE0E14"><enum>(D)</enum><text>marketing, advertising, and educating for the promotion of a drug, including a breakdown of amounts aimed at consumers, prescribers, managed care organizations, and others, irrespective of whether a particular drug is mentioned in the marketing, advertising, or educating;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H592F6A56D5A04AD2BC2FEC23BC78227A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the gross revenue, net revenue, gross profit, and net profit of the manufacturer with respect to drugs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA6055D5297AB4D7CA164DFF1BD408842"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the total number of units of each type of drug that were sold in interstate commerce;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H04C7348E32D645078A2CAC40BFEAF290"><enum>(4)</enum><text>pricing information with respect to the sale of drugs, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA38108E61FC94FCBA0545586904E923F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>wholesale acquisition cost;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB3C7691F110F407ABADB3356C6546859"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">net average price realized by prescription drug benefit managers for drugs provided to individuals in the United States, after accounting for any rebates or other payments from the manufacturer to the pharmacy benefit manager and from the pharmacy benefit manager to the manufacturer; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4679FC3CD4BC41879B178C1FF2F535DF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the net price of each drug, after accounting for discounts, rebates, or other financial considerations, charged to purchasers in each applicable country of the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB5FEDFAB4F64405AF4AC3A6217BEF10"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any Federal benefits received by the manufacturer with respect to a drug, including the amounts and periods of impact for each such benefit, including tax credits; Federal grants, including from the National Institutes of Health, the Department of Defense, the Department of Energy, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, or other Federal departments or agencies; patent applications that benefitted from such grants; patent extensions; exclusivity periods; and waivers of fees;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H150729C854824EEB89BAD6D1033F20C1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the percentage of research and development expenditures described in clauses (i) through (v) of paragraph (1)(A) that were derived from Federal funds;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8330A4AA774E43E1A826B01742E2BBA3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>executive compensation for the chief executive officer, chief financial officer, and the 3 other most highly compensated executive officers, including bonuses, paid by such manufacturer, and stock options affiliated with the manufacturer that were offered to or accrued by such officers; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H83D5E363C517403AA10109D3AA74798F"><enum>(8)</enum><text>any other information as the Secretary may require.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA139E4065E9F4D92A8384779DE346901"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Voluntary supplemental reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A drug manufacturer may supplement a report under subsection (a) with any additional information the manufacturer chooses to provide related to drug pricing decisions, such as—</text>
 <paragraph id="HBE4AB76E099C44D48DAB926EDB91FC79"><enum>(1)</enum><text>total expenditures on drug research, drug development, and clinical trials on drugs that failed to receive approval by the Food and Drug Administration; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB537C14BE7894C8A88706E553BE4EDC6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a list of drugs and drug prices of other manufacturers for purposes of comparison with the manufacturer’s own drugs and drug prices.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB36C5DF4F0C64BF885ECC44F782AD61B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text>A drug manufacturer shall—</text> <paragraph id="HF3A3BF3FD4EA42DFA8CFF44112F672BC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to the extent possible, disaggregate the information required to be reported by this section by the particular drug involved; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB14A41763CEF47389F968CA6809BC761"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit all information required to be reported by this section with respect to each applicable drug in a single annual report.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCB886E0E9E4B4B7EA63747602799DE9F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Submission of reports</header>
						<paragraph id="HD1FA78B0F81B4BE9991EB719F693107D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <subparagraph id="H7C87F345E1F04B5BA2FEE3B80542F391"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Submission by drug manufacturers</header><text>Drug manufacturers shall submit the annual reports required under this section to the Secretary in a usable format, as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8686DFDEF5AF4B2484FCBF40D3AF75F1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Collation by the Secretary</header><text>The Secretary shall collate the reports received as described in subparagraph (A) and submit such collated reports to Congress, together with an analysis of the reports by the Secretary that includes—</text>
 <clause id="HADFC9E70FA864D7D84C65DE2A973A472"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a summary of data from the reports;</text> </clause><clause id="H87E62D3E5C394BDCA64F074633F474A5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>consideration of factors such as trends on research and development costs, Federal benefits, and manufacturer patient assistance programs; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD23DA2CE5C844F1A8C5B71DC69A76B26"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the relationship between the factors described in clause (ii) and prescription drug prices.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74DA4C23118E419A8C1CBBE1567101D2"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Secretary shall make the reports submitted by manufacturers as described in subparagraph (A) and the collated reports together with the analysis of the Secretary described in subparagraph (B) publicly available, including by posting such reports to the internet website of the Department of Health and Human Services, in a searchable format.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H424227BFDE3E41968E4491C58336E125"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial report</header>
 <subparagraph id="HB850515820D2401AA5F7126582C8FD66"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A drug manufacturer shall submit an initial report pursuant to this section not later than one year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Transparent Drug Pricing Act of 2017</short-title> (except as provided in subparagraph (B)).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB8B608B17FCB453491DDE8449C180805"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reporting period</header><text>Notwithstanding the requirement in subsection (a) that each report under such subsection be for the previous calendar year, the initial report of a drug manufacturer under subsection (a) shall include, for each drug marketed by the manufacturer, the information described in paragraphs (1) through (6) of subsection (a) for the calendar year period beginning with the later of—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H71B34E695F3845ABAC13796C145F90C4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the calendar year in which the drug was approved under section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, was licensed under section 351 of this Act, or received an exemption under section 505(i) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act or section 351(a)(3) of this Act; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H90B01890BCB94605892D5EE22296ADEE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the calendar year in which the manufacturer acquired the drug so approved, licensed, or exempted.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H15E412A2CDF34140B9C2A5F30B267AF5"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Small businesses</header><text>In the case of a drug manufacturer that has fewer than 500 employees, the initial report required by in subparagraph (A) shall be submitted by a date determined by the Secretary, which shall be—</text>
 <clause id="H8C8BE266826B4090A96AD9A56B7E4A53"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not earlier than the deadline described in subparagraph (A); and</text> </clause><clause id="HBFBB253DB2A6492B8955F3DE399E35F1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not later than the date that is 3 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Transparent Drug Pricing Act of 2017</short-title>.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9E4893FB022A4CF5BD91E50170EBB671"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Audit by third party</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall select a percentage (to be determined by the Secretary) of the reports submitted under subsection (a) for a fiscal year to be audited by an accredited third-party auditor (to be selected by the Secretary).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF72E64D4E60F42D7AB6BEB61D2B4D7F1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Penalty for noncompliance</header><text>The Secretary shall report to the Office of the Inspector General any manufacturer's failure to submit a complete report as required under this section. Any manufacturer that fails to submit a complete report required under this section shall be subject to a civil penalty of up to $200,000 for each day on which the violation continues. The Secretary shall collect the civil penalties under this subsection and, without further appropriation, shall use such funds to support research of the National Institutes of Health.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0DF51C9E41BC4613B0E060474CF5453D"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>drug manufacturer</term> means the manufacturer of an approved drug (including a drug approved under subsection (c) or (j) of section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act and a biological product licensed under subsection (a) or (k) of section 351 of this Act).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


