<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCA8991C4BBAE45B7802611FD8973CFBC" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4573 IH: Gun Violence Research Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4573</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171206">December 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="R000588">Mr. Richmond</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001049">Mr. Clay</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000586">Mr. Lawson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000287">Mr. Lewis of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000581">Mrs. Lawrence</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000455">Ms. Fudge</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To clarify that the Dickey Amendment does not prevent the use of funds for research on mental
			 health, gun violence, and how they intersect, and to provide for reporting
			 on the effects of gun violence.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H584AE63C076A4967B1B9DC1B258E65F8" style="OLC">
 <section id="H9DB33F628CF24CFFBB11596A381EDAA7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Gun Violence Research Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HB42F1F3DEA6941B5A29C0605BBF80150"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="H46A97F9718E74338A16F621F3F9541E6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As of December 4, 2017, there have been 56,825 incidents of gun violence in the United States in 2017.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3478BBC3B9204978820886B961EF0163"><enum>(2)</enum><text>As of December 4, 2017, there have been 14,319 deaths related to gun violence in the United States in 2017.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8DF5A2D79832453CB6B8377B2271E56B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Defining a mass shooting as an incident of violence during which four or more people are shot, not including the shooter—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBB17576BE1044F92BEBAF2CC2A23705C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>there have been 327 mass shootings in the United States in 2017;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB74A3216AC5A497AA088E12FAA239CF8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>on average, there is more than one mass shooting each day in the United States; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12F4791B7EAB426FB93CBA941A4DBC7D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">there have been more than 1,500 mass shootings in the United States since the shooting at Sandy Hook Elementary in 2012.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H4A5DF37E3AEF40829DEF382551D44518"><enum>3.</enum><header>Research on mental health, gun violence, and how they intersect</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Effective on the date of enactment of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/113">Public Law 114–113</external-xref>), section 210 (prohibiting the availability of funds to advocate or promote gun control) of title II of division H of such Act (relating to the Department of Health and Human Services) is amended to read as follows:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H916D6D7701A54ADEB8FA978C7E056DB9" style="appropriations">
 <section id="H04054B5D829C4CB19647EC5A8B28504A"><enum>210.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available in this title may be used, in whole or in part, to advocate or promote gun control. Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit funding for the conduct or support of research on mental health, gun violence, and how they intersect.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="HB7EECB19E80E4ADF8885C43893CB5F02"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report on effects of gun violence on public health</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Surgeon General of the Public Health Service shall submit to Congress a report on the effects on public health, including mental health, of gun violence in the United States during the preceding year, and the status of actions taken to address such effects.</text>
 </section><section id="HBB93DFCED661423D8C607DC1860E7E00"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report on effects of gun violence on mental health in minority communities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Deputy Assistant Secretary for Minority Health in the Office of the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to Congress a report on the effects of gun violence on public health, including mental health, in minority communities in the United States, and the status of actions taken to address such effects.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


