<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H24504CE43D5A4DFCB2E36576A03E7F2B" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4183 IH: Domestic Violence Records Reporting Improvement Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4183</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171031">October 31, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001106">Mr. Costello of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000602">Miss Rice of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To condition a State’s eligibility for grants under the National Criminal History Improvement
			 Program on compliance with certain requirements relating to increasing
			 reporting of domestic violence records, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HA99C90DC55DA41878995B59E3A48FC4F" style="OLC">
 <section id="H026AF57D02D54689BF62D384D76E1EC6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Domestic Violence Records Reporting Improvement Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H5FAACB28DE4346749B6C0334570E5079"><enum>2.</enum><header>Restriction on NCHIP grants</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 102 of the Crime Identification Technology Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40301">34 U.S.C. 40301</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="HEADA3B8507C94593B7096C5C965F6ABC" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="H2B5B3853E4C74C7C8D75E01CFE3C6806"><enum>(g)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE0936914D7C54BECBD2F8969230F70D3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>National instant criminal background check system</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>National Instant Criminal Background Check System</quote> means the National Instant Criminal Background Check System established under section 103(b) of the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/922">18 U.S.C. 922</external-xref> note) for firearms eligibility determinations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE558AB3D71324A81849E6E7F54431DD1" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Domestic violence record defined</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (3), a domestic violence record is the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H0B6B52AF9FDF4338B4568D5DC74ED7A7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A record that identifies a person who is subject to a court order described in section 922(g)(8) of title 18, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H95A00777D8344C279F52BE24E343FF48"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A record that identifies a person who was convicted in any court of a misdemeanor crime of domestic violence, as defined in section 921(a)(33) of title 18, United States Code, during the 5 years preceding the date of enactment of this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5934F1FFDE1D4A3DAF4C4B76581D53BB" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report to congress</header><text>Not later than January 31 of each year, the Attorney General shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate a report identifying the percentage of records described in paragraph (2) from each State that are accessible through the National Instant Criminal Background Check System.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3557925D76CF4FDEBDFA1887A35F58A9" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Methodology</header><text>The method established to calculate the number of records identified in paragraph (2) accessible through the National Instant Criminal Background Check System, as set forth in paragraph (2) and State compliance with the required level of reporting under paragraph (6), shall be determined by the Attorney General, after consultation with the States, in accordance with the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H81727773061D4BEC8447576A3D8D9F4D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A record of an individual convicted of a misdemeanor crime of domestic violence shall be counted as accessible through the National Instant Criminal Background Check System if a record identifying the individual has been submitted to the NICS Index or a record identifies the individual in the Interstate Identification Index and the record in the Interstate Identification Index either complies with paragraph (c)(2) of section 102 of the NICS Amendment Improvements Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40912">34 U.S.C. 40912</external-xref>), or otherwise clearly indicates that the person is ineligible to purchase or possess firearms as a result of the conviction.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41CA644E35F04A599181CC18C527E201"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A record of an individual subject to a court order described in section 922(g)(8) of title 18, United States Code shall be counted as accessible through the National Instant Criminal Background Check System if either a record identifying the individual has been submitted to the NICS Index, or the individual is identified in the Protection Order File of the National Crime Information Center and the record in the Protection Order File of the National Crime Information Center clearly indicates that the person is ineligible to purchase or possess firearms as a result of the court order.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H103EA35D752648809A3D70D4E5525BDB" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Grant eligibility</header><text>Starting in each year as stated below, a State shall not be eligible for a grant under this section for purposes that do not contribute to the accessibility of the records described in paragraph (2) through the National Instant Criminal Background Check System, unless at least the following percentage of such records from that State are accessible through the National Instant Criminal Background Check System, as determined by the Attorney General in accordance with paragraph (4):</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0F620C11FFDA4FDF8752D60A96DB780B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>30 percent of such records, starting 2021;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6186DC570661429FA2E8168F74FEC7CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>50 percent of such records, starting 2023; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4915426748EA46B8B8E0B8BD2E58D47E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>70 percent of such records, starting 2025.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAEBF3F8A66BC436991364514BB7ABC3A" indent="up1"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Reallocation</header><text>Any funds that are not allocated to a State because of the failure of the State to comply with the requirements of this subsection shall be reallocated to States that meet such requirements.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="H06782627339843B2ABDE7E48EA3E8180"><enum>3.</enum><header>NARIP funding for domestic violence reporting</header>
 <subsection id="H91419E9233E54F68AA53624954EA32A2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Implementation assistance to States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 103(c) of the NICS Improvement Amendments Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40913">34 U.S.C. 40913</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H26DC04DD72EF4AF0A922B7ABEB412310"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(1)</quote> after <quote>(c)</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4FF35C3D64604389A23AD7420A32FD88"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end, the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H6C29967FD6E44583B4147D72B5E11F25" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HDD27EA559F544B2489A47CB33C93CD2C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Attorney General shall waive the requirement of a relief from disabilities program for any State to receive a grant under this section if the primary purpose of the grant is to improve the accessibility through the National Instant Criminal Background Check System of the records identified in subsection (g)(3) of section 102 of the Crime Identification Technology Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40301">34 U.S.C. 40301</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H161D43FF21FE4C7F9C40FF08454D6056"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Disposition records automation and transmittal improvement grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 301(d) of the NICS Improvement Amendments Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40941">34 U.S.C. 40941</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HEEE3602E4EB34769976EE4BABF98D579"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(1)</quote> after <quote>(d)</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H449C9C4D75D542D0A90C2CFB68EB8E3D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end, the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H077FCB2829254438B77C66AC08D468EC" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H2244061999BA4ABBA2D7DDB08027A504"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Attorney General shall waive the requirement of a relief from disabilities program for any State to receive a grant under this section if the primary purpose of the grant is to improve the accessibility through the National Instant Criminal Background Check System of the records identified in subsection (g)(3) of section 102 of the Crime Identification Technology Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40301">34 U.S.C. 40301</external-xref>).</text>
						</paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


