<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H87376329BDF140D086BEB7AFA9A3A483" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2326 IH: Climate Solutions Commission Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2326</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170503">May 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000620">Mr. Delaney</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000464">Mr. Faso</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001107">Mr. Curbelo of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001181">Mr. Meehan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000435">Ms. Ros-Lehtinen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To accelerate reductions in climate pollution in order to leave a better planet for future generations, and to create a bipartisan commission to develop economically viable policies to achieve science-based emissions reduction targets.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB918C1056ABE4A12811C192EFA1652AC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD2222F9E62164725B1FB8732A2C052EE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Climate Solutions Commission Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3C0A5A0DAA3A412898747F043C28180B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H166B3DC53FF64F44B272B84CFE149B89"><enum>(1)</enum><text>there has been a marked increase in extreme weather events and the negative impacts of a changing climate are expected to worsen in every region of the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H24E1863452F94AA2B41A0CB1BB2127FC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if left unaddressed, the consequences of a changing climate have the potential to adversely impact the health of all Americans, harm the economy, and impose substantial costs on State and Federal budgets;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H136EF76EAE2D498FB8718B62200EC1F7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>efforts to reduce climate risk should protect our Nation’s economy, security, infrastructure, agriculture, water supply, and public safety; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H33894D757E524C88958188B916CE5B8C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>there is bipartisan support for pursuing efforts to reduce greenhouse gas emissions through economically viable, broadly supported private and public policies and solutions.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H04EFB477E5904231A7F953F5B0702784"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of Commission</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Effective immediately upon the enactment of this Act, there shall be established a bipartisan commission to be known as the <quote>National Climate Solutions Commission</quote> (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Commission</quote>).</text></section> <section id="H70F0CF0B6A2344B0A21427B451D617B2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Purposes of Commission</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Commission shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC04B332E24A349EC9245332902CCD812"><enum>(1)</enum><text>undertake a comprehensive review of economically viable public and private actions or policies to reduce greenhouse gas emissions in the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6F340A475DF641DF9F6157003AFA5A54"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make recommendations for reducing greenhouse gas emissions to the President, Congress, and the States; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE1CC03F537874B279263A7ED37B79BC7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use as its goals for emissions reductions those estimated rates of reduction that reflect the latest scientific findings of what is needed to avoid serious human health and environmental consequences of a changing climate.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H236B75EA3FF54584ADFB6597DCB39DD3"><enum>5.</enum><header>Membership of Commission</header> <subsection id="HEC31CD41C6F040F4A0A2189F2E66DC54"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall be composed of 10 members, appointed not later than 3 months after the date of enactment of this Act, as follows:</text> 
<paragraph id="HFA22AB2DB7614F8AAE6E852CCA4BE830"><enum>(1)</enum><text>One member shall be appointed by the President, who shall serve as cochairman of the Commission.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2C1786B6C4964841A18B3AE5C3D51760"><enum>(2)</enum><text>One member shall be appointed by the leader of the Senate, in consultation with the leader of the House of Representatives, that are members of the opposite party of the President, who shall serve as cochairman of the Commission.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0D1D332385CF4BA592057D2418E0AE07"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Two members shall be appointed by the Majority Leader of the Senate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF826E1C6BDDC4CDDB8715DDD28051DC7"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Two members shall be appointed by the Minority Leader of the Senate.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAFA59B99D4E642B6BA978C43ED2C30C0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Two members shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF3C75E7863EA4440BB05B49C1D4505BA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Two members shall be appointed by the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7F6CD9071D8442598AD47006CD107C77"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Initial meeting</header><text>The Commission shall meet not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H6CB426EC0E6A41ABB003655D17B40EAF"><enum>(c)</enum><header> Recommendations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall provide the recommendations described in section 4(2), based on the goals described in section 4(3), not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H942154914ED24F859563DA39B8E869C5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligible members</header><text>To be considered for membership on the Commission, an individual must be a representative from—</text> <paragraph id="H6AC981F668F6447190C84DE5E28E9329"><enum>(1)</enum><text>academic, scientific, or other nongovernmental organizations with expertise in the economy, energy, climate, or public health; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2BF480D33B4A4CBB9C40AFF2379F7761"><enum>(2)</enum><text>industry organizations, including small businesses, from relevant sectors such as—</text> <subparagraph id="HB31C1BEE01EB47F89442ADE3319B221C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">energy supply and transmission, including fossil fuels and renewable energy;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3D0249E206154E249F02FB9FDC2BDFDF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">energy exploration and production, including fossil fuels and renewable energy;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEC86D587033642CAB307E2BF44A7226C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>solid waste and wastewater;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDFB9172D8A4B435A894F8390538021AA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>transportation;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF06779BAFC024A58AC349C07EA236882"><enum>(E)</enum><text>chemical manufacturing and user industries;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H032D9E4404D14334B2B300AD0ED9A87E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>agriculture;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA2D9479BEF1D495AB16C7030D0AE09A1"><enum>(G)</enum><text>construction and development; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEE878275F8B148248DEAF1B085DF6209"><enum>(H)</enum><text>forestry.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE8930756181E426B95D2E55F1ADC7E08"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Ineligible members</header><text>No employee, owner, director, or other affiliated person of an entity which has contributed pursuant to section 6(b) may be appointed to the Commission.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HC489D8FC681844B99980EE743C051FCA"><enum>6.</enum><header>Funding for the activities of the Commission</header> 
<subsection id="HF5331269C43E48E6A71CEF2A3D98FB53" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>No additional amounts may be authorized to be appropriated to establish or otherwise pay for the activities or salaries of the Commission.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HAA9527C0C5064B409146838933EA405D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Private sector donations</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury may collect and disseminate to the Commission private sector funds donated for the purposes of this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBEB426254660478BB477A3BC3CA6A3BF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transparency</header><text>The amounts and sources of all funds donated pursuant to subsection (b) and all spending by the Commission shall be made publicly available on an Internet website.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HC458F90B97CD485B85E5B610198C9633"><enum>7.</enum><header>Government Accountability Office study and report</header> <subsection id="HFB883B6C42EF47BF90DBD7652072259C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study required</header><text>The Comptroller General shall conduct a study of State, Federal, and private sector energy efficiency and renewable energy guaranteed loan programs, Green Banks, and other financial tools and institutions that are focused on—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3E729FDFE8A944BE976398086E861933"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reducing the level of greenhouse gas emissions, including through sequestration and recycling; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H17312B170D354AA4B037E37C3E4217C5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encouraging the research, development, prototyping, and deployment of energy efficiency and renewable energy technologies.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8C2917FCADEE4E339F670D4E62F854F5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which the Comptroller General completes the study required by subsection (a), the Comptroller General shall submit to Congress a report containing—</text> <paragraph id="H4672CA5866F649B3A879D4A69E180037"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the results of the study; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE77E54E55A43457799CCF382B3CDD058"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of those financial tools, policies, and institutions most successful at contributing to the reduction of greenhouse gas emissions while protecting economic growth and employment.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

