<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H903BE45A20BB4AC3A3847956E5F06F71" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4700 IH: Increasing and Mobilizing Partnerships to Achieve Commercialization of Technologies for Energy Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4700</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171220">December 20, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000570">Mr. Ben Ray Luján of New Mexico</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000563">Mr. Lipinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000585">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001059">Mr. Hultgren</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the IMPACT for Energy Foundation.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H164258BC80594259B9F4C17A715C5B5F" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE0F6DBB8B3934A59B68744B9F2F7B5DF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Increasing and Mobilizing Partnerships to Achieve Commercialization of Technologies for Energy Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>IMPACT for Energy Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H731A55E67A13431BA4208F1A44FAED15"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="H3E9790D292BA417FA8FE695EAE1141F0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Board</header><text>The term <term>Board</term> means the Board of Directors for the Foundation described in section 3(c).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H37B720B8E3444F1BAC55ABF7A9DB15BE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Chair</header><text>The term <term>Chair</term> means the Chair of the Board described in section 3(c)(2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC4E8A6F5D574947AC818E67F238FD11"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Executive Director</header><text>The term <term>Executive Director</term> means the Executive Director of the Board described in section 3(f)(2).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1DD86B6CE5B34301B7F8DD09C793320D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Foundation</header><text>The term <term>Foundation</term> means the IMPACT for Energy Foundation established under section 3(a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H440FAFA025334385B27305C309CCDA55"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Energy.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H66C5DA4AE5C14CFD9339F45F3AE67DBE" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of IMPACT for Energy Foundation</header> <subsection id="H3DC109B0E5A9472698F5C4EBDEB3FF99"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header> <paragraph id="HC4BE4BBB395C45CD9CF7DE16BDDD607E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than February 1, 2019, the Secretary shall establish a nonprofit corporation to be known as the <quote>IMPACT for Energy Foundation</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD5873DC531AC4A2EA24936D2864E7FCA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Foundation shall not be an agency or instrumentality of the Federal Government.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2DBFAC264C8449A4898F8F3529D807BF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose and activities of foundation</header> <paragraph id="H729D86C221E94314A03AF89CE7C5DC19"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the Foundation is to provide a mechanism to channel private sector investments that support efforts to create, develop, and commercialize innovative technologies that address energy challenges, by methods that include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC6C54B654788486C8BFDDE38E3491CF7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>fostering collaboration and partnerships with energy researchers from the Federal Government, State governments, institutions of higher education, federally funded research and development centers, industry, and nonprofit organizations for the research, development, or commercialization of transformative energy technologies;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F4FA5B7969A4EC0A7F69ED63189ABED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>leveraging technologies to support new product development that supports regional economic development; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50BC1787C79C4524A20CD3CAAC4AAE32"><enum>(C)</enum><text>administering prize competitions to accelerate private sector competition and investment.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE06016DAD34641C5A81110937AD49C18"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Activities</header> <subparagraph id="H5F909133AFA24C17B8D0728184C78C0C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Foundation may solicit and accept gifts, grants, and other donations, establish accounts, and invest and expend funds in support of the programs and activities described in subparagraphs (B) through (D).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF227F67F101D4DAB9A814A466FC18E28"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Studies, competitions, and projects</header><text>The Foundation may conduct and support studies, competitions, projects, research, development, commercialization, and other activities that further the purpose of the Foundation described in paragraph (1).</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0186865010DB4AE68379389D63EC77CF"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Fellowships and grants</header>
 <clause id="H35A31DF7187E467F8AD94900E8CB8B6E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Foundation may provide fellowships and grants to recipients selected under clause (iii) for activities relating to research, development, prototyping, maturing, or commercializing of energy technologies.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3A54C6DEB3894154847FBCD3A2AB3DB6"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Uses of fellowships and grants</header><text>A fellowship or grant under clause (i) may include stipends, travel, health insurance benefits, and other appropriate expenses.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H146E87F9DEB3497EA2FDDA05E61F3BBC"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Selection</header><text>The Executive Director shall select the recipient of a fellowship or grant based on the technical and commercialization merits of the project.</text>
						</clause><clause id="H0CC614F072854BA79C912EDB67DBBA95"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Federal laboratories</header>
 <subclause id="H19FE8D9792E3455E8CADB14BD67C133C"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Federal Laboratories, including laboratories of the Department of Energy, may apply for and accept grants under clause (i).</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HACBBD8146F5A466CBA40E6023ED27EBB"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>A Federal laboratory that applies for or accepts a grant under subclause (I) shall not be considered to be engaging in a competitive procedure.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34A51EB5D67844C0B7A829952F6852D4"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Supplementary programs</header><text>The Foundation may carry out supplementary programs—</text> <clause id="H31A8E12EECC04A48BE4D4EDB6CE142C8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to conduct and support forums, meetings, conferences, courses, and training workshops consistent with the purpose of the Foundation described in paragraph (1);</text>
 </clause><clause id="H56657D1642674CF6AC3B38CF85814112"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to support and encourage the understanding and development of—</text> <subclause id="HD688B67935D14D06ABF6A2F26635199C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>data reporting models that promote the translation of technologies from the research stage, through development and maturation, and to the market; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H4D4B11B4C1BA417BAE11AC0B779BAAB1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>policies that make regulation more effective and efficient by leveraging the technology translation data described in subclause (I) for the regulation of relevant technology sectors;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H1CEE00AB37AE46078666BE3961FA0AC2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>for writing, editing, printing, publishing, and vending books and other materials relating to research carried out under the Foundation; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H475096706B96491B8306EE3C7A8DFA17"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to conduct other activities to carry out and support the purpose described in paragraph (1).</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE044D2B2C8B843FB9F1E638C3457BEFB"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Authority of foundation</header><text>The Foundation shall be the sole entity responsible for carrying out the activities described in this paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5ED64402EB284F0DB0D6439700A55001"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Administrative control</header><text>No participant in a program under this paragraph or employee of the Foundation shall exercise any administrative control over any Federal employee.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H69C8DF196A1A40B7B9B8BD1D33BFBA03"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Board of directors</header>
				<paragraph id="H9BDC379F9B7F41ED81339BA51BB3F12F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Membership</header>
 <subparagraph id="H212B8EF32940497EB628889ED1C8EB59"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Foundation shall operate under the direction of a Board of Directors, which shall be composed of—</text>
 <clause id="H1D57C46B070F498AB4EDFFFE1CC971E4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>ex-officio members described in subparagraph (B); and</text> </clause><clause id="H5955A51BBAF54D2680A280397D397443"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>appointed members described in subparagraph (C).</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED2FF22908714BCD87FA83726B3DF7FA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Ex-officio members</header>
						<clause id="HBFE3B8FD801E4DFBBE456B9859CC49B5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Initial members</header>
 <subclause id="HA74AB3C6BC7D4131B5E5F1D031529994"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subclause (II), the initial ex-officio members of the Board shall be—</text> <item id="HEA03AABFB2904648B2CF5B4B684A9D38"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the chair of the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate (or a designee);</text>
 </item><item id="H3453D069F0B34B6CA022291AC9504B45"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the ranking minority member of the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate (or a designee);</text>
 </item><item id="HEF74107243F740B99BBA232DB8C72E74"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the chair of the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives (or a designee);</text> </item><item id="H6F5D1609A7F14CB2B18B4A9F6977ACE1"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>the ranking minority member of the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives (or a designee);</text>
 </item><item id="H6F99AA4BDE5B466E909DEC72576B776B"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>the chair of the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate (or a designee);</text> </item><item id="HB69D6DDC2910482D98A7A7106B9D091A"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>the ranking minority member of the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate (or a designee);</text>
 </item><item id="HD4B2CC6BD5A94D45B1755EBD8C150BE2"><enum>(gg)</enum><text>the chair of the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives (or a designee);</text>
 </item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA6365096444A4A83B281A3E65932B6A6"><enum>(hh)</enum><text>the ranking minority member of the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives (or a designee); and</text>
 </item><item id="HC375D284AB4346FD99148D2F08F08A9D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Secretary (or a designee).</text> </item></subclause><subclause id="H3A33B61CDAD146708CADE750D6022893"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Designees</header><text>A designee under subclause (I) shall be a member of the staff of the applicable chair, ranking minority member, or Secretary.</text>
							</subclause></clause><clause id="HFEFE703B9347428386257579316A0532"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Permanent members</header>
 <subclause id="H6A59D63C25D44B70B1CF5632EADECB36"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>On the appointment of appointed members of the Board under subparagraph (C), the terms of service of the ex-officio members of the Board described in items (aa) through (hh) of clause (i)(I) shall terminate.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HED03AF8641F44934A12930940682E842"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Permanent member</header><text>The Secretary shall serve as a permanent ex-officio member of the Board.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HD306F58973C347B4B8DC5B1F3D02081E"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Nonvoting members</header><text>The ex-officio members of the Board shall be nonvoting members.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H854DA560768242C19105F5329A7FE46E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Appointed members</header>
 <clause id="H89EEC8BE3F7F4CA5B5DDF3B01BE1951E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The appointed members of the Board shall be composed of 11 individuals, which shall include not fewer than 1 but not more than 5 representatives of each of—</text>
 <subclause id="H7051B32639B84781B7ADB42AF2B60A31"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the academic community;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HE67CBAEC90D848DF91D7F01603A7D290"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the business community;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE29AB7D2E5DA4FE48920931826D50E27"><enum>(III)</enum><text>nonprofit organizations;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HA305CEDA6764453B9180598BA779B670"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the communities surrounding the laboratories and facilities of the Department of Energy; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H4EF00E5DCAAE4567848E8F7FD4FCE6DD"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the technology transfer and commercialization community.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HFEDC2F3A80BB472CA36958845E10F0F7"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Method of appointment</header> <subclause id="H3B842E2CD4954848A31DAA439BC43F80"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the ex-officio members of the Board shall select from a list of candidates, to be provided by, at the discretion of the Secretary, the Secretary of Energy Advisory Board or the National Academy of Sciences, individuals for appointment as members of the Board.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HEC99EF4DE0EF455EA7566A5E5E978C02"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Vote</header><text>For the initial membership of the Board, an individual selected for appointment under subclause (I) shall be appointed on a vote of not fewer than <fraction>3/5</fraction> of the initial ex-officio members of the Board.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HCC47BD34DE2646DBB4D37C6F2AA8DDA3"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Restriction on membership</header><text>No employee of the Department of Energy shall be appointed as a member of the Board.</text> </clause><clause id="H524B77B2410542B49AA604F10A155760"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Amendment to number of appointed members</header><text>The Board, through amendments to the bylaws of the Foundation, may provide that the number of appointed members of the Board shall be greater than the number specified in clause (i).</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C2F4E3FFCDC4B8E988052C21BE22B68"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Terms and vacancies</header>
						<clause id="H91BCE4E3FCA94D9DA4267B5268B229AF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Terms</header>
 <subclause id="HBA7810E9C8E849FEB0831F68ADC95ACF"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subclause (II), the term of service of each appointed member of the Board shall be 5 years.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HAF4A004BE8CA4BE789A4914B1119957B"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Initial appointed members</header><text>The term of service for each initial appointed member of the Board shall be—</text> <item id="HFD9DEC4780A447EA83E978A926554535"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>determined by the initial ex-officio members of the Board and the initial Chair to ensure that the continuity of representation of board members from each of the areas described in subclauses (I) through (V) of subparagraph (C)(i); and</text>
 </item><item id="H81F84FECB0684220B3C099278AFEB87D"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>for a term of either 3 or 4 years.</text> </item></subclause></clause><clause id="H792490999B4A4BC0AAD610F058D2B5ED"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Vacancies</header> <subclause id="HD5523954688A4DFA83523278F342356E"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any vacancy in the membership of the appointed members of the Board—</text>
 <item id="H6243C39FB04B4E10B4686ABAEF35C039"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>shall be filled in accordance with the bylaws of the Foundation established under subsection (d)(1)(B); and</text>
 </item><item id="HA6B9B1B9B7DC45F9AE4C46398CC6644F"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>shall not affect the power of the remaining appointed members to execute the duties of the Board.</text> </item></subclause><subclause id="HA7E67E3992BC48C897F761B06074AE78"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Filling unexpired term</header><text>An individual appointed to fill a vacancy shall be appointed for the unexpired term of the member replaced.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HC6DB725D04CA4B7C88A7895BB8AD41BA"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Service until vacancy filled</header><text>An appointed member of the Board may continue to serve on the Board after the expiration of the term of the member until a successor is appointed.</text>
							</subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2141E4CEDB88491AB2B62D6F0053F710"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Chair</header>
 <subparagraph id="HE7782CDEA6054C82A5B765A93BD05DB4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Initial chair</header><text>The initial Chair of the Board shall be an initial ex-officio member elected by the initial ex-officio members of the Board for a 3-year term that shall expire on the appointment of the next Chair.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H14AFB9D21C6147F9BADAB61DEB772B3C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Chair after members are appointed</header><text>On the termination of the term of service of the initial Chair under subparagraph (A), the appointed members of the Board shall elect an appointed member of the Board to serve as the Chair, who shall serve as the Chair for the entire remaining term of service of that member.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H27E29294FD4545CA9547918003982300"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Compensation</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFD30F4DA6524436EA1C87C4386283517"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of the Board may not receive compensation for service on the Board.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3F46BB26D9D84E1AB0C149C53A26488C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Certain expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In accordance with the bylaws of the Foundation, members of the Board may be reimbursed for travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, and other necessary expenses incurred in carrying out the duties of the Board.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H697697026E4B467EB123C38394881A6F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Meetings and quorum</header>
 <paragraph id="H99957D2470C44ED1BCE3994CF2F47A01"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the establishment of the appointed Board, the initial appointed members of the Board shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA80A7FFC0F17449AA01C0DA1C5C0239E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>serve as incorporators; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB8BEA160ABD4BA1A6E2C10086D3FF64"><enum>(B)</enum><text>take such actions as are necessary—</text>
 <clause id="H0C12B183059841E296A894401628BCC8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to incorporate the Foundation;</text> </clause><clause id="H20B666EFAA0E4DF3A508C2D58AB0935E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to establish the bylaws of the Foundation;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAC118C66574D4860ADB1C6357A6F6E7A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to establish the general policies of the Foundation for carrying out the purpose described in subsection (b)(1); and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAA9BE6B0CC89483CA6C3B1E823495871"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to appoint the members of the Board in accordance with subsection (c)(1)(C)(ii).</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H020347AFDA5A422A8000E8264CB8D8FE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>A majority of the members of the Board shall constitute a quorum for purposes of conducting the business of the Board.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H304E47866A17430ABD6E6BB873614084"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Certain bylaws</header>
 <paragraph id="H37FA058D18BE47E58C724D217D030387"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Board shall include in the bylaws of the Foundation established under subsection (d)(1)(B) the following policies:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4DDBC4C7523545ACBD7536EA7683F2DC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Policies for the selection of the officers, employees, agents, and contractors of the Foundation.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9195FEDDA3042948CD54F3C1E21C216"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Policies, including ethical standards, for the acceptance, solicitation, and disposition of gifts, grants, and other donations to the Foundation, which shall require that—</text>
 <clause id="H92DDDD158A3648B0A68CD93C2A44F870"><enum>(i)</enum><text>officers, employees, agents, and contractors of the Foundation (including members of the Board) avoid encumbrances that would result in a conflict of interest, including a financial conflict of interest or a divided allegiance; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8436C151D09442E284B8D15E5A8A555E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>information concerning any ownership or controlling interest in any entity related to the activities of the Foundation be disclosed by officers, employees, agents, and contractors of the Foundation (including members of the Board) and the relatives (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc-act" parsable-cite="usc-act/Ethics in Government Act of 1978 /109">section 109</external-xref> of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)) of the officers, employees, agents, contractors, and members.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H432A851CD22644E9A6E3A913B33B6E4C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Policies for the disposition of the assets of the Foundation.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0856E6A4DED6489985D1CE0C06D15D5B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Policies for the conduct of the general operations of the Foundation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1816F15699884B0BBA70F16CF8662F35"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Policies for writing, editing, printing, publishing, and vending of books and other materials.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H980A754F4CFA4C21B2DEF6FB29C1536A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In establishing the bylaws of the Foundation, the Board shall ensure that the bylaws of the Foundation and the activities carried out under the bylaws of the Foundation shall not—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H934A4C1A6CE047D1B0B443F408132BD0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reflect unfavorably on the ability of the Foundation or the Secretary to carry out responsibilities or official duties in a fair and objective manner; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H56834F2F38774B8786F5B25AEED38151"><enum>(B)</enum><text>compromise, or appear to compromise, the integrity of any agency or program of the Federal Government, or any officer or employee involved in the program.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB588A89C7E4C42EE973920B9ACC359D3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Powers and duties</header>
 <paragraph id="HD2E6A489743E4ED5AE680423D9023E67"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Operation under direction of Board</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Foundation shall operate under the direction of the Board.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3DFD5AD38DBB4B97856F11616D2D44A9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Executive director</header> <subparagraph id="H5257231983244FE19E25AB8200A9C06E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An Executive Director of the Foundation shall be—</text>
 <clause id="H527EE306F8274A8AA7746E5937B43B73"><enum>(i)</enum><text>appointed by, and serve at the pleasure of, the Board; and</text> </clause><clause id="H2599BBA007C249CB846F8B281427FBD0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>responsible for—</text>
 <subclause id="H10C6A81239A340B1AFC12FCA2BFD56A8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the day-to-day operations of the Foundation; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H8227F514D35D474F8C3215C37E165DEF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>such specific duties and responsibilities as the Board may prescribe.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCBFA655E442A4D89A88BD3248DB34E0A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>The rate of compensation of the Executive Director shall be fixed by the Board.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAEF5BE747EDD47AA8A89BCEB0E7903AA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Corporate seal</header><text>The Foundation may adopt, alter, and use a corporate seal, which shall be judicially noticed.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H307E67ECB20149AC999600B067D861D6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Officers, employees, and agents</header><text>The Foundation may—</text> <subparagraph id="HB4182730DF4A4BCA8C83411C3632DA15"><enum>(A)</enum><text>hire, promote, compensate, and discharge officers, employees, agents, and contractors;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA3CCB67185C4D188687E11C00AF2DD8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>define the duties of the officers, employees, agents, and contractors;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H561F4914649741C181B69612176877D8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>require surety bonds or make other provisions against losses occasioned by acts of the officers, employees, agents, or contractors;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D28151BCE134ED1BB798AE0222C0A79"><enum>(D)</enum><text>with the consent of any Federal agency, use the information, services, staff, and facilities of the agency; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA48A3E664FC1484EBDE0C85625141486"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">appoint other groups of advisors as may be determined necessary.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA799A2C3E4E4E75BFE61F272E4BCF35"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Other powers</header><text>The Foundation may—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H01AF75E7786E46EB9FCC4A9B0449B514"><enum>(A)</enum><text>modify or consent to the modification of any contract or agreement to which the Foundation is a party or in which the Foundation has an interest;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82A5DBCF82DD428FBAE98D435D5CCC28"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enter into contracts with public and private organizations for the writing, editing, printing, and publishing of books and other material;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BC8E6AE036C49D99DA0E77E8A71198F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>take such action as may be necessary to obtain patents and licenses for devices and procedures developed by the Foundation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H750C80EAB51B4578A415F0E5FF651A4B"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enter into contracts, leases, cooperative agreements, and other transactions as the Executive Director considers appropriate to conduct the activities of the Foundation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H605C2EEA16754235A7C32654E5C4E285"><enum>(E)</enum><text>solicit, accept, hold, administer, invest, and spend any gift, devise, or bequest of real or personal property made to the Foundation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6B75F126040748388278588A66049FD1"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">sue and be sued in its corporate name and complain and defend itself in any court of competent jurisdiction; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDBBD164E539F43CE8B598EF0DBCC4ED7"><enum>(G)</enum><text>exercise such other powers, including incidental powers, as are necessary to carry out the powers, duties, and functions of the Foundation under this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H098C7EF7DF2E4E2CBE527504AAE2D48C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Fees</header><text>The Foundation may assess fees for the provision of professional, administrative, and management services by the Foundation in amounts determined reasonable and appropriate by the Executive Director.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3E264527950B48F08CE436CDC6451E1B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Incorporation</header><text>The initial members of the Board shall serve as incorporators and shall take any actions necessary to incorporate the Foundation.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCEC11586E16F447896EC67A37D05555C"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Nonprofit status</header><text>The Foundation shall be considered to be an organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Code.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HDE46E3C423BA4527800F142CB9AC08BC"><enum>(i)</enum><header>General provisions</header>
 <paragraph id="H74C6D309515F42D5AD31CBCBC17F0BC3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Foundation integrity</header><text>The Board shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H4615E6BA31454F2AA6D62BD8CCBD7F13"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be accountable for the integrity of the operations of the Foundation; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3FACE0422884678AADE0A48113E1781"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that integrity through the development and enforcement of criteria and procedures relating to—</text>
 <clause id="H3264CAB70A1242C8AE3174C638B6ACC4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>standards of conduct;</text> </clause><clause id="H308F7C39B4134E4DB40981FBD76D4048"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>financial disclosure statements;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H96D9F88DD7724DFDA6D8DA0E0CF3D4CB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>conflicts of interest;</text> </clause><clause id="H595AB345F9D64451A198B2D8F0F01E3B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>recusals and waivers;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H27FD7019BE84434B8A01CC70DCC12325"><enum>(v)</enum><text>audits; and</text> </clause><clause id="H998F396566054EF1880E962320101784"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>other matters determined appropriate by the Board.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5357FE8FD34D433BAC951D59B0BC7989"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Financial conflicts of interest</header><text>Any individual who is an officer, employee, or member of the Board shall not, in accordance with the policies established under subsection (e)(1)(B)(ii), personally or substantially participate in the consideration or determination by the Board of any matter that would directly and foreseeably affect any financial interest of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H23AADB08E40644259282F7D50F439F3D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the individual;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0ACA690DA7B47D7B8B98E41A9B7689E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a relative (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc-act" parsable-cite="usc-act/Ethics in Government Act of 1978 /109">section 109</external-xref> of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)) of the individual; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0F08F8633F14399903CC59924F222AA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any business organization or other entity—</text> <clause id="H51AFB306213C43A08531A52B66548DC8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>of which the individual is an officer or employee;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H47AAD3C59C864B35A1766EDBE1AA806E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>of which the individual is negotiating for employment; or</text> </clause><clause id="H7ECD1FFC257040CD97B6BD63DB57ADB1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in which the individual has any other financial interest.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE949662337934BCFA026DC9BF5460637"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Audits; availability of records</header><text>The Board shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H759D9BC21B5C431B89F14FAB7FA165B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct annual audits of the financial condition of the Foundation; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H287FC9E4A2104344B0D0CB3F067675D4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make those audits, and all other records, documents, and other papers of the Foundation, available to the Secretary and the Comptroller General of the United States for examination or audit.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC413EF92062E40CFB61327CE3E8A314C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reports</header>
 <subparagraph id="H63DE9F7E1BDF41DAA19CBD06E4B6206D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 150 days after the end of each fiscal year, the Board shall publish a report describing the activities of the Foundation during the preceding fiscal year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF0C9939FD13471FBF2EA5DFEA41474F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each report published under subparagraph (A) shall include, for the applicable fiscal year—</text> <clause id="H55BE4431650D4E18AAD743292E2CB1A9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a comprehensive statement of the operations, activities, financial condition, and accomplishments of the Foundation, including an accounting of the use of amounts transferred under subsection (k)(1); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD63289E394644AC789F8BD7DE919E417"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect to the financial condition of the Foundation—</text> <subclause id="HDD76CD75B1374F0A8F3D177564A8D663"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the source, and a description, of each gift or grant of real or personal property to the Foundation;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HC0AD22E5DD8041CF971B734817365168"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the source and amount of each cash gift or grant to the Foundation; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H2A1DBE41D7E2422CB67C95EE99420325"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a specification of any restrictions on the purposes for which the gifts and grants described in subclauses (I) and (II) may be used.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D0C54C8E50F4A1C8A18FCDF776573D7"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>The Board shall—</text> <clause id="H7D7970FA1A794C1F893331490C50C588"><enum>(i)</enum><text>make copies of each report submitted under subparagraph (A) available—</text>
 <subclause id="H04239D99F7A646F4AFBBD92E1D9549DA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>for public inspection; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HC68DF3F967F84AC18CCF0BE5EF536259"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to the appropriate committees of Congress; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H2C85CECAB64C46DE8DAC200DF8E4654B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>on request, provide a copy of any report submitted under subparagraph (A) to any individual for a charge that shall not exceed the cost of providing the copy.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF56061E762FE469FBFE12A67571CBCEC"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Public meeting</header><text>The Board shall annually hold a public meeting—</text> <clause id="H69DD47C0E59E42A0BA781115DDD8BA0D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to summarize the activities of the Foundation; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7B4C69F35D0040578A4ED36A55179DBB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to distribute written reports describing—</text> <subclause id="H1310DAA39B6A4BF88822920A09A2A638"><enum>(I)</enum><text>those activities; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H9F67500388C7473D841EDDC65BDEA2D5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the scientific results derived from those activities.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H605A1152BB954F329493EDE254078DDF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Service of Federal employees</header><text>A Federal employee may serve on a committee advisory to the Foundation and otherwise cooperate with and assist the Foundation in carrying out this Act, subject to the condition that the Federal employee shall not direct or control any activity of the Foundation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1BFB450EA8F04E61AFDA85D8701B0F8B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Relationship with existing entities</header><text>The Board may, in accordance with appropriate agreements, merge the Foundation with, acquire, or use the resources of an existing nonprofit private corporation that has a mission similar to the purpose of the Foundation described in subsection (b)(1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB6D8986A78C5408A98FEEAEC72E09D5E"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Intellectual property rights</header><text>The Board shall adopt written standards with respect to the ownership of any intellectual property rights derived from the collaborative efforts of the Foundation before the commencement of any collaborative efforts.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7BCAEF7475964CC1AF7C014926377BB1"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Transfer of funds</header><text>The Board may transfer amounts to the Secretary, and the Secretary may accept transfers of amounts from the Foundation.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5C5FE1CA814749249E050E71DBCA3C5B"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Support services</header><text>The Secretary may provide facilities, utilities, and support services to the Foundation if it is determined by the Secretary to be advantageous to the research programs of the Department of Energy.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H86EC5D125B6747CD9A6778C96AB27345"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as are necessary for fiscal year 2018 and each fiscal year thereafter.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HB85477D7CB9D4788A9CDC267A50C0C3A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Establishment of for-profit subsidiaries</header>
 <subsection id="H28EA371F36BC47D3AF93859DC145A4FB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Board may establish 1 or more for-profit subsidiaries, which may include an impact investment fund—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFDE06CDC87E34094846191049FFC0F21"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to stimulate economic development activities relating to the purpose of the Foundation described in section 3(b)(1); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H852F1DEEB911440B8071C60748B15928"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to attract for-profit investment partners for technology translation and commercialization activities.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H13DAADD549F6459D88067178CD2E39F1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorities of the for-Profit subsidiary</header>
 <paragraph id="HC3A4FD8276AB4B268E91DF877328BE82"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), a for-profit subsidiary established under subsection (a) may—</text> <subparagraph id="HFE307C3885F34C10A258D7E32294530A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enter partnerships with economic development corporations, including incubators, accelerators, and small business investment companies;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE50C22E8F4204F0D93CE42FEA446D7C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>pay for the cost of building and administering facilities, including microlabs and incubators, to support the activities of the Foundation described in section 3(b)(2); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H27E3703436FB42BDB6C3B39ECE31A004"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide funding to startups.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBBF1AF9457A443339BDFFEC5575093A0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cost recovery requirements</header><text>A for-profit subsidiary established under subsection (a) shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3450EAA8342B41F297D0675440925D7E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure that the Foundation owns any intellectual property rights generated through activities funded by the for-profit subsidiary, if appropriate; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCDB5984141FC482AB304256AFFC9FA1F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>own an equity stake in any startup invested in by the for-profit subsidiary.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

