<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H9EDDA4A6D1B6408184CCCBB2BB998082" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4375 IH: STEM Research and Education Effectiveness and Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4375</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171113">November 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001105">Mrs. Comstock</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000583">Mr. Smith of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000387">Mr. Knight</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for a study on broadening participation in certain National Science Foundation research
			 and education programs, to collect data on Federal research grants to
			 science agencies, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H23826DC856E54E5CB5849DF1AFE87711" style="OLC">
 <section id="HBCCDEB7CBAB74F5589A4ED487D78ED6C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>STEM Research and Education Effectiveness and Transparency Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H5B4709229B044B78A9DB263E7486600B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Broadening participation in STEM program effectiveness study</header> <subsection id="H068D1ECF94DE481AA1509EF738D616CA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 12 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the National Science Foundation shall submit a report to Congress on the effectiveness of all National Science Foundation research and education programs for broadening the participation of women and other historically underrepresented individuals in STEM studies and careers, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="H679F2ACC2F7D45069062C09387296BF2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>development or identification of performance metrics to evaluate such programs;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB5F55A74BBCA4B4692A3AC8377516DD9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>information on student outcomes using all available data, including dropout rates, enrollment in graduate programs, internships or apprenticeships, and employment;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF941D1198A82432CA1650033103C4A45"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identification of any data gaps for evaluating the effectiveness and outcomes of National Science Foundation programs to broaden participation; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H306FD413978E407F91A805516F966B34"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations for maintaining, translating, and disseminating outcomes data for STEM programs funded by the National Science Foundation.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H31C91C0357744D3093783521DBD6BAE4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition of STEM</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>STEM</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 2 of the America COMPETES Reauthorization Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6621">42 U.S.C. 6621</external-xref> note).</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H58AFD8B129D2486E95EA9E94FA2931CC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Collection and reporting of data on Federal research grants</header>
			<subsection id="H7D112A20CB4E42A9B2F60CC2B6FF3B04"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Collection of data</header>
 <paragraph id="HCA55ED287BEC4136A1006DB97B665636"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each Federal science agency shall collect standardized record-level annual information on demographics, primary field, award type, review rating, budget request, funding outcome, and awarded budget for all applications for merit-reviewed research and development grants to institutions of higher education and Federal laboratories supported by that agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1722353F075344A7A2CAAAEC340FC2E8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Uniformity and standardization</header><text>The Director shall establish a policy to ensure uniformity and standardization of the data collection required under paragraph (1).</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H9EE1956568EB4DDA995F75E45EC18B82"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Record-level data</header>
 <subparagraph id="H400F17BA063045A4A97D8638103A9DC0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>On an annual basis, beginning with the deadline under subparagraph (C), each Federal science agency shall submit to the Director of the National Science Foundation record-level data collected under paragraph (1) in the form required by such Director.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B11A297305941EE9D69C74205DAEA7C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Previous data</header><text>As part of the first submission under subparagraph (A), each Federal science agency, to the extent practicable, shall submit comparable record-level data for the 5 years preceding the deadline under subparagraph (C).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9064C3DAE264402395448F8A500C92A8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>The deadline under this paragraph is not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H56EA53CEB27C42CD92356DDDC932D35D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reporting of data</header><text>The Director of the National Science Foundation shall publish statistical summary data collected under this section, disaggregated and cross-tabulated demographically and by years since completion of doctoral degree, including in conjunction with the National Science Foundation’s report required by section 37 of the Science and Technology Equal Opportunities Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1885d">42 U.S.C. 1885d</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/96/516">Public Law 96–516</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE1F298FB19F24585B2A543CCED01BE7F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H6902B5261EBE4D2FBBC5901627D3CD0C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <quote>Director</quote> means the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9B71331936784E3C8FF3FB40100885A5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal laboratory</header><text>The term <quote>Federal laboratory</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 4 of the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3703">15 U.S.C. 3703</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA5FD37311A6740A896C0934F4062C705"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federal science agency</header><text>The term <quote>Federal science agency</quote> means any Federal agency with at least $100,000,000 in research and development expenditures in fiscal year 2017.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H89143E10EC26492C89F6B5FE9A49641E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <quote>institution of higher education</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


