<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7106361FB894499B81642609361BD9BF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3682 IH: Blue Whales and Blue Skies Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3682</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170906">September 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Director of the Office of National Marine Sanctuaries of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to create a Blue Whales and Blue Skies Program to reduce air pollution and harmful underwater acoustic impacts and the risk of fatal vessel whale strikes by recognizing voluntary reductions in the speed of vessels transiting the Greater Santa Barbara Channel Region, California, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H199E4497DA53476193589421A57574DD" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5CC812B5FADF415B9EFDDCB01E7AFAC6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Blue Whales and Blue Skies Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HE865F3EE9C7245F1BE3C28DE805B0F9F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Blue Whales and Blue Skies Program</header> <subsection id="HEB5292AAD9DC45408676D69B24111017"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 12 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of National Marine Sanctuaries of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, in consultation with the Commandant of the Coast Guard, shall establish the Blue Whales and Blue Skies Program, to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3E2206B64CEF4EBBB49396D89C4DE1FA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reduce air pollution and harmful underwater acoustic impacts and the risk of fatal whale strikes by encouraging voluntary reduction in the speed of eligible vessels transiting the Greater Santa Barbara Channel Region; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFB2E4FA3E43C45CD8D0374F9FB59A691"><enum>(2)</enum><text>annually award Blue Whales and Blue Skies Excellence Awards for verified successful participation in, and compliance with, the program by eligible vessels.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8FF7FEF94978476BA9BD2824ABC3D5EB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program requirements</header><text>The Director shall—</text> <paragraph id="H4540C52CC0964FD3BE7CB4A1D29E056D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">model the program after the pilot Vessel Speed Reduction Program administered by the Santa Barbara County Air Pollution Control District, the Ventura County Air Pollution Control District, the Channel Islands National Marine Sanctuary, the Environmental Defense Center (a nonprofit corporation established under the laws of the State of California as in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act), and the National Marine Sanctuary Foundation, except the Director may not provide a financial incentive for participation in the program; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEB1565972A764010A14DF047D8CB85A1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop the program in consultation with the entities referred to in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3BD4CBB0C0974BC2AF9F5757904607EF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual awards</header> <paragraph id="H205FD982808945DAB66B99A903D5F4A9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Under the program, the Director shall annually award Blue Whales and Blue Skies Excellence Awards to owners of eligible vessels that have complied with the program during the preceding year.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0FE1B01CA6914192B61DA4C3E3270E65"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Award conditions</header><text>As a condition of an award under this subsection, the Director shall require, at a minimum, that each eligible vessel of the awardee—</text> <subparagraph id="H6F69F49173374964993EBDED5D181026"><enum>(A)</enum><text>transit the Greater Santa Barbara Channel Region at speeds of 12 knots or lower, or at a lower maximum speed as provided in guidance established under the program; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE9498051C2C2472A89FE615BFC19BDAA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>participate in the Port of Los Angeles or Port of Long Beach vessel speed reduction program, respectively, if the vessel calls at that port in the transit for which the award is considered.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H43A7E2C58EBF4436A3AF6EDFF2399935"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Official seal</header><text>The Director shall create an official seal to be recognized as the symbol of excellence in compliance with the program, that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H791CC4DE19384004BBA8050E91DB1C90"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may be used by shipping companies with eligible vessels for which a Blue Whales and Blue Skies Excellence Award is awarded under this section;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H53656313E7874A03A7DE9E685FD98A63"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes the name of the shipping company;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2781B872E0B1414090BEF1A93B45E51F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>includes the year for which such award was made; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H24DCC68F3AC94D6A8A9D619C944928F5"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes the percentage of transits through the Greater Santa Barbara Channel Region by eligible vessels of the shipping company in such year that were in compliance with the program, calculated as—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA7A3F3C97B7447279BE3703C1177B22D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of such transits, divided by</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4EA889E1CD3844208455A67544EAC877"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total number of transits through the Greater Santa Barbara Channel Region by all vessels of the shipping company in such year, excluding transits directed by the Coast Guard to proceed in excess of the speed requirements of the program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAF11768EA32346CB89DCBC9171C68F98"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Extension of program</header><text>No later than 4 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director shall—</text> <paragraph id="HE8D05787355B4087A1DFE67CF4D6B869"><enum>(1)</enum><text>consider the feasibility of extending the program to encompass all shipping channels along the United States Pacific coast between Canada and Mexico; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEF475E11E2464C6E849F9B8F78912916"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">report the findings and recommendations under paragraph (1) to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives, and to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5ED9A7D0439C4219800C6F52E3027758"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed—</text> 
<paragraph id="HFFA589F68BD7478496D1A77BB7B2DB94"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to require participation in the program;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H60AC3638942642E09BA43E0ADA08D717"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to authorize appropriations for, or the provision of, any financial incentive for participation in the program; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB3DD0D26F6FA44B182C49560EAAC0760"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to authorize any action that affects navigation safety.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDB431E002E0C49768245AD83D2CBBA01"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H146F75888D8146BEA288FF230FA70599"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible vessel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>eligible vessel</quote> means a vessel that has been approved by the Director to participate in the program.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB2B09F5F43DB42F09AE954B6B01162FB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The term <quote>program</quote> means the Blue Whales and Blue Skies Program established under this section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBCD259C713B94560B214851F59AB9B78"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Greater Santa Barbara Channel Region</header><text>The term <quote>Greater Santa Barbara Channel Region</quote>—</text> <subparagraph id="HF7577574537A46A2ADF426E361E6A6D1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means such portion of the geographic zone used by vessels transporting goods to transit the area surrounding the Channel Islands, including the Santa Barbara Channel, California, as is designated by the Director for purposes of this section; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2219AB51D2FB439D900D6CF2DAD6F122"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes, at a minimum, the geographic area identified in the pilot Vessel Speed Reduction Program referred to in subsection (b)(1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

