<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC011537B712C4DD9A8DF12E644CF263E" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3965 IH: Veterans Armed for Success Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3965</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171005">October 5, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000586">Mr. Lawson of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to make grants to eligible organizations for the
			 provision of transition assistance to members of the Armed Forces recently
			 separated from active duty service and spouses of such members.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HF81F4269944C495F85D4F7E64E877A39" style="OLC">
 <section id="HDE6540159DE84EDF89A509B5FFAE1F3B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Armed for Success Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H866651FD663644B593F0EEE00CE0F586"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants for provision of transition assistance to members of the Armed Forces recently separated from active duty service</header> <subsection id="H9AAF72E0BC5849EC909E672AD7EFA96C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall make grants to eligible organizations for the provision of transition assistance to members of the Armed Forces who are recently retired, separated, or discharged from the Armed Forces and spouses of such members.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9D99FDD33E0D46F29257EBE15C249334"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The recipient of a grant under this section shall use the grant to provide to members of the Armed Forces and spouses described in subsection (a) resume assistance, interview training, job recruitment training, and related services leading directly to careers, as determined by the grant recipient.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD896AD2DA9B541A3A7A4A866889A6D57"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible organizations</header><text>To be eligible for a grant under this section, an organization shall submit to the Secretary an application containing such information and assurances as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCB5E6B1718724EC68F30DD57710A8642"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Amount of grant</header><text>A grant under this section shall be in an amount that does not exceed 50 percent of the amount required by the organization to provide the services described in subsection (b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC7CD19091729465B83A3A802C4CE42B8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The authority to provide a grant under this section shall terminate on the date that is five years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4D2BD7B1109A4E748D405B43D584D048"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 to carry out this section.</text> </subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

