<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD883BE2C489C49C3B2ABB0F87E88D3B6" key="S" public-private="public" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 699 RS: Mount Hood Cooper Spur Land Exchange Clarification Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 72</calendar><congress>115th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 699</legis-num><associated-doc role="report">[Report No. 115–59]</associated-doc><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20170228">February 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSEG00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><action stage="Reported-in-Senate"><action-date>May 9, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Reported by <sponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</sponsor>, without amendment</action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 to modify provisions relating to certain
			 land exchanges in the Mt. Hood Wilderness in the State of Oregon.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H29E1EE71B7274BB98F0280B3C3474E42" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE577AC15DC6049219F38090CC1D1C9C0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Mount Hood Cooper Spur Land Exchange Clarification Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H5BF1BFD2E6F745A9B066DF3759169BB9"><enum>2.</enum><header> Cooper Spur land exchange clarification amendments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1206(a) of the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/11">Public Law 111–11</external-xref>; 123 Stat. 1018) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HBA07A90B47584A95BAEC34B2B2DC9CBB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="HFE7436B0118141E7B4986BEC31D078F2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>120 acres</quote> and inserting <quote>107 acres</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H806EB6B764814D7AA25A7CCB6B73821B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (E)(ii), by inserting <quote>improvements,</quote> after <quote>buildings,</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1CF034D2F4F471E8760A6A18BED7E03"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB5CAD5EB98E545C3B2805CA970A196A5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D)—</text> <clause id="H97DD55CEDF494E9ABB1B6468ED305401"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary and Mt. Hood Meadows shall select</quote> and inserting <quote>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of the Mount Hood Cooper Spur Land Exchange Clarification Act, the Secretary and Mt. Hood Meadows shall jointly select</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3FD28C1B82AF41FC9CDDCA045DF0CCD3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (ii), in the matter preceding subclause (I), by striking <quote>An appraisal under clause (i) shall</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided under clause (iii), an appraisal under clause (i) shall assign a separate value to each tax lot to allow for the equalization of values and</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA96A29A0C1554B9FBFE29E22E360E2D3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H07E8D1CF8F3D47899BF2EDB082961893" style="OLC"> <clause id="H4D8512E50DC0479CACAFCEC70C71F063"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Final appraised value</header> <subclause id="HF987F7CB5BA14DC8BD588ECFFFC3F578"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subclause (II), after the final appraised value of the Federal land and the non-Federal land are determined and approved by the Secretary, the Secretary shall not be required to reappraise or update the final appraised value for a period of up to 3 years, beginning on the date of the approval by the Secretary of the final appraised value.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H605CCD037121406C84F554D474CB8E93"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Subclause (I) shall not apply if the condition of either the Federal land or the non-Federal land referred to in subclause (I) is significantly and substantially altered by fire, windstorm, or other events.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H59768E7E59A34FE398B99F7A66BF105E"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Public review</header><text>Before completing the land exchange under this Act, the Secretary shall make available for public review the complete appraisals of the land to be exchanged.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E867300913B410DB157B7EE97C54BD0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (G) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H6733416B6BAE4484863639D8A4C62E04" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HEDD352AFBEE342E2ABCE747C31FAE2BC"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Required conveyance conditions</header><text>Prior to the exchange of the Federal and non-Federal land—</text>
 <clause id="HCBD58064809A46FFBAA57FF5E6CE6883"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary and Mt. Hood Meadows may mutually agree for the Secretary to reserve a conservation easement to protect the identified wetland in accordance with applicable law, subject to the requirements that—</text>
 <subclause id="HA3B01B27A3FD416AA956B39464B44BFD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the conservation easement shall be consistent with the terms of the September 30, 2015, mediation between the Secretary and Mt. Hood Meadows; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB4C03C9F92474F8DA11C6539CF3C4AEF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in order to take effect, the conservation easement shall be finalized not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of the Mount Hood Cooper Spur Land Exchange Clarification Act; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HD23E99F118664FE0AB7D5554674559E9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Secretary shall reserve a 24-foot-wide nonexclusive trail easement at the existing trail locations on the Federal land that retains for the United States existing rights to construct, reconstruct, maintain, and permit nonmotorized use by the public of existing trails subject to the right of the owner of the Federal land—</text>
 <subclause id="H1DF06A4F7A374F0290D3113186548670"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to cross the trails with roads, utilities, and infrastructure facilities; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HE19B51C4E40F4BEE88F94C837D976A96"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to improve or relocate the trails to accommodate development of the Federal land.</text>
								</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6E9E0825A5914B1497BEEEDF596515EC"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Equalization of values</header>
 <clause commented="no" id="HFF940B2755DB4FC08374A81D0F6B5ADA"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), in addition to or in lieu of monetary compensation, a lesser area of Federal land or non-Federal land may be conveyed if necessary to equalize appraised values of the exchange properties, without limitation, consistent with the requirements of this Act and subject to the approval of the Secretary and Mt. Hood Meadows.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H4166C7C862A84FFCB0530F426790F521"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Treatment of certain compensation or conveyances as donation</header><text>If, after payment of compensation or adjustment of land area subject to exchange under this Act, the amount by which the appraised value of the land and other property conveyed by Mt. Hood Meadows under subparagraph (A) exceeds the appraised value of the land conveyed by the Secretary under subparagraph (A) shall be considered a donation by Mt. Hood Meadows to the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body><endorsement><action-date>May 9, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Reported without amendment</action-desc></endorsement></bill>


