<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H8ADA911B8C494F9CA06F847900E4C744" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 938 IH: Medicaid Third Party Liability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 938</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170207">February 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="F000461">Mr. Flores</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to provide clarification with respect to the
			 liability of third party payers for medical assistance paid under the
			 Medicaid program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H3DDA40A572CA4C718999B2B84B0EC222" style="OLC">
 <section id="H2621AC28544441DCACB87775E08E36F2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medicaid Third Party Liability Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H01E48112EDD3435685809257092CD438"><enum>2.</enum><header>Medicaid third party liability</header> <subsection id="HE13498E386374C97A06898246F5E6104"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Clarification of definitions applicable to third party liability</header> <paragraph id="HD1BB3FA30D6D47B7B9031977B265F3FB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1902 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF12EDE55C1BA4317B37E14F3362274DC" style="traditional">
 <subsection id="HD71F31E68E4645EAA1389B96FA17778E"><enum>(nn)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (a)(25) and section 1903(d)(2)(B), the term <quote>responsible third party</quote> means a health insurer (including a group health plan, as defined in section 607(1) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, a self-insured plan, a fully-insured plan<italic></italic>, a service benefit plan, a managed care organization, a pharmacy benefit manager, and any other health plan determined appropriate by the Secretary), the TRICARE program under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/55">chapter 55</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, an accountable care organization, or any other party that is, by statute, contract, or agreement, legally responsible for payment of a claim for a health care item or service.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H042CBFA6F33243398310CC0057603D10"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1902(a)(25) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)(25)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HABE4A50F06DA4463BA2FC132BB793A56"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>third parties</quote> and all that follows through <quote>item or service)</quote> and inserting <quote>responsible third parties</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0AE7604CE97F449083FECCDF41F132B1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (G), by striking <quote>health insurer</quote> and all that follows through <quote>item or service)</quote> and inserting <quote>responsible third party</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7514A2841FF94BD4A7B72C3D3ED97817"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (I), in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>health insurers</quote> and all that follows through <quote>item or service</quote> and inserting <quote>responsible third parties</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6BD9B32E7EFA4C0EB932B04ED54446B7"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting <quote>responsible</quote> before <quote>third</quote> each place it appears in subparagraphs (A)(i), (A)(ii), (C), (D), and (H).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC41A3DE3B9AD46BCAA76DA7B0751411D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Removal of special treatment of certain types of care and payments under Medicaid third party liability rules</header><text>Section 1902(a)(25) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)(25)</external-xref>) is amended by striking subparagraphs (E) and (F).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H0610D012F2EF44DF855960B4E5ECF232"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clarification of role of health insurers with respect to third party liability</header>
 <paragraph id="HFDB95041F60B4A1FA5123780D3B8584D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1902(a)(25) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)(25)</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (b), is further amended by inserting after subparagraph (D) the following new subparagraphs:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB18A9401691C46069B8C192ABE59124C" style="traditional">
 <subparagraph id="H0B230AD3F44A4A01B220A8B2B02B2FE3"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that, in the case of a State that provides medical assistance under this title through a contract with a health insurer (including a group health plan, as defined in section 607(1) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, a self-insured plan, a fully-insured plan, a service benefit plan, a managed care organization, a pharmacy benefit manager, and any other health plan determined appropriate by the Secretary), such contract shall specify whether the State is—</text>
 <clause id="H19397880A1834DB88E47EA4C34633D77"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">delegating to such insurer all or some of its right of recovery from a responsible third party for an item or service for which payment has been made under the State plan (or under a waiver of the plan); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3EF7542DC4DD4DAE8404F094B6767959"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">transferring to such insurer all or some of the assignment to the State of any right of an individual or other entity to payment from a responsible third party for an item or service for which payment has been made under the State plan (or under a waiver of the plan);</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34182DA3FCC94CCBBFB6191EC9C92C4F"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that, in the case of a State that elects an option described in clause (i) or (ii) of subparagraph (E) with respect to a health insurer (including a group health plan, as defined in section 607(1) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, a self-insured plan, a fully-insured plan<italic></italic>, a service benefit plan, a managed care organization, a pharmacy benefit manager, and any other health plan determined appropriate by the Secretary), the State shall provide assurances to the Secretary that the State laws referred to in subparagraph (I) confer to the health insurer the authority of the State with respect to the requirements specified in clauses (i) through (iv) of such subparagraph;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD03C84353A78427BA4274C32EFB93217"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of collected amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1903(d)(2)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396b">42 U.S.C. 1396b(d)(2)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>For purposes of this subparagraph, reimbursements made by a responsible third party to health insurers (including group health plans, as defined in section 607(1) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, self-insured plans, fully-insured plans, service benefit plans, managed care organizations, pharmacy benefit managers, and any other health plan determined appropriate by the Secretary) pursuant to section 1902(a)(25)(E) shall be treated in the same manner as reimbursements made to a State under the previous sentence.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H601EA8C08E0E4E058634EC45104B6370"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this subsection shall take effect on October 1, 2017.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4358D1A71B8C47E5904AA43963CD9440"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Increasing State flexibility with respect to third party liability</header><text>Section 1902(a)(25)(I) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)(25)(I)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0C843937DE434DC8AB3CAE18FEB951B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause (i), by striking <quote>medical assistance under the State plan</quote> and inserting <quote>medical assistance under a State plan (or under a waiver of the plan)</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H248A50AD2F574DC09A1C9A0F50D28507"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking clause (ii) and inserting the following new clause:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF0F444B7612A4254BB0FE87BB2325103" style="traditional">
 <clause id="H86D108F0260C4180A317E8E97122DEF2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>accept—</text> <subclause id="HF940D4B318124EFC80D8F93A7B3A21C8"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any State’s right of recovery and the assignment to any State of any right of an individual or other entity to payment from the party for an item or service for which payment has been made under the respective State’s plan (or under a waiver of the plan); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA8796421C74F47B7A724CF278E0235C8"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as a valid authorization of the responsible third party for the furnishing of an item or service to an individual eligible to receive medical assistance under this title, an authorization made on behalf of such individual under the State plan (or under a waiver of such plan) for the furnishing of such item or service to such individual;</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA2C6E098FDF2493F943DDF3A2DF0F0F7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in clause (iii)—</text> <subparagraph id="H7DCE96EB1526413F920ADCA0C1077CDD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>respond to</quote> and inserting <quote>not later than 60 days after receiving</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8FDC4508E8384F1687DE525DB4E49A86"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>; and</quote> at the end and inserting <quote>, respond to such inquiry; and</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HED53877205F94D1A9A81154D2CC4E9EE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in clause (iv), by inserting <quote>a failure to obtain a prior authorization,</quote> after <quote>claim form,</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFC950A3DCAED442CA8FA7C07415635F0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>State incentive To pursue third party liability for newly eligibles</header><text>Section 1903(d)(2)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396b">42 U.S.C. 1396b(d)(2)(B)</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (c)(2), is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>In the case of expenditures for medical assistance provided during 2017 and subsequent years for individuals described in subclause (VIII) of section 1902(a)(10)(A)(i), in determining the amount, if any, of overpayment under this subparagraph with respect to such medical assistance, the Secretary shall apply the Federal medical assistance percentage for the State under section 1905(b), notwithstanding the application of section 1905(y).</quote>.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HC2A7C6B4E285462080741FEB97BBDAD1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Compliance with third party insurance reporting</header>
 <subsection id="H362B021C7074466C9054A7DEF6A21F56"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1903 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396b">42 U.S.C. 1396b</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after subsection (m) the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD93F11520571422ABA62C5A9D219D318" style="traditional">
					<subsection id="H875621A4D16045589BA67842AA44B4B3"><enum>(n)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF4379088B8A540A9BBA62D68B5F68347"><enum>(1)</enum><text>For any year beginning after 2020 (except as provided in paragraph (2)), unless a State complies with the requirements of section 1902(a)(25) with respect to each calendar quarter in such year, the Federal medical assistance percentage shall be reduced by 1 percentage point for calendar quarters in each subsequent year in which the State fails to so comply (and cumulatively for a failure to so comply for a period of consecutive years).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2BCD706943EC455CA8A147E489665978" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), the reduction in the Federal medical assistance percentage shall apply—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H85F5F3D63E5C4074AD2E07F729ACC660"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a failure of the State to comply with the requirements of section 1902(a)(25) with respect to payment for items and services furnished to individuals described in subclause (VIII) of section 1902(a)(10)(A)(i), for any year beginning after 2018; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H880ADD7BF2704916ACD6E7515DBAAC77"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a failure of the State to comply with the requirements of section 1902(a)(25) with respect to payment for items and services furnished to individuals described in subdivision (i), (iii), or (iv) of section 1905(a), for any year beginning after 2019.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H9F83417EF3654A9B9EB8B4448BF77202"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Verification of insurance status required</header>
 <paragraph id="H6E1325021465438A9D5252DF57DBB055"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1902(a)(25)(A)(i) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)(25)(A)(i)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, including the collection of, with respect to an individual seeking to receive medical assistance under this title, information on whether the individual has health insurance coverage provided through a health insurer (as described in section 1902(nn)) and the plan of such insurer in which the individual is enrolled</quote> after <quote>sufficient information</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H38A458D1F35B4CA39A378BD4438C44BB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>FFP unavailable without insurance status verification</header><text>Section 1903(i)(25) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396b">42 U.S.C. 1396b(i)(25)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H255D43DDA77847C48EE123C7B73FA287"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>with respect to</quote> and inserting <quote>(A) with respect to</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD667D52A38442FCACB5ECC7175868BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting before the semicolon at the end the following: <quote>and (B) with respect to any amounts expended for medical assistance for individuals for whom the State has not obtained and verified, in accordance with section 1902(a)(25)(A)(i), information on whether such an individual has health insurance coverage provided through a health insurer (as described in section 1902(nn)) and the plan of such insurer in which the individual is enrolled</quote>.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H52B42624113A40108579DEF0DFCFB7E4"><enum>4.</enum><header>Application to CHIP</header>
 <subsection id="H9086DA69E16A4D7DB13C45AF7DB9E086"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2107(e)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397gg">42 U.S.C. 1397gg(e)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H2DF8E6DE99FE451A947301214DF4C296"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (B) through (R) as subparagraphs (C) through (S), respectively; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE0AE542F345E4AEAB56C1E92E4FB37DC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (A) the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6B56ABBA7C8F4E7493700A26A55B9497" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HA2FB0827FE6D413AB19C7671C0687640"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1902(a)(25) (relating to third party liability).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD3B749F726FC41C6A36FBE3ECD3C4207"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Mandatory reporting</header><text>Section 1902(a)(25)(I)(i) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)(25)(I)(i)</external-xref>), as amended by section 1(d), is further amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9F8B60C475814B96B8456E3F0E63D0AA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(and, at State option, child</quote> and inserting <quote>and child</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBA372200E1BE443EA43B6E75D67A3C0A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>title XXI)</quote> and inserting <quote>title XXI</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA907C193DFD14FE48D8E56AE5DF14200"><enum>5.</enum><header>Training on third party liability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1936 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396u-6">42 U.S.C. 1396u–6</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H686F2DDFD474445C9C54802AE0F2188C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(4), by striking <quote>and quality of care</quote> and inserting <quote>, quality of care, and the liability of responsible third parties (as defined in section 1902(nn))</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9AF02F460C4B4AE9BA05F6298EAAC659"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HECDE3400D8174B9D81833897CC4A55DA" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H0B9F8C27EF414D5C998C06B8549C8CF6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Third party liability training</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to education or training activities carried out pursuant to subsection (b)(4) with respect to the liability of responsible third parties (as defined in section 1902(nn) for payment for items and services furnished under State plans (or under waivers of such plans)) under this title, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC008C611CC7E4070ABA0629AA2EE44EC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>publish (and update on an annual basis) on the public Internet website of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services a dedicated Internet page containing best practices to be used in assessing such liability;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF9B29410D9F24D90970FA873581C6466"><enum>(2)</enum><text>monitor efforts to assess such liability and analyze the challenges posed by that assessment;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA8ED89A7CC9A4D1C81FB78D7C3787E48"><enum>(3)</enum><text>distribute to State agencies administering the State plan under this title information related to such efforts and challenges; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFA53C8785BC7474E8EAC9C178DA7A65C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide guidance to such State agencies with respect to State oversight of efforts by medicaid managed care organizations (as defined in section 1903(m)(1)) to assess such liability.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H287219BA3418419FA94269EB9E417F2E"><enum>6.</enum><header>Development of model uniform fields for States to report third party information</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than January 1, 2018, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall, in consultation with the States, develop and make available to the States a model uniform reporting field that States may use for purposes of reporting to the Secretary within CMS Form 64 (or any successor form) information identifying responsible third parties (as defined in subsection (nn) of section 1902 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a</external-xref>)) and other relevant information for ascertaining the legal responsibility of such third parties to pay for care and services available under the State plan (or under a waiver of the plan) under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
		</section><section id="HF2BE67EBB4D44EF6A9192BD3B44DCCE9"><enum>7.</enum><header>Effective date</header>
 <subsection id="H21EAB3B9992E4E1B9EC6D162880C6A10"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in <internal-xref idref="H3974E699600D4213883E427D45D062E5" legis-path="6.(b)">subsection (b)</internal-xref>, this Act and the amendments made by this Act (other than as specified in the preceding provisions of this Act) shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act and shall apply to medical assistance provided on or after such date.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3974E699600D4213883E427D45D062E5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception if State legislation required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a State plan for medical assistance under title XIX of the Social Security Act that the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines requires State legislation (other than legislation appropriating funds) in order for the plan to meet the additional requirement imposed by the amendments made under this section, the State plan shall not be regarded as failing to comply with the requirements of such title solely on the basis of its failure to meet this additional requirement before the first day of the first calendar quarter beginning after the close of the first regular session of the State legislature that begins after the date of the enactment of this Act. For purposes of the previous sentence, in the case of a State that has a 2-year legislative session, each year of such session shall be deemed to be a separate regular session of the State legislature.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


