<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H510EDACAD29C45A498256EFC7DF6EAAF" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1096 IH: Judgment Fund Transparency Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1096</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170215">February 15, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001192">Mr. Stewart</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000576">Mr. Long</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000580">Mr. Roskam</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000470">Mr. Tipton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001076">Mr. Chaffetz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000588">Mr. Pearce</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001177">Mr. McClintock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001250">Mr. Bishop of Utah</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 31, United States Code, to provide for transparency of payments made from the
			 Judgment Fund.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H053061ECDE044B9D9E2EF9935E2AEEEC" style="OLC">
 <section id="H7C1B3C979A7140BB8482F87E8C6D9DE0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Judgment Fund Transparency Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H2B41D603A2E24A3C8F42EDFA77743DDB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Judgment fund transparency</header> <subsection id="HFB02CF613EE84E1B988761BD86F652F6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Transparency requirement</header><text>Section 1304 of title 31, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H2FC6FA176B07481E8B8CB0609CC19280" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="HBCF73FABBBE54E50815BE5A9683E059E"><enum>(d)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H05ABC796052D4FA99693410E14DD10D5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Unless the disclosure of such information is otherwise prohibited by law or court order, the Secretary of the Treasury shall make available to the public on a website, as soon as practicable, but not later than 30 days after the date on which a payment under this section is tendered on or after January 1, 2016, the following information with regard to that payment:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H219F5A60688847128D7EF51751208DDA" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The name of the specific agency or entity whose actions gave rise to the claim or judgment.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB4E8620C9DEA49CFAD382E5388C1ADC1" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The name of the plaintiff or claimant.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C9F21519CD242C791ED826A2BECDB8D" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The name of counsel for the plaintiff or claimant.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB83714AFB4D4779BF59998295A22F03" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The amount paid representing principal liability, and any amounts paid representing any ancillary liability, including attorney fees, costs, and interest.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01C2FAEA88314B8DA33590E5CD7E1EDC" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A brief description of the facts that gave rise to the claim.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0EFD440C8FF4C55BEB8DC4410EA3475" indent="up1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The name of the agency that submitted the claim.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H882C1F121A47464DB62CB8ED341E0455" indent="up1"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any information available on reports generated by the Judgment Fund Payment Search administered by the Treasury Department.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BBD025A0A974FB0BDAB67EFF17CE0C4" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In addition to the information described in paragraph (1), if a payment under this section is made to a foreign state on or after January 1, 2016, the Secretary of the Treasury shall make available to the public in accordance with paragraph (1), the following information with regard to that payment:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H68EED50BC1A445C38ECCBCD222FAE74B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of the method of payment.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66FA01E01B0B4CBAACFA3274DD1BFEA3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of the currency denominations used for the payment.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F667D76B264451C9A6E1CC77F554A27"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The name and location of each financial institution owned or controlled, directly or indirectly, by a foreign state or an agent of a foreign state through which the payment passed or from which the payment was withdrawn, including any financial institution owned or controlled, directly or indirectly, by a foreign state or an agent of a foreign state that is holding the payment as of the date on which the information is made available.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H916D547A691F40879C6F96D2EA74BC6E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>foreign state</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 1603 of title 28.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2682EAB201B54433B9CBB7093E0077E5"><enum>(e)</enum><text>Except with regard to children under eighteen, the disclosure of information required in this section shall not be considered a <quote>clearly unwarranted invasion of personal privacy</quote> for purposes of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H396CE8461E3B4504A9B095041CE080AD"><enum>(f)</enum><text>No payment may be made under this section to a state sponsor of terrorism, as defined in section 1605A(h) of title 28.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H742054A6FFC84BDB8AAF0F232DBA63CB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall carry out the amendment made by this section by not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


