<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD4573CAFE57D45F39545ABC49FD0D784" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3793 IH: HUD Manufactured Housing Modernization Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3793</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170914">September 14, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to consider the appropriate inclusion of
			 residential manufactured homes in certain programs, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H7C5D473D5D5348F1904A32BD7739FF7A" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE7B834C6AA8E49B8AEF52085D24FFEBC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>HUD Manufactured Housing Modernization Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H216E7E03CE1B4E17BDDCAD341AC8EAE2" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HDE5520F539574EE9B9296A0E9C35A9AD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Manufactured housing is the largest source of unsubsidized affordable housing in the country.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3BC829ECCFD34661AA2CA9689C80E7BE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Nearly 18,000,000 Americans live in manufactured housing, which opens the door to homeownership for families who, in many housing markets, cannot afford to buy a site-built home.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC0E39A47FEF24D819BDB744A5762F1DE"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A manufactured home qualified under the Energy Star program established by section 324A of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6294a">42 U.S.C. 6294a</external-xref>) can save homeowners an average of 24 to 29 percent on total heating and cooling costs, compared to a typical manufactured home.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H69280AFD4080493481E3A728F9555412"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Over 40 percent of manufactured homes are found in land lease communities or <quote>parks</quote>, but new ownership structures, such as resident-owned cooperatives or communities owned by nonprofits or public housing authorities, can provide homeowners greater land tenure security and stability that enhances the value of their homes.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H57D2ACE0AC8A4E85AFC0E34B4FB97B2F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>These advances position manufactured homes to appreciate in value and open the door to homeownership for millions of families, and have proven to be an effective long-term affordable housing preservation strategy for communities across the United States.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H02417370AFB3466B86118F043841451F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Issuance of guidelines relating to residential manufactured homes</header>
 <subsection id="H30993703A91D4DB2B2B0A24529899F64"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any new rule or regulation, or any revision of a rule or regulation, issued by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall include, as appropriate, guidelines that assess the impact of the rule or regulation on owners of residential manufactured homes and the production and sale of residential manufactured homes.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H52C879C3ACE24DF296A0043C218494F3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consolidated Plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall issue guidelines for jurisdictions relating to the appropriate inclusion of residential manufactured homes in a Consolidated Plan of the jurisdiction.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HA24B77DD6B9E482CBB0E59D48B7BF3EF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H7131CDEFCD9840D9831DFE0E12CA96D0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Residential manufactured home</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>residential manufactured home</term> means a manufactured home (as defined in section 603(6) of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5402">42 U.S.C. 5402(6)</external-xref>)) which is used as a residence.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC3F3C4B970644906A3913700CB48E162"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consolidated Plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Consolidated Plan</term> means a comprehensive housing affordability strategy and community development plan required under part 91 of title 24, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


