<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H14E38AB8F8A545C2857A1C4EB34F2E25" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4596 IH: Cooperative Research and Development Fund Authorization Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4596</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171207">December 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000570">Mr. Ben Ray Luján of New Mexico</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To make funds available to the Department of Energy National Laboratories for the Federal share of
			 cooperative research and development agreements that support maturing
			 Laboratory technology and transferring it to the private sector, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HF5E73D12528B4E4189ADFEE795722DB5" style="OLC">
 <section id="H0C8EBC7812224F89B587177CE6E5C56C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cooperative Research and Development Fund Authorization Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HE0D5EFDF023349BC80E69764EFB68D19"><enum>2.</enum><header>Cooperative research and development fund</header> <subsection id="H21F27C630B414F3E966990E26961D8EB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Energy shall make funds available to Department of Energy National Laboratories for the Federal share of cooperative research and development agreements that support maturing laboratory technology and transferring it to the private sector.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HAD817A04954541F9AB61A0AFBF3381B4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Apportionment</header>
 <paragraph id="HAE5EEC2D6F5047729D875E48DC3EAF90"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Energy shall determine the apportionment of such funds to each Department of Energy National Laboratory and shall ensure that special consideration is given to small business firms and consortia involving small business firms in the selection process for which cooperative research and development agreements will receive such funds.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H85053538BDA640B680F423FD1A44F7F0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>small business firm</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 4 of the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3703">15 U.S.C. 3703</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6B0DC3198CCA49D88AEF6A7965A40868"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Performance evaluation metrics</header><text>The Secretary of Energy shall ensure that the performance evaluation metrics of each National Laboratory operating contractor provide incentives for, and measure the effectiveness of, the contractor’s cooperative research and development agreement program at maturing laboratory technology and transferring it to the private sector.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HB4AC104BD9DF463892EE34F81CB76161"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reporting</header>
 <paragraph id="HBA29AD2A07CF4BAF95EB1D1754E03E10"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Energy shall annually transmit to Congress a report that describes how funds were expended under this section, including a description of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H69516385FFD74D6DA9A1C05F7755C343"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the types and sizes of non-Federal entities that participated in cooperative research and development agreements receiving funds under this section; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H24326531E0C54B4BA14E28E71EB65560"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the economic benefits resulting from cooperative research and development agreements that received funds under this section in previous years.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0AED4FA9659D455CB23DE03570EC46BC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consolidation of reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reports required under this subsection may be consolidated with other related reports required from the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3DF47EF8A5064F808EB293B3E2562E66"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to preclude or limit the use of funding provided under other authority of law for entering into or increasing the Federal share of cooperative research and development agreements, either in combination with funding provided under this section or separately.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8DB25328DB0649D7A421966618FD4E68"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Energy to carry out this section $20,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2018 through 2022.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


