<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC06487587E7F43799C93C67C66491BB1" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2412 IH: Keep Our Pension Promises Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2412</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170511">May 11, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001049">Mr. Clay</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000127">Mr. Nolan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000799">Mr. Walz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000062">Mr. Yarmuth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000410">Mr. Gene Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000108">Mr. Visclosky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001050">Ms. Hanabusa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986
			 to modify certain provisions relating to multiemployer pensions, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H4A3151C909D941A2A428501D6EBA1B96" style="OLC">
 <section id="H7842A7D9692C41A2AF5CE517465F9375" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Keep Our Pension Promises Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H25C5FB42F5E846248F7E62D2A4243FB0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Restoring anti-cutback provisions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 201 of the Multiemployer Pension Reform Act of 2014 (division O of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/235">Public Law 113–235</external-xref>) and the amendments made by such section are repealed, and the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall be applied as if such section and amendments had never been enacted.</text>
		</section><section commented="no" id="HAEAA9E8D263C460181345C738A1AF1D3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Partitions of eligible multiemployer plans</header>
 <subsection id="HC8D286847BE24D9EAC60E16D3B5B7058"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 4233 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1413">29 U.S.C. 1413</external-xref>), as amended by section 122 of the Multiemployer Pension Reform Act of 2014 (division O of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/235">Public Law 113–235</external-xref>), is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H355131A4FA0D4A0F95E37C3A6D453163" style="OLC">
					<section id="H9C65FCF31C7F419DAA05E7DD4C41FE60"><enum>4233.</enum><header>Partitions of eligible multiemployer plans</header>
						<subsection id="H1410EC2C16D44AD09ED4F5A39996357A"><enum>(a)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H750E7973C5CA4D2490D0913EFB710DFA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Upon the application by the plan sponsor of an eligible multiemployer plan for a partition of the plan, the corporation may order a partition of the plan in accordance with this section. The corporation shall make a determination regarding the application, in accordance with regulations promulgated by the corporation, not later than 270 days after—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7616E3D6041E4554AC3521C61AD9C1D1" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the date such application was filed; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDFAC56CC7B024389B5AC669F4B9255A6" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if later, the date such application was completed.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H27030F9FADBF47C38FD3C5F48373F45F" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>At least 14 days before submitting an application for partition of a plan under paragraph (1), the plan sponsor of the plan shall notify all participants and beneficiaries of such application, in the form and manner prescribed by regulations issued by the corporation.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCAB7707FBA4345DA9FE218084AEA881B"><enum>(b)</enum><text>For purposes of this section, a multiemployer plan is an eligible multiemployer plan if—</text> <paragraph id="HDAA6DA9FEBBC4840BBBE7997E7852FF3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the plan is in critical status and is projected to become insolvent within the meaning of section 4245—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEA3E5C8562D04D8B8B7F66D0C18D942F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>during the current plan year or any of the 14 succeeding plan years; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC939E2075A3D486C964BF75B6F17D382"><enum>(B)</enum><text>during the current plan year or any of the 19 succeeding plan years, if the plan has a ratio of inactive participants to active participants that exceeds 2 to 1 and the funded percentage of the plan is less than 80 percent;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H86881F9135FA489692572F40FE196D1E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the corporation determines, after consultation with the Participant and Plan Sponsor Advocate selected under section 4004, that the plan sponsor has taken (or is taking concurrently with an application for partition) all reasonable measures described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/432">section 432(e)(3)(A)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, and has made (or is making) benefit adjustments under section 432(e)(8) of such Code to reduce the risk of insolvency;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE8B38CA510824968B45FAEDE644ECE7A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>20 percent or more of the amount by which the liabilities of the plan exceed the value of plan assets is attributable to the service of participants whose employers—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7CE337783E7A49AA9CA87BE6EBB87D16"><enum>(A)</enum><text>withdrew from the plan prior to the date of enactment of the <short-title>Keep Our Pension Promises Act</short-title>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5168D5061FE24E399D2C633DFB568688"><enum>(B)</enum><text>failed to pay (or are delinquent with respect to paying) the full amount of the employer's withdrawal liability under section 4201(b)(1) or as otherwise determined under an agreement with the plan;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA7E201086744CEAB42FB8D101EAB66A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the corporation reasonably expects that—</text> <subparagraph id="HECDA6D23A4D742DBBE22FA2B81B23748"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a partition of the plan will reduce the corporation’s expected long-term loss with respect to the plan; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HFEDE5C9115AF4EB7B551ED30094BA630"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a partition of the plan is necessary for the plan to remain or become solvent; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9B11270D376489FBE0856424E66EAB9"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the corporation certifies to Congress that after partition the corporation will continue to have the ability to meet existing financial assistance obligations to other plans (including any liabilities associated with multiemployer plans that are insolvent or that are projected to become insolvent within 10 years).</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HD7695E3041634A2C95311D796232350C"><enum>(c)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HCBC4B0DFB06643219D576593B0E2FC49"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A partition under this section shall consist of a transfer to the plan created by the partition order of benefits to which eligible participants and beneficiaries were entitled under the plan that was partitioned, in an amount not to exceed the amount that would be guaranteed under section 4022A if the plan were insolvent as of the date of the partition order.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF2715D3D46DC4A07B78591E884DAFEB0" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The corporation's partition order shall provide for an annual transfer by the corporation to the plan created by the partition order of an amount equal to the yearly benefits that would be guaranteed under section 4022A to the eligible participants and beneficiaries if the plan were insolvent as of the date of the partition order.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2D48438818934EE88205B78A01DD1349" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF6F76AAD5D0A4EF6B8D1B4ABCDCFD127"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Where practicable, the initial transfer in accordance with paragraph (2) shall be completed at least 60 days prior to the plan year that immediately follows the partition start date. The partition order shall require that the initial transfer be sufficient to satisfy the guaranteed benefits in the first plan year of the partitioned plan.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0816002991824864983425C2FD4105CA" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsequent transfers in accordance with paragraph (2) shall be completed at least 60 days prior to the first day of each succeeding plan year.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFA3E2D95066E4C97B86E0AEEE2D07BC6"><enum>(d)</enum>
							<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0ACB784F7DAC403298A447364F042745"><enum>(1)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD0CBDCD140B9419284DBDDBE57D0918F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The plan created by the partition order is a successor plan to which section 4022A applies.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H29FF6B1775034312B3149C10535306A2" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>At the discretion of the plan sponsor, the plan created by the partition order may remain a part of the plan that was partitioned or be maintained as a separate plan.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCFF5780D3DC04F7AAEFED3DC21919D4F" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H88CD0CC6F51B48B69EC241DBB210F300"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The plan sponsor and the administrator of an eligible multiemployer plan prior to the partition shall be the plan sponsor and the administrator, respectively, of the plan created by the partition order, and shall adopt reasonable procedures to reduce administrative expenses and to coordinate benefit payments and communications with the participants and beneficiaries in the plan created by the partition order.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85C7A5D0533C432A8C88E9292EBD4F10" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Benefit payments equal to the amount of an eligible participant or beneficiary's guaranteed benefits shall be paid to such participant or beneficiary and may be—</text>
 <clause id="HB4FAB61D8E9C4C95BCA67634B91A71BA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>paid separately by the plan created by the partition order; or</text> </clause><clause id="H3D436DB4705F4E0E827E6153D3236930"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>paid in a single, monthly payment by the plan that was partitioned.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C2B3C2316F148AA96A2FB5D33DEA64B" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the event an employer withdraws from the plan that was partitioned, withdrawal liability shall be computed under section 4201 with respect to both the plan that was partitioned and the plan created by the partition order.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9008FA675D884388AA618B8DC93EBC28"><enum>(e)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the payment of guaranteed benefits under subsection (d)(2)(B), each eligible participant or beneficiary of the plan created by the partition order shall receive a monthly benefit for each month the benefit is in pay status in an amount that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H116FCAA5B6F742DEB70AC9C42C24D25A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the corporation, in consultation with the Participant and Plan Sponsor Advocate, determines to be fair to the plan, the participant or beneficiary, the employers, and the corporation; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H95E352F2BD3D4E758E6CE8F175E84B6A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">when aggregated with the payment under subsection (d)(2)(B), results in a monthly benefit that is at least equal to the lesser of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB9407F49A01346D981CFAFE497EE1F9F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the monthly nonforfeitable benefit for such participant or beneficiary payable under the plan that was partitioned; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF50A22ECEA504BB98B5847C2296ABCAC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">80 percent of the maximum benefit commencing at age 65 guaranteed under section 4022(a) for participants and beneficiaries in terminated single employer plans, unreduced for early retirement.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">Such monthly benefit may be combined with the monthly payment under subsection (d)(2)(B)(ii).</continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="H578263FD7239439EB680071368EC9206"><enum>(f)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD178DF571D694D77AF89B5B8DA5A51CD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The corporation shall establish a legacy fund for the purposes of funding the administrative and benefit costs to the corporation arising from partitions under this section, as described in paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEEE75BAB6E8A412C8C31432AED1419F3" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any administrative and benefit costs to the corporation arising from a partition ordered under this section in excess of amounts available in such legacy fund shall be paid from the fund for basic benefits guaranteed for multiemployer plans.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0E0B84E9885A47B887592C824990582F"><enum>(g)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Only one partition order shall be issued with respect to each eligible multiemployer plan.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HFE0C6F9FECF640CAB308D81C8B2734D3"><enum>(h)</enum><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>eligible participant or beneficiary</term> means a participant or beneficiary of an eligible multiemployer plan that is partitioned in accordance with a petition order under this section, and who is an employee or beneficiary of an employee of an employer that is described in subsection (b)(3).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEB4C03817ED947E6A6C311C0396B132B"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 14 days after the issuance of a partition order under this section, the corporation shall provide notice of such order to the Committee on Finance of the Senate, the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives, and to all eligible participants or beneficiaries whose guaranteed benefits will be paid directly or indirectly by the plan created by the partition order.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD5E500A4A2DE40479122EFD5A9848D7E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to plan years beginning after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7C6BFFBCC9FC4C54BEB3DB3F5961D896"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transfers to legacy fund</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall from time to time transfer from the general fund of the Treasury to the legacy fund established under section 4233(f)(1) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1413">29 U.S.C. 1413(f)(1)</external-xref>) (as amended by subsection (a)) amounts equal to the increase in revenues to the Treasury by reason of the amendments made by sections 6 and 7 of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H253C73B736624BC9BC3A5F53C4EAD01D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Transfers between funds of the PBGC</header><text>Section 4005 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1305">29 U.S.C. 1305</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA4C5C106CC1F4C6F92E19234038A81BA" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H845C200473804B9EBF4C3AB2C5DB96BD"><enum>(i)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE8D32B2657E94866B1067368BF88AC9B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An eighth fund is established under section 4233(f) and credited with the amounts described in section 3(c) of the <short-title>Keep Our Pension Promises Act</short-title>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBDE422DEDB9540F983AA438FE11D549B" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Notwithstanding subsection (g), the corporation may transfer amounts into the legacy fund established under section 4233(f)(1) from other funds established under this section, as the corporation determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section id="HAF87BF6414B84F518BE4AA97124ABE2F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Employer withdrawals relating to multiemployer plans</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The matter preceding paragraph (1) of section 4225(b) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1405">29 U.S.C. 1405(b)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, including an employer undergoing liquidation under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/11/7">chapter 7</external-xref> of title 11, United States Code, or similar provisions of State law,</quote> after <quote>dissolution,</quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="HD8681F59DE154C13A7DF3C9B7A6C4817"><enum>5.</enum><header>Priorities of claims in bankruptcy</header>
 <subsection id="HCD7E424BE21643ECB8B27FE4CD692343"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 507(a) of title 11, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HC893A31557604A65BA68C07257541DC4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1) through 10 as paragraphs (2) through (11), respectively;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3E7D6EF065FE4D2BB5B7F6B83A8DF35D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting before paragraph (2) (as redesignated) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4CAEC3BB7D9F45408D91A11E48A04C30" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H758BF316A63A4744927F51CF8C22034C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>First, withdrawal liability determined under part 1 of subtitle E of title IV of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1381">29 U.S.C. 1381</external-xref> et seq.).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9E2E13766A9D49859301AE1AAB30C38C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A) of paragraph (2) (as redesignated), by striking <quote>First:</quote> and inserting <quote>Second:</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9DB42DAC09944B569B722011CBDC3B75"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (3) (as redesignated), by striking <quote>Second,</quote> and inserting <quote>Third,</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE5F0CAAD626B4C11A4C5B3DD5A44FD61"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in paragraph (4) (as redesignated), by striking <quote>Third,</quote> and inserting <quote>Fourth,</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H91C5D64002EB4DE69916A03C8BD6D12A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A) of paragraph (5) (as redesignated), by striking <quote>Fourth,</quote> and inserting <quote>Fifth,</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB340BA998AFB418896048CF4A50890D5"><enum>(7)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A) of paragraph (6) (as redesignated), by striking <quote>Fifth,</quote> and inserting <quote>Sixth,</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H370D7B90BC4D40CD97C240B118748022"><enum>(8)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A) of paragraph (7) (as redesignated), by striking <quote>Sixth,</quote> and inserting <quote>Seventh,</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDC07A44AAA544E7D89C2AE2D9B4CB262"><enum>(9)</enum><text>in paragraph (8) (as redesignated), by striking <quote>Seventh,</quote> and inserting <quote>Eighth,</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H47D7F3C294324E8893F4BF0290C96D90"><enum>(10)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A) of paragraph (9) (as redesignated), by striking <quote>Eighth,</quote> and inserting <quote>Ninth,</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H54E66AEC1B854AD89A0AAE1A81B63140"><enum>(11)</enum><text>in paragraph (10) (as redesignated), by striking <quote>Ninth,</quote> and inserting <quote>Tenth,</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4327B96180184350959636D4A9CEAFA3"><enum>(12)</enum><text>in paragraph (11) (as redesignated), by striking <quote>Tenth,</quote> and inserting <quote>Eleventh,</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC7ECED17B17D4A1E93F558163C9BF34A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="H60733CBBC7FA4A47AE70C4151BE95CFE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 502(i) of title 11, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>section 507(a)(8)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 507(a)(9)</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H64F125F7C8894ADC88A75EA1FE94C38B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 503(b)(1)(B)(i) of title 11, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>section 507(a)(8)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 507(a)(9)</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0BD413BEC54E43B5913B0FC72A115B6D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Section 507(d) of title 11, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>(a)(1), (a)(4), (a)(5), (a)(6), (a)(7), (a)(8), or (a)(9)</quote> and inserting <quote>(a)(2), (a)(5), (a)(6), (a)(7), (a)(8), (a)(9), or (a)(10)</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB06A6353FB2842878FEDF0FC98F20D29"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Section 523(A) of title 11, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>section 507(a)(3) or 507(a)(8)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 507(a)(4) or 507(a)(9)</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA54FD6A4E6F64C9F939529842756C703"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Section 724 of title 11, United States Code, is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H9984E755F5EB48318992B1FE6E9E7397"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(2), by striking <quote>section 507(a)(1)(C) or 507(a)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 507(a)(2)(C) or 507(a)(3)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F765EEC6C354FE183A4DCC8251737A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (f)—</text> <clause id="H195DB33296064A97B729E82D0B7C257D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>section 507(a)(4)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 507(a)(5)</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H60DC1FD687534015BE9A322897138851"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>section 507(a)(5)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 507(a)(6)</quote>.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H75FF3C88DD704FDE88CC8CC85595CD66"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Section 726(b) of title 11, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>paragraph (1), (2), (3), (4), (5), (6), (7), (8), (9), or (10) of section 507(a)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (2) through (11) of section 507(a)</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0855145BCD7E4F9C8D44B1C3D5DE08A2"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Section 752(a) of title 11, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>section 507(a)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 507(a)(3)</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HABEB24DC96B2498980A56B54489BC3FB"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Section 766 of title 11, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0E07D3655CB94D3185C98BAF5BBE7314"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (h), by striking <quote>section 507(a)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 507(a)(3)</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6796E2D0F93147F793FFC3C2DBB122B8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (i)—</text>
 <clause id="H681F261FAA804D8F9919FE0A3CC5D097"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>section 507(a)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 507(a)(3)</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H94B15900B53947E1975242BBDF1A2E32"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>section 507(a)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 507(a)(3)</quote>.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE3CBFA03B0140BDB99FC90DF8E99DA8"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Section 901 of title 11, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>507(a)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>507(a)(3)</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H52F52B999FA045EC9424762397D1D986"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Section 943(b)(5) of title 11, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>section 507(a)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 507(a)(3)</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6484EA6414D34162BEFA864EA249FDD5"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Section 1123(a)(1) of title 11, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>section 507(a)(2), 507(a)(3), or 507(a)(8)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 507(a)(3), 507(a)(4), or 507(a)(9)</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCB09CB62D6CF4FFD842E30CD045BC40F"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Section 1129(a)(9) of title 11, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9BCDB3FE35D04BC6B3982E851614E780"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>section 507(a)(3) or 507(a)(4)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 507(a)(4) or 507(a)(5)</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H951A902840324C1F8AC510482CCA83A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i) of subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>section 507(a)(1), 507(a)(4), 507(a)(5), 507(a)(6), or 507(a)(7)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 507(a)(2), 507(a)(5), 507(a)(6), 507(a)(7), or 507(a)(8)</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7197A29F013F4C7A9277D4F1FCB43DA7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i) of subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>section 507(a)(8)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 507(a)(9)</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C4403656CA74D109D2EBE2184947AAF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking <quote>section 507(a)(8)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 507(a)(9)</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6644B2E07D846C2A88ED387A18FEE9F"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Section 1222(a)(4) of title 11, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>section 507(a)(1)(B)</quote> and inserting <quote>507(a)(2)(B)</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5DF919C227A242FFAC85328F9F550E04"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Section 1226(b)(1) of title 11, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>section 507(a)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 507(a)(3)</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3120813C5CF44139B4E432A640E1DAEC"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Section 1322(a)(4) of title 11, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>section 507(a)(1)(B)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 507(a)(2)(B)</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1C3BCE4A7E2F484798650D13FC18064D"><enum>(16)</enum><text>Section 1326(b)(1) of title 11, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>section 507(a)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 507(a)(3)</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H85D7EDB0B1C845679E1F816F328D89A3"><enum>(17)</enum><text>Section 1328(a)(2) of title 11, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>section 507(a)(8)(C)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 507(a)(9)(C)</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H146A67687B87417C8FCA457C098D4E01"><enum>6.</enum><header>Limitation of nonrecognition of like-kind exchanges</header> <subsection id="H9C8AE6D367C148CFA1B54FB2123C3035"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Paragraph (2) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1031">section 1031(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD94B780361E14E98A118202B1963F997"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (A), (B), (C), (D), (E), and (F) as clauses (i), (ii), (iii), (iv), (v), and (vi), and by moving such clauses 2 ems to the right,</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3A56151B76294A5CAF0D22D549F51632"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by moving the flush language after the first sentence 2 ems to the right,</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7DB23A056C4049028BF09BC0628860B0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(2) <header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Exception</header-in-text>.—This subsection</quote> and inserting “(2) <header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Exceptions</header-in-text>.—</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0E42AA278F7B447EB21368F83D426BA5" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H7D46CBCDC153414AA5497769F1071452"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Excluded property</header><text>This subsection</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>, and </after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9BD993F4E27741D6BACA297C9A44896F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
					<quoted-block act-name="" id="HE58157888C044F3084DF9EE73A23EBFA" style="OLC">
						<subparagraph id="H7669A9BA3C6B4872864D0EB168F69BD2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Dollar limitation for exchanges of real property</header>
 <clause id="H2FC56291AAD24875B3FBBB3CE5D02685"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply so much of the gain which, but for such paragraph, would be recognized by the taxpayer with respect to real property exchanged during the taxable year as exceeds $1,000,000.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC5C3CD5ECCFD4696825E7687FD1B36E7"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Special rules for partnerships and S-corporations</header><text>In the case of a pass-through entity, clause (i) shall be applied at both the entity and at the partner or owner level.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF6D83587F08443DEB6E2386F87CD89E9"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Aggregation rules</header><text>For purposes of this subparagraph—</text> <subclause id="H8798D642DA0048E383AEC79AE8763B4C"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Family members</header><text>Individuals who are spouses or who bear any of the relationships described in section 152(d)(2) to each other shall be treated as 1 taxpayer (without regard to whether spouses file a joint return).</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H2FFA00CF69024D9E9B8596C34A05BF78"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Corporations and other entities</header><text>All persons treated as a single employer under subsection (a) or (b) of section 52 or subsection (m) or (o) of section 414 shall be treated as 1 person.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HB15F3CEE894B4A9EB8ADD81D66CEE50F"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Adjustment for inflation</header><text>In the case of exchanges completed in a taxable year beginning after December 31, 2017, the $1,000,000 amount in clause (i) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</text>
 <subclause id="H202B2BC8263046F2AA6A12C143078684"><enum>(I)</enum><text>such dollar amount, multiplied by</text> </subclause><subclause id="H7231F331C49B4B2C8A5CE42B4F5D36B8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for the calendar year in which the taxable year begins, determined by substituting <quote>calendar year 2016</quote> for <quote>calendar year 1992</quote> in subparagraph (B) thereof.</text>
								</subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">If any amount as adjusted under the preceding sentence is not a multiple of $1,000, such amount
			 shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $1,000.</continuation-text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8B08CD9DD3B9401FA368DA382A7FA950"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exclusion of art and collectibles</header><text>Subparagraph (A) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1031">section 1031(a)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended by subsection (a), is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA40EE19101164C3AB2C3EF5212E07307"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of clause (v),</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEDFD7A7F4C7F426DA49F3BEA8982B3EA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of clause (vi) and inserting <quote>, or</quote>, and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9C5F9ECE8C3D4250902D1BF1CD308D0B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after clause (vi) the following new clause:</text> <quoted-block act-name="" id="H80A0C544090D4B3D95A63D10CDB19FD3" style="OLC"> <clause id="HC068B0DA645A4CFE916B41DD496BDE66"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>any collectible (within the meaning of section 408(m), without regard to paragraph (3) thereof).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6DC556003D5D4BFB8C87731E78F6C8CC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regulatory authority</header><text>Subsection (f) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1031">section 1031</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block act-name="" id="H4635B3F69C3A4AC595574F603AE5B672" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H614ED7EDD8EA4ED1866322F06EEBF26E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rules relating to dollar limitation</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe such guidance as is necessary for applying subsection (a)(2)(B)(i) in the case of the exchange of multiple pieces of real property by related persons.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H3097862709D142E2B29D84B3CD67731F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="HD8218B9DC4284E7FABD9F0414F22A2EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Subsection (b) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1031">section 1031</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HF4C49309A28D42B683647B449CD21DCF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">in kind</header-in-text>.—If an exchange</quote> and inserting “<header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">in kind</header-in-text>.—</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB59E2EF2C2354D54A30E573E7AF04706" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H3922E7BED6284C36AAF8134D70A0C886"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If an exchange</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>, and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01134645D6B94262B1DE8151D20803DA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
						<quoted-block act-name="" id="HFF2E9A438B194B63A70E4B360DCF0E15" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HDAB787CD2E94491DA88F844BBC55A3BE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination with subsection <enum-in-header>(a)(2)(B)</enum-in-header></header><text>In the case of an exchange to which paragraph (1) applies—</text> <subparagraph id="H29172F92393846A7BE12134EB3DCE706"><enum>(A)</enum><text>paragraph (1) shall be applied before the application of subsection (a)(2)(B), and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F69A56B858546EF8C6B7973351DE1FF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subsection (a)(2)(B) shall be applied—</text> <clause id="H06E4E3BF0FC1440E92B82BBB2AF8EF39"><enum>(i)</enum><text>as if such exchange were within the provisions of subsection (a), and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H471F21B4B6E246099746837339A4ABC8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by increasing the basis of the property disposed of by the taxpayer in such exchange by the amount of any gain determined under paragraph (1).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H32CEB21F63564707A1482A94F6A1B136"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Subsection (d) of section 1031 of such Code is amended by striking <quote>in the amount of gain</quote> and inserting <quote>in the amount of gain (including any gain recognized by reason of subsection (a)(2)(B)(i))</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4BBE1BC6A36F406F9223256B93AEE7BF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Subsection (i) of section 1031 of such Code is amended by striking <quote>(a)(2)(B)</quote> and inserting <quote>(a)(2)(A)(ii)</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9632F56F86864899844FB3A4DEDFE948"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to exchanges completed in taxable years beginning after December 31, 2016.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H1BD17D93DC1D43E79D3F44221F8C2C60"><enum>7.</enum><header>Contribution limit and increased minimum distributions for certain retirement plans with large
			 account balances</header>
			<subsection id="H8462C761AC46433AB609822B2859E8FE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Contribution limit</header>
 <paragraph id="H76884251449F41269DC89CF16968FE37"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart A of part I of subchapter D of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA18D8D8F86E847CDA071D67188FF3DB6" style="OLC">
						<section id="H07230F1807094EE285B2A2F5FC4DA96F"><enum>409B.</enum><header>Contribution limit on certain retirement plans with large account balances</header>
 <subsection id="HE7192A6B361E4F72B7300620683D3268"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General rule</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, no applicable annual additions shall be made by, or on behalf of, an individual for the taxable year to any applicable retirement plan to the extent such applicable annual additions exceed the excess (if any) of—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4BF57B75B9F047FF8392E2CB2D1EA3EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the applicable dollar amount for the taxable year, over</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFC9A1DC7FE45451AA96666DEB67FADF4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the aggregate balances to the credit of the individual (whether as a participant, owner, or beneficiary) in all applicable retirement plans (determined as of the close of the calendar year preceding the calendar year in which the taxable year begins).</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFE23143B07D4463880A1AD912B7A72B4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rules relating to contribution limitations</header>
								<paragraph id="H19E354C9BDF8451F8132AF900E7F8896"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Plans other than certain IRAs</header>
 <subparagraph id="H269ABB75E6F4495C85E6648C2E44BD37"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), applicable annual additions in excess of the limitation under subsection (a) shall be treated for purposes of this title in the same manner as excess deferrals are treated under section 402(g).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HADBB8000A0BD409995027508BB693212"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Special rule for after tax contributions</header><text>If, without regard to this paragraph, any portion of an applicable annual addition to which subparagraph (A) applies with respect to an individual is not excludable from gross income of the individual (or no deduction is allowable to the individual with respect to such portion), such portion shall not be—</text>
 <clause id="H02FF856A234F4A7696E59EFE0F288AB2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>includible in gross income by reason of the application of subparagraph (A), or</text> </clause><clause id="HA0168CCF7B6943D1AD145D108E48BE94"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>taken into account in computing the investment in the contract for purposes of section 72.</text>
										</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF9860388DC3045D79B3EC4B9E1058A7D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rule for IRAs</header>
 <subparagraph id="H3C3D36851A0B4878BE780F736A2AFB31"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of an applicable retirement plan which is an individual retirement plan (other than a simplified employee pension under section 408(k) or a simple retirement account under section 408(p)), any applicable annual addition to such plan in excess of the limitation under subsection (a) shall be treated for purposes of sections 408 and 408A as a contribution for the taxable year in excess of the maximum amount allowable as a deduction under section 219 for the taxable year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC63C467E79AC492A8D56CB6F1CF761F6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>After tax contributions</header><text>In the case of applicable annual additions in excess of the limitation under subsection (a)—</text> <clause id="HF7FF34AF80294A08B7FA0684F31BD6EA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>which are treated as designated nondeductible contributions under section 408(o), rules similar to the rules of paragraph (1)(B) shall apply, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H493EF86818884073A4839FA1AB332008"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to a Roth IRA, section 408A(d)(2)(C) shall apply to such additions and to any net income allocable to such additions.</text>
										</clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">For purposes of clause (ii), distributions from a Roth IRA shall be treated as first made from
			 amounts described in clause (ii) and section 408A(d)(2)(C) shall be
			 applied in the same manner as if there were a distribution of a
			 contribution described in section 408(d)(4) (without regard to whether
 such distribution is timely made).</continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF06852C46DD546BF95B8493CEF2D8508"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Allocation of excess applicable annual additions</header><text>If the applicable dollar amount for a taxable year exceeds the amount described in subsection (a)(2), the taxpayer may, in such form and manner as the Secretary may prescribe, allocate such excess to applicable annual additions to each applicable retirement plan in such manner as the taxpayer chooses.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H67BA31293DAA490AABDB7498ACD1A9C1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions and special rules</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H11A0F17C36A64179890ADB612331D5B8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applicable annual addition</header> <subparagraph id="HE39BC25D89BD47358AAFC11AEBAA43A0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>applicable annual addition</term> means any of the following made to or on behalf of an individual:</text>
 <clause id="H9D80270E896A46498616BA67CAB767EA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>An annual addition (within the meaning of section 415(c)(2)).</text> </clause><clause id="H8E2809C956874423AF1098CA28F56F3F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Any contribution to an individual retirement plan, including any employer or employee contribution to a simplified employee pension under section 408(k) or a simple retirement account under section 408(p).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H22D4D64B76EA46B79CAF562D9C4E0262"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Any deferral under an eligible deferred compensation plan described in section 457(b) which is maintained by an eligible employer described in section 457(e)(1)(A).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD61132ABDE7A42D8A53E3AA877DDCF17"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rollover contributions disregarded</header><text>A rollover contribution under section 402(c), 403(b)(8), 408(d)(3)(A)(ii), or 457(e)(16) shall not be treated as an annual addition.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H636D14359EEA4CFAA319FF20943FE7CA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicable dollar amount</header>
 <subparagraph id="HD77E88F14A824932A05F7D8A9CADB8FB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>applicable dollar amount</term> means $5,000,000.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H796BA1D2AB0E4FCBA4794DEFCEA66B50"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Adjustment for inflation</header><text>In the case of any taxable year beginning after 2017, the $5,000,000 amount under subparagraph (A) shall be increased by an amount equal to the product of—</text>
 <clause id="H0DC7D9D30A8D404DA705EDDF14F3E76D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such amount, and</text> </clause><clause id="H85E3BC3BF0D049B784EB27CE92AE272F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the cost-of-living adjustment under section 1(f)(3) for the calendar year in which such taxable year begins, determined by substituting <quote>calendar year 2016</quote> for <quote>calendar year 1992</quote> in subparagraph (B) thereof.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9192D6C899124A32B1DAA6B0C6D7137C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Rounding</header><text>If any amount as adjusted under subparagraph (B) is not a multiple of $1,000, such amount shall be rounded to the next lowest multiple of $1,000.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA4EE58489D540FBA93CD32B6F5DC787"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applicable retirement plan</header><text>The term <term>applicable retirement plan</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H0CEE83EE16CD4729BB2AA0A91280A6A2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a defined contribution plan to which section 401(a) or 403(a) applies,</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H07C59F90B77F440F9E4290CDCF55D180"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an annuity contract under section 403(b),</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E9B37B3D6E54540B18FC8A249DF4FA6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an eligible deferred compensation plan described in section 457(b) which is maintained by an eligible employer described in section 457(e)(1)(A), or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4001BC5086A841A2871599EE6EC1843D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an individual retirement plan.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HED1AD0E17A1A4999B4109EF43FCDE7A2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations and guidance as are necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section, including regulations or guidance that provide for the application of this section and section 4974(e) in the case of plans with a valuation date other than the last day of a calendar year.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H446E9CE183DD47488A6C48819ACA852F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <subparagraph id="HD0E5307F3F8248D586E517A1E5FCB8B6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The table of contents for subpart A of part I of subchapter D of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by adding after the item relating to section 409A the following new item:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF3348162CF854647A696EE5C76A03FBD" style="OLC">
							<toc>
								<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 409B. Contribution limit on certain retirement plans with large account balances.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69A1B793A32B44689E9FC74BB2AE7D09"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 402(g) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8BF9DDC2553E47E1B1196A938C52E952" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H6236B82164F44974853A57AF39AF16F6"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Aggregate limitation</header><text>For additional limitation on contributions to certain plans with large account balances, see section 409B.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C43E2D187874BEA9C932C209272B5D4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Section 403(b)(1) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>For additional limitation on contributions to certain plans with large account balances, see section 409B.</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6B7C42FF3654950911B27A5370207AF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Section 408(r) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEF723A482A2D4277A2E7DA5F2BA9EC6A" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H2B60567F49A64A1E9B67E3C2C84DE1F6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>For additional limitation on contributions to certain plans with large account balances, see section 409B.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC285FCA1CB3047D38CBC4E5FE43C6C1F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Section 457(c) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>For additional limitation on contributions to certain plans with large account balances, see section 409B.</quote>.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBF48B4D1551F44DDA94278FEB0973744"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Excise tax on excess annual additions</header>
 <paragraph id="HE2C6B8ECF75B401CAE9E04C9CA6124D8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subsection (a) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4973">section 4973</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HB59E1A772B254DC59B0971D522583BAF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of paragraph (5),</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H60ACFF9ACC424339878EC476F7587CF9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or</quote> after the comma at the end of paragraph (6), and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB775256100ED49108678AB012C587E35"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (6) the following new paragraph:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC1E0BA84A33140DF91BB04956DC07369" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H4C9DB4FC748A405991F08DA78DD3CF61"><enum>(7)</enum><text>an applicable retirement plan (within the meaning of section 409B(c)(3)),</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9978601A607D477D8FAEFDE23002FFF4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Excess contributions to applicable retirement plans</header><text>Section 4973 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFC4FD76E315D4262A056BB4270E3B4AB" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H85A35BE5281F40B1B73C69BA807E4CD4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Excess contributions to applicable retirement plans</header><text>For purposes of this section, in the case of applicable retirement plans (within the meaning of section 409B(c)(3)), the term <term>excess contributions</term> with respect to any taxable year means the sum of—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDEF3A20229B14048B19F0FD651483AA1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the excess of the applicable annual additions (within the meaning of section 409B(c)(1)) to such plans over the limitation under section 409B(a) for such taxable year, and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDF4B52071B1D42A2AD90B4D236C12B91"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the lesser of—</text> <subparagraph id="HB265E8E889F0430BB4CD5E2C33DBF71D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amount determined under this subsection for the preceding taxable year, reduced by the aggregate distributions from such plans for the taxable year (including distributions required under section 4974(e)) to the extent not contributed in a rollover contribution to another eligible retirement plan in accordance with section 402(c), 403(b)(8), 457(e)(16), 408(d)(3), or 408A(d)(3), or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61FEB095EBFC41DEBD9E012808415781"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount (if any) by which the amount determined under section 409B(a)(2) for the taxable year exceeds the applicable dollar amount under section 409B(c)(2) for the taxable year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA5246F72AB7A45A781D4A149DC9E4E51"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Subsection (a) of section 4973 of such Code is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H7B62FEDD177246FD817ADECB21C3FE8B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>accounts or annuities</quote> and inserting <quote>accounts, annuities, or plans</quote>, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F10990C6F7D40799D8BD30DFD4D2D18"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>account or annuity</quote> and inserting <quote>account, annuity, or plan</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H50D1009A40A34799A8F45F8B03CFE4C9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Increase in minimum required distributions</header> <paragraph id="H805903DE44B74478B11EAFB0756459B3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4974">Section 4974</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H27958C8A8C3C43158124C1D900B248CE" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="H37D91251D5C745508B72E36E7CCEB3D9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Increase in minimum required distributions for payees with large aggregate account balances</header>
 <paragraph id="HDE0EFF8318744C76B7BF219F67D3EC61"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If this subsection applies to a payee for any taxable year—</text> <subparagraph id="H651F5B34655A4C4CB8DA6B17AFA948DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>all qualified retirement plans and eligible deferred compensation plans of the payee which are applicable retirement plans taken into account in computing the excess described in paragraph (2)(A) shall be treated as 1 plan solely for purposes of applying this section to the increase in minimum required distributions for the taxable year described in subparagraph (B), and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6749B7A2D80445DCB96AC7849E1F6676"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the minimum required distributions under this section for all plans treated as 1 plan under subparagraph (A) with respect to such payee for the taxable year shall be increased by the excess (if any) of—</text>
 <clause id="H3C9B4791852A4296B4F76AA1A7E92F2A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the excess described in paragraph (2)(A), over</text> </clause><clause id="HA1A57DD410F04201A647A9A9D26E088B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the sum of the minimum required distributions (determined without regard to this subsection) for all such plans.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3098287F4279469490E27B5C17F0B042"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text>This subsection shall apply to a payee for a taxable year—</text> <subparagraph id="H9BB3456A7DDB4C43BBCA04CC7D5A460D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if the aggregate balances to the credit of the payee (whether as a participant, owner, or beneficiary) in all applicable retirement plans (determined as of the close of the calendar year preceding the calendar year in which the taxable year begins) exceed the applicable dollar amount for the calendar year in which the taxable year begins, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFCF45780ED7141268C8630916B457853"><enum>(B)</enum><text>without regard to whether amounts with respect to the payee are otherwise required to be distributed under section 401(a)(9), 403(b)(10), 408(a)(6), 408(b)(3), or 457(d)(2).</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9FC28B3002242D7A8A2AC9AA405F85F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Coordination and allocation</header>
 <subparagraph id="HAD98650D62E542E2BDAA0EB92AC336C0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Minimum distribution requirements</header><text>If this subsection applies to a payee for any taxable year—</text> <clause id="HEBB35A8D542B4B5D9DB5CF3AA6563D67"><enum>(i)</enum><text>this section shall apply first to minimum required distributions determined without regard to this subsection and then to any increase in minimum required distributions by reason of this subsection, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE57CC30801EB4473A0F9AB98E314C52E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>nothing in this subsection shall be construed to affect the amount of any minimum required distribution determined without regard to this subsection or the plan or plans from which it is required to be distributed from.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF2DB5110C4345DB8F9E297D3D0A281C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Allocation of increase in minimum required distributions</header><text>The taxpayer may, in such form and manner as the Secretary may prescribe, allocate any increase in minimum required distributions by reason of this subsection to applicable retirement plans treated as 1 plan under subparagraph (A) in such manner as the taxpayer chooses.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB4D84ED1CBE4DCD85455170A169DF89"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Treatment of Roth IRAs</header>
 <subparagraph id="HB247D9C5D4CA4CCAA86A8E1AA30BB600"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding section 408A(c)(5)—</text> <clause id="HCEBA07FF8B194B14B083C108A0871B37"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the aggregate balance to the credit of a payee of any Roth IRA shall be taken into account for purposes of this subsection, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAB937D2A79AC427CB3F84DEB50945E12"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>distributions from a Roth IRA may be taken into account in determining whether the required increase in minimum required distributions by reason of this subsection has been satisfied.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D459F132D6D4BB68EE9639B22523413"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusion in income of distributed earnings</header><text>If any distribution from a Roth IRA is taken into account under subparagraph (A)(ii), then, notwithstanding section 408A(d)(5), the portion of such distribution which is properly allocable to net income on contributions to the Roth IRA shall not be treated as a qualified distribution and shall be included in gross income of the payee.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5F4CA15BD464F3F95DD7C333B338F49"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Ratable inclusion for first year of increase</header><text>If the first taxable year of a taxpayer for which there is a required increase in minimum required distributions by reason of this subsection begins before January 1, 2019, any amount required to be included in gross income by reason of such increase shall be included in income ratably over the 6-taxable-year period (or such shorter period as the taxpayer may elect) beginning with such first taxable year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF6BB0643A81E4DED982CB23CEB7D8D43"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, any term used in this subsection which is also used in section 409B shall have the same meaning as when such term is used in such section.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9C114C18B18943D9A2C4031CA97F9B51"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception from 10 percent additional tax on early distributions</header><text>Section 72(t)(2) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block act-name="" id="H61ED38B4EDD848EA82D0E75F844DEA70" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HD354FF2258C24AD8B9A5CC5B9F4C15A9"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Distributions of excess balances</header><text>Distributions from applicable retirement plans (within the meaning of section 409B) to the extent such distributions during the taxable year do not exceed the amount (if any) by which—</text>
 <clause id="H42D51A1DE6D04EAFA9BD1E16E85B916C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount determined under section 409B(a)(2) for the taxable year, exceeds</text> </clause><clause id="H696EFCB0080A4EF1B423BEE7BA01E2F8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the applicable dollar amount under section 409B(c)(2) for the preceding taxable year.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB8C4F6BAA271438D933B154F4278485B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6047">Section 6047</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by redesignating subsection (g) as subsection (h) and by inserting after subsection (f) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H59F3BAADBC7E4C00BA7C88FAA57046C2" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H3EC170C4AA444109B215391DA9FC3181"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reporting relating to aggregate contribution and balance limits on certain retirement plans</header><text>The Secretary shall require the plan administrator or trustee of an applicable retirement plan (as defined in section 409B) to make such returns and reports to the Secretary and participants and beneficiaries as are necessary to apply the aggregate limits on contributions imposed by section 409B and the increases in minimum required distributions required by section 4974(e). If the account balance of a plan as of the close of a calendar year is not otherwise required under this title to be reported to a participant, a beneficiary, or the Secretary, such requirements shall include a requirement that the plan administrator or trustee shall notify the participant, the beneficiary, or the Secretary of such account balance at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may prescribe.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H7EB7F95C0E1E4932937A19A73977C05C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective dates</header>
 <paragraph id="HCE0BD35C552F4AE5BD6DDC317072B8E7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H056B8E9A0A1F4011A896C608C6BD612E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Plan requirements</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (d) shall apply to years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


