<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H389E815739FD42DA9EDE763301300F47" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4611 IH: Disaster Response Workforce Flexibility Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4611</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171211">December 11, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000627">Mrs. Demings</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide an increase in premium pay for certain employees of the Federal Emergency Management
			 Agency during fiscal years 2017 and 2018, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HCB941B51D1004B48A8C8FDAC6D98EAE0" style="OLC">
 <section id="H00148A9774434380B81F0947EE05131C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Disaster Response Workforce Flexibility Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H9A921DD950BB423B926B1D533666F548"><enum>2.</enum><header>Premium pay exception for FEMA employees</header> <subsection id="H545532CE0ED44029996287E06788B9B6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of covered employee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>covered employee</quote> means any employee of the Federal Emergency Management Agency who, during any of fiscal years 2017 or 2018, performs duties directly related to, or in support of, disaster preparation, response, and recovery efforts.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA284CBB3DC3E4D08918F2904E0B0282F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception for limitation on premium pay</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, during fiscal years 2017 and 2018, section 5547(a) of title 5, United States Code, shall not apply to any covered employee to the extent that its application would prevent the covered employee from receiving premium pay, except that such premium pay shall not be payable to a covered employee to the extent that the aggregate of the covered employee's basic and premium pay for the year would exceed the rate of basic pay payable for a position at level II of the Executive Schedule under section 5313 of such title.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA19AD67C65C0481CB97B2600A3041AEE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Treatment of additional pay</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If subsection (b) results in the payment of additional premium pay to a covered employee of a type that is normally creditable as basic pay for retirement or any other purpose, that additional pay shall not—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE14B9F4EE9964361B1E9A122BB0D832C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be considered to be basic pay of the covered employee for any purpose; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H00088AAD61CB4BB892604B046417613B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be used in computing a lump-sum payment to the covered employee for accumulated and accrued annual leave under section 5551 or section 5552 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD1873C0B91C141FC8FFE1C34055A6D8C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Aggregate limit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the application of section 5307 of title 5, United States Code, the payment of any additional premium pay to a covered employee as a result of subsection (b) shall not be counted as part of the aggregate compensation of the covered employee.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H64667C80328B4D31AEF5EC9698745301"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall take effect as if enacted on October 1, 2016.</text> </subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

