<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H59D5ECDA69F84E46956F448B27F8A25B" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 893 IH: 21st Century Voting Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>115th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 893</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20170203">February 6, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name>, and in addition to the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To protect, improve, and modernize the act of voting.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H6ADFEF7A1A9845FFBB0DC5397DB443AE" style="OLC">
		<section id="H70CA8620FAA340AA8B426DE9518AAC95" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>21st Century Voting Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id11D0F13F23FB414698DD60AD1E371CB5" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Commission established</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is hereby established the <quote>Commission on Voting</quote> (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Commission</quote>).</text></section><section id="id1B9FAE0D5DC346F6A3DD0B5C6E446697" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Commission duties</header> <subsection id="idB7DC62F4EE8648BAB3D2EBC8C45A38A6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Proposed legislation</header><text>The Commission shall report to Congress proposed legislation that would accomplish the following:</text><paragraph id="id33191DA209CC4AEC9019D4E82403B4C3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Election Day shall be made a national holiday.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id86217907FEC4402CA89C2492DCD98821"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Every American shall be automatically, and permanently, registered to vote at the age of 18, or upon receipt of citizenship if older than 18 years of age.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0DB1ADA4535649CE87781250432DCF17"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Every person released from prison who formerly held the right to vote shall have that right restored immediately upon release.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idB2193FBABE234EE3A4E796C2EC32F5C6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Voter registration shall be made portable among every State and locality.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4E3506EE6DE146DF92E5A378C1C47CA3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Polling place and registration status shall be made available to individual voters online.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7D1FC2FBCFD94A039489271D212D613E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Voting cybersecurity protection efforts carried out by Federal agencies shall be streamlined and strengthened.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9237868E30C94C5186BA9524739A555F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Additional Federal resources shall be made to State and local election boards and agencies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idD73B655B0B494BB591CE0F9A694DA0EB"><enum>(8)</enum><text>A quadrennial review of voting in America shall be performed each year following the election of the President of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idB58B7AD089BD4484A04AD71C8D13B90C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>The proposed legislation required by subsection (a) shall be submitted to Congress not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="id4DD0B6C994FB49D3BEE423D37B6AA92B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Introduction and vote required</header><text>The proposed legislation submitted to Congress pursuant to subsection (b) shall be introduced by the Speaker of the U.S. House of Representatives within 14 days of receipt of the proposal, and receive a vote in the House within 14 days thereafter. Should the measure pass the House, it shall receive consideration and a vote in the Senate within 14 days of passage in the House.</text></subsection></section><section id="id0DDEDF37810B4F888855E63A8106515D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Commission membership</header><subsection id="id20A377424CE24A78A093793898D27133"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Number and appointment</header><text>The Commission shall be comprised of 15 members appointed, in equal number, by the President, the Majority Leader of the Senate, the Minority Leader of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives.</text></subsection><subsection id="id96B3E07BB4F74BFF9CF765AA643C7D99"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Chair</header><text>The President shall select the Chair of the Commission.</text></subsection><subsection id="id775F647A5F0644C381F4020B2ADB4686"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Timing of appointments</header><text>Appointments to the Commission shall be made not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="idF01DDB2C12E54174B1EC6BDD045AE2A4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>Any vacancy in the Commission shall not affect its powers and shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made.</text></subsection><subsection id="id4757035AD6894BF985CCC17E1D33BBCD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>Members of the Commission shall serve without pay.</text></subsection><subsection id="id4F08A6B98F244872A117CC2889BCF415"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text>Each member of the Commission shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the Commission.</text></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


