<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H6BC2576DD2EB40569397ED1DE3519AD2" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2999 IH: Patients’ Access to Treatments Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2999</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170622">June 22, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001251">Mr. Butterfield</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act to limit co-payment, coinsurance, or other
			 cost-sharing requirements applicable to prescription drugs in a specialty
			 drug tier to the dollar amount (or its equivalent) of such requirements
			 applicable to prescription drugs in a non-preferred brand drug tier, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HDA358062CE0C4C599AF3B9A45B7D70B8" style="OLC">
 <section id="H75E2B2EA9B0348909E2B837C7405232E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Patients’ Access to Treatments Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H8AE40DFA59F343BAA4EFBF0B49C0A34F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Cost-sharing requirements applicable to prescription drugs in a specialty drug tier</header> <subsection id="H722AE4E43D5544E38EB98472F3256EF7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart II of part A of title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg">42 U.S.C. 300gg</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE847D7B755F94BC1A528F01019166B8F" style="OLC">
					<section id="HE985D2F3E1F9409E88152E2D95AAB1DF"><enum>2719B.</enum><header>Cost-sharing requirements applicable to prescription drugs in a specialty drug tier</header>
 <subsection id="H920DC44159CF4A81B872B5147B61E994"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>A group health plan, or a health insurance issuer offering group or individual health insurance, that provides coverage for prescription drugs and uses a formulary or other tiered cost-sharing structure shall not impose cost-sharing requirements applicable to prescription drugs in a specialty drug tier that exceed the dollar amount (or its equivalent) of cost-sharing requirements applicable to prescription drugs in a non-preferred brand drug tier (or prescription drugs in a brand drug tier if there is no non-preferred brand drug tier).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8DB90912B5FD465AA9A48470FABB04FD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text>If a formulary used by a group health plan or a health insurance issuer offering group or individual health insurance contains more than one non-preferred brand drug tier, then the requirements of subsection (a) shall be applied with respect to the non-preferred brand drug tier for which beneficiary cost-sharing is lowest.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE965B8F780F6430AA9583F710CF96248"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H7D36A9810DFF46E1BD92B15BEE344223"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>cost-sharing</term> includes co-payment and coinsurance.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBCAA36F8B66C4FF0BB3C0A949BCF8D7C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>drug tier</term> means, with respect to a group health plan or health insurance issuer offering group or individual health insurance coverage that uses a formulary or other cost-sharing structure, a category of drugs—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDDE823A164674FFE94A5AB342267901D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>within such formulary or structure for which the total dollar amount of cost-sharing requirements for any drug does not vary by more than ten percent from the total dollar amount of cost-sharing requirements for any other drug; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF85171E1E8644C14B30414CDA5B9B394"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that are prescription drugs.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEFE299953F7542AD81EB79C17D781D29"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>non-preferred brand drug tier</term> means, with respect to a group health plan or health insurance issuer offering group or individual health insurance coverage that uses a formulary or other tiered cost-sharing structure, a category of drugs—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5AD0F307033B40D0829AB90EBAAE168B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">within a drug tier in such formulary or structure for which beneficiary cost-sharing is greater than drug tiers for generic drugs or preferred brand drugs in the formulary or structure;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9FD3A89F78DD43D4AA1BA769393F57FA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that are prescription drugs; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA74C03CCE5BA43F7A1844572335AFE4D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that are not included within a specialty drug tier.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H79E3D28677D14758BACD06CB55D6E354"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>prescription drug</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HC258710384AB49EBB9B40730C6A4AA10"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a drug subject to section 503(b)(1) of the Federal Food, Drug, or Cosmetic Act; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C70E20E5AA345D3A3AE40368AF969FC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a drug described in subparagraph (A) that is a biological product (as defined in section 351(i) of this Act).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5FF95E73C18043D298E936CACB9226A7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <term>specialty drug tier</term> means, with respect to a group health plan or health insurance issuer offering group or individual health insurance coverage that uses a formulary or other tiered cost-sharing structure, a category of drugs—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCE7F8BFADB6342608056CDDADA1A90B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">within a drug tier in such formulary or structure for which beneficiary cost-sharing is greater than drug tiers for generic drugs, preferred brand drugs, or non-preferred drugs in the plan’s formulary; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D04ABCB2BE2497E97C9A97898386F4B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that are prescription drugs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H3B5BD66B4F714B3E87462DAE1F812D7B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Section 2719B of the Public Health Service Act, as added by subsection (a), applies to plan years beginning on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


