<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H5A78C4F141854770904B32866F1D0789" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2796 IH: Civil Rights Uniformity Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2796</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170607">June 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000168">Mr. Olson</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000374">Mr. Abraham</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001053">Mrs. Hartzler</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To repeal executive overreach, to clarify that the proper constitutional authority for social
			 transformation belongs to the legislative branch.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HD3C30D03E0754C26AC1D83C77AF8255C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H78D84DF592AD49AC81379218B8B17738" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Civil Rights Uniformity Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H26CC33D5CE244234B0D5FBA69C60CE22"><enum>2.</enum><header>Congressional findings and declaration of purpose</header> <subsection id="HB8EE5C63B33D4423B24B9CDF473B959F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H372491B4F4ED4538B83403EE9D9FB0D4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Over the past half century, Congress has passed numerous civil rights laws prohibiting discrimination on the basis of <quote>sex</quote>, a designation long understood to be grounded in objective biology up to the present day. There is no evidence that Congress or the American people ever understood the word sex or gender in civil rights laws to include subjective self-identification.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5C24DA66166448D2954A9103EB07497B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For years, advocates have pressed Congress to include a person’s subjective self-declared <quote>gender identity</quote> in Federal civil rights laws that prohibit sex discrimination. Congress has declined to do so except for the Shepard-Byrd Act of 2009 and the Violence Against Women Reauthorization Act of 2013 where gender identity is defined as <quote>actual or perceived gender-related characteristics</quote> with <quote>gender</quote>, there referring to characteristics associated with biological males and females.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0CFD54CBACBD4A6ABD086B4B31C4F038"><enum>(3)</enum><text>This demonstrates that when Congress wants to protect sex, it does so explicitly; when it wants to also elevate gender identity it does so explicitly; and when it does not want to elevate gender identity, it can do so either explicitly or by simply not disturbing the status quo.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE95C0026A494107B53551E270CA517A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Despite the complete clarity of this point, President Barack Obama’s administration has attempted to effectively replace the word <quote>sex</quote> with the phrase <quote>gender identity</quote> for purposes of Federal antidiscrimination law and policy through a series of unilateral executive actions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5D1707BF3A904CB88F7229E2217674C5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>For example, on December 15, 2014, Attorney General Eric Holder announced that the Department of Justice would reinterpret the ban on <quote>sex</quote> discrimination under title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 to encompass <quote>gender identity</quote>. This was followed on March 27, 2015, by an Equal Employment Opportunity Commission decision holding that declining to use a female pronoun to address a male who identifies as female constituted <quote>sex</quote> discrimination under title VII.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE9715039060D47428B660F9495ABA597"><enum>(6)</enum><text>On May 9, 2016, the Obama administration sued the State of North Carolina and threatened it with fines and loss of Federal funding if it did not adopt the administration’s incorrect readings of title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 and title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H496F4858128B4F71A6FC689E983377E7"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On May 13, 2016, the Departments of Justice and Education issued a “significant guidance” letter stating that under title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 “when a school provides sex-segregated activities and facilities, transgender students must be allowed to participate in such activities and access such facilities consistent with their gender identity.” The guidance further states that schools “must treat a student’s gender identity as the student’s sex” including in the context of “sex-segregated restrooms, locker rooms, shower facilities, housing, and athletic teams, as well as single-sex classes.” In other words, the Departments consider it a title IX violation if a person of the male sex who self-identifies as a female is not granted unfettered access to women’s or girls’ dorms, showers, locker rooms, and bathrooms. This, despite assurance that such a thing would never happen from the likes of Ruth Bader Ginsburg who wrote in 1975 that “separate places to disrobe, sleep, perform personal bodily functions are permitted, in some situations required, by regard for individual privacy.” This position was codified in Federal regulations, 34 CFR 106.33, which state that recipients of Federal funds “may provide separate toilet, locker room, and shower facilities on the basis of sex,” with sex obviously referring to biology.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE1165CF2540A4E4D86F424463A112E4E"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Also on May 13, 2016, the Department of Health and Human Services finalized regulations that redefined the Affordable Care Act’s prohibition on <quote>sex</quote> discrimination in federally funded health programs and activities to cover <quote>gender identity</quote>, thereby opening health care professionals and insurers to extensive liability if they decline to participate in or pay for <quote>gender transition</quote> treatments or <quote>sex change</quote> operations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC7A6F9F958F9479B8C1B9EDBC6C3003F"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The Obama administration’s actions are an affront to the rule of law, the separation of powers, the will of the people, language, history, safety, privacy, and biological realities.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEEF837DBA5794028AB202F965AC21904"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purposes of this Act are—</text> <paragraph id="H78E5B7A5F47348078CB94379C552BB02"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to prevent the executive branch from unilaterally rewriting Federal civil rights laws by enacting or implementing any policy or undertaking any enforcement action that is based on construing the term <quote>sex</quote> or <quote>gender</quote> to mean <quote>gender identity</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF3E19015060745959A0818A8854E7CBF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to ensure that gender identity is not treated as a protected class in Federal law or policy without the affirmative approval of the people’s representatives in Congress.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HAF8E43038F1A485AA7A6EAD0ED7D326D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition of policies redefining sex to mean gender identity</header>
 <subsection id="HBBBB7B71B2BF4E6AA30BC5F1E62C3D8A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rule of Construction</header><text>In determining the meaning of any Federal civil rights law, and of any related ruling, regulation, guidance, or interpretation of the various administrative bureaus and agencies of the United States, the words <quote>sex</quote> and <quote>gender</quote> and their equivalents shall not be interpreted to mean <quote>gender identity</quote> or its equivalent, and the words <quote>man</quote> and <quote>woman</quote> and their equivalents shall refer exclusively to a person’s genetic sex.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBDE29770D1F3495CA25503C2B947FEB8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of Interpretation</header><text>No Federal civil rights law shall be interpreted to treat gender identity or transgender status as a protected class, unless such law expressly designates <quote>gender identity</quote> or <quote>transgender status</quote> as a protected class.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC629D5159ADF4F548BBA6B446DF79235"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition of <quote>Federal civil rights law</quote></header><text>For purposes of this Act, the term <quote>Federal civil rights law</quote> means any Federal law prohibiting discrimination on the basis of sex or gender, including title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681</external-xref> et seq.), the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000a">42 U.S.C. 2000a</external-xref> et seq.), the Fair Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3601">42 U.S.C. 3601</external-xref> et seq.), the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref>), and any other Federal law or provision thereof prohibiting discrimination on the basis of sex or gender.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


