<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC25C673B5BF84B25A968734E8B39AB5B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2963 IH: To amend the Federal Home Loan Bank Act to provide investment authority to support rural infrastructure development, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2963</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170620">June 20, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000611">Mr. Poliquin</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Home Loan Bank Act to provide investment authority to support rural infrastructure development, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0D33EEC07E804678BC8330C66F4ADE33" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7880233BC83D4534B8EBA8FE24A96EDB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Cooperative associations that support rural infrastructure development</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 11 of the Federal Home Loan Bank Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1431">12 U.S.C. 1431</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2396C2BEF6E349DF967544FA0FD20B32" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H65DD87CEDF724D99AEE4C96702D00AEB"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Cooperative associations that support rural infrastructure development</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each Federal Home Loan Bank is authorized to purchase investment-grade securities from nonmember lenders that are organized as cooperatives and that have received financing from the Federal Financing Bank and that have demonstrated experience in making loans to cooperatives that are eligible to receive loans or commitments for loans from the Rural Utilities Service (or any successor agency). Such securities shall be secured investments collateralized by loans of the cooperative lender. The purchase of such securities shall be at the sole discretion of each Federal Home Loan Bank, consistent with such regulations, restrictions, and limitations as may be prescribed by the Agency.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

