<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H176052608E4643F19418ED16BA4D8E39" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3008 IH: George W. Bush Childhood Home Study Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3008</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170622">June 22, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001062">Mr. Conaway</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001048">Mr. Culberson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001051">Mr. Carter of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000583">Mr. Smith of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a special resource study of the George W.
			 Bush Childhood Home, located at 1412 West Ohio Avenue, Midland, Texas, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H8B16C32DCB434E64AB52A925CF370ADC" style="OLC">
 <section id="HCE3AFC7C05C24875809865FDDEDF6CA2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>George W. Bush Childhood Home Study Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HEA0E2A3B246D4F24B1AF05D4F89C5AF0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Special resource study</header> <subsection id="H77E62978D6884B4EB1E5ED0D55576D5E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior shall conduct a special resource study of the George W. Bush Childhood Home, located at 1412 West Ohio Avenue, Midland, Texas (referred to in this section as the <quote>site</quote>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7A8E1B2B3C674C0D80A67689D6E25929"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>In conducting the study under subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="H65F53EF4411447BFB72A02D2FDA7E7FF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>evaluate the national significance of the site;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2F4DA9CF2F044646BE641D938768FB35"><enum>(2)</enum><text>determine the suitability and feasibility of designating the site as a unit of the National Park System;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC48CB658E9CA40E5A236A78C9AD2295B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>consider other alternatives for preservation, protection, and interpretation of the site by Federal, State, or local governmental entities, or private and nonprofit organizations;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF78F8BE035F24A6AB8FA01C22B8D2F77"><enum>(4)</enum><text>consult with interested Federal, State, or local governmental entities, private and nonprofit organizations or any other interested individuals;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCF6A2C1EFED041459A91D6F0CD329241"><enum>(5)</enum><text>determine the effect of the designation of the site as a unit of the National Park System on existing commercial and recreational uses, and the effect on State and local governments to manage those activities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2169798D6D6A489F994C99D7D3B63178"><enum>(6)</enum><text>identify any authorities, including condemnation, that will compel or permit the Secretary to influence or participate in local land use decisions (such as zoning) or place restrictions on non-Federal land if the site is designated a unit of the National Park System; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDEE3ED7FDFB84D638215714A4408CA3C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>identify cost estimates for any Federal acquisition, development, interpretation, operation, and maintenance associated with the alternatives.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBBA0218C93D74F3991D1CA500A67CA23"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicable law</header><text>The study required under subsection (a) shall be conducted in accordance with section 100507 of title 54, United States Code.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H43B54737465A415BBF250A939A4CAC8C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Study results</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date on which funds are first made available for the study under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate the results of the study and any conclusions and recommendations of the Secretary.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


