<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H27F2C8ED096848FB80455391386C3CE6" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3556 IH: Taxpayer Protections and Market Access for Mortgage Finance Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3556</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170728">July 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000487">Mr. Royce of California</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac to engage in credit risk transfer transactions, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HAE65481EAA5C494B9391C29DA974F3B6" style="OLC">
 <section id="HCA0EAFFFBC56462EB0525CEE06DC8C46" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Taxpayer Protections and Market Access for Mortgage Finance Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HB3D33224B01C4605A0FAE03080A29A2E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Credit risk-transfer transactions</header> <subsection id="H02DEB49224104208BF127D5D52994FF6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement for enterprises</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart A of part 2 of subtitle A of the Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4541">12 U.S.C. 4541</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H53BC48C882DD4F529337F512C2770AD7" style="OLC">
					<section id="H40668F75A34641ABA12902DD0B46C055"><enum>1328.</enum><header>Enterprise credit risk-transfer transactions</header>
 <subsection id="H009E37E236A64ADB90C43B5B91BF0B69"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 12 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall, after taking into consideration market conditions and the safety and soundness of the enterprises, establish guidelines requiring that each enterprise engage in significant, increasing, and varied credit risk-transfer transactions, with an emphasis on front-end transactions.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6E073A597FC94E0BBD7ADC3FD5102E6A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In establishing the guidelines under subsection (a), the Director shall—</text> <paragraph id="H469E1B59652C43219A6D3C069B5BC985"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">seek to promote a deep, broad market for a variety of structures that together insulate the taxpayer from losses, minimize ongoing risks to the enterprises, remain stable through the economic cycle, maintain adequate access to the secondary market for lenders of all sizes, and promote credit for borrowers in all communities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H19445AAAEB00445D805EB7E55FEBA22B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">continue and seek to increase the amount of credit risk transferred to the private sector and the types of risk-transfer transactions that the enterprises engaged in each year with the goal that the risk transferred by an enterprise by all credit risk-transfer transactions shall be at least 400 basis points of risk in total, starting from the first dollar of credit loss among all the different credit risk-transfer structures;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8AEB64B6AC0B48B3A7994D8335A79DF9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">continue and seek to increase front-end risk transfer transactions, including those done at the time of origination; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF71712B8EC1D419D88AA9DD636D79C40"><enum>(4)</enum><text>continue and seek to increase transactions in which the first loss position is transferred or shared and through structures that are scalable and transparent.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3612E6DCEC6C4FC7A0EE203B8C217D39"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Guarantee fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The enterprises shall set and publish guarantee fees, including up-front delivery fees and loan level price adjustments, commensurate with the enterprises’ reduced credit risk resulting from any new risk-transfer transaction.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE61C77D141E14DAC935EACB11EDC9870"><enum>(d)</enum><header>APA compliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The guidelines required under subsection (a) shall be issued and made available to the public pursuant to section 553 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDC72667681A845C2A0D2B7ADAC7FD628"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall adjust individual and corporate scorecards used in determining compensation for relevant enterprise employees to align with the considerations of subsection (b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7428D1B792604A68BBEC0AC127CBEF4A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Exemption from certain Commodity Exchange Act provisions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A swap (as such term is defined in section 1a of the Commodity Exchange Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1a">7 U.S.C. 1a</external-xref>)) entered into for the purpose of transferring or sharing credit risk in connection with a risk-transfer transaction shall not be deemed to be a commodity interest (as such term is defined in section 1.3(yy) of the regulations of the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (17 C.F.R. 1.3(yy))), and no swap counterparty or other person sponsoring or arranging a risk-transfer transaction shall be deemed to be a commodity pool operator (as such term is defined in section 1.3(cc) of such regulations), solely by virtue of entering into or sponsoring or arranging such a swap in connection with such transaction.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H730C04F560354DCDAC46ABB426A9C643"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Director shall submit a report, not later than October 30 of each year, to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate, on the activities of each enterprise in meeting the guidelines established under subsection (a) and any obstacles the Director has determined have impeded the ability of the enterprises to meet such guidelines.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF81A358B5EB744ECA7FBCE5B7DA7FDA2"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:</text> <paragraph id="H4DCBFB9CECF346C39D0F911C23B77AC4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Credit risk</header><text>The term <quote>credit risk</quote> means, with respect to a mortgage loan on a one- to four-family residential property that is held or guaranteed, or intended to be held or guaranteed, by an enterprise or any security backed by such residential mortgage loans held or guaranteed by the enterprise, the risk of loss to the enterprise that could result from a mortgagor’s failure to repay any such loan in accordance with its terms.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFD3AB61D136B4ADCAEAAC8E540CF26A1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>First loss</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>first-loss</quote> means the risk of loss for an enterprise on a mortgage loan on a one- to four-family residential property or a security backed by such residential mortgage loans, beginning with the first dollar of loss.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE927F0049D9949EAA7757D695B631ED3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Front-end risk transfer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>front-end risk transfer</quote> means, with respect to a mortgage loan on a one- to four-family residential property or any security backed by such residential mortgage loans, a risk transfer or risk share that occurs before or simultaneous with the acquisition of such loan or security by an enterprise.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFA050A29A82B43D6A6BC10CAF67D24F9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Guarantee fee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>guarantee fee</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 1327(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4547">12 U.S.C. 4547(a)</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBC9E06B1AAA740D28FB7097E3F5BE534"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Risk-transfer transaction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>risk-transfer transaction</quote> means any transaction that provides for—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBA78C2299D024C7D9FD750B7A3320800"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the sale, disposition, retention, or transfer within the private sector of credit risk on any residential mortgage loan on a one- to four-family residential property or a pool of such residential mortgage loans that back securities on which the enterprise guarantees the timely payment of principal and interest; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0CA78A4B1F94147A359437F69B28CE7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the retention by the private sector of any such credit risk in connection with the sale of any such loan or security to an enterprise.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0B74D65A630E41E29D33D59874E518D9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment to Commodity Exchange Act</header><text>Paragraph (10) of section 1a of the Commodity Exchange Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1a">7 U.S.C. 1a(10)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H92E7412A718B413D8369176B03E89A81" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="HCB15734FE583437DAA32433045713FF8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A swap (as such term is defined in section 1a) entered into for the purpose of transferring or sharing credit risk in connection with a risk-transfer transaction shall not be considered to be a commodity interest (as such term is defined in section 1.3(yy) of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations), and no swap counterparty or other person sponsoring or arranging a risk-transfer transaction shall be considered to be a commodity pool operator (as such term is defined in section 1.3(cc) of such title), solely by virtue of entering into or sponsoring or arranging such a swap in connection with such transaction.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H2FDC211472CE41288EFECE1421CC1FE7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendments to existing laws</header>
 <paragraph id="HEC7128F8F7B44C8980E93B7AC33E8AB3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Investment Company Act of 1940</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3(c)(5) of the Investment Company Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80a-3">15 U.S.C. 80a–3(c)(5)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting before the period the following: <quote>, including notes, bonds, other evidences of indebtedness, certificates, securities, and other interests, issued in connection with or otherwise related to a risk-transfer transaction (as such term is defined in section 1328(h) of the Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992)</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H01E4FB6399124A6F999DF72A3179475F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Asset and income test clarification for enterprise risk-transfer transactions</header><text>The Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H1B46A506D54A410FA1B6F16C02DFFC65"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in each of paragraphs (2)(B) and (3)(B) of section 856(c) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/856">26 U.S.C. 856(c)</external-xref>), by inserting before the semicolon at the end the following <quote>, and gross income resulting from participation in any transaction, including notes, bonds, other evidences of indebtedness, certificates, securities, and other interests, that are risk-transfer transactions (as such term is defined in section 1328(h) of the Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90886AA1F5FD4E00BC4E8C90C28FFB49"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B) of section 856(c)(5) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/856">26 U.S.C. 856(c)(5)(B)</external-xref>), by inserting before the period at the end of the first sentence the following: <quote>, and participation in any transaction, including notes, bonds, other evidences of indebtedness, certificates, securities, and other interests, that are risk-transfer transactions (as such term is defined in section 1328(h) of the Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992)</quote>.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF66B0635AD6D4D20BBE3B50FE97D17DA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Pilot program for small lender risk transfer</header>
 <subsection id="H41818014CD80411493EFCFF38B0DB134"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency shall require each enterprise (as such term is defined in section 1303 of the Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4502">12 U.S.C. 4502</external-xref>)) to establish a pilot program under which the enterprise shall annually engage, for each of the next 5 consecutive years, in at least one front-end risk-transfer transaction for which at least 75 percent of the credit risk transferred is transferred to bank or non-bank mortgage originators having under $10,000,000,000 in assets.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HA0BC8A481DF44D74BE4DECF3ECB1822A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than the conclusion of the fifth year of the pilot program, the Director shall submit a report to the Congress that assesses the extent to which the pilot program under this section has—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H4C8A1C30F1D14165B98B1D383E4BF669"><enum>(1)</enum><text>transferred credit risk from the Federal Government to mortgage originators; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF18D14817C794916A58AE4E3362E3277"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">resulted in increased participation in credit risk-transfer transactions by bank or non-bank mortgage originators having under $10,000,000,000 in assets.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5493C6A67BD24ED29142428B6E375190"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Extension of program</header><text>Based on the assessments in the report required under subsection (b), the Director may extend the program beyond its fifth year of operation if the Director determines that such extension would be in the public interest.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H66859BD221A6410B97D8264E3C1CD134"><enum>4.</enum><header>Pilot program for mortgage insurance risk transfer</header>
 <subsection id="H3947C71B56D64692A7661BB34FFFBC9B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director shall require each enterprise to establish a pilot program to increase the amount of risk that is shared by the enterprise using private mortgage insurance.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEB932BC6062C4B78BC4DEEC85BF3B7A6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program requirements</header><text>Each pilot program established pursuant to subsection (a) shall meet the following requirements:</text> <paragraph id="HE18053577D444222B0EB6EA32E08032F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The pilot program shall have a duration of 5 years.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H6D8277B4146C4448B7EA152DCE813C1A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amount of mortgage purchases</header>
 <subparagraph id="H6270FFC3598E4D1C868FCFF61BA7AB76"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), in each year each enterprise shall purchase under its pilot program sufficient qualifying loans or pools of qualifying loans such that the aggregate unpaid principal balance of all qualifying loans or loan pools purchased by the enterprise is not less than $25,000,000,000.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0DA43982E76842088A988BB33AC3004E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The amount of qualifying loans that each enterprise is required to purchase each year under paragraph (1) may be reduced if the Director and the Secretary of the Treasury jointly—</text>
 <clause id="H5EA6651AF2F449C091E1DB6EB7D894AC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>make a determination that such a reduction is necessary to prevent an adverse impact to the housing market; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDB4468533CA94AE4B47C5B4D3A3CB075"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>submit to the Congress a report describing the justification for the determination referred to in clause (i).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H33D3CA2AC9FE443AB1D34B1830104C10"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Selection of mortgage insurance</header><text>For each transaction under the pilot program involving a qualifying loan, the loan originator shall select an eligible mortgage insurance provider or providers, consistent with existing market practice.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H03C98F2F86244074BF7396075C4BCC77"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Mortgage insurance premiums</header><text>Mortgage insurance premiums applicable to qualifying loans purchased by an enterprise under the pilot program shall be subject to requirements and limitations under applicable State laws.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3A79473D61354B07A75320CF9A7CC63B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Guarantee fees</header><text>Each enterprise shall set and publish guarantee fees, including up-front delivery fees and loan level price adjustments, commensurate with the enterprise’s reduced credit risk resulting from any new risk-transfer transaction under the pilot program.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6C918293E2E14503B4E018AE63B3E359"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than the conclusion of the fifth year of the pilot program, the Director shall submit a report to the Congress that assesses the extent to which the pilot program under this section has—</text>
 <paragraph id="H99D7259FB38E42D3BE08BDD6B3806093"><enum>(1)</enum><text>transferred credit risk from the enterprises to the private sector;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0BD76ED1508042C3B57BC0F1F8D19CBF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>resulted in reduced guarantee fees for mortgage originators; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD67B4391C6D5420F8E8AF2C34CD8E34D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>produced benefits or costs for borrowers under qualifying loans under the program.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC8F11A302EEE4D0AB2DB1F9A589978D7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Extension of program</header><text>Based on the assessments in the report required under subsection (c), the Director may extend the program beyond its fifth year of operation if the Director determines that such extension would be in the public interest.</text>
 </subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1ABD1796BFBB4BDF95C5B497EC60F23F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Mitigating counterparty risk</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall prevent the Director from establishing additional requirements on participants in the pilot program necessary to mitigate counterparty risk to the enterprises comparable to other credit risk-transfer structures.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HED494D1381424CCB927A8F1B303D360A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:</text> <paragraph id="H3EC50FF368B946D598A4B443B4DD3E9A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Director</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Director</quote> means the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD05B65CA96224D028F551554E6F04AA7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible mortgage insurance provider</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>eligible mortgage insurance provider</quote> means a company that—</text> <subparagraph id="HC65E9130521E4A69AA3C5F47361C5CB9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is regulated as a mortgage guaranty insurance company by its State of domicile;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5DEE1EF615844DA08002B98B113F8FCE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides qualifying mortgage insurance; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H055420F9BB0C4BCAA7D4EF87F96A05E3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>satisfies—</text>
						<clause id="HC0E9C066F8FA4E20A6733DD7BC6D652F"><enum>(i)</enum>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H142F84E1AEFD4505B03F6C4F2C2E1533"><enum>(I)</enum><text>minimum requirements established or recognized by the Director, pursuant to public notice and comment, with respect to capital, leverage, and reserve requirements; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE1554D1D000E4152AF3BAAFEA58C853A" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Private Mortgage Insurer Eligibility Requirements published by the enterprises on April 17, 2015; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HA9A1CFA0C33B45FCA876538B11722FB3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any additional requirements added by subsection (e) of this section.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H81EC0AA447F9425BAED28C56D9C18134"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Enterprise</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>enterprise</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 1303 of the Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4502">12 U.S.C. 4502</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H94B09042E43E44A2930EDF1ED1B24373"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Qualifying loan</header><text>The term <quote>qualifying loan</quote> means a first mortgage loan that—</text> <subparagraph id="H2AF033CC3FA3476B806ABE3266552B5F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is secured by a one- to four-family residence; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC364003A99940C6A7490348A4AFFAEC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is subject to qualifying mortgage insurance.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA33701F616DB4602BDC450FFDF09236F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Qualifying mortgage insurance</header><text>The term <quote>qualifying mortgage insurance</quote> means, with respect to a qualifying loan, primary mortgage guaranty insurance for such qualifying loan that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H80B60E5B495C4E18B1461CA4F70F07F5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is placed at the time the qualifying loan is originated;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50D27263C7D7422388F0F830AB54AA60"><enum>(B)</enum><text>guarantees or insures that portion of the unpaid principal balance of the qualifying loan that is in excess of 50 percent of the value of the property securing the mortgage; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C254C6C525D4CED917EF3A45795D314"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is provided by an eligible mortgage insurance provider.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB37219CB65C44A64B144AD1435B153CB"><enum>5.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act or the amendments made by this Act shall be affected solely by termination of the conservatorship of an enterprise pursuant to section 1367 of the Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4617">12 U.S.C. 4617</external-xref>).</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


