<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCC2032BF97D64DD4A56F8DEA6F94E253" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3086 IH: Space Weather Research and Forecasting Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3086</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170627">June 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000593">Mr. Perlmutter</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001283">Mr. Bridenstine</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Intelligence (Permanent Select)</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve understanding and forecasting of space weather events, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HA893E22182F64BFEB4EB18CD5FC05A5F" style="OLC">
 <section id="H21D00665ADA544E8A322198209F150BF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Space Weather Research and Forecasting Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HCE3D716FCAF9456A8F86DEC3C8EDD44C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Space weather</header> <subsection id="H36C079606C3342F6A13BFBC3032D0C78"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle VI of title 51, United States Code, is amended by adding after chapter 605 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9E232E1B55E8471FA537CEFA17EE5B04" style="USC">
					<chapter id="H7F2CEF7FD50341308CF8A2844C59E6F7" style="OLC"><enum>607</enum><header>Space weather</header>
						<toc container-level="chapter-container" idref="H7F2CEF7FD50341308CF8A2844C59E6F7" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
							<toc-entry idref="H7C479678836047C2BDE63C2C7A70CEED" level="section">Sec.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry level="section">60701. Space weather.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H4FAB0DD394B54BD88488F82224D1AEFC" level="section">60702. Observations and forecasting.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="HB4271E0984BF4B16BC2105976AA0C5FF" level="section">60703. Research and technology.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H41DCB227808C47D2A875FE0D247DC3AB" level="section">60704. Space weather data.</toc-entry></toc>
						<section id="H7C479678836047C2BDE63C2C7A70CEED"><enum>60701.</enum><header>Space weather</header>
 <subsection id="H9DEF3436D1E94E2FAAE79F31CBD987A7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress makes the following findings:</text> <paragraph id="HC91D5614A37646999166D5A9D9B757F7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Space weather events pose a significant threat to humans working in the space environment and to modern technological systems.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC34ED02763CF4F34AE5791A434712D44"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The effects of severe space weather events on the electric power grid, satellites and satellite communications and information, airline operations, astronauts living and working in space, and space-based position, navigation, and timing systems could have significant societal, economic, national security, and health impacts.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9662083AD9EA404E8EF5C605B97A4681"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Earth and space observations provide crucial data necessary to predict and warn about space weather events.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEFDBCD7AAD9945378F220A92341347BF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Clear roles and accountability of Federal departments and agencies are critical for an efficient and effective response to threats posed by space weather.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H31B7BEE30C7F41A890347D859C5F4A1A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In October 2015, the National Science and Technology Council published a National Space Weather Strategy and a National Space Weather Action Plan seeking to integrate national space weather efforts and add new capabilities to meet increasing demand for space weather information.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6A2AA3465FF94C28A8C8C080683E92AB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Federal agency roles</header>
 <paragraph id="H9E128E93E84941FFABCE36B22BAA9029"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that—</text> <subparagraph id="H6F8FBE3D643441BE8630B69CA15CE3A5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration provides operational space weather forecasting and monitoring for civil applications, maintains ground and space-based assets to provide observations needed for forecasting, prediction, and warnings, provides research to support operational responsibilities, and develops requirements for space weather forecasting technologies and science;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17429346246B4225B5D97CC0CDB0BA0E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Department of Defense provides operational space weather forecasting, monitoring, and research for the department's unique missions and applications;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD4CB0BA1B6442119D7444AC8A8CECC5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the National Aeronautics and Space Administration provides increased understanding of the fundamental physics of the Sun-Earth system through space-based observations and modeling, develops new space-based technologies and missions, and monitors space weather for NASA's space missions;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F2ABDBF69434D258F8973217EFEFA72"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the National Science Foundation provides increased understanding of the Sun-Earth system through ground-based measurements, technologies, and modeling;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2EBCFB75E32948558FD9D836F9BB5C18"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Department of the Interior collects, distributes, and archives operational ground-based magnetometer data in the United States and its territories, works with the international community to improve global geophysical monitoring, and develops crustal conductivity models to assess and mitigate risk from space weather-induced electric ground currents; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF03B6013EC114FD08BC5D9A919C2FBB2"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Federal Aviation Administration provides operational requirements for space weather services in support of aviation and for coordination of these requirements with the International Civil Aviation Organization, integrates space weather data and products into the Next Generation Air Transportation System, and conducts real-time monitoring of the charged particle radiation environment to protect the health and safety of crew and passengers during space weather events.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6CA76A1065C645CEB84325F825C3F1BA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Office of Science and Technology Policy</header><text>The Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H7479EC04C93A4F3790E43ED642846E7B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>coordinate the development and implementation of Federal Government activities to improve the Nation's ability to prepare, avoid, mitigate, respond to, and recover from potentially devastating impacts of space weather events; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5551535C90441B9A20897CB0DBAD220"><enum>(B)</enum><text>coordinate the activities of the space weather interagency working group established under subsection (c).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H32371C7F2E1042F991E11CE3301F8B9D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Space weather interagency working group</header><text>In order to continue coordination of executive branch efforts to understand, prepare, coordinate, and plan for space weather, the National Science and Technology Council shall establish an interagency working group on space weather.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H76F3A3F782764E579A08CF4D0D448F77"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>In order to understand and respond to the adverse effects of space weather, the interagency working group established under subsection (c) shall leverage capabilities across participating Federal agencies, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="H5290A84CF636447D950CDF9FA12A8FE7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC0A71DC6DA2E4242849B4BDC3002CECC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the National Aeronautics and Space Administration;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC4334654BCF14EA0BA58EE00A0D35035"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the National Science Foundation;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA7B8C9D712344586A3398025102D058A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Department of Defense;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4999019CE2F2477A8C75E0E9BDC02ECC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Department of the Interior;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HADC0A047D37D4C189FE698199A4AA769"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the Department of Homeland Security;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAF5B962CA5CC48558AD884F45505E45C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the Department of Energy;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF468259F61F9408892AE7AF72A3D916B"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the Department of Transportation, including the Federal Aviation Administration; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H738D0E88851D49AC8859B86C1C07C198"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the Department of State.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H63C522907DEB4A8EA99455EF5E4AA477"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Interagency agreements</header> <paragraph id="HF5BBD0EE89174DEF858BDA9F3E9C5CAA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the interagency collaboration between the National Aeronautics and Space Administration and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration on terrestrial weather observations provides—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5B29EACEE93E4FF48BEA8FAAB28EED98"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an effective mechanism for improving weather and climate data collection while avoiding unnecessary duplication of capabilities across Federal agencies; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE1029C085ED4027ABA86E22F89C16AD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an agency collaboration model that could benefit space weather observations.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H802563261CBF4DA2B297A38BD7C12425"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Interagency agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration and the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall enter into one or more interagency agreements providing for cooperation and collaboration in the development of space weather spacecraft, instruments, and technologies and in the transition of research to operations in accordance with this chapter.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H3281DD269ACD41ACB401AC95F27FF32A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>International, commercial, and academic collaboration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Participating Federal agencies in the space weather interagency working group established under subsection (c) shall, to the extent practicable and appropriate, increase engagement and cooperation with the international, commercial, and academic communities on the observational infrastructure, data, and scientific research necessary to advance the characterization, prediction, and mitigation of space weather events.</text>
							</subsection></section><section id="H4FAB0DD394B54BD88488F82224D1AEFC"><enum>60702.</enum><header>Observations and forecasting</header>
 <subsection id="H3388360C1DDD4A18A12D62E2A1E2CEBE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Policy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States to establish and sustain a baseline space and ground-based capability for space weather observations.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="HADB7249A1EAF4E92A8C1121121AF3880"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Integrated strategy</header>
 <paragraph id="H36808BEA83E045CD9F26ADF9521DDBE0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, in coordination with the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the Director of the National Science Foundation, and the Secretary of Defense, and in consultation with the academic and commercial communities, shall develop an integrated strategy for space and ground-based space weather observations, including solar and solar wind observations beyond the lifetime of current assets, that considers—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFCDC76102F8E484D950D2226681740E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the provision of solar wind measurements and other measurements essential to space weather forecasting; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB711A60F29124A44AFD0DA3396466129"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the provision of solar and space weather measurements important for scientific purposes.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H08961EA80C164BADB79FD583666A1304"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the strategy under paragraph (1), the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall consider small satellite and microsatellite options, hosted payloads, commercial options, international options, and prize authority.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H30485466611D411A9952E01E4A0FBA76"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Critical observations</header><text>In order to sustain current space-based observational capabilities, the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H629DB92E7D804A56AE2BD5B72D3EF357"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as appropriate, in cooperation with the European Space Agency, maintain operations of the Solar and Heliospheric Observatory/Large Angle and Spectrometric Coronagraph (referred to in this section as <quote>SOHO/LASCO</quote>) for as long as the satellite continues to deliver quality observations; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC537FADE236546FD8CB00A7AA7D660C5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prioritize the reception of LASCO data.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0CB132A2D97B4059BD05A0D65CE95C0D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Additional capability for solar imaging</header> <paragraph id="H6D6A0D29411549E28D51594AB529AF8C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall secure reliable secondary capability for near real-time coronal mass ejection imagery.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD96A39BB79524C13B56045765253CFEA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Options</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense and the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, shall develop options, including commercial solutions, to build and deploy one or more instruments for near real-time coronal mass ejection imagery.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC15E14D9A2CB40AE99D9222C7D918E00"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing options under paragraph (2), the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall consider commercial solutions, prize authority, academic and international partnerships, small satellites and microsatellites, ground-based instruments, and opportunities to deploy the instrument or instruments as a secondary payload on an upcoming planned launch.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF165F4B7C787400BB8FC9ECBB6677A5B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Costs</header><text>In implementing paragraph (1), the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall consider a cost-effective and reliable solution.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4DE55BE7CB854A1D95869EA6D3506024"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Operational planning</header><text>The Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall develop an operational contingency plan to provide continuous space weather forecasting in the event of a SOHO/LASCO failure.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE03C68ADD58743EDA33C44114D491C33"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Space Weather Research and Forecasting Act</short-title>, the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall provide a briefing to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate</committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives</committee-name> on the options for building and deploying the instrument or instruments described in paragraph (2) and the operational contingency plan developed under paragraph (5).</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H55E3CBE30A3240978AAA89E8A3559A42"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Follow-On space-Based observations</header>
 <paragraph id="H35644B101A644E6D9621B3D7FD2E8244"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, shall develop requirements and a plan for follow-on space-based observations for operational purposes, in accordance with the integrated strategy developed under subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H00309C0A475B4BD4B19A18816F7CDA75"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Research needs</header><text>In developing the requirements and plan under paragraph (1), the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall coordinate with the National Aeronautics and Space Administration and the National Science Foundation regarding the research necessary to improve space weather forecasting and the space-based observations that will advance research and development.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCA1213A8C9C64CE58C893A00380DAC96"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Space Weather Research and Forecasting Act</short-title>, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall submit to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate</committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives</committee-name> a report on the integrated strategy under subsection (b), including the Plan for follow-on space-based observations under subsection (e).</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="H7B89F8DDD23F47F5A34C7FC30C101B55"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Review of integrated strategy</header>
 <paragraph id="HA6B56554A1D84631ABD8D6D130F86959"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Science Foundation, in conjunction with Federal agencies participating in the space weather interagency working group established under section 60701(c), shall enter into an agreement with the National Academies to review the integrated strategy developed under subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H1BE4AB4DA1F54E73934EEAEE97E510E8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transmittal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Science Foundation shall transmit the results of the review required under paragraph (1) to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate not later than 18 months after the enactment of the <short-title>Space Weather Research and Forecasting Act</short-title>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2B4458C627004872A336BBF9C83D7977"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Ground-Based observations</header><text>The National Science Foundation, the Air Force, and, where practicable in support of the Air Force, the Navy shall each—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB9578C8E4A24421D9341F38D9D232687"><enum>(1)</enum><text>maintain and improve, as necessary and advisable, ground-based observations of the Sun in order to help meet the priorities identified in section 60703(a); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCC5B64F528E34840B37FFADFD0BF817F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide space weather data by means of its set of ground-based facilities, including radars, lidars, magnetometers, radio receivers, aurora and airglow imagers, spectrometers, interferometers, and solar observatories.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFDD1DAB57DE94237957DC003957A2568"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Ground-Based observations data</header><text>The National Science Foundation shall—</text> <paragraph id="H6642C626C54647D69FD9F86672A6B55D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide key data streams from the platforms described in subsection (h) for research and to support space weather model development;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA7F602460C714C9E89D636AF7097E121"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop experimental models for scientific purposes; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H49F47AD4A20849E89504DEE17B027B4F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>support the transition of the experimental models to operations where appropriate.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB4271E0984BF4B16BC2105976AA0C5FF"><enum>60703.</enum><header>Research and technology</header>
							<subsection id="HAAA467FFCEFF4B139173BBD096C38C5A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>User needs</header>
 <paragraph id="HB06A8FCE518D4FAB89D1A2D05D19D678"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the Secretary of the Air Force, and where practicable in support of the Air Force, the Secretary of the Navy, in conjunction with the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration and the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall conduct a comprehensive survey to identify and prioritize the needs of space weather forecast users, including space weather data and space weather forecast data needed to improve services and inform research priorities and technology needs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBA12C91CBA804738AA61F12783B52B1B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>In conducting the comprehensive survey under paragraph (1), the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the Secretary of the Air Force, and where practicable in support of the Air Force, the Secretary of the Navy, at a minimum, shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDBE1FC32D0064C4EBE18ACD6B08BB071"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consider the goals for forecast lead time, accuracy, coverage, timeliness, data rate, and data quality for space weather observations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5ED0176AA0244C54800F1D10494C8DA1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify opportunities to address the needs identified under paragraph (1) through collaborations with academia, the commercial sector, and the international community;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC44DDDEFBA58467B84DB83B7864816F0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identify opportunities for new technologies, research, and instrumentation to address the needs identified under paragraph (1); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB537E18A2F241ADAB7905FB41254DEA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>publish a report on the findings under subparagraphs (A) through (C).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF89D7AA7886C42AE8E601AEA9DC88412"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Space Weather Research and Forecasting Act</short-title>, the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the Secretary of the Air Force, and where practicable in support of the Air Force, the Secretary of the Navy, shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6B108BA9ABAF4007B9ED9217B4EFEFCB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>make the results of the comprehensive survey publicly available; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5719A6B27DBB4DD6BEA9B20CEF8E2659"><enum>(B)</enum><text>notify the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate</committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives</committee-name> of the publication under subparagraph (A).</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCD6D4396D08242A68694DCC92E397225"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Research activities</header>
 <paragraph id="H0BFDBB01CF6A4BA6B74E1F9D96763EFA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Basic research</header><text>The Director of the National Science Foundation, Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, and the Secretary of Defense shall continue to carry out basic research activities on heliophysics, geospace science, and space weather and support competitive, merit-based, peer-reviewed proposals for research, modeling, and monitoring of space weather and its impacts, including science goals outlined in Solar and Space Physics Decadal surveys conducted by the National Academy of Sciences.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3D893CF0DF714BB68AFA03580F583E29"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other research activities</header><text>The Director of the National Science Foundation and the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall support basic research activities in the social, behavioral, and economic sciences that will lead to improved national preparedness and encourage mitigation and protection measures before a space weather event.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="H6198D34D4F4044F8A92431B1E3085425"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Multidisciplinary research</header>
 <subparagraph id="HF69E95506979443C942D2CDA060D336E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that the multidisciplinary nature of solar and space physics creates funding challenges that require coordination across scientific disciplines and Federal agencies.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFFF242EAA9D64D379C9B24BE291FFEF8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Multidisciplinary research</header><text>The Director of the National Science Foundation, the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration shall pursue multidisciplinary, coordinated research in subjects that further our understanding of solar physics, space physics, and space weather.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34D1D359B26F4A2DB949719DB6F5AD4F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration and Director of the National Science Foundation should support competitively awarded Heliophysics Science Centers that support research to operations and operations to research.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H67DDBC720FCD4AF8ABF5A2C529577A91"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Science missions</header><text>The Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration shall seek to implement missions that meet the science objectives identified in Solar and Space Physics Decadal surveys conducted by the National Academy of Sciences.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="H46C69C359F1F4C468A7FFE2247248AFD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Research to operations</header>
 <paragraph id="H0C7FAE259A514C18A3FAE251CC6C249F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the Director of the National Science Foundation, the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the Secretary of the Air Force, and where practicable in support of the Air Force, the Secretary of the Navy, shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9F8CA752E2C24790911209E4BE4E747D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop a formal mechanism to transition National Aeronautics and Space Administration, National Science Foundation, Air Force, and Navy research findings, research needs, models, and capabilities, as appropriate, to National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and Department of Defense space weather operational forecasting centers; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7015332CCFA84CA5B038D813BEBC4FC8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enhance coordination between research modeling centers and forecasting centers.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4BF244CEB1B4E23B6FC28175E3D417E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Operational needs</header><text>The Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration and the Director of the National Science Foundation, shall develop a formal mechanism to communicate the operational needs of space weather forecasters to the research community.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H75117D8773EB40AE97A3710DC15FA381"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Technology development</header>
 <paragraph id="HCAFF3BFDB9A54EB9B88B81307C96E934"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that observations and measurements closer to the Sun and advanced instrumentation would provide for more advanced warning of space weather disturbances (as defined in section 3 of the <short-title>Space Weather Research and Forecasting Act</short-title>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB309A1F81407443794804A41268E0D1C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technology and instrumentation development</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration and the Director of the National Science Foundation shall support the development of technologies and instrumentation that address research priorities and improve space weather forecasting lead-time and accuracy to meet the needs identified by the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H41DCB227808C47D2A875FE0D247DC3AB"><enum>60704.</enum><header>Space weather data</header>
 <subsection id="H2824474D43B54FB0B18D1B0F075F6B2E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration and the Director of the National Science Foundation shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HCF87BDB7C7994BB88E71223919160C6C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>make space weather related data obtained for scientific research purposes available to space weather forecasters and operations centers; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD6C1ACA5D08A49A4AF4C75836BC54067"><enum>(2)</enum><text>support model development and model applications to space weather forecasting.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H26E788CB6AAF474DA0664A77C70D454E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Research</header><text>The Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall make space weather related data obtained from operational forecasting available for scientific research.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC06732CD514C4A498D5424172EE60765"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Space weather government-Industry-University roundtable</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, in collaboration with the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration and the Director of the National Science Foundation, shall enter into an arrangement with the National Academies to establish a Space Weather Government-Industry-University Roundtable to facilitate communication and knowledge transfer among Government participants in the space weather interagency working group established under section 60701(c), industry, and academia to—</text>
 <paragraph id="HAA1CF6DAA815446FA94318F930206DAA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>facilitate advances in space weather prediction and forecasting;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H82D9C34892624701989381146473BFE9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>help enable the 2-way coordination of research and operations; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H457AC0EC7465462DB53EF3D55C2857F8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>improve preparedness for potential space weather events.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></chapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="HD28399D9DA9A4E9E918C05B744D6E65F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header> <paragraph id="HD7EB349EEE2640C8AD041DBAF7706917"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Repeal of section 809</header><text>Section 809 of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18388">42 U.S.C. 18388</external-xref>) and the item relating to that section in the table of contents under section 1(b) of that Act (124 Stat. 2806) are repealed.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAA2A778DE6CD429BB65DF18660D296C7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Table of chapters</header><text>The table of chapters of title 51, United States Code, is amended by adding after the item relating to chapter 605 the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H03FA7C680764472C802055DA8DF47942" style="OLC">
						<toc>
							<multi-column-toc-entry bold="off" level="section"><toc-enum>607.</toc-enum><level-header level="section">Space weather</level-header><target>60701</target></multi-column-toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA3220DB5AA9F4233A4552855A1B39DB3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Space weather metrics</header>
 <subsection id="H59FAC13125DA40EE8C0761715DF57708"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H8DBAA9065E974F21880A056F123BEFB1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Space weather disturbance</header><text>The term <term>space weather disturbance</term> includes geo-electric fields, ionizing radiation, ionospheric disturbances, solar radio bursts, and upper atmospheric expansion.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEC6A9C78F0AA461A9A1C7E2A4316851D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Space weather benchmark</header><text>The term <term>space weather benchmark</term> means the physical characteristics and conditions describing the nature, frequency, and intensity of space weather disturbances.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H136778F7B7A048AF951F7F4B285A965C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Benchmarks</header>
 <paragraph id="H8FFE7D95D17445638FF7FED8C5E2827A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Preliminary</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the space weather interagency working group established under section 60701(c) of title 51, United States Code, in consultation with academic and commercial experts, shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H690722DFD67D41F9B54F83B95E760847"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assess existing data, the historical record, models, and peer-reviewed studies on space weather; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD64C19754A944D6DB14B1529DD17EA29"><enum>(B)</enum><text>develop preliminary benchmarks, based on current scientific understanding and the historical record, for measuring solar disturbances.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H50BB23A4BAB946A68D403F08CA13FE2F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date the preliminary benchmarks are developed under paragraph (1), the space weather interagency working group shall publish final benchmarks.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H65F988E5619D4A1481BFF243767C964C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Review</header><text>The Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration shall contract with the National Academy of Sciences to review the benchmarks established under paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1F4D946645CB45329135201C560BD61E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Revisions</header><text>The space weather interagency working group shall update and revise the final benchmarks under paragraph (2), as necessary, based on—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8955AB4ABB714FEFAA4D8DBD8A5AB9E5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the results of the review under paragraph (3);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H468B2CAC4F3343F980C362A615392093"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any significant new data or advances in scientific understanding that become available; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F4AC007FC2C482CB9715B480A8B8A2F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the evolving needs of entities impacted by solar disturbances.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HFFABBE796D464C85A2274CBB6EFA89B4"><enum>4.</enum><header>Protection of critical infrastructure</header> <subsection id="HC55EACEC9A1647F289FCCA3393F30E6A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, in consultation with the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall provide information about space weather hazards to the Secretary of Homeland Security for purposes of this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB7AB9E4A60B842B0B62B110DEA40ECCD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Critical infrastructure</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with sector-specific agencies, the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and the heads of other relevant agencies, shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HAE1702AAE6C540F0B5DCB68177B55625"><enum>(1)</enum><text>include, in meeting national critical infrastructure reporting requirements, an assessment of the vulnerability of critical infrastructure to space weather events, as described by the space weather benchmarks under section 3; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD563E99238C742D3B0B8F866DE156407"><enum>(2)</enum><text>support critical infrastructure providers in managing the risks and impacts associated with space weather.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE36AD2A2D3764C48AFDF7E87F14F5B9F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition on new regulatory authority</header><text>Nothing in subsection (b) may be construed to grant the Secretary of Homeland Security any authority to promulgate regulations that was not in effect on the day before the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H160D5D6BE2FF48B5BE53D63F46530E5E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition of sector-Specific agency</header><text>In this section, the term <term>sector-specific agency</term> has the meaning given the term in Presidential Policy Directive–21 of February 12, 2013 (Critical Infrastructure Security and Resilience), or any successor.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H67DE5F8BE555432D91A5B63F54DA8825"><enum>5.</enum><header>Protection of national security assets</header>
 <subsection id="H05C6286F434C408DA3CF056023225E2A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The National Security Council, in consultation with the Office of the Director of National Intelligence, the Secretary of Defense, and the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE8AC320D652540738516EF86A2572881"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assess the vulnerability of the national security community to space weather events, as described by the space weather benchmarks under section 3; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H916A75BB7F194837A3D025BFCDA27B1B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop national security mechanisms to protect national security assets from space weather threats.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H53D5BD5021494BBA8A20F6DBE3DE76DF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Cooperation</header><text>The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall provide information about space weather hazards to the National Security Council, Director of National Intelligence, and heads of Defense Agencies for purposes of this section.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HB1EC577D6FFE469F86834BA0FE6FE2B6"><enum>6.</enum><header>Ensuring the safety of civil aviation</header>
 <subsection id="H60EEFF5BF0244B32B8CA70036A3EFE6E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, in consultation with the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2520EE276D91401B8A7B958CA33FFA05"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assess the safety implications and vulnerability of the national airspace system by space weather events, as described by the space weather benchmarks under section 3;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA772273CD8034AF7A4C466640FA36479"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assess methods to mitigate the safety implications and effects of space weather on aviation communication systems, aircraft navigation systems, satellite and ground-based navigation systems, and potential health effects of radiation exposure; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H191E6BE35B1349E287820BC8B0D5AC79"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assess options for incorporating space weather into operational training for pilots, cabin crew, dispatchers, air traffic controllers, meteorologists, and engineers.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFB6EFB24929B4FF5A78C0D85DB143D42"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Space weather communication</header><text>The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, in consultation with the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall develop methods to increase the interaction between the aviation community and the space weather research and service provider community.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


