<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H29A0B9B142A14D2798088043AD1C749F" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2762 IH: White House Ethics Transparency Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2762</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170530">May 30, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Maxine Waters of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001168">Mr. Sarbanes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000171">Mr. O'Halleran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001049">Mr. Clay</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000627">Mrs. Demings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001303">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001170">Ms. Shea-Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000754">Mr. Cooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require that waivers and authorizations for certain Federal employees relating to ethics
			 requirements are made public and submitted to the Office of Government
			 Ethics, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HA2474797A2BC4B2C9B707761B3C5EE00" style="OLC">
 <section id="H4D237AAA076141A2BC8CE8F70479BAF7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>White House Ethics Transparency Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H19EE608B40C8493ABDFD8CBF038C79CA" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Procedure for waivers and authorizations relating to ethics requirements</header> <subsection id="H52FA402A20584319BE698BFD7991B519"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, not later than 30 days after an officer or employee issues or approves a waiver or authorization pursuant to a provision listed in subsection (d) to a covered employee, such officer or employee shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H665FD2782DF54E22ACE0A4724A2705B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>transmit a written copy of such waiver or authorization to the Director of the Office of Government Ethics; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9389E360118D49C6A71F1BB4EAD64D90"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make a written copy of such waiver or authorization available to the public on the website of the employing agency of the covered employee.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3FF6F258BCAD41BBB5D921871C686398"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Retroactive application</header><text>In the case of a waiver or authorization described in subsection (a) issued during the period beginning on January 20, 2017, and ending on the date of enactment of this Act, the issuing officer or employee of such waiver or authorization shall comply with the requirements of paragraphs (1) and (2) of such subsection not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H33DBE7B4B52F451ABBE7437312E3E633"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Office of Government Ethics public availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 14 days after receiving a written copy of a waiver or authorization under subsection (a)(1), the Director of the Office of Government Ethics shall make such waiver or authorization available to the public on the website of the Office of Government Ethics.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H04183B3A39504DDF839874B0EA598BAC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applicable provisions</header><text>The provisions referred to in subsection (a) are as follows:</text> <paragraph id="HAF202B1EE95E41C19DF06EFF8EB80BB4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3 of Executive Order 13770 (82 Fed. Reg. 9333, relating to ethics commitments by executive branch appointees), or any subsequent similar order.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDDE27466730C47CB9378196ACA4ABA79"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3 of Executive Order 13490 (74 Fed. Reg. 4673, relating to ethics commitments by executive branch personnel).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEF98E32B479C41C1B1E9841AACB10C44"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Subsection (b)(1) of section 208 of title 18, United States Code, notwithstanding subsection (c) of such section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC170CFA43B9419D8142DBA5A21E5886"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Executive Order 12674, as amended by Executive Order 12731 (81 Fed. Reg. 8008, relating to principles of ethical conduct for Government officers and employees).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3FEEF75399314853BD8CD5C8573803A8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definition of covered employee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>covered employee</quote> means an appointee, as defined in section 2 of Executive Order 13770 (82 Fed. Reg. 9333, relating to ethics commitments by executive branch appointees), who was appointed on or after January 20, 2017.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


