<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H5D635F6299654150B074DF00A1E00F25" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3826 IH: Protecting Seniors During Disasters Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3826</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170925">September 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Frankel of Florida</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="R000435">Ms. Ros-Lehtinen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XXVIII of the Public Health Service Act to establish a National Advisory Committee
			 on Seniors and Disasters.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HA4133FEDF4844445A4C8CF4F88C14060" style="OLC">
 <section id="H95BFFE6A58334796A218779F3174A69A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Seniors During Disasters Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HA50564EA729046A5B954BD7A19AE8C8E"><enum>2.</enum><header>National Advisory Committee on Seniors and Disasters</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subtitle B of title XXVIII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300hh">42 U.S.C. 300hh</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by inserting after section 2811A the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2A112DC11A3141A2AFCB8BEEF00E1196" style="OLC">
				<section id="H373BD17066AF414BBE482AFEB271152B"><enum>2811B.</enum><header>National Advisory Committee on Seniors and Disasters</header>
 <subsection id="H5B026E3B923B415BB84E163249B0AAC6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, shall establish an advisory committee to be known as the <quote>National Advisory Committee on Seniors and Disasters</quote> (referred to in this section as the <quote>Advisory Committee</quote>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H499477C5DDF04D6191D778EEC0BACCD1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall—</text> <paragraph id="H86FB551BBCCE41508AF05B6249C18960"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide advice and consultation with respect to the activities carried out pursuant to section 2814, as applicable and appropriate;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H196849F96BCD42E398EF85424C15E36C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>evaluate and provide input with respect to the medical and public health needs of seniors as they relate to preparation for, response to, and recovery from all-hazards emergencies; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1E0B9D11D90640A08034279C1C39462C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide advice and consultation with respect to State emergency preparedness and response activities and seniors, including related drills and exercises pursuant to the preparedness goals under section 2802(b).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6C72878CC46E43ACAC689A5F66324A10"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional duties</header><text>The Advisory Committee may provide advice and recommendations to the Secretary with respect to seniors and the medical and public health grants and cooperative agreements as applicable to preparedness and response activities authorized under this title and title III.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="HBD9C5ED6111F4B498C65CB04980F91B6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Membership</header>
 <paragraph id="HA63F59B7107A445DB0BD55F8BAA75988"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with such other Secretaries as may be appropriate, shall appoint not to exceed 15 members to the Advisory Committee. In appointing such members, the Secretary shall ensure that the total membership of the Advisory Committee is an odd number.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H266206C0335249B6AFD9D28BD214D49E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Required members</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with such other Secretaries as may be appropriate, may appoint to the Advisory Committee under paragraph (1) such individuals as may be appropriate to perform the duties described in subsections (b) and (c), which may include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9DEC06F72631498EBE555F351AF3B39B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61D4756CE1F24D8B881CD302811ED273"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Director of the Biomedical Advanced Research and Development Authority;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF03F8F8125DB45A88D25133CBD11CF9D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6B54B1750EF4D63BDA00138EA89B4CB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Commissioner of Food and Drugs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8488E98CEAAD45838E2134FDDA2A92E8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Director of the National Institutes of Health;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF1A585BC4E549E9A7DB57913B39657F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD7A5030597E4ED997604855CE4A0896"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the Administrator for Community Living;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F11A218E4414EED9DA9D070B713007C"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62FBE4A549DA44D9A6D09B52E1204820"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Under Secretary for Health, Veterans Health Administration;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A831B093FB14E62819A84E2BC5A3C21"><enum>(J)</enum><text>at least two non-Federal health care professionals with expertise in medical disaster planning, preparedness, response, or recovery;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0EC304D71494F6C90BE10636FE5366B"><enum>(K)</enum><text>at least two representatives from State, local, territorial, or tribal agencies with expertise in disaster planning, preparedness, response, or recovery; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEAEB87587EBE45FCBC4CC54F7E2C454A"><enum>(L)</enum><text>representatives from such Federal agencies (such as the Department of Energy and the Department of Homeland Security) as determined necessary to fulfill the duties of the Advisory Committee, as established under subsections (b) and (c).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB2EE5EC77EE14ED7B4B9CD43E4026FFF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall meet not less than biannually.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H4917F92DC52846F28F3115E54630CDCC"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall terminate on September 30, 2021.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


