<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H4F24CDC49526432A9E8BEAE41A9A5783" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1945 IH: Wildlife and Hunting Heritage Conservation Council Advisory Committee Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1945</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170405">April 5, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000566">Mr. Latta</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000460">Mr. Farenthold</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001053">Mr. Cole</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000799">Mr. Walz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Wildlife and Hunting Heritage Conservation Council Advisory Committee to advise
			 the Secretaries of the Interior and Agriculture on wildlife and habitat
			 conservation, hunting, recreational shooting, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H5EC5550373094BA094DFD8BC0BA96A31" style="OLC">
 <section id="H3CC07E09C02F42CAA3892FD052056B35" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Wildlife and Hunting Heritage Conservation Council Advisory Committee Act</short-title></quote> .</text> </section><section id="H45CBBB54AD4041938352EA7F1FD49708"><enum>2.</enum><header>Wildlife and Hunting Heritage Conservation Council Advisory Committee</header> <subsection id="HE7E79893576A45F6B3DC9E2A8C8942A1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Fish and Wildlife Coordination Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/661">16 U.S.C. 661</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H11564233B45B4784990A268EFBE1385A">
					<section id="HC1A6E86E30C74B81A6F34132C244E40C"><enum>10.</enum><header>Wildlife and Hunting Heritage Conservation Council Advisory Committee</header>
 <subsection id="HA82A1733788C48C0B773FFFB3FD27E12"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is hereby established the Wildlife and Hunting Heritage Conservation Council Advisory Committee (in this section referred to as the <term>Advisory Committee</term>) to advise the Secretaries of the Interior and Agriculture on wildlife and habitat conservation, hunting, and recreational shooting.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H925F16CCAD9C42CAAD1FCFD34634BD2D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties of the advisory committee</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall advise the Secretaries with regard to—</text> <paragraph id="H29999546C17246E3BC56BA5337FE2C14"><enum>(1)</enum><text>implementation of Executive Order No. 13443: Facilitation of Hunting Heritage and Wildlife Conservation, which directs Federal agencies <quote>to facilitate the expansion and enhancement of hunting opportunities and the management of game species and their habitat</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE0308E039CE04282AE2127A0ACCB5961"><enum>(2)</enum><text>policies or programs to conserve and restore wetlands, agricultural lands, grasslands, forest, and rangeland habitats;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD9D436CB54DB4692B240AF6AEE9DD38D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>policies or programs to promote opportunities and access to hunting and shooting sports on Federal lands;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H702F64A2BB66470AAC635FA42329A5EF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>policies or programs to recruit and retain new hunters and shooters;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H111BE95F12564CB2BB716959973B2BCA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>policies or programs that increase public awareness of the importance of wildlife conservation and the social and economic benefits of recreational hunting and shooting; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC2004924790342C8B16BB04B04C8BE88"><enum>(6)</enum><text>policies or programs that encourage coordination among the public, the hunting and shooting sports community, wildlife conservation groups, and States, tribes, and the Federal Government.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8A05599542AF476790C6999B6762F4A7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header>
							<paragraph id="HF53C0A646FE744DDA9EDA843DC494EA5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appointment</header>
 <subparagraph id="H7233F79FC358493DABE5A874B1E9F348"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Advisory Committee shall consist of no more than 16 discretionary members and 7 ex officio members.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0ADDBCA29F364851B54B2BDA5EC690E9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Ex officio members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The ex officio members are—</text> <clause id="HE922036B71534377AB117644DFC7268B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service or a designated representative of the Director;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDA6051B075B445329FFBFAD9FE9EEEFB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Director of the Bureau of Land Management or a designated representative of the Director;</text> </clause><clause id="H937A28EB3FAC4422A7270D3B2EA53C75"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Director of the National Park Service or a designated representative of the Director;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBA22311E272444B0B7BD95D1C4800768"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Chief of the Forest Service or a designated representative of the Chief;</text> </clause><clause id="HB4D7096F3CD74E15A1AB780CD60CC658"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the Chief of the Natural Resources Conservation Service or a designated representative of the Chief;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4EDD388286BD49C59FE53B69DF01E5A6"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the Administrator of the Farm Service Agency or a designated representative of the Administrator; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC2459BA5453D4B9EBCCEDD89602407C7"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the Executive Director of the Association of Fish and Wildlife Agencies.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H193099F7EBA94F8C80525F11BA9638A8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Discretionary members</header><text>The discretionary members shall be appointed jointly by the Secretaries from at least one of each of the following:</text>
 <clause id="HFD4BAB404E6D4A4E8B7C4CEE2F1E7F96"><enum>(i)</enum><text>State fish and wildlife agencies.</text> </clause><clause id="H53B29622CF284454988695D28666B98C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Game bird hunting organizations.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2DB7AD50104B4DE0A02A0B71DDA6B3D0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Wildlife conservation organizations.</text> </clause><clause id="H11ED092CF20444F7A810291EA2064F60"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Big game hunting organizations.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H00323A7DE91F41AB9960ACEF3C2829B3"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The tourism, outfitter, or guiding industry.</text> </clause><clause id="H8399AB3BF2584C458B3B6B062F2AA9E3"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The firearms or ammunition manufacturing industry.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8C52830BD10948E993B7043563053B35"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>The hunting or shooting equipment retail industry.</text> </clause><clause id="H41A15E8E248448CBB586A6B88552F7D6"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Tribal resource management organizations.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H51CEFCF0CA694BD2A7A3FE8342B7D5DB"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>The agriculture industry.</text> </clause><clause id="HE5EDBF83747B44848C692A367610805D"><enum>(x)</enum><text>The ranching industry.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC7047396F9024E419D6999ED1654BB99"><enum>(xi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Waterfowl hunting organizations.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4A25E2AC3704FB59D9F28BB1DD65D7D"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prior to the appointment of the discretionary members, the Secretaries shall determine that all individuals nominated for appointment to the Advisory Committee, and the organization each individual represents, actively support and promote sustainable-use hunting, wildlife conservation, and recreational shooting.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H95538142817C4CF28EFD561DBF2B08A8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Terms</header>
 <subparagraph id="H32601615F785465E8A960204E004EBF9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), members of the Advisory Committee shall be appointed for a term of 4 years. Members shall not be appointed for more than 3 consecutive or nonconsecutive terms.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CA3311F0F134133B7EA94C2ACF57562"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Terms of initial appointees</header><text>As designated by the Secretary at the time of appointment, of the members first appointed—</text> <clause id="HA898EAE37EDC453B9284FCC4F6004334"><enum>(i)</enum><text>6 members shall be appointed for a term of 4 years;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0521EEB6A26D48F58DCD28616C817760"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>5 members shall be appointed for a term of 3 years; and</text> </clause><clause id="H22C0FA9FDF044F1E84FE493610613943"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>5 members shall be appointed for a term of 2 years.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3FD13E4A365044BA9C57B85F48719F37"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Preservation of public advisory status</header><text>No individual may be appointed as a discretionary member of the Advisory Committee while serving as an officer or employee of the Federal Government.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="HA059646B6DDB4ACD9B6651D7308B1489"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Vacancy and removal</header>
 <subparagraph id="H95F92DE4908B4CBAA599797C53004C57"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any vacancy on the Advisory Committee shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDBD25415E7274D64972BD69B60C314B1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Removal</header><text>Advisory Committee members shall serve at the discretion of the Secretaries and may be removed at any time for good cause.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H498CA3BB91284401BC316B0A207B749A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Continuation of service</header><text>Each appointed member may continue to serve after the expiration of the term of office to which such member was appointed until a successor has been appointed.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7C0EE02823DE49218A9B22D5E468EA93"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>The Chairperson of the Advisory Committee shall be appointed for a 3-year term by the Secretaries, jointly, from among the members of the Advisory Committee. An individual may not be appointed as Chairperson for more than 2 consecutive or nonconsecutive terms.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H38F2ADFB331841809B11DAA5246B4E7C"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Pay and expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of the Advisory Committee shall serve without pay for such service, but each member of the Advisory Committee may be reimbursed for travel and lodging incurred through attending meetings of the Advisory Committee approved subgroup meetings in the same amounts and under the same conditions as Federal employees (in accordance with section 5703 of title 5, United States Code).</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H6825529646054ECDBC95295956C3192D"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Meetings</header>
 <subparagraph id="H56011F0ACCEF4BFABF8DC879989DF594"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall meet at the call of the Secretaries, the chairperson, or a majority of the members, but not less frequently than twice annually.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61E77D1E7406410F891FF62DE6E13782"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Open meetings</header><text>Each meeting of the Advisory Committee shall be open to the public.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA966E35349547D889B2843A7D344608"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Prior notice of meetings</header><text>Timely notice of each meeting of the Advisory Committee shall be published in the Federal Register and be submitted to trade publications and publications of general circulation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5ACE4D780CBB4E19AF44E8223AFEBCB8"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Subgroups</header><text>The Advisory Committee may establish such workgroups or subgroups as it deems necessary for the purpose of compiling information or conducting research. However, such workgroups may not conduct business without the direction of the Advisory Committee and must report in full to the Advisory Committee.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE82C68F3AF4147B1821B9A6CC6ABDC08"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>Nine members of the Advisory Committee shall constitute a quorum.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0A44E6E9E3A14113B9179A541BC27065"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Expenses</header><text>The expenses of the Advisory Committee that the Secretaries determine to be reasonable and appropriate shall be paid by the Secretaries.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA7366780D4DB4AE39B7BBDFE2445C243"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Administrative support, technical services, and advice</header><text>A designated Federal Officer shall be jointly appointed by the Secretaries to provide to the Advisory Committee the administrative support, technical services, and advice that the Secretaries determine to be reasonable and appropriate.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H41F8F3763EB14CECB2B118C0D5FD928D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Annual report</header>
 <paragraph id="H9289FC13E16748ABB2D0B2A2FFC26F7E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Required</header><text>Not later than September 30 of each year, the Advisory Committee shall submit a report to the Secretaries, the Committee on Natural Resources and the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate. If circumstances arise in which the Advisory Committee cannot meet the September 30 deadline in any year, the Secretaries shall advise the Chairpersons of each such Committee of the reasons for such delay and the date on which the submission of the report is anticipated.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDBCC51CA7D754F42ADEC359FE319E47E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall describe—</text> <subparagraph id="H430C376E9F8F44D8808B0AD0B4B79BB4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the activities of the Advisory Committee during the preceding year;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92A959F0169F4775B5EF70B970970CEC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the reports and recommendations made by the Advisory Committee to the Secretaries during the preceding year; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H983B98E6D4984128A34EA455127AB374"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an accounting of actions taken by the Secretaries as a result of the recommendations.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H47E121B5E171468A97528DA07AF8FBDC"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Federal Advisory Committee Act</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall be exempt from the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H62D296B8255A4621829CA17D861C8DEC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Continuance and abolishment of existing Wildlife and Hunting Heritage Conservation Council</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Wildlife and Hunting Heritage Conservation Council established pursuant to section 441 of the Revised Statutes (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1457">43 U.S.C. 1457</external-xref>), section 2 of the Fish and Wildlife Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/742a">16 U.S.C. 742a</external-xref>), and other Acts applicable to specific bureaus of the Department of the Interior—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC37382A4126D4458A5BA59A3E3F51C2A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall continue until the date of the first meeting of the Wildlife and Hunting Heritage Conservation Council established by the amendment made by subsection (a); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC2EEEC71407940C9895418D75EA3C3A2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is hereby abolished effective on that date.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

