<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H0189B509E61A40BABA6F3C68369FD26E" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3832 IH: Veterans Opioid Abuse Prevention Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3832</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170926">September 26, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000628">Mr. Dunn</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000611">Mr. Poliquin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000375">Mr. Arrington</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to enter into a memorandum of understanding with the
			 executive director of a national network of State-based prescription
			 monitoring programs under which Department of Veterans Affairs health care
			 providers shall query such network, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HF80F0F73401C4DCC967638087810A9F0" style="OLC">
 <section id="H086E506BAD3646ACBB487CCE85F249E2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Opioid Abuse Prevention Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H3312C5F5CD3443ABAB80227DD50861C8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs participation in national network of State-based prescription drug monitoring programs</header> <subsection id="H8B410A47CD994D1C8DA48254153A5EE8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Memorandum of understanding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall enter into a memorandum of understanding with the executive director of a national network of State-based prescription drug monitoring programs under which Department of Veterans Affairs health care providers shall query such network to support the safe and effective prescribing of controlled substances to covered patients. Under such memorandum of understanding—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD76EDBAF7F754CB9B740D78672A108FB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Department health care providers practicing in a State that participates in such network shall query such network in accordance with the agreement between that State’s prescription drug monitoring program and such network in accordance with applicable Veterans Health Administration policies; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H119DD4263B1746C3A55FFE1661A80AA6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Department health care providers practicing in States that do not participate in such network shall query such network through the drug monitoring program of the participating State that is in closest proximity to the State where the provider is practicing.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H05FB119A3CE14E468A3C8A7E37AF20C3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered patients</header><text>For purposes of this section, a covered patient is a patient who—</text> <paragraph id="HBF3B92A9DAE7410D8FD74EA14F0E79B9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>receives a prescription for a controlled substance for a period of 90 days or longer; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8B5C12FB682242BAA80799B210F0ED3B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is not receiving palliative care or enrolled in hospice care.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDADF5A50AC25406383AFC752977724EB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The memorandum of understanding under subsection (a) shall provide for an exception to ensure that Department health care providers are not obligated to comply with the provisions of the memorandum of understanding if such provisions are in violations of applicable State law.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H29C6C3F47EB44474A68AD7036F488F69"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HBC872A15DE494B06B594A7215F7644F5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>controlled substance</quote> has the meaning given such term in paragraph (6) of section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802(6)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9A5737BEB2C742DBB7E8786791BA6F36"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>national network of State-based prescription monitoring programs</quote> means an interconnected nationwide system that facilitates the transfer of State prescription drug monitoring program data across State lines.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


