<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE4C793F5FD414ECA9361B7E93BDDAD66" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1249 : DHS Multiyear Acquisition Strategy Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code>
		<congress>115th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1249</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date date="20170321">March 21, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require a multiyear acquisition strategy of the
			 Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HB940F8181E15406198A795BC3912C072" style="OLC">
 <section id="H4DE6A52261264D91B353D07A6F619F78" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>DHS Multiyear Acquisition Strategy Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HFFA45774769B40FAB89C27467774276E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Multiyear Acquisition Strategy</header> <subsection id="H3BBEB85EFC4240DAA06998EE6D7C506B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle D of title VIII of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/391">6 U.S.C. 391</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBC0F0F9E5CDC4793AB22A54C447AC5F7" style="OLC">
					<section id="H37BADC5FA4F04507B37D97C3DC85161C"><enum>836.</enum><header>Multiyear acquisition strategy</header>
						<subsection id="HD1B4CB23853749ACA213930DCA20CD3A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Multiyear acquisition strategy required</header>
 <paragraph id="HC91473DA8E87427CAF2C6CCA2C15E278"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees and the Comptroller General of the United States a multiyear acquisition strategy to guide the overall direction of the acquisitions of the Department while allowing flexibility to deal with ever-changing threats and risks, and to help industry better understand, plan, and align resources to meet the future acquisition needs of the Department. Such strategy shall be updated and included in each Future Years Homeland Security Program required under section 874.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H37C9851E45D34F119E3A1B5C31EF226E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The strategy required under paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex for any sensitive or classified information if necessary. The Secretary shall publish such strategy in an unclassified format that is publicly available.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5A753B2986FE491F948CACE79A0A5026"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In developing the strategy required under subsection (a), the Secretary shall, as the Secretary determines appropriate, consult with headquarters, components, employees in the field, and individuals from industry and the academic community.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE7A2ADA552D6457D878C3FB5D40F8481"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Contents of strategy</header><text>The strategy shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="HE98AE812624A4FAAB240DB47D25DE2AF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prioritized list</header><text>A systematic and integrated prioritized list developed by the Under Secretary for Management in coordination with all of the Component Acquisition Executives of Department major acquisition programs that Department and component acquisition investments seek to address, including the expected security and economic benefit of the program or system that is the subject of acquisition and an analysis of how the security and economic benefit derived from such program or system will be measured.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H16FF8C99A04440D1812F882EA456255E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inventory</header><text>A plan to develop a reliable Department-wide inventory of investments and real property assets to help the Department—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE40EBCE57E9B401589B8E2F824CE4F52"><enum>(A)</enum><text>plan, budget, schedule, and acquire upgrades of its systems and equipment; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE91A242C2814A02BC203300DA5393E4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>plan for the acquisition and management of future systems and equipment.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2DB48C1497E40138213136DED2B0AC1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Funding gaps</header><text>A plan to address funding gaps between funding requirements for major acquisition programs and known available resources, including, to the maximum extent practicable, ways of leveraging best practices to identify and eliminate overpayment for items to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H877C32FD46464A63A750AC7D03B66113"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prevent wasteful purchasing;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF066305A3465497A88FE8B3686CEA1A7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>achieve the greatest level of efficiency and cost savings by rationalizing purchases;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6C9E811C686483191FFC365F571701B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>align pricing for similar items; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H781EC793266842D4AA04AFD2283161A9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>utilize purchase timing and economies of scale.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H239462C7F7D5444C9DD6214FC1A04A5D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Identification of capabilities</header><text>An identification of test, evaluation, modeling, and simulation capabilities that will be required to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF3882EF034CF4D42977563618E76148A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>support the acquisition of technologies to meet the needs of such strategy;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1ABBA6910525495FA77AA1E17275166D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>leverage to the greatest extent possible emerging technological trends and research and development trends within the public and private sectors; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36E54F0486254699AF98FA2BA74FBDB3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identify ways to ensure that appropriate technology is acquired and integrated into the Department’s operating doctrine to improve mission performance.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5945244417C34851BB00EE67573BE6C0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Focus on flexible solutions</header><text>An assessment of ways the Department can improve its ability to test and acquire innovative solutions to allow needed incentives and protections for appropriate risk-taking in order to meet its acquisition needs with resiliency, agility, and responsiveness to assure homeland security and facilitate trade.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8B9D2AA42DF04FD6A623B6D7C5FDE92F"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Focus on incentives to save taxpayer dollars</header><text>An assessment of ways the Department can develop incentives for program managers and senior Department acquisition officials to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5ED871700B0045F48F05EAE95F9EC48D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prevent cost overruns;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E2A6A6B3BA84D4E95FAFDE2C1AAEE14"><enum>(B)</enum><text>avoid schedule delays; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3DB79C302DE0417D9C31036A9AAD0E68"><enum>(C)</enum><text>achieve cost savings in major acquisition programs.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3FEB27FFCBB04CF9AAE21733F5AB3127"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Focus on addressing delays and bid protests</header><text>An assessment of ways the Department can improve the acquisition process to minimize cost overruns in—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAD094E3A450844FD8C5F3EA4DC27FF92"><enum>(A)</enum><text>requirements development;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBBFA7772C3BF47B4B779F37A8B851D83"><enum>(B)</enum><text>procurement announcements;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38E3C0B78D5742509B2D03CE0FFBD90C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>requests for proposals;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB670015C626C4CAAB8848F5FABCE78E5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>evaluation of proposals;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H79DCB647F88C42388504AB628A3A9D0D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>protests of decisions and awards; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE29492B24BD406C9C12ED050AFA9D4C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the use of best practices.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3018D3A9D2C841FCAD53B84DD9CF5901"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Focus on improving outreach</header><text>An identification and assessment of ways to increase opportunities for communication and collaboration with industry, small and disadvantaged businesses, intra-government entities, university centers of excellence, accredited certification and standards development organizations, and national laboratories to ensure that the Department understands the market for technologies, products, and innovation that is available to meet its mission needs and to inform the Department’s requirements-setting process before engaging in an acquisition, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE115A7B6A72D4413BC65E05E48F0F17B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>methods designed especially to engage small and disadvantaged businesses, a cost-benefit analysis of the tradeoffs that small and disadvantaged businesses provide, information relating to barriers to entry for small and disadvantaged businesses, and information relating to unique requirements for small and disadvantaged businesses; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC0079CF5B5646968E6DC652E08D9D1A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>within the Department Vendor Communication Plan and Market Research Guide, instructions for interaction by acquisition program managers with such entities to—</text>
 <clause id="HDDEADE5001884BE8B0ADA7CC3B92A3E9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>prevent misinterpretation of acquisition regulations; and</text> </clause><clause id="HDF9EF15955CC4D98B8599715B82F5981"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>permit, within legal and ethical boundaries, interacting with such entities with transparency.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EC506F84ED44356B189F30BB7E4B568"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Competition</header><text>A plan regarding competition under subsection (d).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC53834469FBB43FABC5C8748F7D7DBDD"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Acquisition workforce</header><text>A plan regarding the Department acquisition workforce under subsection (e).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8B9021F126114F8990DA4A4D41D952E2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Competition plan</header><text>The strategy required under subsection (a) shall also include a plan to address actions to ensure competition, or the option of competition, for major acquisition programs. Such plan may include assessments of the following measures in appropriate cases if such measures are cost effective:</text>
 <paragraph id="H8DA9A82A9A714DE48693C4E9B7C3668F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Competitive prototyping.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF82C06A6A886485CB737F95911F1F3CF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Dual-sourcing.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC7089442CF7E4C26B624E482BE6CFD48"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Unbundling of contracts.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA9DB939047004ECE9194A607AA51EDE8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Funding of next-generation prototype systems or subsystems.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6BCDFE2917A745318AC0FF3F07C1583F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Use of modular, open architectures to enable competition for upgrades.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC0FCDC912F194C7D94DE6DAE064E2774"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Acquisition of complete technical data packages.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF3BABD00674041EAB0F5FEF449A439CD"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Periodic competitions for subsystem upgrades.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6DAAE03114B249C8BAE4E8092C868922"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Licensing of additional suppliers, including small businesses.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H950CBF20B8EA4E6C96E0323570A4CE63"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Periodic system or program reviews to address long-term competitive effects of program decisions.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB98953315B114E3581E96B89CB9EF8C2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Acquisition workforce plan</header> <paragraph id="H11D3668931BE472D9152810CB722C391"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Acquisition workforce</header><text>The strategy required under subsection (a) shall also include a plan to address Department acquisition workforce accountability and talent management that identifies the acquisition workforce needs of each component performing acquisition functions and develops options for filling such needs with qualified individuals, including a cost-benefit analysis of contracting for acquisition assistance.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1F3618CC5B8347DD99495690F0428375"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional matters covered</header><text>The acquisition workforce plan under this subsection shall address ways to—</text> <subparagraph id="H76B048427ECF4204AE29189E226B065F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>improve the recruitment, hiring, training, and retention of Department acquisition workforce personnel, including contracting officer’s representatives, in order to retain highly qualified individuals who have experience in the acquisition life cycle, complex procurements, and management of large programs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8BF3D6D79CD54502BBD70566A361E6C7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>empower program managers to have the authority to manage their programs in an accountable and transparent manner as such managers work with the acquisition workforce;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6678612741E845D8852DDEE1600F4B29"><enum>(C)</enum><text>prevent duplication within Department acquisition workforce training and certification requirements through leveraging already-existing training within the Federal Government, academic community, or private industry;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB1843E88B201444D9F5E618B600ACF0E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>achieve integration and consistency with Government-wide training and accreditation standards, acquisition training tools, and training facilities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF0855B70D88425CBC3EAC7044B294EC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>designate the acquisition positions that will be necessary to support the Department acquisition requirements, including in the fields of—</text>
 <clause id="HABE2EA3A329D40E98DE03FCFCF3ECDE7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>program management;</text> </clause><clause id="HCCFBD3A8BC704C619AD942471A30FDB7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>systems engineering;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HACA8E12A70B1415F9C9E5391B5E3C6BA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>procurement, including contracting;</text> </clause><clause id="H37A3115AD989470086FC755E89D66BBA"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>test and evaluation;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3A8FF84F51A1405CA438769A0A762A6B"><enum>(v)</enum><text>life cycle logistics;</text> </clause><clause id="H03F80C64A22846628340E043DDB143AD"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>cost estimating and program financial management; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEBDFFF1A9DF6453FB39DBED67B621868"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>additional disciplines appropriate to Department mission needs;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A1A6165E0344DF5B99074854E2B23EE"><enum>(F)</enum><text>strengthen the performance of contracting officers’ representatives (as defined in subpart 1.602–2 and subpart 2.101 of the Federal Acquisition Regulation), including by—</text>
 <clause id="H100A8E0762C8446C8B40F6D4FA6FE4CE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>assessing the extent to which such representatives are certified and receive training that is appropriate;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H906C4019117C42668D527BE1E2AB26EF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>assessing what training is most effective with respect to the type and complexity of assignment; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2DFBBF8E03B440A69CD4498D643D132E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>implementing actions to improve training based on such assessments; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B6869A263BF46A184C7DFB911115343"><enum>(G)</enum><text>identify ways to increase training for relevant investigators and auditors of the Department to examine fraud in major acquisition programs, including identifying opportunities to leverage existing Government and private sector resources in coordination with the Inspector General of the Department.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8FC7813072D646538CB56802364E9EE6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H70A70296F90347E69A1A5995BF6C07C8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Acquisition</header><text>The term <term>acquisition</term> has the meaning given such term in section 131 of title 41, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H634891B4617F41F1BDD87648749CA175"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HB625DC78BE4A4BDA9AB271363774D8C3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20010DE6E8F24B3791BCAE74A74C8261"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H56FEEFD1D293468DAB24C02532FEA0B3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Best practices</header><text>The term <term>best practices</term>, with respect to acquisition, means—</text> <subparagraph id="H6AEA5880CCD54110AED05C46CAC453C6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a knowledge-based approach to capability development that includes identifying and validating needs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEBE5D4B19750428390D6D654BF889A3F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assessing alternatives to select the most appropriate solution;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H40ADDD21E6364FD5B00BB7C6F7AB8198"><enum>(C)</enum><text>clearly establishing well-defined requirements;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDAACF0496D8417DB002F0E779F45AFD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>developing realistic cost assessments and schedules;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H652F59FD8C3946F2A52422215D8319F0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>securing stable funding that matches resources to requirements;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF60D764042546EA959E68BA1A4A6C2E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>demonstrating technology, design, and manufacturing maturity;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC132A7326C04560B94CF43CDDE818C5"><enum>(G)</enum><text>using milestones and exit criteria or specific accomplishments that demonstrate progress;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8B0AB200ED642DF949DA9A501235F2D"><enum>(H)</enum><text>adopting and executing standardized processes with known success across programs;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD51E84561FB4492A93DA7C1E31420822"><enum>(I)</enum><text>establishing an adequate workforce that is qualified and sufficient to perform necessary functions; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96967033127644508FE5ED62F6E57E1F"><enum>(J)</enum><text>integrating into the mission and business operations of the Department of Homeland Security the capabilities described in subparagraphs (A) through (I).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A6119D7B0974D5FBE4CE60F4B21A6A8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Component Acquisition Executive</header><text>The term <term>Component Acquisition Executive</term> means the senior acquisition official within a component who is designated in writing by the Under Secretary for Management, in consultation with the component head, with authority and responsibility for leading a process and staff to provide acquisition and program management oversight, policy, and guidance to ensure that statutory, regulatory, and higher level policy requirements are fulfilled, including compliance with Federal law, the Federal Acquisition Regulation, and Department acquisition management directives established by the Under Secretary for Management.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H034D540CCA1E4A29AF6B172D6967D371"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Major acquisition program</header><text>The term <term>major acquisition program</term> means a Department acquisition program that is estimated by the Secretary to require an eventual total expenditure of at least $300,000,000 (based on fiscal year 2017 constant dollars) over its life cycle cost.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF027551031B8458ABB97BA825297F597"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 835 the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCC84EBF5A06645D5B5CC181302634531" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 836. Multiyear acquisition strategy.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H4CD952EFCA884CD098C0B3D248C244B9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Government Accountability Office review of multiyear acquisition strategy</header>
 <subsection id="H883506C0A3FE4D8988A54C2A1AC0C274"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After submission of the first multiyear acquisition strategy in accordance with section 836 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (as added by section 2 of this Act) after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a review of such plan within 180 days to analyze the viability of such plan’s effectiveness in the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H2C4939DF1AE347A38350C0CD652B4101"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Complying with the requirements of such section 836.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H760A7DF8B51E453EA894A5A5CF959763"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Establishing clear connections between Department of Homeland Security objectives and acquisition (as such term is defined in such section) priorities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H342328F837E44FE0A9E98B9024ED0701"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Demonstrating that Department acquisition policy reflects program management best practices (as such term is defined in such section) and standards.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H963332BB90144374A5649FB4A62695F1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Ensuring competition or the option of competition for major acquisition programs (as such term is defined in such section).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H06797466919C4CF18C09C9B85974BA89"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Considering potential cost savings through using already-existing technologies when developing acquisition program requirements.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2BBF47D5017D4577BC411EAD043827CB"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Preventing duplication within Department acquisition workforce training requirements through leveraging already-existing training within the Federal Government, academic community, or private industry.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H830064F5EFD7486481B8604C638C0F3F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Providing incentives for acquisition program managers to reduce acquisition and procurement costs through the use of best practices and disciplined program management.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDD4A8F15C29349BAB83DCF2D6FEF0A11"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate a report on the review conducted under this section. Such report shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
	<attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20170320">Passed the House of Representatives March 20, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill>


