<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H8EF69EE0F3014E71BE4F38B901EA52BB" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2132 : Traveler Redress Improvement Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2132</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date date="20170621">June 21, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To require the implementation of a redress process and review of the Transportation Security
			 Administration’s intelligence-based screening rules for aviation security,
			 and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H0D2DF5D89CE44AFE836C1DFB86218D36" style="OLC">
 <section id="H88A38C40035B4E8DA277363AB1DD79F5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Traveler Redress Improvement Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H9ED6EEA634FB4E44BF74F984FBBC0BD4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Implementation of redress process and review of the Transportation Security Administration’s intelligence-based screening rules for aviation security</header> <subsection id="H2D78FF642F26462E90106A9D13A0816B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Redress process</header> <paragraph id="H802510CE63C640E886BFD5ABA2098FEC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall, using existing resources, systems, and processes, ensure the availability of the Department of Homeland Security Traveler Redress Inquiry Program (DHS TRIP) redress process to adjudicate inquiries for individuals who—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEB28A15D2DE34CB1AD1CBC0CAE3F393C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are citizens of the United States or aliens lawfully admitted for permanent residence;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64E49F8A5F084FA68F294E9EA71D3913"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have filed an inquiry with DHS TRIP after receiving enhanced screening at an airport passenger security checkpoint more than 3 times in any 60-day period; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE46FEFE5229743699B444919261A1854"><enum>(C)</enum><text>believe they have been wrongly identified as being a threat to aviation security.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H271443D78FB649E49AB5FB2FF7242D37"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report on the implementation of the redress process required under paragraph (1).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5D71220ADB934BD4AEFFB1CEA4CBE543"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Privacy impact review and update</header>
 <paragraph id="H8ED1D04C01D240EDA6A33E4FC1BF9BBC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall review and update the Privacy Impact Assessment for the Secure Flight programs to ensure such Assessment accurately reflects the operation of such programs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB45E3A53BF1A4AE593803FD1A6D15F5B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public dissemination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secure Flight Privacy Impact Assessment review required under paragraph (1) shall be published on a publically accessible Internet webpage of the Transportation Security Administration and submitted to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H08C0B441A6544BCA9CE9DB9A9E85A854"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transportation Security Administration rule review and notification process</header>
 <paragraph id="H95C260E0FE554562A905F13AAB90D711"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rule review</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and every 120 days thereafter, the Assistant Administrator of the Office of Intelligence Analysis of the Transportation Security Administration, in coordination with the entities specified in paragraph (2), shall conduct a comprehensive review of the Transportation Security Administration’s intelligence-based screening rules.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7B951388879F4E63A07D1E6642D1CE7D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 48 hours after changing, updating, implementing, or suspending a Transportation Security Administration intelligence-based screening rule, the Assistant Administrator of the Office of Intelligence Analysis of the Transportation Security Administration shall notify the following entities of any such change, update, implementation, or suspension, as the case may be:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H12DBF5CE949A49EBBE5BD769895B9191"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Office of Civil Rights and Liberties of the Transportation Security Administration.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H384ED223979743849889785957A51129"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Office of the Ombudsman of the Administration.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF6B593454D14F61B120889EBB1823EB"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Office of Traveler Engagement of the Administration.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H354F36D554D24D7B90FC2E961BE18082"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Office of Civil Rights and Liberties of the Department of Homeland Security.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9331CA044A44C44BF7DAB4FC7302977"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Office of Chief Counsel of the Administration.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3CF6347B871249DDA92651CF435BF4A0"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The Office of General Counsel of the Department.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H26BBACDBD57044E88EDCAB4D4EAC379D"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The Privacy Office of the Administration.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F8CFD4108334F769DD8C7F409BD9A3A"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The Privacy Office of the Department.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF50F900572214EE38E1E8B2529A7BD32"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The Federal Air Marshal Service.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B904E987EB74DB9A7C78E3A65AC0794"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Traveler Redress Inquiry Program of the Department.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3C1B3C4C8D2541958C087664B6470AEE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Federal Air Marshal Service coordination</header>
 <paragraph id="HBD39E61836CF412CBF31DD02020EA996"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall ensure that the Transportation Security Administration’s intelligence-based screening rules are incorporated in the risk analysis conducted during the Federal Air Marshal mission scheduling process.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBB8FEE449E17419EBD13E8DDC9F685B8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report on how the Transportation Security Administration’s intelligence-based screening rules are incorporated in the risk analysis conducted during the Federal Air Marshal mission scheduling process.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H170E39ADB11147F19EF45F319901D7B6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>GAO report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a study on the Transportation Security Administration’s intelligence-based screening rules and the effectiveness of such rules in identifying and mitigating potential threats to aviation security. Such study shall also examine coordination between the Transportation Security Administration, the Department of Homeland Security,<pagebreak></pagebreak> and other relevant partners relating to changing, updating, implementing, or suspending such rules as necessary.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
	<attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20170620">Passed the House of Representatives June 20, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill>


