<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HBEAF659D5E7F481C84AC857A592788A0" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3728 IH: Educating Medical Professionals and Optimizing Workforce Efficiency and Readiness Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3728</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170911">September 11, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001275">Mr. Bucshon</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title VII of the Public Health Service Act to reauthorize certain programs relating to the
			 health professions workforce, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H35E86C5081F84396BEE89585CE9ED5B1" style="OLC">
 <section id="HA096BA7209444892BECC6D16C9736956" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Educating Medical Professionals and Optimizing Workforce Efficiency and Readiness Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>EMPOWER Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HF46FE47BB0E348E489B3639D403AA639"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reauthorization of health professions workforce programs</header> <subsection id="H6B454E0CA39C43A38C60E3B3DD141BB0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Centers of excellence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (i) of section 736 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/293">42 U.S.C. 293</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAE93BD47827E435AB62E330C342B96F3" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H49A0B618AA7A420884F93B9EF6740CBD"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $21,711,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H220E07E46EAD4EC0904FA01E95DAC8A2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Health professions training for diversity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 740 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/293d">42 U.S.C. 293d</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H061B97BB6D684F9989368A687007D7E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>$51,000,000 for fiscal year 2010, and such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2011 through 2014</quote> and inserting <quote>$45,970,000 for each of the fiscal years 2018 through 2022</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA206099F80F845B4951D3C28859D2524"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking <quote>$5,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2010 through 2014</quote> and inserting <quote>$1,190,000 for each of the fiscal years 2018 through 2022</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD5B756DAB44648FCA308D235D01DBEA7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by striking <quote>$60,000,000 for fiscal year 2010 and such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2011 through 2014</quote> and inserting <quote>$14,189,000 for each of the fiscal years 2018 through 2022</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF063A8AA27B94C1A9E2F2DC28EBA82B7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Primary care training and enhancement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 747(c)(1) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/293k">42 U.S.C. 293k(c)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>$125,000,000 for fiscal year 2010, and such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2011 through 2014</quote> and inserting <quote>$38,924,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H87E32B9339794BF4B5065F21DC5FE312"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Training in general, pediatric, and public health dentistry</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 748(f) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/293k-2">42 U.S.C. 293k–2(f)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>$30,000,000 for fiscal year 2010 and such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2011 through 2015</quote> and inserting <quote>$36,673,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC9372D47AF0A41A7BF79D15FC03D1C48"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Area health education centers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 751(j)(1) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/294a">42 U.S.C. 294a(j)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>$125,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2010 through 2014</quote> and inserting <quote>$30,250,000 for each of the fiscal years 2018 through 2022</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H935FB64AE7564F66A4503612F2EB1A69"><enum>(f)</enum><header>National Center for Healthcare Workforce Analysis</header> <paragraph id="HE67399922BFB4FE0B6B121AD6D771A04"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 761(e)(1)(A) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/294n">42 U.S.C. 294n(e)(1)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>$7,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2010 through 2014</quote> and inserting <quote>$4,663,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7E49A54FD402433485F09F6D22DA6BAB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical correction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 761(e)(2) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/294n">42 U.S.C. 294n(e)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>subsection (a)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (1)</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3E839D7B22A544C3904D4D77417AF16A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Public health workforce</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 770(a) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/295e">42 U.S.C. 295e(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>$43,000,000 for fiscal year 2011, and such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2012 through 2015</quote> and inserting <quote>$21,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2018 through 2022</quote>.</text>
 </subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H03C733E137CE48A993B022BBC2349D48"><enum>3.</enum><header>Education and training relating to geriatrics</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 753 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/294c">42 U.S.C. 294c</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA2F9DC1D3303475DAD25288AFDF7D0F0" style="OLC"> <section id="HC398730136FF419AB9B47815D3249BF9"><enum>753.</enum><header>Education and training relating to geriatrics</header> <subsection commented="no" id="H160053FCECCB461786C63DFF21246817"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Geriatrics workforce enhancement program</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="HB796FD51E85C4CCC9CD94CE10FD97B64"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall award grants under this subsection to entities described in paragraph (1), (3), or (4) of section 799B, section 801(2), or section 865(d), or other health professions schools or programs approved by the Secretary, for the establishment or operation of geriatric workforce enhancement programs that meet the requirements of paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HFF2075034864408C963392A365603169"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>A geriatrics workforce enhancement program meets the requirements of this paragraph if such program supports the development of a health care workforce that maximizes patient and family engagement and improves health outcomes for older adults by integrating geriatrics with primary care and other appropriate specialties. Special emphasis should be placed on providing the primary care workforce with the knowledge and skills to care for older adults and collaborating with community partners to address gaps in health care for older adults through individual, system, community, and population level changes. Areas of programmatic focus may include the following:</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H2FF74FD54A0D4B61AB6A4E438F2D79B1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Transforming clinical training environments to integrated geriatrics and primary care delivery systems to ensure trainees are well prepared to practice in and lead in such systems.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3BD7428962A7442BAB3E4F3A374AE673"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Developing providers who can assess and address the needs and preferences of older adults and their families and caregivers at the individual, community, and population levels.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA5B7C01106644C5690ABDEC8496DD373"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Creating and delivering community-based programs that will provide older adults and their families and caregivers with the knowledge and skills to improve health outcomes and the quality of care for such adults.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H69AC7E94D430465E89799372193690D4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Providing Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias (ADRD) education to the families and caregivers of older adults, direct care workers, health professions students, faculty, and providers.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H84F193C0468C41E6B76B4210466CFD0E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The Secretary shall award grants under paragraph (1) for a period not to exceed five years.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H47CC58E2292F43B580609A8B01A517FC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under paragraph (1), an entity described in such paragraph shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD36C1F85201249D6B23CA2C5ED978EC3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Equitable geographic distribution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may award grants under paragraph (1) in a manner which will equitably distribute such grants among the various regions of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD478268AFB0144E99EBD7EE8F3E205ED"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under paragraph (1), the Secretary may give priority to programs that—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HEFBA38009C5040C0A3353EF074187ABC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have the goal of improving and providing comprehensive coordinated care of older adults, including medical, dental, and psychosocial needs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4DF8754DBDFC413C94EE2D64A4BCEC3F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support the training and retraining of faculty, preceptors, primary care providers, and providers in other specialties to increase their knowledge of geriatrics and gerontology;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H27169178D96A471D97EBBD48E191BC41"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide clinical experiences across care settings, including ambulatory care, hospitals, post-acute care, nursing homes, federally qualified health centers, and home and community-based services;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA41877BB5F75412BAC9057A234B08191"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">emphasize education and engagement of family caregivers on disease self-management, medication management, and stress reduction strategies;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HCB16866F46DB488B9AAEFA153CF5E0FD"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide training to the health care workforce on disease self-management, motivational interviewing, medication management, and stress reduction strategies;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1B1EE9E2508D40E28A1E3C5317D0546B"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide training to the health care workforce on social determinants of health in order to better address the geriatric health care needs of diverse populations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA7755D60F3F84636B1A6CFF9BE041549"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">integrate geriatrics competencies and interprofessional collaborative practice into health care education and training curricula for residents, fellows, and students;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2FAE42F6FE0949D3994DECBE395B1D37"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">substantially benefit rural or underserved populations of older adults;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HDF6768A653814C159AAA67725DD431A1"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">integrate behavioral health competencies into primary care practice, especially with respect to elder abuse, pain management, and advance care planning; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H95D5438804894F5CB37215E592B259DC"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">offer short-term intensive courses that—</text> <clause id="HE6DBA2120BAE4EFFAD3AB78BA4F1CAF7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>focus on geriatrics, gerontology, chronic care management, and long-term care that provide supplemental training for faculty members in medical schools and other health professions schools or graduate programs in psychology, pharmacy, nursing, social work, dentistry, public health, allied health, or other health disciplines, as approved by the Secretary; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3EE0CEE84065481E917BCBE577E663DF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are open to current faculty, and appropriately credentialed volunteer faculty and practitioners, to upgrade their knowledge and clinical skills for the care of older adults and adults with functional and cognitive limitations and to enhance their interdisciplinary teaching skills.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE9B866A2A7604E7F849B0DE95BA0BD93"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Geriatric Academic Career Awards</header>
 <paragraph id="H37FFE938054F47AE922B9781473C74C8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment of program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a program to provide Geriatric Academic Career Awards to eligible entities applying on behalf of eligible individuals to promote the career development of such individuals as academic geriatricians or other academic geriatrics health professionals.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H04DF1A19753E4329917510BE0A47209C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligibility</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HEC2D4150958249818D05C2E2708194D0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H93E5748933BF4375A791A0AEA2168BEE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an entity described in paragraph (1), (3), or (4) of section 295p or section 296(2); or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HECA3849EF4B94922BD4033159AEB1C4A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an accredited health professions school or graduate program approved by the Secretary.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3E51349CD73C4B16AE5A6AFD82490EE1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligible individual</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>eligible individual</term> means an individual who—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H42614B71C8A84801ABB5FFF1A88EA074"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is board certified or board eligible in internal medicine, family practice, psychiatry, or licensed dentistry, or has completed any required training in a discipline and is employed in an accredited health professions school or graduate program that is approved by the Secretary; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HCF2459F417844EF6990F56B58479D990"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has completed an approved fellowship program in geriatrics or gerontology, or has completed specialty training in geriatrics or gerontology as required by the discipline and any additional geriatrics or gerontology training as required by the Secretary; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HCD03DA3E8C5F4749A9DA57FF8324366C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>has a junior (non-tenured) faculty appointment at an accredited school of allopathic medicine, osteopathic medicine, nursing, social work, psychology, dentistry, pharmacy, or other allied health disciplines in an accredited health professions school or graduate program that is approved by the Secretary.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H96798F23E0EF496FA1DE3F83799B6758"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity may not receive an award under paragraph (1) on behalf of an eligible individual unless the eligible entity—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H336E8DB95D8D43359453FA81B5BDE014"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submits to the Secretary an application, at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, and the Secretary approves such application;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB1668D2A8CD14E65AD598FEC28AC3CC6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides, in such form and manner as the Secretary may require, assurances that the eligible individual on whose behalf an application was submitted under subparagraph (A) will meet the service requirement described in paragraph (7); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C93D42AD5144999854C44EF52F89795"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provides, in such form and manner as the Secretary may require, assurances that such individual has a full-time faculty appointment in an accredited health professions school or graduate program and documented commitment from such school or program to spend 50 percent of the total time of such individual on teaching and developing skills in interdisciplinary education in geriatrics.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H591B6FD4CFB442429F7A309A98F2A085"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H5E11D60DA7A34205924561DFDEFAB361"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall give priority to eligible entities that apply on behalf of eligible individuals who are on the faculty of institutions that integrate geriatrics education, training, and best practices into academic program criteria;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HFEF3DCE1AAAB45EC90960CCBB269C32C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may give priority to eligible entities that operate a geriatrics workforce enhancement program under subsection (a);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4710FAD5A0764D1B9F973B39B58B4184"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall ensure that grants are equitably distributed among rural or underserved populations of older adults across the various geographical regions of the United States;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7B154FF18D264DE08A27819CB5E8FE5C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>shall pay particular attention to geriatrics healthcare workforce needs among underserved populations and rural areas;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF35A323F9E404DCFB77AA5F548E65560"><enum>(E)</enum><text>may not require an eligible individual, or an eligible entity applying on behalf of an eligible individual, to be a recipient of a grant or contract under section 753(a) or 750 of title VII of the Public Health Service Act; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H225892561CCE44D6B922FA4FE907D332"><enum>(F)</enum><text>shall award a maximum of 120 grants during any three-year period.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB49D8E0C7F4249EA9EFC05A8F1AEED4C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Maintenance of effort</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity receiving an award under paragraph (1) on behalf of an eligible individual shall provide assurances to the Secretary that funds provided to such individual under this subsection will be used only to supplement, not to supplant, the amount of Federal, State, and local funds otherwise expended by such individual.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H88716E26BFE348A88ADC64EE9463C15C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Amount and term</header>
 <subparagraph id="H994DB5BC3F834429BBBA4295F11F1B47"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of an award under this subsection for eligible individuals who are physicians shall equal $50,000 for fiscal year 1998, adjusted for subsequent fiscal years to reflect the increase in the Consumer Price Index. The Secretary shall determine the amount of an award under this subsection for individuals who are not physicians.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H147466A573AD41789F1FCC45EA3E2C37"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Term</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term of any award made under this subsection shall not exceed 3 years.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA19CE6A13F304A4294A2B8034FCC691A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Payment to institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall make payments to institutions which include schools of medicine, osteopathic medicine, nursing, social work, psychology, dentistry, and pharmacy, or other allied health discipline in an accredited health professions school or graduate program that is approved by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H913D0F9A58EC42EA9CD40AD908A43BBB"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Service requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible individual on whose behalf an application was submitted and approved under paragraph (3)(A) shall provide training in clinical geriatrics or gerontology, including the training of interdisciplinary teams of health care professionals.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF51FB1AF83FC4064A89B5324FEA28A06"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection $38,737,000 for the period of fiscal years 2018 through 2022.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


