<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H83FF8EB4B9074B30BFCAC0C9BF2D017C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3422 IH: Interstate Teaching Mobility Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3422</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170726">July 26, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson of Indiana</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to authorize an interstate teaching application program.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3F845CF324B145408834CA7AC11974DB" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HBF8E1D97018941B09A48135C524C00F6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Interstate Teaching Mobility Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H41C0C2DA966F46C6ADF5212BE26A9DED"><enum>2.</enum><header>Program for interstate teaching applications</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title II of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6601">20 U.S.C. 6601</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5D484CED09B84EBDA3451E1F384FA4D1" style="OLC"> 
<part id="HE59A4B891DDA40FAA06D0FEB9C11F83D"><enum>D</enum><header>Interstate Teaching Applications</header> 
<section id="H88FB9FFB86AF4CA29636A287374AFB0C"><enum>2401.</enum><header>Program for interstate teaching applications</header> 
<subsection id="HDE924262DD8F472BAC878F81781A37C8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with an eligible entity, may establish and carry out a program to allow States to voluntarily participate in an interstate teaching application process that allows teachers who are licensed or certified in any participating State—</text> <paragraph id="H9A97927C6DDC4C40B581DDAB6050DF8D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to be eligible for licensure or certification in other participating States without subsequently completing additional licensure or certification requirements; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD9F6C47CA8904D0386CE318BAAE32DE8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to be able to apply for open teaching positions in schools that receive funds under part A of title I in other participating States, unless the open position falls outside the applicant's content area or grade level for which the applicant is already licensed or certified.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC4BB6FF6DC264EB6BCF3E1056290040F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program requirements</header><text>In carrying out a program established under subsection (a), the Secretary, in consultation with an eligible entity, shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H29B03791811840EA9D7CC8CCF4D46E5E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>create an application for eligible teachers licensed or certified in a State participating in the program who wish to teach in other States participating in the program;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6EC5EEDCD1F94D55A87E556D44644D3C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>require each participating State to recognize a teaching licensure or certification of each such teacher who meets the application requirements under subsection (c)(1), and allow such teacher to teach in an open teaching position described in subsection (a)(2), without requiring such teacher to complete additional requirements for licensure or certification;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB9060D350CCA40A7A6DF48605D617934"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure that participating States maintain the eligibility requirements described in subsection (d);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7D806BCA8E974EB5AFA21FB65A19D329"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide technical assistance to participating States; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFDA102DD0C7F462195102BBDB0C059C2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>provide an electronic application process for teachers to apply for the program.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H98FD84636BB44B39B14D1A31873F7171"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Participating teachers</header> <paragraph id="HF82E7E1F3B394DDEA3211D1C91F46441"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each teacher seeking to participate in a program established under subsection (a) shall submit an application containing—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB9979EE5DB50463BB7B22907B97AB009"><enum>(A)</enum><text>proof of an active teaching license or certification in a participating State;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H130E6E8A881843E295197081944EBA11"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the teacher's results on each of the assessments described in subparagraphs (A) through (C) of subsection (d)(1) that are required by the initial licensing or certifying participating State; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2C63FA63E2294F89A1058DAE71B77958"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5C0FEAE21CC74F939B379E61F1A3C21E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contract</header><text>The eligible entity referred to in subsections (a) and (b) shall collect and assist the Secretary in reviewing the teacher applications submitted under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H996D7030239840EAB35BC6BD1FD4633F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Participating States</header><text>A State shall be eligible to participate in a program established under subsection (a) if—</text> <paragraph id="HA728AB349B1F49FB9BF095FF7540C9F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>such State, in awarding a teaching license or certification to an individual, requires—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1A090FEB69E74A04B758ADE0689207B8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an assessment of the content knowledge necessary for postsecondary education and a career before a teacher begins teaching in a classroom;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6C46A48C84274009AF5637176077F639"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an assessment of pedagogical skills not later than 1 year after the date on which a teacher first begins teaching in a classroom; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H61540B2DF8844D128FD032472CFCC449"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a performance assessment not later than one year after the date on which a teacher first begins teaching, which may include a performance assessment completed as part of a teacher preparation program; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HAB251FE3122743908C177ACAEBE8FF6E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the assessments described in paragraph (1) and required by such State are identified as sufficiently rigorous by an organization such as the Council of Chief State School Officers.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8ED7383429C749FE90C4B2B6C912B2AD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary may issue such regulations as the Secretary considers necessary to carry out this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3B9F392E3CEA44EDB4E678410B05398F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>eligible entity</term> means an organization or other entity that provides support to States and teachers in teacher certification and licensure, approved by the Secretary.</text></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="HEAF0D5E1B32E4637A5900C3166076FB2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents for the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 2302 the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9E612A35E53641FBB011C8CFB147B6A7" style="OLC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="part">Part D—Interstate Teaching Applications</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2401. Program for interstate teaching applications.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

