<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H440CF7F5379F4497940287C1BADDAA16" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4591 IH: Preventing Iranian Destabilization of Iraq Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4591</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171207">December 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000378">Mr. Kinzinger</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000600">Mr. Diaz-Balart</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000181">Mr. Nunes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Z000017">Mr. Zeldin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000168">Mr. Olson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001048">Mr. Hunter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000579">Mr. Gallagher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000604">Mr. Russell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To impose sanctions with respect to Iranian persons that threaten the peace or stability of Iraq or
			 the Government of Iraq.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H7AE621B8AA3449AB94D1BC1C233905CD" style="OLC">
 <section id="H808CC6E344F048DC949F512C51F2519D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preventing Iranian Destabilization of Iraq Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H6626372BDC094B15950E08E1712D3A56"><enum>2.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It shall be the policy of the United States to impose sanctions with respect to terrorist organizations and foreign countries, including the Government of Iran, that threaten the peace or stability and impede the democratic processes of Iraq or the Government of Iraq.</text>
		</section><section id="H67004EF352504C31AE0B4437EF0872A9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions with respect to Iranian persons threatening peace or stability in Iraq</header>
 <subsection id="H9A124E3924AC4B0AB9CD9CCE8408CBE8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of State should continue to implement Executive Order 13438 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note; relating to blocking property of certain persons who threaten stabilization efforts in Iraq).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H56C90DF549644F179776F35A1A608A65"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions</header><text>The President shall impose the sanctions described in subsection (c)(1)(A) and the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of one of such Secretaries) shall impose the sanctions described in subsection (c)(1)(B) with respect to any Iranian person that the President, acting through the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of one of such Secretaries), as the case may be, determines—</text>
 <paragraph id="H3053077EE4E74F13AC906A5671179AEB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to have knowingly committed, or to pose a significant risk of committing, an act or acts of violence that have the purpose or effect of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB4139D9AAE664DFBB311B3DABC9CB3C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>threatening the peace or stability of Iraq or the Government of Iraq;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H52AC856A7A75430BA7E165B2DC810BA3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>undermining or attempting to undermine, co-opt, or confound the democratic process in Iraq; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE12593E219064DFAAF72C4B8F228F2D0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>undermining efforts to promote economic reconstruction and political reform in Iraq or to provide humanitarian assistance to the Iraqi people;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5961F5B523DE478697A752EFE37F4A96"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has knowingly materially assisted, sponsored, or provided financial, material, or technological support for, or goods or services to or in support of, any activity described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of paragraph (1); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5CE12CFC8F374CCAB7DA7EB1C572266F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is owned or controlled by, or has acted or purported to act for or on behalf of, directly or indirectly, a foreign person that has carried out any activity described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of paragraph (1) or paragraph (2).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HADDC3FD96A1B4168B5995D6E472F4B61"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header>
 <paragraph id="HC584CDC106324CA4882F80A3357602B6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The sanctions described in this subsection are the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HAFDD17DA756D439C8598F13719BFCAFE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Asset blocking</header><text>The exercise of all powers granted to the President by the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of an entity determined by the President to be subject to subsection (b) if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD20964F7AF3F4339AA2E5F7D1EE2E18A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Aliens ineligible for visas, admission, or parole</header>
 <clause id="HFC5ED2D7225743C7B1A8EC0ACD16A900"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Visas, admission, or parole</header><text>An alien who the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of one of such Secretaries) knows or has reasonable grounds to believe meets any of the criteria described in subsection (b) is—</text>
 <subclause id="H94E00B9F812846D0A5A8854584CC9E2A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H803641860F164657B5D6EE5EFDFF0B4C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HCCC42E6823AE4E34AA3A376396E6AB08"><enum>(III)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
							</subclause></clause><clause id="HA4CFF0FD8AC24864B89EF5A4DB7E7475"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header>
 <subclause id="H4150A1A599E54B929C773CDDFD8BB1F8"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any visa or other documentation issued to an alien who is an Iranian person on the list required under subsection (b), regardless of when such visa or other documentation was issued, shall be revoked and such alien shall be denied admission to the United States.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HBEA6B2392CCF4C6BA0E50AEF293D9739"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Effect of revocation</header><text>A revocation under subclause (I) shall take effect immediately and shall automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the alien’s possession.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1835924F62BA4EDD9EA288CA148F628F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inapplicability of national emergency requirement</header><text>The requirements of section 202 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref>) shall not apply for purposes of the imposition of sanctions under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB917EC21337147E7A5F7462EA04A5374"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>A person that is subject to sanctions described in paragraph (1)(A) shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of that section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H74823EE6692841E89E4393B6456A6CEE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exception to comply with united nations headquarters agreement</header><text>Sanctions under paragraph (1)(B) shall not apply to an alien if admitting the alien into the United States is necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States, or other applicable international obligations.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC2C55F0ED505407A82778C53505C66E3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The President may, on a case-by-case basis and for periods not to exceed 90 days, waive the application of sanctions in this section with respect to an Iranian person if the President certifies to the appropriate congressional committees at least 15 days before such waiver is to take effect that such waiver is vital to the national security interests of the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H38238767EA934411868A3FB029407D56"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Implementation authority</header><text>The President may exercise all authorities provided to the President under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1702">50 U.S.C. 1702</external-xref> and 1704) for purposes of carrying out this section.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H644FBFDFD35A4E0CA2ADBEE647A8AB28"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Regulatory authority</header>
 <paragraph id="H19C749CDCFEB4CA3842597F635B3548F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall, not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, promulgate regulations as necessary for the implementation of this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H1637B246BCE741BCA0411C5508FC1079"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification to congress</header><text>Not less than 10 days before the promulgation of regulations under paragraph (1), the President shall notify and provide to the appropriate congressional committees the proposed regulations and the provisions of this section that the regulations are implementing.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEF054D02C9804E7EB3FDF74BE823E446"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="H0D4458AC3F6F406DBF6D3962C40828AF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H34613A2172494F3D9FA0E7714C14D842"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on the Judiciary, the Committee on Ways and Means, and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H419ACB3558924F3A8708AE99AF5EB265"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7FF08D45281474EAFF79BC29421DF40"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Iranian person</header><text>The term <quote>Iranian person</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H25048142B110487C95815E841EBF791A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual who is a citizen or national of Iran; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19E66EC7CBA9446FAC1BA09A5142A1C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of Iran or otherwise subject to the jurisdiction of the Government of Iran.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD8278C09F8B9482C831F38CB6AD84DBB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>United states person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> has the meaning given that term in section 576.317 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on June 22, 2016.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF68DC22A8A7E4B05BD05DE9EAA6E7969"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Admitted; alien</header><text>The terms <term>admitted</term> and <term>alien</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 101(3) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(3)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD3DFFEE4B8BF42009B0F9A2DF9D3E3BE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Knowingly</header><text>The term <term>knowingly</term>, with respect to conduct, a circumstance, or a result, means that a person has actual knowledge, or should have known, of the conduct, the circumstance, or the result.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H1F9BA3C0CC6D47658CEF4BA438EB8F99"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Government of iraq</header><text>The term <term>Government of Iraq</term> has the meaning given that term in section 576.310 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on June 22, 2016.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3D5C2196B4EC4FE780C2DEEAAC635935"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Person</header><text>The term <term>person</term> has the meaning given that term in section 576.311 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on June 22, 2016.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4F25331D4D5949F5A8E3DB2F7BA4131B"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Property; property interest</header><text>The terms <term>property</term> and <term>property interest</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 576.312 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on June 22, 2016.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H4C772FB8974140E69C97A248E5975A35"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>This section shall cease to be effective beginning on January 1, 2022.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H3BA6A6BAC609468A8546723A4B435F41"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report on activities of the Government of Iran in Iraq</header> <subsection id="H1053078B9DE44C8EA69E55050283D2B4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter for a period not to exceed 5 years, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on activities of the Government of Iran in Iraq.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H506D95CACA45420694DC2D105DEDF37D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters To be included</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include a description of the following:</text> <paragraph id="HC919F344139D4199B7EE9A4B012B2FA5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Government of Iran’s support for Iraqi militias or political parties, including weapons, financing, and other forms of material support.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H14906CAA022B49FCAF50B55F03FFCD34"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A list of referrals to the relevant United Nations Security Council sanctions committees by the United States Permanent Representative to the United Nations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCC917A956A0841C4BA33865A471DD9C0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Iranian persons that are in Iraq despite the asset freeze and visa ban sanctions imposed against such entities pursuant to United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA46D39373B3A430880A5491643AF42D9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Iraqi persons that have aided, abetted, or facilitated the Government of Iran’s transport of personnel, money, and munitions into Syria to aid the regime of Bashar al-Assad.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H95ED5EFA0F66484B9378A1ADEBE9096B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Iraqi financial institutions that are providing credit, loans, or other assistance to Government of Iran-backed irregular or militia forces responsible for engaging in activities described in section 3(b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB0C51AC37AE34CCB99AFE5647225E63C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Actions taken by the Government of Iran to influence Shia institutions in Najaf, Iraq.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H58DE3AC497464AD0B0C470CD78B586EF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in classified form if it is determined that it is necessary for the national security interests of the United States to do so.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA3BAD333CC4C43879915F72378FBFC32"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="H8363E289FD1F4B779F47E3710E2ABDF7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Ways and Means, and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAAEA33F144B74E4BB618795E17D07F65"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Finance, and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


