<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE amendment-doc PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/amend.dtd//EN" "amend.dtd">
<amendment-doc amend-stage="proposed" amend-type="engrossed-amendment" amend-degree="first" key="H"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2266 EAH: Additional Supplemental Appropriations for Disaster Relief Requirements Act, 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<engrossed-amendment-form>
<distribution-code display="no"><?xm-replace_text {distribution code}?></distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<current-chamber display="yes">In the House of Representatives, U. S.,</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20171012">October 12, 2017</action-date> 
</action> 
<legis-type display="yes">HOUSE AMENDMENT TO SENATE AMENDMENT:</legis-type></engrossed-amendment-form> 
<engrossed-amendment-body> 
<section section-type="resolved" id="H483024832"> <text>That the House agree to the amendment of the Senate to the bill (H.R. 2266) entitled <quote>An Act to amend title 28 of the United States Code to authorize the appointment of additional bankruptcy judges; and for other purposes.</quote>, with the following </text></section><amendment> <amendment-instruction line-numbers="off"><text>In lieu of the matter proposed to be inserted by the Senate amendment, insert the following: </text></amendment-instruction> 
<amendment-block style="OLC" id="HBC7B9366B5F8482FB36DF61DBC0DE189" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic"> 
<section id="HDC6D976D39F646CBB9E984ABEA8079B6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Additional Supplemental Appropriations for Disaster Relief Requirements Act, 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <division id="H0117E6C63AD24C9D842DED5D99233D8A" level-type="subsequent" style="appropriations"><enum>A</enum><header>Additional Supplemental Appropriations for Disaster Relief Requirements Act of 2017</header> <section id="HC4CB207AFFBF4033AD30844F4E7E6429"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following sums are hereby appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, and out of applicable corporate or other revenues, receipts, and funds, for the several departments, agencies, corporations, and other organizational units of Government for fiscal year 2018, and for other purposes, namely:</text></section> 
<title id="HB53039EE1DFA49B9A22886D19DCCC791" style="appropriations"><enum>I</enum><appropriations-major id="HD931FC33953045709E4510FB35137A12"><header>Department of Homeland Security</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="H29D81C73E44540CDB84D82FC18699138"><header>Federal Emergency Management Agency</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H44A1A854EE4948F69011673973B37975"><header>disaster relief fund</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H0992CC9BA0224BB198A5FB798FD44AD5"><header>(including transfers of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Disaster Relief Fund</quote> for major disasters declared pursuant to the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121</external-xref> et seq.), $18,670,000,000, to remain available until expended, of which $10,000,000 shall be transferred to the Department of Homeland Security Office of Inspector General for audits and investigations related to disasters: <italic>Provided</italic>, That the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall publish on the Agency’s website not later than 5 days after an award of a public assistance grant under section 406 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5172">42 U.S.C. 5172</external-xref>) that is in excess of $1,000,000, the specifics of each such grant award: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That for any mission assignment or mission assignment task order to another Federal department or agency regarding a major disaster in excess of $1,000,000, not later than 5 days after the issuance of such mission assignment or mission assignment task order, the Administrator shall publish on the Agency’s website the following: the name of the impacted State, the disaster declaration for such State, the assigned agency, the assistance requested, a description of the disaster, the total cost estimate, and the amount obligated: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That not later than 10 days after the last day of each month until a mission assignment or mission assignment task order described in the preceding proviso is completed and closed out, the Administrator shall update any changes to the total cost estimate and the amount obligated: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That for a disaster declaration related to Hurricane Harvey, Hurricane Irma, or Hurricane Maria, the Administrator shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, not later than 5 days after the first day of each month beginning after the date of enactment of this Act, and shall publish on the Agency’s website, not later than 10 days after the first day of each such month, an estimate or actual amount, if available, for the current fiscal year of the cost of the following categories of spending: public assistance, individual assistance, operations, mitigation, administrative, and any other relevant category (including emergency measures and disaster resources): <italic>Provided further</italic>, That not later than 10 days after the first day of each month, the Administrator shall publish on the Agency’s website the report (referred to as the Disaster Relief Monthly Report) as required by <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/4">Public Law 114–4</external-xref>.</text><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> Of the amounts provided in this division for the Disaster Relief Fund, up to $4,900,000,000 may be transferred to the Disaster Assistance Direct Loan Program Account for the cost of direct loans as authorized under section 417 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5184">42 U.S.C. 5184</external-xref>) to be used to assist local governments in providing essential services as a result of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, or Maria: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such amounts may subsidize gross obligations for the principal amount of direct loans not to exceed $4,900,000,000 under section 417 of the Stafford Act: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That notwithstanding section 417 of the Stafford Act, a territory or possession, and instrumentalities and local governments thereof, of the United States shall be deemed to be a local government for purposes of this paragraph: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That notwithstanding section 417(b) of the Stafford Act, the amount of any such loan issued to a territory or possession, and instrumentalities and local governments thereof, may be based on the projected loss of tax and other revenues and on projected cash outlays not previously budgeted for a period not to exceed 180 days from the date of the major disaster, and may exceed $5,000,000: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That notwithstanding any other provision of law or the constitution of a territory or possession that limits the issuance of debt, a territory or possession, and instrumentalities and local governments thereof, may each receive more than one loan with repayment provisions and other terms specific to the type of lost tax and other revenues and on projected unbudgeted cash outlays for which the loan is provided: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That notwithstanding section 417(c)(1) of the Stafford Act, loans to a territory or possession, and instrumentalities and local governments thereof, may be cancelled in whole or in part only at the discretion of the Secretary of Homeland Security in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall determine the terms, conditions, eligible uses, and timing and amount of Federal disbursements of loans issued to a territory or possession, and instrumentalities and local governments thereof: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such costs, including the cost of modifying such loans, shall be as defined in section 502 of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/661a">2 U.S.C. 661a</external-xref>): <italic>Provided further</italic>, That FEMA may transfer up to 1.5 percent of the amount under this paragraph to the Disaster Assistance Direct Loan Program Account for administrative expenses to carry out under this paragraph the direct loan program, as authorized by section 417 of the Stafford Act: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That of the amount provided under this paragraph for transfer, up to $150,000,000 may be transferred to the Disaster Assistance Direct Loan Program Account for the cost to lend a territory or possession of the United States that portion of assistance for which the territory or possession is responsible under the cost-sharing provisions of the major disaster declaration for Hurricanes Irma or Maria, as authorized under section 319 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5162">42 U.S.C. 5162</external-xref>): <italic>Provided further</italic>, That of the amount provided under this paragraph for transfer, up to $1,000,000 may be transferred to the Disaster Assistance Direct Loan Program Account for administrative expenses to carry out the Advance of Non-Federal Share program, as authorized by section 319 of the Stafford Act.</text><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amount provided under this heading is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small></title> <title id="H166B8019054641CBB8DC791C498240DF" style="appropriations"><enum>II</enum> <appropriations-major id="H4F5F567791D84BB5BA2FB61BD7E54B75"><header>Department of Agriculture</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="H1D65D9047B524997828BBF64AA564C27"><header>Forest Service</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H7BCAF5DC1E804A7680208E5BD13866C5"><header>Wildland Fire Management</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HD1B48636DA6449708D95384B2D033BDD"><header>(Including transfer of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Wildland Fire Management</quote>, $184,500,000, to remain available through September 30, 2021, for urgent wildland fire suppression operations: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such funds shall be solely available to be transferred to and merged with other appropriations accounts from which funds were previously transferred for wildland fire suppression in fiscal year 2017 to fully repay those amounts: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H8B5BC2B2507440BE9E03076685C7BCB6"><header>FLAME wildfire suppression reserve fund</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H954D1428A39C45DB854CA97D42649BDE"><header>(Including transfer of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>FLAME Wildfire Suppression Reserve Fund</quote>, $342,000,000, to remain available through September 30, 2021, for necessary expenses for large wildland fire suppression operations of the Department of Agriculture and as a reserve fund for suppression and Federal emergency response activities: <italic>Provided</italic>, That notwithstanding the FLAME Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1748a">43 U.S.C. 1748a(e)</external-xref>), such funds shall be solely available to be transferred to and merged with other appropriations accounts from which funds were previously transferred for wildland fire suppression in fiscal year 2017 to fully repay those amounts: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-major id="HE02A7C2BDA5346A8BAC2B2902594A5A3"><header>Department of the Interior</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="H398D66C7847A43CA910D790F94C70F70"><header>Department-Wide programs</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H71EDBA6E42F54EDCB1E0C860962B970C"><header>Wildland Fire Management</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HAAF38B74A5134B0D978B76B727A09636"><header>(Including transfer of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Wildland Fire Management</quote>, $50,000,000, to remain available until expended, for urgent wildland fire suppression activities and funds necessary to repay any transfers needed for these costs: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such funds may be available to be transferred to and merged with other appropriations accounts to fully repay amounts previously transferred for wildland fire suppression: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small></title> <title id="HB41D928045D2438A82C37C0B4FE72D05" style="appropriations"><enum>III</enum><appropriations-major id="HAA3EEC2B293144C98F26B0114EC855D7"><header>General Provisions</header></appropriations-major> <section id="H9F9FC5881DD342C5A7D243EA84492561"><enum>301.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each amount appropriated or made available by this division is in addition to amounts otherwise appropriated for the fiscal year involved.</text></section> 
<section id="H994EC1255B8E4CEFA31EA80DDABA7A80"><enum>302.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No part of any appropriation contained in this division shall remain available for obligation beyond the current fiscal year unless expressly so provided herein.</text></section> <section id="H57D2DA4AD7BC4BFA922F00215C8B2B52"><enum>303.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms and conditions applicable to the funds provided in this division, including those provided by this title, shall also apply to the funds made available in division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/56">Public Law 115–56</external-xref>.</text></section> 
<section id="HE8988338511C4D7B965B566883E3BF7C"><enum>304.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each amount designated in this division by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 shall be available only if the President subsequently so designates all such amounts and transmits such designations to the Congress.</text></section> <section id="H686A82A9BF634745A5DBDF3E4FE26449"><enum>305.</enum> <subsection id="H3709FE195B1C4A08B80886A2BA63AE2D" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum> <paragraph id="HB57F72C7CB8346BAB6593CEFD91F5B24" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than December 31, 2017, in accordance with criteria to be established by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (referred to in this section as <quote>OMB</quote>), each Federal agency shall submit to OMB, the Government Accountability Office, the respective Inspector General of each agency, and the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate internal control plans for funds provided by this division and division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/56">Public Law 115–56</external-xref>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAAE126AF82E2401F8128C6A7CC3837EC" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than March 31, 2018, the Government Accountability Office shall review for the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate the design of the internal control plans required by paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1198BD9938524347AA891723DED999E5"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All programs and activities receiving funds under this division shall be deemed to be <quote>susceptible to significant improper payments</quote> for purposes of the Improper Payments Information Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/3321">31 U.S.C. 3321</external-xref> note), notwithstanding section 2(a) of such Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HABEF473044614E58A07466F345017ABC"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds for grants provided by this division or division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/56">Public Law 115–56</external-xref> shall be expended by the grantees within the 24-month period following the agency’s obligation of funds for the grant, unless, in accordance with guidance to be issued by the Director of OMB, the Director waives this requirement for a particular grant program and submits a written justification for such waiver to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate. In the case of such grants, the agency shall include a term in the grant that requires the grantee to return to the agency any funds not expended within the 24-month period.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H9CFD54D178F24036A39923F3EC44F098" commented="no"><enum>306.</enum> <subsection id="HDEFA31E920FE4DB69C32C6E3311A783F" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The first proviso under the heading <quote>Department of Housing and Urban Development—Community Planning and Development—Community Development Fund</quote> in division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/56">Public Law 115–56</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>State or unit of general local government</quote> and inserting <quote>State, unit of general local government, or Indian tribe (as such term is defined in section 102 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5302">42 U.S.C. 5302</external-xref>))</quote>. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H020D1D10EB42464AB11C035691F6B24E"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Amounts repurposed pursuant to subsection (a) that were previously designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 are designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of such Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HB55DFC66AE2245E3A3BB0CCD063F87A2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>307.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 101(a)(7) of division D of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/56">Public Law 115–56</external-xref> is amended to read as follows: </text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2DE135FFF9274245B44EF8832509D898" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H83541E6E3B8D4C4382EE3E0E400CC294"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2017 (division G of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/31">Public Law 115–31</external-xref>), except the language under the heading <quote>FLAME Wildfire Suppression Reserve Fund</quote> in the Departments of Agriculture and the Interior.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H8D95DAE641BB443990CDD5C77C750797"><enum>308.</enum> <subsection id="H1B31BE6D3E7C4BCDB580D148E72F57C1" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text>Notwithstanding sections 1309, 1310, and 1310a of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4016">42 U.S.C. 4016–4017a</external-xref>) and section 15(e) of the Federal Flood Insurance Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2414">42 U.S.C. 2414(e)</external-xref>), and any borrowing agreement entered into between the Department of the Treasury and the Federal Emergency Management Agency, of the indebtedness of the Administrator under any notes or other obligations issued pursuant to section 1309(a) of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4016">42 U.S.C. 4016(a)</external-xref>) and section 15(e) of the Federal Insurance Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2414">42 U.S.C. 2414(e)</external-xref>) that is outstanding as of the date of the enactment of this Act, an amount of $16,000,000,000 is hereby cancelled. To the extent of the amount cancelled, the Administrator and the National Flood Insurance Fund are relieved of all liability to the Secretary of the Treasury under any such notes or other obligations, including for any interest due under such notes and any other fees and charges payable in connection with such notes, and the total amount of notes and obligations issued by the Administrator pursuant to such sections shall be considered to be reduced by such amount for the purposes of the limitation on such total amount under such section 1309(a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9266365594BE4A0AAF6B8AA4DC4620E9"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The amount of the indebtedness cancelled under subsection (a) may be treated as public debt of the United States.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDF8D92F881A245CB9CA9ED9CB0F08DA1"><enum>(c)</enum> <paragraph id="HB4717DB2F15C4495B3D0048B1C5C388A" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>This section is designated as an emergency requirement pursuant to section 4(g) of the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/933">2 U.S.C. 933(g)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H13B8ED18365743AC8DDC645C246338A9" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount provided in this section is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H77091FB935454F799C7D8D4B4CCF5730"><enum>309.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 19(a)(2)(B) of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2028">7 U.S.C. 2028</external-xref>), not to exceed $1,270,000,000 of funds made available for the contingency reserve under the heading <quote>Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program</quote> of division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/113">Public Law 114–113</external-xref> shall be available for the Secretary to provide a grant to the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico for disaster nutrition assistance in response to the Presidentially declared major disasters and emergencies: <italic>Provided</italic>, That funds made available to Puerto Rico under this section shall remain available for obligation by the Commonwealth until September 30, 2019, and shall be in addition to funds otherwise made available: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></section> 
<section id="H2CECC79292F249E6BCF6737336B5D007"><enum>310.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 2208(l)(3) of title 10, United States Code, during fiscal year 2018, the dollar limitation on advance billing of a customer of a working-capital fund in such section shall not apply with respect to the advance billing of the Federal Emergency Management Agency. In the preceding sentence, the term <quote>advance billing</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 2208(l)(4) of title 10, United States Code.</text></section> <section id="HF0D781ABB71145ADA8AC36C82B3FC593" section-type="undesignated-section"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This division may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Additional Supplemental Appropriations for Disaster Relief Requirements Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section></title></division> 
<division id="H2F0F7A07FDD946DA9D13258A000ABA9F" style="OLC"><enum>B</enum><header>Bankruptcy Judgeship Act of 2017</header> 
<section id="HDC35EAE33DC54C1E9E61470A86784274" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>1001.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This division may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bankruptcy Judgeship Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HCC355372DC5E4317B0B02400EAC52C5B"><enum>1002.</enum><header>Extension of temporary office of bankruptcy judges in certain judicial districts</header> <subsection id="HE44AFBF198274B50BC42FD9965BC4C23"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Temporary office of bankruptcy judges authorized by the Bankruptcy Judgeship Act of 2005</header> <paragraph id="H5E293C98E7734989A25E5CD928286DF5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Extensions</header><text>The temporary office of bankruptcy judges authorized for the following districts by subsection (b) of the Bankruptcy Judgeship Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/28/152">28 U.S.C. 152</external-xref> note) are extended until the applicable vacancy specified in paragraph (2) in the office of a bankruptcy judge for the respective district occurs:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCA3A9D8CB48A4C7BA3336E6BE8F4B68E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The district of Delaware.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC929479AA79E414DA47A4678FDFAC112"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The southern district of Florida.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0B04E662F42F4A24A62AB5F68592A8FC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The district of Maryland.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCD252FED151B40C0B48E18013F15F26E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The eastern district of Michigan.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBC77634E0A044186968EF67753780AB2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The district of Nevada.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1BABD29F330E497C99AC88E359596C52"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The eastern district of North Carolina.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA2CF5024413048FCB04EB539AC3EBDE7"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The district of Puerto Rico.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB4C1194CBB4B43EFAAEB861BC84A22E5"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The eastern district of Virginia.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCE0225B8C9DF469DA592F5D24A53192E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Vacancies</header> 
<subparagraph id="H7FEACE2DCA0B4D099A0F261D5AC5DE39"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Single vacancies</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraphs (B), (C), and (D), the 1st vacancy in the office of a bankruptcy judge for each district specified in paragraph (1)—</text> <clause id="H77D20D1F6AE643E997FA159511AA7E78"><enum>(i)</enum><text>occurring more than 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7016257899EC4E85AB779049B41E96ED"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>resulting from the death, retirement, resignation, or removal of a bankruptcy judge,</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">shall not be filled.</continuation-text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA7498B130C5A49E7891E73345ADFA0B7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>District of Delaware</header><text>The 1st, 2d, 3d, and 4th vacancies in the office of a bankruptcy judge for the district of Delaware—</text> 
<clause id="H76FFE497B6A24B1994E960048F7D934F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>occurring 5 years or more after the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></clause> <clause id="H60E2D54FFC4844F4BB28A3BF2A431918"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>resulting from the death, retirement, resignation, or removal of a bankruptcy judge,</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">shall not be filled.</continuation-text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H028F79076FF140AEA7A90E5B1DFCCD10"><enum>(C)</enum><header>District of Maryland</header> 
<clause id="H488193F5C77A465A9E146367591B2266"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The 1st vacancy in the office of a bankruptcy judge for the district of Maryland—</text> <subclause id="HAD505A0A79F8444EBE5920D69814BBA9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>occurring more than 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H3D09B25D382240FCA2C5DB358F1DE23B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>resulting from the death, retirement, resignation, or removal of a bankruptcy judge,</text></subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">shall not be filled.</continuation-text></clause> <clause id="H54E7D7AF512D40378A2F8A3746A4C61B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The 2d and 3d vacancies in the office of a bankruptcy judge for the district of Maryland resulting from the death, retirement, resignation, or removal of a bankruptcy judge, shall not be filled.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5F712412290D44E8981986D097F19442"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Southern district of Florida</header><text>The 1st and 2d vacancies in the office of a bankruptcy judge for the southern district of Florida—</text> <clause id="H667AE22BBB06441DAD92F9B3DBD1CACA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>occurring more than 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC9D41CBD42D84C8990B3BC07B501F13F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>resulting from the death, retirement, resignation, or removal of a bankruptcy judge,</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">shall not be filled.</continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0559B977AB524B9DBCE0EACA167C9F62"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applicability of provisions</header><text>Except as provided in paragraphs (1) and (2), all other provisions of subsection (b) of the Bankruptcy Judgeship Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/28/152">28 U.S.C. 152</external-xref> note) and section 2 of the Temporary Bankruptcy Judgeships Extension Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/28/152">28 U.S.C. 152</external-xref> note) remain applicable to the temporary office of bankruptcy judges referred to in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDF3DA219B5604D99B05E54C5A734030E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Temporary office of bankruptcy judges extended by the Bankruptcy Judgeship Act of 2005 and the Temporary Bankruptcy Judgeships Extension Act of 2012</header> 
<paragraph id="H16B3349AD779499A854A431E75C125DC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Extensions</header><text>The temporary office of bankruptcy judges authorized by section 3 of the Bankruptcy Judgeship Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/28/152">28 U.S.C. 152</external-xref> note) and extended by subsection (c) of the Bankruptcy Judgeship Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/28/152">28 U.S.C. 152</external-xref> note) and further extended by section 2 of the Temporary Bankruptcy Judgeships Extension Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/28/152">28 U.S.C. 152</external-xref> note) for the district of Delaware and the district of Puerto Rico are extended until the applicable vacancy specified in paragraph (2) in the office of a bankruptcy judge for the respective district occurs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDEEA233DFFC64F478DC463DB2764DA1B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Vacancies</header> <subparagraph id="HD74D9F91EC974543933B7DC8BFF9AB17"><enum>(A)</enum><header>District of Delaware</header><text>The 5th vacancy in the office of a bankruptcy judge for the district of Delaware—</text> 
<clause id="H38FB1CE08D204D51871DB049C190C805"><enum>(i)</enum><text>occurring more than 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></clause> <clause id="H7F3A85DB69974690AFD49CA46F0C3E72"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>resulting from the death, retirement, resignation, or removal of a bankruptcy judge,</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">shall not be filled.</continuation-text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H43B68F10BD49449BB4FB0A9972945B03"><enum>(B)</enum><header>District of Puerto Rico</header><text>The 2d vacancy in the office of a bankruptcy judge for the district of Puerto Rico—</text> <clause id="HBB4C743E22894F648002AFC7D8602BB9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>occurring more than 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC4CE853081D545DEA2C8554028CD22D6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>resulting from the death, retirement, resignation, or removal of a bankruptcy judge,</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">shall not be filled.</continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H822BE61BA2F44679A3EC138FEACFD9C3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applicability of other provisions</header><text>Except as provided in paragraphs (1) and (2), all other provisions of section 3 of the Bankruptcy Judgeship Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/28/152">28 U.S.C. 152</external-xref> note), subsection (c) of the Bankruptcy Judgeship Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/28/152">28 U.S.C. 152</external-xref> note), and section 2 of the Temporary Bankruptcy Judgeships Extension Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/28/152">28 U.S.C. 152</external-xref> note) remain applicable to the temporary office of bankruptcy judges referred to in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HA6992E59A7A1458C848E2670B79F85EC"><enum>1003.</enum><header>Temporary office of bankruptcy judge authorized</header> 
<subsection id="H826E0B16A42F47CAA7C892DE68A65001"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Appointments</header><text>The following bankruptcy judges shall be appointed in the manner prescribed in section 152(a)(1) of title 28, United States Code, for the appointment of bankruptcy judges provided for in section 152(a)(2) of that title:</text> <paragraph id="HD861F386707E4F0FB6E2D15D8BAC3E01"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Two additional bankruptcy judges for the district of Delaware.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDEDB441CC2254F81B4644EDBBF67D524"><enum>(2)</enum><text>One additional bankruptcy judge for the middle district of Florida.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6A9BF8FCD26E49F5B1695ECA2C330FE9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>One additional bankruptcy judge for the eastern district of Michigan.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0C1460A2C7BC417D986C8FCE14F5AC85"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Vacancies</header> 
<paragraph id="H4C0256DB0DF345689456441E832367B8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>District of Delaware</header><text>The 6th and 7th vacancies in the office of a bankruptcy judge for the district of Delaware—</text> <subparagraph id="H5A4391B3DA454DBB809154F9CB16C9BE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>occurring 5 years or more after the appointment date of the bankruptcy judge appointed under subsection (a)(1) to such office; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HACE81518580B4EB0AF47078AF181F922"><enum>(B)</enum><text>resulting from the death, retirement, resignation, or removal of a bankruptcy judge,</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">shall not be filled.</continuation-text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H25593BFADF8B4EFF99E54515CF371176"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Middle district of Florida</header><text>The 1st vacancy in the office of a bankruptcy judge for the middle district of Florida—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDF55D669915D4527BCF938484D628A8D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>occurring 5 years or more after the appointment date of the bankruptcy judge appointed under subsection (a)(2) to such office; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7C54A42AA04B468D8CFABE98E0CAD78F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>resulting from the death, retirement, resignation, or removal of a bankruptcy judge,</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">shall not be filled.</continuation-text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1C8AB102E6EE49598B93D0DA156FC35F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eastern district of Michigan</header><text>The 2d vacancy in the office of a bankruptcy judge for the eastern district of Michigan—</text> <subparagraph id="H9782CDA0E0D54241AC2C7242F4D9C67A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>occurring 5 years or more after the appointment date of the bankruptcy judge appointed under subsection (a)(3) to such office; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H702A9A0DF62448D199215A8014E3000F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>resulting from the death, retirement, resignation, or removal of a bankruptcy judge,</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">shall not be filled.</continuation-text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HEEEC53EAF08F4E7BBE2E9CE2E29E6DE6"><enum>1004.</enum><header>Bankruptcy fees</header> <subsection id="H9E6BAE1B61FB44F1B1CEE05BD1B8669E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendments to title 28 of the United States Code</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1930(a)(6) of title 28, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4E55DE4CDECF40D6ACE69205FF705653"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>(6) In</quote> and inserting ‘‘(6)(A) Except as provided in subparagraph (B), in’’; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC7CD5AC207E94861A51849A800A6D55D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB7CCF97D6360404CA061B7CA5B6FB4AE" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="HB8D833BF7A8C4DAAACD858125D8B20A8" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022, if the balance in the United States Trustee System Fund as of September 30 of the most recent full fiscal year is less than $200,000,000, the quarterly fee payable for a quarter in which disbursements equal or exceed $1,000,000 shall be the lesser of 1 percent of such disbursements or $250,000.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9BF3F72685E643469A3FDA492DE7FE64"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deposits of certain fees for fiscal years 2018 through 2022</header><text>Notwithstanding section 589a(b) of title 28, United States Code, for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022—</text> 
<paragraph id="H922A62AF52F245ABBBEBD2B2AFDAA76B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>98 percent of the fees collected under section 1930(a)(6) of such title shall be deposited as offsetting collections to the appropriation <quote>United States Trustee System Fund</quote>, to remain available until expended; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB2E07C42EC2046CC9145F460AB98065F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>2 percent of the fees collected under section 1930(a)(6) of such title shall be deposited in the general fund of the Treasury.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H93BFB0AD353447F9A2F33F1C84928E4F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application of amendments</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to quarterly fees payable under section 1930(a)(6) of title 28, United States Code, as amended by this section, for disbursements made in any calendar quarter that begins on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA46EFFA792F74C25839406F8CD8E8D4D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>1005.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Clarification of rule allowing discharge to governmental claims arising from the disposition of farm assets under chapter 12 bankruptcies</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1ED1BCD254834A96855E59F07176D909"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/11/12">chapter 12</external-xref> of title 11, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H54316ADD453B497ABC6B3D99E70EEF34" style="USC"> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8531A881843D46D08CDA891174B3BC38" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>1232.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Claim by a governmental unit based on the disposition of property used in a farming operation</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6AE55A5B67F9446E81D4C263E6474962"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any unsecured claim of a governmental unit against the debtor or the estate that arises before the filing of the petition, or that arises after the filing of the petition and before the debtor’s discharge under section 1228, as a result of the sale, transfer, exchange, or other disposition of any property used in the debtor’s farming operation—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8AF74E004A01460C8C89DF104A9060D9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be treated as an unsecured claim arising before the date on which the petition is filed;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H341FCDC01D2443DAB44AB7796B9DFD40"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall not be entitled to priority under section 507;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H170B92D3543A43E4853BCECECA377E2F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be provided for under a plan; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE507B156C1874BAAB08ACEF6E38D7B17"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be discharged in accordance with section 1228.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB69FC66617DF4F1591B1D156645A8477"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of applying sections 1225(a)(4), 1228(b)(2), and 1229(b)(1) to a claim described in subsection (a) of this section, the amount that would be paid on such claim if the estate of the debtor were liquidated in a case under chapter 7 of this title shall be the amount that would be paid by the estate in a chapter 7 case if the claim were an unsecured claim arising before the date on which the petition was filed and were not entitled to priority under section 507.</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H50E50C21E88E457A9FE463D72665924A"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of applying sections 523(a), 1228(a)(2), and 1228(c)(2) to a claim described in subsection (a) of this section, the claim shall not be treated as a claim of a kind specified in subparagraph (A) or (B) of section 523(a)(1).</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0208A0374E2A4BBC981E4D2B382DC4F8"><enum>(d)</enum> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H928BDA9BD7A946C1A578423474B36463"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A governmental unit may file a proof of claim for a claim described in subsection (a) that arises after the date on which the petition is filed.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB2146F97B94B403FB9AE1CADFC71DA7A" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a debtor files a tax return after the filing of the petition for a period in which a claim described in subsection (a) arises, and the claim relates to the tax return, the debtor shall serve notice of the claim on the governmental unit charged with the responsibility for the collection of the tax at the address and in the manner designated in section 505(b)(1). Notice under this paragraph shall state that the debtor has filed a petition under this chapter, state the name and location of the court in which the case under this chapter is pending, state the amount of the claim, and include a copy of the filed tax return and documentation supporting the calculation of the claim.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H31CE2B0E0BB74686BC8B4505EED412C5" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If notice of a claim has been served on the governmental unit in accordance with paragraph (2), the governmental unit may file a proof of claim not later than 180 days after the date on which such notice was served. If the governmental unit has not filed a timely proof of the claim, the debtor or trustee may file proof of the claim that is consistent with the notice served under paragraph (2). If a proof of claim is filed by the debtor or trustee under this paragraph, the governmental unit may not amend the proof of claim.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4EACEA90717342368268CE59FDAE07D4" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A claim filed under this subsection shall be determined and shall be allowed under subsection (a), (b), or (c) of section 502, or disallowed under subsection (d) or (e) of section 502, in the same manner as if the claim had arisen immediately before the date of the filing of the petition.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H514CCC2CA7E84DAEAB381CA7B3D8E6EE"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Technical and conforming amendments</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5447515A937840EF98AE941E70E1D56E"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/11/12">chapter 12</external-xref> of title 11, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H93FF8E1A053541E4839EDFCCE9E1D334"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 1222(a)—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1E6A2054E2B24B209CE187BB13DC1D6B"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>unless—</quote> and all that follows through <quote>the holder</quote> and inserting <quote>unless the holder</quote>;</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF4458E0817C345A3B7419A1EC8136985"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE6FF011E770D4D6988F1C65CAE412A80"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (4), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7BC7195FAC57420A8BB55EB5D8AFBDBE"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HABAE46F68B2B4E1D976444010E9688C8" style="OLC"> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBA273D567AEF41DDAFF655C3A62B4E5B"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subject to section 1232, provide for the treatment of any claim by a governmental unit of a kind described in section 1232(a).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H48376DC344C14EC5A23A356E368AFC8B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 1228—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2BC820D619DC4D869BA440EF0067A042"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a)—</text> 
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1561D20A01AA4D44A2F80BD6F42C31B3"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the matter preceding paragraph (1)—</text> <item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H736248217D174ABDA4420A0AE36E2E8A"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting a comma after <quote>all debts provided for by the plan</quote>; and</text></item> 
<item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5D988B8B60A94C40855798542F4AE11D"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting a comma after <quote>allowed under section 503 of this title</quote>; and</text></item></subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H32794FED4E034457A98B116C1BFB0756"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>the kind</quote> and all that follows and inserting <quote>a kind specified in section 523(a) of this title, except as provided in section 1232(c).</quote>; and</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF7914FD94E174E0EA808A4065E29C25B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c)(2), by inserting <quote>, except as provided in section 1232(c)</quote> before the period at the end; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H170EEC28FBA3471B8A7869C6A6DC3E90"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 1229(a)—</text> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF87CE29876BB42CE8936AEBCE54CF638"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H28CE0DAF1C95468E88B938024E6AE8D9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (3), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD3D82AC9674C4566AAB62BCCCA7116B8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE6580269E9D74B8992AB71D172834F9D" style="OLC"> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFD4FC6B00E504ECD8F5A707A277706C6"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide for the payment of a claim described in section 1232(a) that arose after the date on which the petition was filed.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3A0017BE213D4C17BB0313BD166EBD28"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Table of sections</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/11/12">chapter 12</external-xref> of title 11, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H63DC982C325B409694A4FEC8D66BE91B" style="USC"> <toc> <toc-entry bold="off" idref="H8531A881843D46D08CDA891174B3BC38" level="section">1232. Claim by a governmental unit based on the disposition of property used in a farming operation.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H954EF149797F4C7D9F3820C636F06523"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply to—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFDEB3A1287A04C62A2ADFE1559074A18"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any bankruptcy case—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1463E52FF487444396E35591F2A2896A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is pending on the date of enactment of this Act;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3426DEF1E6E64FEC870B9EA79B38B118"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in which the plan under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/11/12">chapter 12</external-xref> of title 11, United States Code, has not been confirmed on the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2C5E382DEA8849E682F268B49C1F1405"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">relating to which an order of discharge under section 1228 of title 11, United States Code, has not been entered; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H91C7EAEA74BC4E7FB59BAAD742CBA841"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any bankruptcy case that commences on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></division> </amendment-block> </amendment></engrossed-amendment-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation><endorsement></endorsement></amendment-doc> 

