<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HAB2B85DD946D4992AB6424D5D98440AF" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 865 IH: Emergency Forest Restoration Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 865</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170203">February 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001177">Mr. McClintock</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001094">Mr. Cook</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001192">Mr. Stewart</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001165">Mr. McCarthy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000821">Mr. Westerman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000573">Mr. Labrador</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000181">Mr. Nunes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000612">Mr. Denham</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000387">Mr. Knight</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To make a categorical exclusion available to the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the
			 Interior to develop and carry out a forest management activity on National
			 Forest system lands derived from the public domain or public lands to
			 address insect or disease infestation declared as an emergency in a State
			 by the Governor of such State, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HC32D1C2903CD4D9698149CF47D0C7893" style="OLC">
 <section commented="no" id="H10D04A801D4F41C9AAD06BDFCFEF28F2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Emergency Forest Restoration Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H5AB5FBBFE0454F5AAD91EED0E03D61A7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Categorical exclusion to address a declared emergency</header> <subsection id="H8E63D4DAC721447BA28335CEE80A79C9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority To conduct forest management activity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary concerned may develop and carry out a forest management activity on National Forest System lands or public lands in a State when the primary purpose of the forest management activity is to address a declared emergency.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1C03E334DC804CF89858F701104F8548"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability of categorical exclusion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in section 4, a categorical exclusion is available to the Secretary concerned to develop and carry out a forest management activity described in subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H5DCAF203EE444C10A27A6F0796306711"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>For purposes of this section, there is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary concerned $300,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2025.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HB4EF23E48A304007B1A92A53C4EC2BB9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Use of timber sale revenues to offset funds appropriated to address a declared emergency</header>
			<subsection id="H066D9614B07E476689486B549492D04F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Timber sales required</header>
 <paragraph id="HB2E45BF5DA8B44E99333BD135813BBA7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Identification of amounts appropriated</header><text>For fiscal year 2019 and each fiscal year thereafter, the Secretary of Agriculture shall identify the amount of funds, if any, appropriated in the prior fiscal year pursuant to the authorization of appropriations in section 2(c).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H76A32FFA198B4DFBA874E7C7680095DD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sales</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 5 years after the end of the fiscal year in which an identification is made under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Agriculture shall sell (in the manner provided for under section 14 of the National Forest Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/472a">16 U.S.C. 472a</external-xref>)) an amount of timber the sale of which is sufficient to recoup the amount identified under paragraph (1) and any costs associated with such sale.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCBC55E8607DD473D8E8EFC022D2F9C95"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Proceeds</header><text>Proceeds from the sale of timber described under paragraph (2) shall be deposited as follows:</text> <subparagraph id="H0C60AF7A7BEF4F6D9313B32964B44CFD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An amount equal to the appropriated amount identified under paragraph (1) shall be deposited in the general fund of the Treasury of the United States as miscellaneous receipts.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF8F6AD4AA0D4FE5815FB88DF6390623"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An amount equal to the costs associated with the sale shall be deposited in a designated fund from which sums are to be used, to cover the cost to the United States for design, engineering, and supervision of the construction of needed roads and the cost for Forest Service sale preparation and supervision of the harvesting of such timber.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB96A15E962C14029B13EF182460DF4AE"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any amounts not described under subparagraph (A) or (B) shall be deposited in the general fund of the Treasury of the United States as miscellaneous receipts.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7F2F907D34C04A099D979B8A052D5D2C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Categorical exclusion</header><text>Except as provided in section 4, a categorical exclusion is available to the Secretary of Agriculture for timber sales conducted pursuant to subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H92334B06864D437EA6D475C30892CA8D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Limitation of categorical exclusion</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A categorical exclusion under this Act may not be used on National Forest System lands or public lands—</text>
 <paragraph id="H094CFC2C74FE4B5CBFFC576FA19080F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>that are included in the National Wilderness Preservation System;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBEC297E3AA894B8C85D53A0173AF4024"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that are located within an inventoried roadless area unless the reforestation activity is consistent with the forest plan applicable to the area; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB629EBB6BE88480888E880F66F85BFFF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>on which timber harvesting for any purpose is prohibited by statute.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H280074D6CFDC4C83A9DF914809ECB5AB"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="H6B7B653AD1E6426AAF5AD5D9275463DA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Categorical exclusion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>categorical exclusion</term> means an exception to the requirements of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4331">42 U.S.C. 4331</external-xref> et seq.) for a project or activity relating to the management of National Forest System lands or public lands that would otherwise be considered a major Federal action.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE0B01C2BD62541B9B0EF9A5E3EB3171E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Declared emergency</header><text>The term <term>declared emergency</term> means an insect or disease infestation in a State that has been declared an emergency by the Governor of such State.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA89FC4102BC4463F9949B2FC4A7A28E2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>National Forest System lands</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>National Forest System lands</quote> means Federal lands derived from the public domain that are included in the National Forest System (as such term is defined in section 11(a) of the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1609">16 U.S.C. 1609(a)</external-xref>)), including such lands within the boundaries of a national monument managed by the Forest Service.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE95BAA7FBF444118E4E50023367B807"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary concerned</header><text>The term <term>Secretary concerned</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H0536558F08E24D9E876603C646D0F279"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to National Forest System lands; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H52AFB2B2BE8C4637A5B72C0EEA7BDAF7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior, with respect to public lands.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H67E1ADF7DBE34B1F81BC8F8728085072"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means any of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and any other territory or possession of the United States.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


