<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2207C420E1144509840C517506545B2E" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1423 IH: National Flood Insurance Program Reauthorization and Improvement Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1423</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170308">March 8, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To reauthorize and improve the national flood insurance program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HD7F74B67EEE341A998FE5324B2279C2A" style="OLC">
		<section id="HF14B9C3528C344298539860E054D1F9C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="H5F3F8B92E52C4AA09C0671B574F95DD5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Flood Insurance Program Reauthorization and Improvement Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H8DB7913CB8284B6AAA6D51AF17CFCC9A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
					<toc-entry idref="HF14B9C3528C344298539860E054D1F9C" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H59DB70BB90A64152BE6804E14F070099" level="section">Sec. 2. Extension of national flood insurance program.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HD32DD0467E66474A934A7B408E2C4A34" level="section">Sec. 3. Improved disclosure requirement for standard flood insurance policies.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H6E73B394D23F46D09C364091B26D478F" level="section">Sec. 4. Properties with preexisting conditions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H68CDFDF6E2C64DAAA2BF6D8A93EA9A19" level="section">Sec. 5. Improvement of administrative and litigation process for claims adjudication.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H8AB26BC9DA98444C97780BB617B78E8D" level="section">Sec. 6. Improvement of oversight of engineers.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HEBF3773E98F64F0DAD95832E84F66904" level="section">Sec. 7. Publicly searchable online registry.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H8FDED41168C04EEA8DCA08EF7F77CEA3" level="section">Sec. 8. Penalties for fraud and false statements in the National Flood Insurance Program.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H69D4A8B870CD4E24A84E0C6E77458ED5" level="section">Sec. 9. Whistleblower protection for employees.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HD8E58B1781A2491DB0E15C1B4937B2F7" level="section">Sec. 10. Engineering firm independence.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HF5283E726E1E443585B150C68072AD58" level="section">Sec. 11. GAO reports.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H46222AE0BC3D46B3B828AAA76D84AF32" level="section">Sec. 12. Regulations.</toc-entry>
				</toc>
			</subsection></section><section id="H59DB70BB90A64152BE6804E14F070099"><enum>2.</enum><header>Extension of national flood insurance program</header>
 <subsection id="H3FFA64C3A1834FE79EBE5767966BEF17"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Financing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1309(a) of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4016">42 U.S.C. 4016(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>September 30, 2017</quote> and inserting <quote>September 30, 2027</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H91ADB35E86DC4319817C485850CB70D7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program expiration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1319 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4026">42 U.S.C. 4026</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>September 30, 2017</quote> and inserting <quote>September 30, 2027</quote> .</text> </subsection></section><section id="HD32DD0467E66474A934A7B408E2C4A34"><enum>3.</enum><header>Improved disclosure requirement for standard flood insurance policies</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 100234 of the Biggert-Waters Flood Insurance Reform Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4013a">42 U.S.C. 4013a</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsections:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H06842C1446D5448B853245583CE13BB2" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="H709674A1129D4851934F0EF445312EF5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Disclosure of coverage</header>
 <paragraph id="H53797BE5DA1048CFB88C04A284792C5A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Disclosure sheet</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each policy under the National Flood Insurance Program shall include a disclosure sheet that sets forth, in plain language—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE7AC09D4783C45359AB49AA69ED20B3B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the definition of the term <term>flood</term> for purposes of coverage under the policy;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H71545C215F0E4051944A3BD77B4FD704"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of what type of flood forces are necessary so that losses from an event are covered under the policy, including overflow of inland or tidal waves, unusual and rapid accumulation or runoff of a surface any source, and mudflow;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0274B9AC0C8F4511B4710088925857FC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a statement of the types and characteristics of losses that are not covered under the policy;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09DF4BBC74764DA6A7AAA34B6FC0BED7"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary of total cost and amount of insurance coverage;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C5FA3E92C1C4391838475CDE06D18DD"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a statement that the disclosure sheet provides general information about the policyholder’s standard flood insurance policy;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34DECFCC40544297B198E66254B3B9F6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a statement that the standard flood insurance policy, together with the application, endorsements, and declarations page, make up the official contract and are controlling in the event that there is any difference between the information on the disclosure sheet and the information in the policy; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5AE8E39E7F724DFDA14A40B8764AC149"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a statement that if the policyholder has any questions regarding information in the disclosure sheet or policy he or she should contact their insurance agent, together with the address and phone number at which to contact such agent.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD878B809F6ED4A3C9356B24321BB2CF9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Acknowledgment sheet</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each policy under the National Flood Insurance Program shall include an acknowledgment sheet that sets forth, in plain language—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF96753EB88FF4EAA89AE659935D22B25"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a statement of whether or not there is a basement in the property to be covered by the policy;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB237F1BDF6C4D25A186713AD9C15BA7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a statement of whether or not the policy provides coverage for the contents of the property covered by the policy;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE3E001F16DF34346AFEFC34F61818C54"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a statement that the standard flood insurance policy, together with the application, endorsements, and declarations page, make up the official contract and are controlling in the event that there is any difference between the information on the acknowledgment sheet and the information in the policy; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB35418BF65C7465AB2C8C753A6AB0228"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a statement that if the policyholder has any questions regarding information in the acknowledgment sheet or policy he or she should contact their insurance agent, together with the address and phone number at which to contact such agent.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEFFADE974BCB4452B32EBEBF91562D53"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Required signatures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A policy for flood insurance coverage under the National Flood Insurance Program may not take effect unless the disclosure sheet required under paragraph (1) and the acknowledgment sheet required under paragraph (2), with respect to the policy, are signed and dated by the policyholder, the insurance agent who sold the policy, and a representative of the Administrator.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7312CB42715B4F46A7CF7423080C7327"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Availability in other languages</header>
 <paragraph id="HD56EAA646AB940B2B223B1175AC6A23D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall make policies under the National Flood Insurance Program, and the disclosure and acknowledgment sheets required by subsection (c), available in Spanish language versions and in such other languages as the Administrator considers appropriate and shall provide such a version at the request of the insured or prospective insured.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5C2F072CC8CD4197B4E153F6AD7D1F4A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publicizing availability</header><text>The Administrator shall take such actions as may be necessary to inform insureds and prospective insures of the availability of policies in such languages other than English.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H610AF505361B4FE6BEB16FF1DB831073"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Conflicting information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any difference between the information that is provided pursuant to this subsection to a policyholder in the English language and in the Spanish or other language, the information provided in the English language shall be determinative.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="H6E73B394D23F46D09C364091B26D478F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Properties with preexisting conditions</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1311 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4018">42 U.S.C. 4018</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC404687DC1B949B58ED3BE1FED2C9AED" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="HD57E4AADACD641C28C0C718684FE4A6A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Program for investigation of preexisting structural conditions</header>
 <paragraph id="HE7819B0B34084E439E21C576539EEAD1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Voluntary program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall carry out a program to provide for companies participating in the Write Your Own program (as such term is defined in section 100202 of the Biggert-Waters Flood Insurance Reform Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4004">42 U.S.C. 4004</external-xref>)) to investigate preexisting structural conditions of insured properties and potentially insured properties that could result in the denial of a claim under a policy for flood insurance coverage under this title in the event of a flood loss to such property. Participation in the program shall be voluntary on the part of Write Your Own companies.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD4B8505FEA8A482C9E818EB926821370"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Investigation of properties</header><text>Under the program under this subsection, a Write Your Own company participating in the program shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H19967474E6494C26AC0F6CF48907DC6F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide in policies for flood insurance coverage under this title covered by the program that, upon the request of the policyholder, the company shall provide for—</text>
 <clause id="HABBB3F6AA8B14E61B8497FF726C4B5F5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an investigation of the property covered by such policy, using common methods, to determine whether preexisting structural conditions are present that could result in the denial of a claim under such policy for flood losses; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9D4FAF4B26684072933A869095504051"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if such investigation is not determinative, an on-site inspection of the property to determine whether such preexisting structural conditions are present;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC0DF8055EF54D50AB91C7BB11BD8469"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">upon completion of an investigation or inspection pursuant to subparagraph (A) that determines that such a preexisting structural condition is present or absent, submit a report to the policyholder and Administrator describing the condition; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H547C64EA243A446C83F7F98C9B24FA64"><enum>(C)</enum><text>impose a surcharge on each policy described in subparagraph (A) in such amount that the Administrator determines is appropriate to cover the costs of investigations and inspections performed pursuant to such policies and reimburse Write Your Own companies participating in the program under this subsection for such costs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="H68CDFDF6E2C64DAAA2BF6D8A93EA9A19"><enum>5.</enum><header>Improvement of administrative and litigation process for claims adjudication</header>
 <subsection id="H7F11D36198564A34A659C968489FC132"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Industry program with Federal financial assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1333 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4053">42 U.S.C. 4053</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H92F41B4803944ED68F98795B174D4DF4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>mailing of notice of disallowance or partial disallowance by the Administrator</quote> and inserting <quote>the final determination by the Administrator disallowing or partially disallowing the claim</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC1AECE8867CF4383A68A1AA76035E04D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding after the period at the end the following: <quote>If the claimant prevails in an action under this section, the court may award costs of litigation, including attorneys fee, litigation expenses, and engineering and other expert expenses, to the claimant. Any such award shall be paid by the Administrator and, upon such payment, the Administrator shall be subrogated to the rights of the claimant to recover such costs for which the Administrator has compensated the claimant from any company or other insurer responsible for the disallowance of the claim.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1F12B55847A546DC97FC4022007B218C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Government program with industry assistance</header><text>Section 1341 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4072">42 U.S.C. 4072</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H832533D275CA402885796FB94297EE70"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>mailing of notice of disallowance or partial disallowance of</quote> and inserting <quote>the final determination disallowing or partially disallowing</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF593FDCDECAC4FE1BD11C5450233FFB7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding after the period at the end the following: <quote>If the claimant prevails in an action under this section, the court may award costs of litigation, including attorneys fee, litigation expenses, and engineering and other expert expenses, to the claimant. Any such award shall be paid by the Administrator and, upon such payment, the Administrator shall be subrogated to the rights of the claimant to recover such costs for which the Administrator has compensated the claimant from any insurance company or other insurer or insurance adjustment organization that may be responsible for the disallowance of the claim.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF2303987E1234203BE43A82CA61D53DD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Awards for costs in appeals to FEMA</header><text>Section 1312 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4019">42 U.S.C. 4019</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H604C8A7B6810467580FF1D9FA71D5217" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H748AE89B22DD4A59908E17269E9E3153"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Awards for costs in administrative proceedings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the claimant prevails in any appeal to the Administrator of the disallowance of a claim for losses covered by flood insurance made available under this title, the Administrator shall award costs of the appeal, including attorneys fee, any proceeding expenses, and engineering and other expert expenses, to the claimant.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC2190AC827874B4D8D2238869D86CF24"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of private counsel</header><text>Section 1347 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4083">42 U.S.C. 4083</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF99C9EC2C27A41B7B81B3B96E5420BCD" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="HB4D728E1213A4564B5B84589009551BB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of private counsel</header>
 <paragraph id="H07B726087E0646B8BA23702257806183"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Fee schedule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall establish a fee schedule for payment of private counsel used to represent the Administrator in controversies, actions, and proceedings in connection with the National Flood Insurance Program under this title.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H901CE3C48DEB4B2FAACC777ED075125B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement for preauthorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall require any private counsel obtained in connection with any controversy, action, or proceeding in connection with the National Flood Insurance Program under this title to obtain authorization from the Administrator before taking any major action associated with such controversy, action, or proceeding, which shall include settlement, hiring experts, and such other actions as the Administrator shall specify.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H8AB26BC9DA98444C97780BB617B78E8D"><enum>6.</enum><header>Improvement of oversight of engineers</header>
 <subsection id="H5FA5BE3DF21C404C83F54359CB85E751"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part C of chapter 2 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4081">42 U.S.C. 4081</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0F4D4D6B68AE4C81A562BACBF406DF60" style="OLC">
					<section id="HBB10AD6C7B844811A2221297EF83D4BE"><enum>1349.</enum><header>Oversight of engineers</header>
 <subsection id="HA03E8AAB1EB64ECFA2B2AE93A7C44C46"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall require that any individual that provides engineering services in connection with flood insurance coverage provided under this title, including inspections under section 1306(e) and services in connection with assessing any claim for losses covered by a policy for such coverage, shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HCD53CFA11D914E1CBD1A0022586C1A91"><enum>(1)</enum><text>have registered with the Administrator and certified to the Administrator that the engineer is professionally licensed to practice as an engineer;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB9CC04E6CB384B63AAD607561C2EC253"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have expertise in a particular discipline of engineering or act within the area of their competency, as the Administrator shall require; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB835D03A08E74855AF375488FF799FD7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>be certified by the Administrator pursuant to subsection (b).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H086A31D15DBD4036B4C60C0F03BB3F83"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certification by FEMA</header> <paragraph id="HC610436EEEFC4545A4BA742502FE5CFB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall carry out a program under this subsection to certify engineers as qualified to provide engineering services in connection with flood insurance coverage provided under this title.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H509578137D5E44FBA5A75E20E14073B5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The program under this subsection shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H379D619BA1EE47F2944D125CB2FE9376"><enum>(A)</enum><text>include an initial training seminar;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2B361012B1E493B98427303D8D0AAEC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide such standards and testing requirements as the Administrator shall establish; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E66D940FFFB4B44A5FF17C2DB9EC571"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require an annual renewal of certification through continuing education.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5AABCA6A7F4D49B7BA2B9DCDA4C3DBC9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Fees</header>
 <paragraph id="H4B745AAB95F24D5788C1FA8EA841E18B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Schedule; collection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall establish and collect fees using a standardized fee schedule for all engineering services provided in connection with flood insurance coverage provided under this title, which schedule shall be similar to the fee schedule of the Administrator used for companies adjusting claims under such coverage.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCFBC891BBAF14C7D883FDEE3D7A376AD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deposit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any fees collected under paragraph (1) section shall be deposited into the National Flood Insurance Fund pursuant to section 1310(b)(6).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H54FE97A0D7F845BD94414313C52FE592"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Identification numbers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall establish a system to provide a unique numerical identifier for each engineer that provides engineering services in connection with flood insurance coverage provided under this title to assist in tracking past performance in the provision of such services.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8DC4462B5E324B948E4BA68D720206F6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Submission of documentation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any insurance company participating in the Write Your Own program (as such term is defined in section 100202 of the Biggert-Waters Flood Insurance Reform Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4004">42 U.S.C. 4004</external-xref>)):</text>
 <paragraph id="H02287DC9568E41A4B851806118CEBFAF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>To Write Your Own insurers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HEB834B9C67134F1AB71813FE3C4922BD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>require all such participating insurance companies to obtain from providers of engineering services provided in connection with flood insurance coverage provided under this title, including any sub-contractors,</text>
 <clause id="HAC47011FD2184307A258ED841EA7E4E0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>documentation sufficient to itemize and disaggregate the costs and fees for such services, including the costs and fees for any subcontractors; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4B00D64977A5486383D3318E93F4C5AF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all photos, notes, draft reports, and other documentation relating to providing such services in connection with a claim under such coverage;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB397ABDE8EF4354A6031D58DB621FCB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make available to such participating insurance companies the fee schedule established under subsection (c) and such other information as may be necessary to enable such participating insurance companies to determine whether the costs and fees charged by providers of engineering services are reasonable in relation to the services provided.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF4F49E272D3459083B47F60767A701E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>To FEMA</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall require each such insurance company to submit to the Administrator, before any reimbursement or other allowance, payment, or compensation is provided under the Write Your Own program in connection with engineering services provided, all supporting documentation relating to such engineering services.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA6FABB2052EE44AF8BC6F2BFB3A9CEAC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of fees</header><text>Subsection (a) of section 1310 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4017">42 U.S.C. 4017(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2798F4D516734F73810E5747C1C7492D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (7) and (8) as paragraphs (9) and (10), respectively; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA7B58C15A7BA49FDA945408D88E1AB89"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (6) the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAC0BE69115E14CA9B90188AD0BD29358" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H090A069C44FA49439842D013F14D680B"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the extent that fees are deposited in the Fund pursuant to section 1349(c)(2), for costs associated with carrying out systems for certification and identification under subsections (b) and (d), respectively, of section 1349;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HEBF3773E98F64F0DAD95832E84F66904"><enum>7.</enum><header>Publicly searchable online registry</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part C of chapter 2 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4081">42 U.S.C. 4081</external-xref> et seq.), as amended by the preceding provisions of this Act, is further amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H684596B933344DA3988381EB5088E0EC" style="OLC">
				<section id="HD68BF3AB1195479198BE3904447B1D2D"><enum>1350.</enum><header>Publicly searchable online registry</header>
 <subsection id="H66A2F5D1B8B1459DBB5680A48FBDAB50"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment and maintenance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall provide for the establishment and maintenance of a national registry, organized by State of residence, of all companies and individuals providing services relating to the selling, writing, or servicing of flood insurance made available under this title or relating to the adjusting of claims under such flood insurance, which shall include all insurance companies participating in the Write Your Own program (as such term is defined in section 100202 of the Biggert-Waters Flood Insurance Reform Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4004">42 U.S.C. 4004</external-xref>)) and all individuals participating in the direct servicing program, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0D1722E0A7EB439E8C4CB136B1BC41D0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all individuals selling and writing policies for flood insurance coverage under this title;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB815159829124B7BB3D3CA3026333612"><enum>(2)</enum><text>all companies and individuals providing adjusting services in connection with such flood insurance;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H81BA6437C9014FB7819EED9871A0F9CF"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all companies and individuals providing engineering services in connection with such flood insurance, identification of engineers using the unique numerical identifier assigned pursuant to section 1349(d), and information regarding past performance in providing such services, including identification of cases worked on, cases that involved litigation, and any association of the engineer with any company convicted of fraud;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD025F34A52954AB6892AD8FBEA25A087"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information identifying all penalties, fines, and criminal convictions of all such companies and individuals relating to the operation of the national flood insurance program; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H70A0FA4B88554B71888C4E5C8366054E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>information identifying any conviction or penalty assessed for fraud pertaining to any such company or individual.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAC70A28681174B0EA9EB7F06F20CEB99"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Administrator shall ensure that the registry required to be established and maintained under this section is publicly available online in a manner that provides the capacity to search the registry by the name of the company or individual.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0D1618C100824009972A78958DFA80E5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual review</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a review of the registry established and maintained under this section on a biennial basis to ensure its accuracy and currency.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="H3A90BCA3330A4D6E9B22B2F41C36702E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Administration</header>
 <paragraph id="H600367FA56A7470EA150884197B9C523"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Nonprofit organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall enter into a contract with an appropriate nonprofit organization to establish and maintain the registry under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB230C42D7EC7432A8CA97A50E214C72F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated for payments under the contract under paragraph (1) such sums as may be necessary for establishment and maintenance of the national registry under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H8FDED41168C04EEA8DCA08EF7F77CEA3"><enum>8.</enum><header>Penalties for fraud and false statements in the National Flood Insurance Program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part C of chapter 2 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4081">42 U.S.C. 4081</external-xref> et seq.), as amended by the preceding provisions of this Act, is further amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
			<quoted-block id="H97B9161580D443848D85F3B45FB0BF59">
				<section id="HF991C46184E74C9FA323FC95454C49FB"><enum>1351.</enum><header>Penalties for fraud and false statements in the National Flood Insurance Program</header>
 <subsection id="HD254BDBE52544210AAA541471D21AC3F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Offense</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be unlawful, in the preparation, production, or submission of any report in connection with the proving or adjusting of a claim for flood insurance coverage made available under this title, including any engineering report or claims adjustment report, to knowingly engage in the practice of engineering without a license, to knowingly forge any such report, or to knowingly make any materially false, fictitious, or fraudulent statement or representation in such a report.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8DFAB10B0A9341EF96B1D6591ADB995D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>Whoever violates subsection (a) shall be subject to any one or more of the following penalties:</text> <paragraph id="H7E067153E4444BEC87A0F48C7D1188EE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Criminal</header><text>In the case of a person who is an individual, imprisonment for not more than 18 months.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3193D5EFAEB3416F98D8D2B71C9C08A3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Civil</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such civil penalties as the Administrator, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Attorney General shall, by regulation, establish, which may include civil monetary penalties and fines, suspension and debarment from participation in the National Flood Insurance Program, and such other civil sanctions as such officials consider appropriate. In the case of any fine or monetary penalty collected pursuant to this paragraph, such amounts collected shall be paid to the owner of the property for which the claim involved was made.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H15E59B35ED6544BDAEAAEE36FD20DC04"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The offense under subsection (a) is exempted from the applicability of the fine provided under section 3571 of title 18, United States Code.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="H69D4A8B870CD4E24A84E0C6E77458ED5"><enum>9.</enum><header>Whistleblower protection for employees</header>
 <subsection id="HE435994E7B7146E1BD5FE89A3A8DE4D7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part C of chapter 2 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4081">42 U.S.C. 4081</external-xref> et seq.), as amended by the preceding provisions of this Act, is further amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEA305A8D05B141ED94B499F885D32684" style="OLC">
					<section id="HD35226AA92D04DF8BF2FC5CB73BA6DEB"><enum>1352.</enum><header>Whistleblower protection for employees</header>
 <subsection id="H561CCAE91E1A4ABD9246E2C8A2E55AAE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No person shall terminate or in any other way discriminate against, or cause to be terminated or discriminated against, any covered employee or any authorized representative of covered employees by reason of the fact that such employee or representative, whether at the initiative of the employee or in the ordinary course of the duties of the employee (or any person acting pursuant to a request of the employee), has—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6BC23FB302964A499200F65C7BC23F60"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provided, caused to be provided, or is about to provide or cause to be provided, information to the employer, the Agency, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, or any other State, local, or Federal, government authority or law enforcement agency relating to any violation of, or any act or omission that there are reasonable grounds to believe (whether or not the employee actually has such belief) to be a violation of, any provision of any law relating to the National Flood Insurance Program or any rule, order, standard, or prohibition prescribed by the Agency in connection with the National Flood Insurance Program;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0A08DFE61DF94C60A251A1AB4BBB7724"><enum>(2)</enum><text>testified or will testify in any proceeding resulting from the administration or enforcement of any provision of any law relating to the National Flood Insurance Program or any rule, order, standard, or prohibition prescribed by the Agency in connection with the National Flood Insurance program;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H58DF0E50624E4589BEB9C5301E0A14BD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>filed, instituted, or caused to be filed or instituted any proceeding under the National Flood Insurance Program; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H43F0BEED23C74FBBA99C8B24AE6B50A8"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">objected to, or refused to participate in, any activity, policy, practice, or assigned task that the employee (or other such person) reasonably believed to be in violation of any law, rule, order, standard, or prohibition, subject to the jurisdiction of, or enforceable by, the Agency in connection with the National Flood Insurance Program.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA32055D6D1FA4EF3A956803CADBD7C0D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Procedures and Timetables</header>
							<paragraph id="H726FCFBDD830489D928AA40C9B49B2AB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Complaint</header>
 <subparagraph id="H324FCF95A263479BA2DA8DC90FDE41F2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A person who believes that he or she has been discharged or otherwise discriminated against by any person in violation of subsection (a) may, not later than 180 days after the date on which such alleged violation occurs, file (or have any person file on his or her behalf) a complaint with the Administrator alleging such discharge or discrimination and identifying the person responsible for such act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H963C0B7C30BF4515B317DF2AB189AECA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Actions of Administrator</header><text>Upon receipt of such a complaint, the Administrator shall notify, in writing, the person named in the complaint who is alleged to have committed the violation, of—</text>
 <clause id="H8A975B95E6764153A71150BFA9216707"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the filing of the complaint;</text> </clause><clause id="HC8CBECC097D94BEC9389657727F79678"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the allegations contained in the complaint;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCA3C190DA25B4F80801E19DD2E7A5818"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the substance of evidence supporting the complaint; and</text> </clause><clause id="HF8EC14006D254CAA9FA5D5E7898458B8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>opportunities that will be afforded to such person under paragraph (2).</text>
									</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A4DB6DBDDA54018A8B8DC7D985B89E8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Investigation by Administrator</header>
 <subparagraph id="H1D3354DD95FD42868F62711F392620C8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of receipt of a complaint filed under paragraph (1), and after affording the complainant and the person named in the complaint who is alleged to have committed the violation that is the basis for the complaint an opportunity to submit to the Administrator a written response to the complaint and an opportunity to meet with a representative of the Administrator to present statements from witnesses, the Administrator shall—</text>
 <clause id="H81427960E11042B987C41E8D6F837CFB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>initiate an investigation and determine whether there is reasonable cause to believe that the complaint has merit; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H54A418171F45425182623325A53BE25A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>notify the complainant and the person alleged to have committed the violation of subsection (a), in writing, of such determination.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H366BC34966A64F909C6D86F10D177D34"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Notice of relief available</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Administrator concludes that there is reasonable cause to believe that a violation of subsection (a) has occurred, the Administrator shall, together with the notice under subparagraph (A)(ii), issue a preliminary order providing the relief prescribed by paragraph (4)(B).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6CF4880A4964338A51D8DF02DDD08CE"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Request for hearing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of receipt of notification of a determination of the Administrator under this paragraph, either the person alleged to have committed the violation or the complainant may file objections to the findings or preliminary order, or both, and request a hearing on the record. The filing of such objections shall not operate to stay any reinstatement remedy contained in the preliminary order. Any such hearing shall be conducted expeditiously, and if a hearing is not requested in such 30-day period, the preliminary order shall be deemed a final order that is not subject to judicial review.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7797A384F711442AADC7019AD22809AF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Grounds for determination of complaints</header>
 <subparagraph id="H3A895B4F3EE842E1A5472B9A7A67314B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall dismiss a complaint filed under this subsection, and shall not conduct an investigation otherwise required under paragraph (2), unless the complainant makes a prima facie showing that any behavior described in paragraphs (1) through (4) of subsection (a) was a contributing factor in the unfavorable personnel action alleged in the complaint.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6CB5588DB4234C939D20FFFAC6FABEBF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rebuttal evidence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding a finding by the Administrator that the complainant has made the showing required under subparagraph (A), no investigation otherwise required under paragraph (2) shall be conducted, if the employer demonstrates, by clear and convincing evidence, that the employer would have taken the same unfavorable personnel action in the absence of that behavior.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF624035327E34926A70F395AD5209B66"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Evidentiary standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator may determine that a violation of subsection (a) has occurred only if the complainant demonstrates that any behavior described in paragraphs (1) through (4) of subsection (a) was a contributing factor in the unfavorable personnel action alleged in the complaint. Relief may not be ordered under subparagraph (A) if the employer demonstrates by clear and convincing evidence that the employer would have taken the same unfavorable personnel action in the absence of that behavior.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H297B6BEE0AEC4F8A8BA9CC78993B85E9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Issuance of final orders; review procedures</header>
 <subparagraph id="HA923CD0AB80B450B978595F8361C3991"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Timing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of conclusion of any hearing under paragraph (2), the Administrator shall issue a final order providing the relief prescribed by this paragraph or denying the complaint. At any time before issuance of a final order, a proceeding under this subsection may be terminated on the basis of a settlement agreement entered into by the Administrator, the complainant, and the person alleged to have committed the violation.</text>
								</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H364F8C9C374F4512A2E2A1949B0447FC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Penalties</header>
 <clause id="H49F3A270B40444CAA9BC6AC1375DC36E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Order of Administrator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, in response to a complaint filed under paragraph (1), the Administrator determines that a violation of subsection (a) has occurred, the Administrator shall order the person who committed such violation—</text>
 <subclause id="HBE8B44C2E8214EA6B6117C59AF18E30D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to take affirmative action to abate the violation;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H4586CAED835048B99EE7AC8FA32D130D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to reinstate the complainant to his or her former position, together with compensation, including twice the amount of back pay due, and restore the terms, conditions, and privileges associated with his or her employment; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HDE9F502158294593BB5C40DC0B66CBEE"><enum>(III)</enum><text>to provide compensatory damages to the complainant.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H6CF018F3E87944EBBB75A6E2DD30EF7E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an order is issued under clause (i), the Administrator, at the request of the complainant, shall assess against the person against whom the order is issued, a sum equal to the aggregate amount of all costs and expenses (including attorney fees and expert witness fees) reasonably incurred, as determined by the Administrator, by the complainant for, or in connection with, the bringing of the complaint upon which the order was issued.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H011EEFAB90ED4112A0E9337DE5645DB3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Penalty for frivolous claims</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Administrator finds that a complaint under paragraph (1) is frivolous or has been brought in bad faith, the Administrator may award to the prevailing employer a reasonable attorney fee, not exceeding $1,000, to be paid by the complainant.</text>
								</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE06E07A135B469FBFF811ADB18F93EB"><enum>(D)</enum><header>De novo review</header>
 <clause id="HB7598C01AF0E4A5FBAEE4F9B33F54BCC"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Failure of the Administrator to act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Administrator has not issued a final order within 210 days after the date of filing of a complaint under this subsection, or within 90 days after the date of receipt of a written determination, the complainant may bring an action at law or equity for de novo review in the appropriate district court of the United States having jurisdiction, which shall have jurisdiction over such an action without regard to the amount in controversy, and which action shall, at the request of either party to such action, be tried by the court with a jury.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD44DD2B1338448CF8844D8F404722A92"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text>A proceeding under clause (i) shall be governed by the same legal burdens of proof specified in paragraph (3). The court shall have jurisdiction to grant all relief necessary to make the employee whole, including injunctive relief and compensatory damages, including—</text>
 <subclause id="H7081A603D4AB469A8A9451E5726C7776"><enum>(I)</enum><text>reinstatement with the same seniority status that the employee would have had, but for the discharge or discrimination;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H5C76F53B7D3C44EE9B9BE960C472625F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>compensation in the amount equal to twice the amount of back pay due, with interest; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H4C02F62EF5E04B60AE2333D64699E331"><enum>(III)</enum><text>compensation for any special damages sustained as a result of the discharge or discrimination, including litigation costs, expert witness fees, and reasonable attorney fees.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H767E2A09ED25440394B743B408FCD022"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Other appeals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Unless the complainant brings an action under subparagraph (D), any person adversely affected or aggrieved by a final order issued under subparagraph (A) may file a petition for review of the order in the United States Court of Appeals for the circuit in which the violation with respect to which the order was issued, allegedly occurred or the circuit in which the complainant resided on the date of such violation, not later than 60 days after the date of the issuance of the final order of the Administrator under subparagraph (A). Review shall conform to <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/7">chapter 7</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code. The commencement of proceedings under this subparagraph shall not, unless ordered by the court, operate as a stay of the order. An order of the Administrator with respect to which review could have been obtained under this subparagraph shall not be subject to judicial review in any criminal or other civil proceeding.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0942EA4076143A78D75EA7AE36321F6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Failure to comply with order</header>
 <subparagraph id="H22F23759744C4D13ADD4EB0E1E1A96B5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Actions by the Administrator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If any person has failed to comply with a final order issued under paragraph (4), the Administrator may file a civil action in the United States district court for the district in which the violation was found to have occurred, or in the United States district court for the District of Columbia, to enforce such order. In actions brought under this paragraph, the district courts shall have jurisdiction to grant all appropriate relief including injunctive relief and compensatory damages.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5DC2CCA26DA431FB1F6118C9AD14BDB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Civil actions to compel compliance</header><text>A person on whose behalf an order was issued under paragraph (4) may commence a civil action against the person to whom such order was issued to require compliance with such order. The appropriate United States district court shall have jurisdiction, without regard to the amount in controversy or the citizenship of the parties, to enforce such order.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF1651AE225D481B82B5FFAAB5B79D16"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Award of costs authorized</header><text>The court, in issuing any final order under this paragraph, may award costs of litigation (including reasonable attorney and expert witness fees) to any party, whenever the court determines such award is appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72FCE18ADDA642EFA60FE0352A13EBC2"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Mandamus proceedings</header><text>Any nondiscretionary duty imposed by this section shall be enforceable in a mandamus proceeding brought under section 1361 of title 28, United States Code.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA13FE0CF7ECC41EDB9C39F12C3EB9454"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Unenforceability of Certain Agreements</header>
 <paragraph id="H5D734F4D5FCB42518404EF7DDB2B94FA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>No waiver of rights and remedies</header><text>Except as provided under paragraph (3), and notwithstanding any other provision of law, the rights and remedies provided for in this section may not be waived by any agreement, policy, form, or condition of employment, including by any pre-dispute arbitration agreement.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9154EB8BEE1A4EE1949E405004835BB7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No pre-dispute arbitration agreements</header><text>Except as provided under paragraph (3), and notwithstanding any other provision of law, no pre-dispute arbitration agreement shall be valid or enforceable to the extent that it requires arbitration of a dispute arising under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7C46A514BCD642A4B2718157A9A7DE9E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraphs (1) and (2), an arbitration provision in a collective bargaining agreement shall be enforceable as to disputes arising under subsection (a)(4), unless the Administrator determines, by rule, that such provision is inconsistent with the purposes of this title.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H96448527F94D4057B112F345F165479C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:</text> <paragraph id="HA6F5824D8CFF4D12A074F2A73CE46881"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAB7CCDA0F1E746B8BBB1FEEB0F3DBB2B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <term>Agency</term> means the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H520B1CB293E6436C98558B714910B186"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered employee</header><text>The term <term>covered employee</term> means any individual performing tasks related to the National Flood Insurance Program, including such employees of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA17339E121134F39AA03C60BC23673EA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Agency;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8932EEC91C34A84B58A1C205F57FF25"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Department of Homeland Security;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A981C1C65544C44B623E0C0B309F3E3"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an insurance company participating in the Write Your Own program (as such term is defined in section 100202 of the Biggert-Waters Flood Insurance Reform Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4004">42 U.S.C. 4004</external-xref>));</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2AC8479EA5E14073BFC717D2A20BC63F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a third-party administrator for an insurance company described in subparagraph (C);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1837B23A68C14ADAAA4E340F8A8F7CFD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an engineer, or engineering company, engaged in providing engineering services in connection with the National Flood Insurance Program, or a sub-contractor of such an engineer or company; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4880FA786F94F6EB373124C1139229C"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a claims adjuster, or claims adjusting company, engaged in providing claims adjusting services in connection with the National Flood Insurance Program, or a sub-contractor of such an claims adjuster or company.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4B0361B3FEBF46299CFB6EFCCF7953D3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability of Flood Insurance Fund</header><text>Subsection (a) of section 1310 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4017">42 U.S.C. 4017(a)</external-xref>), as amended by section 6(b) of this Act, is further amended by inserting after paragraph (7) the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE330B42756B64ADC89AFF00C459627AA" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H0302CBC853BC4A8FA5BDA5E8090A84F7"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for penalties, relief, and costs under section 1352(b), to the extent ordered to be paid by the Administrator or any officer or employee of the Federal Emergency Management Agency;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section id="HD8E58B1781A2491DB0E15C1B4937B2F7"><enum>10.</enum><header>Engineering firm independence</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part C of chapter 2 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4081">42 U.S.C. 4081</external-xref> et seq.), as amended by the preceding provisions of this Act, is further amended by adding at the end the following new sections:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCD362335E09847E2BC1E93FDD7B93800" style="OLC">
				<section id="H2959EFAD70A74F9DA37D7AB325E20EE5"><enum>1353.</enum><header>Selection and replacement of claims adjusting and engineering companies</header>
 <subsection id="H0E4AD6BE45494D15A635050032A9E9DF"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an insurance company participating in the Write Your Own program (as such term is defined in section 100202 of the Biggert-Waters Flood Insurance Reform Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4004">42 U.S.C. 4004</external-xref>)) that engages any adjusting company or engineering company in the adjustment of a claim for losses resulting from structural damage to a property under a policy for flood insurance coverage made available under this title—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8DC726FBA93B4B6EAA87A2CC9EDF7323"><enum>(1)</enum><text>no representative of the adjusting company or engineering company may visit the property before the expiration of the 30-day period beginning upon the date that the insurance company provides notice to the owner of the property that such adjusting or engineering company has been engaged, unless the owner, in writing, consents to an earlier visit; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3E47C73E1DA141D0A85808832F8FD5EC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the policyholder submits to the insurance company written notice of disapproval of the adjusting or engineering company selected by such insurance company before a representative of the adjusting or engineering company first visits the property, such insurance company shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H03ABCAADA349465583EEB68B033A5F66"><enum>(A)</enum><text>within 30 days after the policyholder’s notification of such disapproval—</text> <clause id="HD263A625910B4F91A9133721020A18CE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>submit to the Administrator notice of the policyholders notification of such disapproval; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3C4F42A776A4420AA907371128F6647C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>submit to the policyholder a list of not less than three other adjusting or engineering companies, as the case may be, that are unaffiliated with the disapproved company to conduct the activities involved in adjusting such claim; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00DE73445D004A4894F8B4DAC52BFBEB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>replace the original adjusting or engineering company with the company from such list selected by the policyholder, if the policyholder notifies the insurance company and the Administrator, in writing, of the policyholder’s selected company within 30 days after receiving the list required under subparagraph (A).</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC70BD3E9029F4DAD874B50AE6DB67B2C"><enum>1354.</enum><header>Engineering firm independence</header>
 <subsection id="HC09CBAE3814A4550A5B7FDD4ACBEAF23"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be unlawful, in participating in the Write Your Own program (as such term is defined in section 100202 of the Biggert-Waters Flood Insurance Reform Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4004">42 U.S.C. 4004</external-xref>)), to engage in any act or practice that violates the independence of an engineering company or individual engineer providing engineering services in connection with flood insurance coverage made available under this title.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEFAE6DB349BD49488FEF5178605AD2EC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Violations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (a), acts or practices that violate the independence of an engineering company or individual engineer shall include—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4F377F24793A445A87ABBFE01F2F00DC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the preparation or submission of any engineering report in connection with a claim for damages under flood insurance coverage in which a person with an interest in the award of such damages compensates, coerces, extorts, colludes, instructs, induces, bribes, or intimidates a person, engineering firm, or other entity responsible for assessing damages for the purpose of causing the damages assigned to be based on any factor other than the independent judgment of the engineering company or individual engineer;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDAA5D3F9822647C8964785FDAFB59572"><enum>(2)</enum><text>mischaracterizing, or suborning any mischaracterization of, the damages involved in any such claim;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8F25F717A2FC490F906FA2A6D012D66A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>seeking to influence an engineer or otherwise to encourage a targeted value of damages in order to facilitate the making of a report; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H35F2AC99266447BF978D3954BA1EB860"><enum>(4)</enum><text>withholding or threatening to withhold timely payment for an engineering report or for engineering services rendered.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H727BB3CA890044CD84750E972189B993"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements of subsection (b) shall not be construed as prohibiting an insurance company participating in the Write Your Own program, a claims adjusting company, or an engineering company from asking an engineer to undertake one or more of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H4406D80F6CBB4C1BBD497186B8EF1FBC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Consider additional information.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD955A6C9B3A54ED287CF611623381E7D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Provide further detail, substantiation, or explanation for an assessment of damages.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H893008E583CC41309306917416954A0E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Correct errors in an engineering report.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5480A608007145C1BD1B3A7966AB7011"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibitions on conflicts of interest</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No engineer engaged by an insurance company participating in the Write Your Own program to assess flood damages to a property covered by flood insurance made available under this title may have an ownership or financial interest in—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF467B8948A714092B9B7658D86C104A6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>such insurance company, any claims adjusting company, or any other company, other than the company that employs such engineer, that is connected with assessing such damages; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDA1CFE44C27447DD9570832DC25A1705"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the property being assessed.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE29DAB9815B44AB58772FE3104C8ABC0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Mandatory reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An insurance company participating in the Write Your Own program which knows, upon or before submitting to the Administrator a claim for damages under flood insurance coverage made available under this title, of a violation of the independence standards under this section, may not submit such a claim unless the insurance company includes, together with such claim, a certification that the violation involved does not materially mistake the value of the damages and documentation to support such claim.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="HF5283E726E1E443585B150C68072AD58"><enum>11.</enum><header>GAO reports</header>
 <subsection id="H2FECE80A385D4F11A9772B4701657CE7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report on effects of global warming on flood insurance program solvency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the expiration of the 18-month period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Congress a report analyzing the effects of global warming on the fiscal solvency of the National Flood Insurance Program.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1EF7AD5FA9F9482AB491ABC1FD86506F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report on WYO companies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study of claims under flood insurance coverage provided through insurance companies participating in the Write Your Own program of the National Flood Insurance Program pursuant to losses resulting from Hurricane Sandy of 2012, which shall determine—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8094E1D6955E4FE68EA39C299E5B2FE8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>how much profit such insurers made pursuant to such claims;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H07CCAFE2FEF54B618352E5813EDA26A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>how many of such claims were made and processed; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB3B1806BA3274A8DA3F5669C733155BD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the amount of each such claim that was approved and paid.</text> </paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">Not later than the expiration of the 12-month period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit a report to the Congress regarding the conclusions of the study conducted pursuant to this subsection.</continuation-text></subsection></section><section id="H46222AE0BC3D46B3B828AAA76D84AF32"><enum>12.</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than the expiration of the 12-month period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall issue regulations necessary to carry out this Act and the amendments made by this Act.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


