<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1D369ED3A75749AE97CBE326AAEC1BCC" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4711 IH: Industrial Hemp Banking Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4711</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171221">December 21, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To create protections for depository institutions that provide financial services to industrial
			 hemp legitimate businesses, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HF402232AE73443E9A641F786E24603EA" style="OLC">
 <section id="H2D1E2D47849D4F2FAEFC8EE84F78325B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Industrial Hemp Banking Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H3048ED7E64B04122900223E947EB137A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Secure and fair enforcement of the banking laws</header> <subsection id="H76AFF772CCBE4CA497CE6F871F946CF3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Safe harbor for depository institutions</header><text>A Federal banking regulator may not—</text>
 <paragraph id="HABC2F93A827B42D6BBEF3CAB9BF028DB" indent="down1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">terminate or limit the deposit insurance or share insurance of a depository institution under the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1811">12 U.S.C. 1811</external-xref> et seq.) or the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1751">12 U.S.C. 1751</external-xref> et seq.) solely because the depository institution provides or has provided financial services to an industrial hemp legitimate business;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H57A388D8D204475AA4E4B5410CB65A9D" indent="down1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prohibit, penalize, or otherwise discourage a depository institution from providing financial services to an industrial hemp legitimate business or to a State or political subdivision of a State that exercises jurisdiction over industrial hemp legitimate businesses;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE249605BFBE348C580BFEB772E7DA500" indent="down1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommend, incentivize, or encourage a depository institution not to offer financial services to an account holder, or to downgrade or cancel the financial services offered to an account holder solely because—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA6F11450E59F4B959EF1BDBADCBCC2FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the account holder is the owner, operator, or employee of an industrial hemp legitimate business;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CB1A05D3E684C38B6BAF83605ECAC02"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the account holder later becomes an owner or operator of an industrial hemp legitimate business; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22BC0DF9556745508F72F3898BC479CA"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the depository institution was not aware that the account holder is the owner or operator of an industrial hemp legitimate business; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2348A3B8F3547E0A224D50B23F78D92" indent="down1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">take any adverse or corrective supervisory action on a loan made to an owner or operator of—</text> <subparagraph id="H9A90282C041443768F6DE62C521399D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an industrial hemp legitimate business, solely because the owner or operator owns or operates an industrial hemp legitimate business; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85B22C9074F34B0A8D8675352E865975"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">real estate or equipment that is leased to an industrial hemp legitimate business, solely because the owner or operator of the real estate or equipment leased the equipment or real estate to an industrial hemp legitimate business.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDEA48859209F4D4896CA6808E9EF5C1C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Protections under Federal law</header>
 <paragraph id="H4E269609BD1244D191061FE685BF35E1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In a State or a political subdivision of a State that allows for industrial hemp legitimate businesses, a depository institution that provides financial services to an industrial hemp legitimate business, and the officers, directors, and employees of that depository institution may not be held liable pursuant to any Federal law or regulation—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H359F2FF5EAF2454E9F74A10B37127510"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">solely for providing such financial services pursuant to the law or regulation of such State or political subdivision; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H51253201078444409969F6B79F0C031B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for further investing any income derived from such financial services.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F13F3FAFD894FD2AB6C4B4528B42251"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Forfeiture</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A depository institution that has a legal interest in the collateral for a loan or another financial service provided to an owner or operator of an industrial hemp legitimate business, or to an owner or operator of real estate or equipment that is leased or sold to an industrial hemp legitimate business, shall not be subject to criminal, civil, or administrative forfeiture of that legal interest pursuant to any Federal law for providing such loan or other financial service.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBE79186A69BB4452ACC4933AED25C685"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall require a depository institution to provide financial services to an industrial hemp legitimate business.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H684D966A9596446BAAEE0661A566C1A9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Requirements for filing suspicious activity reports</header><text>Section 5318(g) of title 31, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H929FE7EF0695457CB17334EE1C24B051" style="OLC"> <paragraph commented="no" id="H344906FD047C40E1B96E79FEA8CA8AB2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Requirements for industrial hemp legitimate businesses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A financial institution or any director, officer, employee, or agent of a financial institution that reports a suspicious transaction pursuant to this subsection and the reason for the report relates to an industrial hemp legitimate business (as defined in section 2 of the Industrial Hemp Banking Act), the report shall comply with appropriate guidance issued by the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network. The Secretary shall ensure that the guidance is consistent with the purpose and intent of the Industrial Hemp Banking Act and does not inhibit the provision of financial services to an industrial hemp legitimate business in a State or political subdivision of a State that allows for industrial hemp legitimate businesses.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H31C3793FE2EA43B78CA24131D9964A46"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H16185862D72544AFBDEF6BFB2FBA5914"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Depository institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>depository institution</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H31864DA6AC6F4FE08A541F6BF240B0F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a depository institution as defined in section 3(c) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813(c)</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5BC67DD56D5245A68DDBEE110298BD91"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a Federal credit union as defined in section 101 of the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1752">12 U.S.C. 1752</external-xref>); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4B9351DB95945D997169885FAA28ACB"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a State credit union as defined in section 101 of the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1752">12 U.S.C. 1752</external-xref>).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H28BF65075AA94821AD35A51C404F5B94"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal banking regulator</header><text>The term <term>Federal banking regulator</term> means each of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, the National Credit Union Administration, or any Federal agency or department that regulates banking or financial services, as determined by the Secretary of the Treasury.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H71B04A81A5F54E328AD41DACC7FDC3D8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Financial service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>financial service</term> means a financial product or service as defined in section 1002 of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5481">12 U.S.C. 5481</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7AB3FBF627B6450AA7669FEEAE2FBB49"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Industrial hemp legitimate business</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>industrial hemp legitimate business</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HC578257059F9451C979079A43CDA4986"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an institution of higher education (as defined in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>)) or a State department of agriculture that carries out an agricultural pilot program or other agricultural or academic research under which such institution of higher education or State department of agriculture, either itself or through a third party—</text>
 <clause id="H81B45EC6AB424014AF1269F8C01A56EB"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">grows or cultivates industrial hemp for purposes of research, and such research actually occurs; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2E6A07FC7F8B4B74831F10F43A11CC17"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such growing or cultivation is carried out pursuant to the laws of the State in which such institution of higher education or State department of agriculture is located;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8673170EEBEE46D891FB02FE87CB1BB7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a third party that produces, manufactures, sells, purchases, or transports industrial hemp pursuant to, or otherwise participates in, a program or research described under subparagraph (A); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD040F11460B74851A4E6E31962785F1B"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a person that engages in commerce with industrial hemp products that are exempted from the definition of a controlled substance under the Controlled Substances Act.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8263513B3F69475F8C811D2731B2B743"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, and any territory or possession of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAA991C01C32A4C78A309962167CFEF14"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Agricultural Act of 2014 definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>agricultural pilot program</term>, <term>industrial hemp</term>, and <term>State department of agriculture</term> have the meanings given those terms, respectively, under section 7606(b) of the Agricultural Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/5940">7 U.S.C. 5940(b)</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


