<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE99DD885ACA44CCA8D17D43A7873C443" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2781 RH: Ensuring Veteran Enterprise Participation in Strategic Sourcing Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
		<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 182</calendar>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2781</legis-num>
		<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 115–250]</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20170606">June 6, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000628">Mr. Dunn</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HVR00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<action><action-date date="20170724">July 24, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</cosponsor> and <cosponsor name-id="B001301">Mr. Bergman</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action>
			<action-date date="20170724">July 24, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the
			 Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
			<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction>
			<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on June 6, 2017</action-instruction>
		</action>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-desc display="yes"><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to certify the sufficient participation of small
			 business concerns owned and controlled by veterans and small business
			 concerns owned by veterans with service-connected disabilities in
			 contracts under the Federal Strategic Sourcing Initiative, and for other
			 purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body changed="added" committee-id="HVR00" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H9BE56DF71CB94779833E997E6F170A53" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE09B1FF1308A439CB6CD4CED525802A1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ensuring Veteran Enterprise Participation in Strategic Sourcing Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H6FD133B0905D4B0E9C8B38D6CD2366DE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Secretary of Veterans Affairs certification of sufficient participation of small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans and small business concerns owned by veterans with service-connected disabilities in contracts under the Federal Strategic Sourcing Initiative</header> <subsection id="HDA94A31B6C6C44F28F5172AF837B1EB4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Certification required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate certification in writing that with respect to each contract (except for domestic delivery services) awarded under the Federal Strategic Sourcing Initiative (managed by the Office of Federal Procurement Policy) a sufficient number of small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans and a sufficient number of small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans with service-connected disabilities are represented within each category.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H01FE3D9DC2024EB7845FD65D23B35F08"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Insufficient representation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary determines that the representation by small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans or small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans with service-connected disabilities within a category of the contracts awarded under such Federal Strategic Sourcing Initiative is not a sufficient number, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4224C00845104922BE83C9AB8D8ED436"><enum>(1)</enum><text>consult with the Administrator of the General Services Administration to increase the number of such concerns awarded contracts under such category; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H01099E49D12E4A34949D174193256BED"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require the Department of Veterans Affairs to stop awarding orders under that category of the Initiative, effective on the date of such determination.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA5D264C961E84D05BCE6298CC3FC2C7F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H765320B94B1C4866821F30490AED7A74"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The terms <term>small business concern owned and controlled by veterans</term> and <term>small business concern owned and controlled by veterans with service-connected disabilities</term> have the meaning given such terms in section 8127(k) of title 38, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3C71A5AD331248CBA1B3CC1CA37570BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>category</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H93C42EEA526246B1BB9DBAB990696FCF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a type of supply or service for which a suite of contracts has been established under the Federal Strategic Sourcing Initiative; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45613A82A6B041409DD8B37FA3920FEE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any further subdivision or grouping within such a suite of contracts.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H620C481954A34B3595B1DDAB12801A5E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>sufficient number</term>, with respect to a type of business concern, means not fewer than two and enough to maximize the percentage of orders entered into by the Secretary with such business concerns, as determined by the Secretary.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
	<endorsement display="yes">
		<action-date date="20170724">July 24, 2017</action-date>
		<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the
			 Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill>


