<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H8CAB47E2AA2549B0B9C69D9EEF6B0518" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4118 IH: Master Limited Partnerships Parity Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4118</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171025">October 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000592">Mr. Poe of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="A000369">Mr. Amodei</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001166">Mr. McNerney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to extend the publicly traded partnership ownership
			 structure to energy power generation projects and transportation fuels,
			 and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HA5A5D0FBAA12401285F5E26CD74E131C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H44D4AA28BDD448D983B3B85813B83E92" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Master Limited Partnerships Parity Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HE796C9AB473D4B4B8FD2A97891691CF0" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Extension of publicly traded partnership ownership structure to energy power generation projects, transportation fuels, and related energy activities</header> <subsection id="HF1C741E8D8714ACE8F088147E13F6E57"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (E) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7704">section 7704(d)(1)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8B7F839847724C2BAA582DE09477C31F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>income and gains derived from the exploration</quote> and inserting</text> <quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H76ADA9A5F1BA49A590ACD67F10B9FC63" style="OLC"> <text>income and gains derived from the following:</text><clause id="HDBED37C906BF43ACAEB7EE19B47A5ABF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Minerals, natural resources, etc</header><text>The exploration</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBC9D855CA01B4EE9AE3CA2A6BDB47534"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or</quote> before <quote>industrial source</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3AFF06D30B104E0BB97F3FF942A2B240"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting a period after <quote>carbon dioxide</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBBF5C96F21E24939B2B44DD2CFEF9A6B"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>, or the transportation or storage</quote> and all that follows and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H58E53E544F2B4FB79514988EE8C669DE" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H753DD7025B4244BCADEC3AFC87362301"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Renewable energy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The generation of electric power (including the leasing of tangible personal property used for such generation) exclusively utilizing any resource described in section 45(c)(1) or energy property described in section 48 (determined without regard to any termination date), or in the case of a facility described in paragraph (3) or (7) of section 45(d) (determined without regard to any placed in service date or date by which construction of the facility is required to begin), the accepting or processing of such resource.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H479543DB0E0C477882D9586173FF37BA"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Energy storage property</header><text>The sale of electric power, capacity, resource adequacy, demand response capabilities, or ancillary services that is produced or made available from any equipment or facility (operating as a single unit or as an aggregation of units) the principal function of which is to—</text>
 <subclause id="H28CF2FE7EC1642EBB2C94BE91CF97026"><enum>(I)</enum><text>use mechanical, chemical, electrochemical, hydroelectric, or thermal processes to store energy that was generated at one time for conversion to electricity at a later time, or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H2DEE381DE3EB4DC2953A91C3DB9D0DDE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>store thermal energy for direct use for heating or cooling at a later time in a manner that avoids the need to use electricity at that later time.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H2BD77B480AC845989C00BECF04B284AD"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Combined heat and power</header><text>The generation, storage, or distribution of thermal energy exclusively utilizing property described in section 48(c)(3) (determined without regard to subparagraphs (B) and (D) thereof and without regard to any placed in service date).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H59DE67CCBC07435AAFBCC112041D57CF"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Renewable thermal energy</header><text>The generation, storage, or distribution of thermal energy exclusively using any resource described in section 45(c)(1) or energy property described in clause (i) or (iii) of section 48(a)(3)(A).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H48855E454DD54A9288667C6745E64DB6"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Waste heat to power</header><text>The use of recoverable waste energy, as defined in section 371(5) of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6341">42 U.S.C. 6341(5)</external-xref>) (as in effect on the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Master Limited Partnerships Parity Act</short-title>).</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDEB0776ECEC54CC3B0484A90FA9775BB"><enum>(vii)</enum><header>Renewable fuel infrastructure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The storage or transportation of any fuel described in subsection (b), (c), (d), or (e) of section 6426.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB005AF69E1B443F29E9C9B8DBCFC4952"><enum>(viii)</enum><header>Renewable fuels</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The production, storage, or transportation of any renewable fuel described in section 211(o)(1)(J) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7545">42 U.S.C. 7545(o)(1)(J)</external-xref>) (as in effect on the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Master Limited Partnerships Parity Act</short-title>) or section 40A(d)(1).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8919FB9AC0144E218C545601135BC026"><enum>(ix)</enum><header>Fuel derived from captured carbon dioxide</header><text>The production, storage, or transportation of any fuel which—</text> <subclause id="HE88205CF5AD34ACA8EA6CC7986ED800F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>uses carbon dioxide captured from an anthropogenic source or the atmosphere as its primary feedstock, and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H2F63A752DB074426B2877E6AF6963EEA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is determined by the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, to achieve a reduction of not less than a 60 percent in lifecycle greenhouse gas emissions (as defined in section 211(o)(1)(H) of the Clean Air Act) compared to baseline lifecycle greenhouse gas emissions (as defined in section 211(o)(1)(C) of such Act).</text>
							</subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">This clause shall not apply to any fuel which uses as its primary feedstock carbon dioxide which is
 deliberately released from naturally-occurring subsurface springs.</continuation-text></clause><clause id="H78BD9DC730E740BFA084472AC0778750"><enum>(x)</enum><header>Renewable chemicals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The production, storage, or transportation of any qualifying renewable chemical (as defined in paragraph (6)).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6B5AC96966734D12B0FEBF9F4CD1F294"><enum>(xi)</enum><header>Energy efficient buildings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The audit and installation through contract or other agreement of any energy efficient building property described in section 179D(c)(1).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H13380C9419764F228BBC6FDA1C411A7F"><enum>(xii)</enum><header>Gasification with sequestration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The production of any product or the generation of electric power from a project—</text> <subclause id="H29F26A625F384ADB92B2C09CA39214D9"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">which meets the requirements of subparagraphs (A) and (B) of section 48B(c)(1), and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE2004845A22A4A0CAFA2F1C799E54A5D"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less than 75 percent of the total carbon dioxide emissions of which is qualified carbon dioxide (as defined in section 45Q(b)) which is disposed of or utilized as provided in paragraph (7).</text>
							</subclause></clause><clause id="H3D1490530E23464A94131A0D0B076E7E"><enum>(xiii)</enum><header>Carbon capture and sequestration</header>
 <subclause id="H7B2D21271BDB480E8356997A58C6ECAE"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Power generation facilities</header><text>The generation or storage of electric power (including associated income from the sale or marketing of energy, capacity, resource adequacy, and ancillary services) produced from any power generation facility which is, or from any power generation unit within, a qualified facility which is described in section 45Q(c) and not less than 50 percent (30 percent in the case of a facility or unit placed in service before January 1, 2017) of the total carbon dioxide emissions of which is qualified carbon dioxide which is disposed of or utilized as provided in paragraph (7).</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HCBE526CC8B214AE0B2DC33D9F5D7550E"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Other facilities</header><text>The sale of any good or service from any facility (other than a power generation facility) which is a qualified facility described in section 45Q(c) and the captured qualified carbon dioxide (as so defined) of which is disposed of as provided in paragraph (7).</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEE60734F148D48BCA255D8F3EB861678"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Renewable chemical</header>
 <paragraph id="HC4CE493FB67F4A2EB19CF0827312D4D7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 7704(d) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H163C5D20BDB940D08566E231C167C0C6" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HBA93BFD63DB5428FA3A24A5DFA4C8E92"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Qualifying renewable chemical</header> <subparagraph id="HA520DA9D7E544EFDA7E4FFA3FAC5D6DD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>qualifying renewable chemical</term> means any renewable chemical (as defined in section 9001 of the Agriculture Act of 2014)—</text>
 <clause id="H9AB0CACE46AA414C9AE14A1CE648D04C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>which is produced by the taxpayer in the United States or in a territory or possession of the United States,</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBB94C914612345DCA1633372954100EE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>which is the product of, or reliant upon, biological conversion, thermal conversion, or a combination of biological and thermal conversion, of renewable biomass (as defined in section 9001(13) of the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002),</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA5C4ED31E6CC4B979AB9B61126938847"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the biobased content of which is 95 percent or higher,</text> </clause><clause id="H234A155BE8854939B8BD13611088B549"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>which is sold or used by the taxpayer—</text>
 <subclause id="H934C76021F9843969952513969EA7161"><enum>(I)</enum><text>for the production of chemical products, polymers, plastics, or formulated products, or</text> </subclause><subclause id="HD4B8EE7A4DCB497A868E8E452611F379"><enum>(II)</enum><text>as chemicals, polymers, plastics, or formulated products,</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HE626274470E04D229395944F35181AD2"><enum>(v)</enum><text>which is not sold or used for the production of any food, feed, or fuel, and</text> </clause><clause id="H9C22C120E5F542E88186C7B34339B942"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>which is—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4564CC5B889E426CB2F1D388DF5C68D0"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">acetic acid, acrylic acid, acyl glutamate, adipic acid, algae oils, algae sugars, 1,4-butanediol (BDO), iso-butanol, n-butanol, C10 and higher hydrocarbons produced from olefin metathesis, carboxylic acids produced from olefin metathesis, cellulosic sugar, diethyl methylene malonate, dodecanedioic acid (DDDA), esters produced from olefin metathesis, ethyl acetate, ethylene glycol, farnesene, 2,5-furandicarboxylic acid, gamma-butyrolactone, glucaric acid, hexamethylenediamine (HMD), 3-hydroxy propionic acid, iso-butene, isoprene, itaconic acid, lactide, levulinic acid, polyhydroxyalkonate (PHA), polylactic acid (PLA), polyethylene furanoate (PEF), polyethylene terephthalate (PET), polyitaconic acid, polyols from vegetable oils, poly(xylitan levulinate ketal), 1,3-propanediol, 1,2-propanediol, rhamnolipids, short and medium chain carboxylic acids produced from anaerobic digestion, succinic acid, terephthalic acid, vegetable fatty acid derived from ethyl esters containing vegetable oil, or <italic>p</italic>-Xylene, or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H8C4EE0A9DF80477E86E685C4C1DF3B38"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any chemical not described in clause (i) which is a chemical listed by the Secretary for purposes of this paragraph.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6863FB40987D4741897F893E3555BE52"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Biobased content</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A)(iii), the term <term>biobased content percentage</term> means, with respect to any renewable chemical, the biobased content of such chemical (expressed as a percentage) determined by testing representative samples using the American Society for Testing and Materials (ASTM) D6866.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE66F39B282D44AA2B914E9ABDF8E9A20"><enum>(2)</enum><header>List of other qualifying renewable chemicals</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary's delegate), in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, shall establish a program to consider applications from taxpayers for the listing of chemicals under section 7874(d)(6)(A)(vi)(II) (as added by paragraph (1)).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5D8F7FB231DE4746974BD56E5E97548B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Disposal and utilization of captured carbon dioxide</header><text>Section 7704(d) of such Code, as amended by subsection (b), is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB51A86D872CE4A759E7DDE61748FC545" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H230E5A0D5A1E429E88DD54304963FC14"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Disposal and utilization of captured carbon dioxide</header><text>For purposes of clauses (xii)(III) and (xiii)(I) of paragraph (1)(E), carbon dioxide is disposed of or utilized as provided in this paragraph if such carbon dioxide is—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDEC69E2B18234BBF9118AE7EAA51A9A2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>placed into secure geological storage (as determined under section 45Q(d)(2)),</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H20359FC758C34362A15F45865DDC1693"><enum>(B)</enum><text>used as a tertiary injectant (as defined in section 45Q(d)(3)) in a qualified enhanced oil or natural gas recovery project (as defined in section 45Q(d)(4)) and placed into secure geological storage (as so determined),</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB52F0D1F9BD14A56BFB7B9D877863A64"><enum>(C)</enum><text>fixated through photosynthesis or chemosynthesis (such as through the growing of algae or bacteria),</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0D05D42640D4E4CBCE240CA7BB0BE15"><enum>(D)</enum><text>chemically converted to a material or chemical compound in which it is securely stored, or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4C37CEE50EF4DE38433DDD88EE34DB1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>used for any other purpose which the Secretary determines has the potential to strengthen or significantly develop a competitive market for carbon dioxide captured from man-made sources.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8E32562B3F624C4EA6474FDFFDDC3428"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act, in taxable years ending after such date.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


