<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HAD7748DB11A6466A92892B939A427F34" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2625 IH: Wounded Warrior Service Dog Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2625</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170524">May 24, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001170">Ms. Shea-Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001037">Mr. Capuano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001049">Mr. Clay</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000486">Ms. Roybal-Allard</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000170">Mr. O'Rourke</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000570">Mr. Ben Ray Luján of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000554">Mr. LoBiondo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000620">Mr. Delaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a grant program to encourage the use of assistance dogs by certain members of the
			 Armed Forces and veterans.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H2A5E297EEEE04119869A356D9D5B41B3" style="OLC">
 <section id="H3DC028E3755E4F8EBBF5BC4E35FBCB59" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Wounded Warrior Service Dog Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H1A76377088934ED78C0D4CBA653E0F4C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Wounded Warrior K–9 Corps</header> <subsection id="HD5EEF52049DA469B921A895D4136E5B3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations provided for such purpose, the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall jointly establish a program, to be known as the <quote>K–9 Service Corps Program</quote>, to award competitive grants to nonprofit organizations to assist such organizations in the planning, designing, establishing, or operating (or any combination thereof) of programs to provide assistance dogs to covered members and veterans.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H7F565C5A9E4A4BCCBC4F01092EAA1207"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header>
 <paragraph id="HD8E88D04695D453ABEB9126156566B0E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The recipient of a grant under this section shall use the grant to carry out programs that provide assistance dogs to covered members and veterans who have a disability described in paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCF044081A84442AD8576507D5200706D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Disability</header><text>A disability described in this paragraph is any of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HD1596CFE315B492E9FA4D140C3F4EF7C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Blindness or visual impairment.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05A5AFB7E2334664A679BBBD6220E88E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Loss of use of a limb, paralysis, or other significant mobility issues.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68B98E5B7FA14F1F9C7CF60AC540B6C3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Loss of hearing.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E58F2C5CEBC4DD0AB7568A4D0D4CADC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Traumatic brain injury.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD01126D2FC9C4528AEC5714EE81D7492"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Post-traumatic stress disorder.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB10AA6E81501499F8E2766FBFD15C59D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Any other disability that the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs consider appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5EC257E118745AEA5D32EAF8E3A1A0F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Timing of award</header><text>The Secretaries may not award a grant under this section to reimburse a recipient for costs previously incurred by the recipient in carrying out a program to provide assistance dogs to covered members and veterans unless the recipient elects for the award to be such a reimbursement.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA7A65653462149D6BDC34254F38DF41B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, a nonprofit organization shall submit an application to the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs may require. Such application shall include—</text>
 <paragraph id="H718486AF81B041AA91930ED709C3413F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a proposal for the evaluation required by subsection (d); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC6F8E35E75854A99A3724AAAA60E1B21"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD3DC4D2F4C9E43469E77B20798D73455"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the training that will be provided by the organization to covered members and veterans;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H762840C51E2541C89A5BC46287E3FE1B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the training of dogs that will serve as assistance dogs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F2491B371064C6BA5215B7F6FEC679B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the aftercare services that the organization will provide for such dogs and covered members and veterans;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA9729B1C0B745B28B8407437B58ABEE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the plan for publicizing the availability of such dogs through a targeted marketing campaign to covered members and veterans;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62A756F6F6254CD7BB6E9BFE2ACDDF75"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the recognized expertise of the organization in breeding and training such dogs;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H40804683E126472989156FF68220E322"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the commitment of the organization to humane standards for animals; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E960F02BDCE4F25B7D054EFACD349D9"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the experience of the organization with working with military medical treatment facilities or medical facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H03DCF281C5B54BCA881B17838DA19B37"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a statement certifying that the organization—</text> <subparagraph id="HF0446AB1789F42D9A3EF707AF220F68C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is accredited by Assistance Dogs International, the International Guide Dog Federation, or another similar widely recognized accreditation organization that the Secretaries determine has accreditation standards that meet or exceed the standards of Assistance Dogs International and the International Guide Dog Federation; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4D6F889B27554BF2B201AE4CC8127132"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is a candidate for such accreditation or otherwise meets or exceeds such standards, as determined by the Secretaries.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCB0EB952B92043F08C28DAE80092A9B7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>The Secretary shall require each recipient of a grant to use a portion of the funds made available through the grant to conduct an evaluation of the effectiveness of the activities carried out through the grant by such recipient.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4B6E55CC6998421F811A937DA3E1C3B7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HFD3C2FE7BFE44BABAEA2DADE9AD575EE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Assistance dog</header><text>The term <term>assistance dog</term> means a dog specifically trained to perform physical tasks to mitigate the effects of a disability described in subsection (b)(2), except that the term does not include a dog specifically trained for comfort or personal defense.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3B176167B5214022A94F3C1895539F52"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered members and veterans</header><text>The term <term>covered members and veterans</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H544765FFF249419894E08C1182400C9C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to a member of the Armed Forces, such member who is—</text>
 <clause id="HC59268A3C68F4D9E880A3FD129353097"><enum>(i)</enum><text>receiving medical treatment, recuperation, or therapy under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/55">chapter 55</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H14CBBEF7FD8343919F4A59D73C17A0A6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in medical hold or medical holdover status; or</text> </clause><clause id="H9FDB32767E6A451D8EF8E4FFFCACE1C3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>covered under section 1202 or 1205 of title 10, United States Code; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB838BBD2B4E949BA857BD4737E9C3202"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to a veteran, a veteran who is enrolled in the health care system established under section 1705(a) of title 38, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBFD6E42E24B84835B8DB84EABCC11CDE"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


