<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H3873D0FF087C4E9FA318AC2815E1BDE0" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3885 IH: Senior Citizen Protection Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3885</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170928">September 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000435">Ms. Ros-Lehtinen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Attorney General to establish guidelines for a model elder abuse registry and to
			 provide grants to States for establishing and operating such a registry,
			 and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HF56B04FFBA9F46B7BFE2E2B16BB09BE2" style="OLC">
 <section id="H6FA7EB026E554099B0B59112BDF1CEB6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short Title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Senior Citizen Protection Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HAA436E2E79F9400E9DC3D8D334DD3ADE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Model elder Abuse Registry</header> <subsection id="HAFE1B7B53A534FE7A90D96892D575A9D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall establish guidelines for States to design and implement elder abuse registries.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4F6E5F58B1574E99A277A25566CBCE7E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The guidelines established under subsection (a) shall be designed to provide guidance to States to do the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HE1B0191C71E0449E948E8C09DAE36969"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identify which types of individuals to place on an elder abuse registry, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H035EF7EF05C84E61A1B97D36711E40C2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">individuals convicted of a crime involving elder abuse; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25D67D28A30D406D9074F522841A49E0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">individuals found by a State agency to have committed elder abuse.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4654453FC52C473AAD6FDEB1D0E2C2D6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Provide, for each individual placed on the registry, the information to be included for such individual in the elder abuse registry, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD796E93BDED649D7B32E28BA3C20BE9C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the circumstances surrounding the elder abuse;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H314B5D32F53B471D81AF49B1DC5AD01B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the type of abuse committed; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96EE398594E347FBBE490AC49D1FC4B9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the relationship of the individual to the victim.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2CF0C8F417534AB4B92B33D0892DAB8A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Prior to placement on the registry, notify each individual to be placed on the registry of such individual’s placement on the registry.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC558617256354274B8043998548C050A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Provide, for each individual to be placed on the registry, the opportunity to appeal placement on the registry within a reasonable period of time before such individual’s placement on the registry.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H690EB6054D92492587FB412F158A6054"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Provide the duration of placement on the registry.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFDD048DE27DA4495A0E96E464402E8B3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Provide for the removal of individuals who should no longer be placed on the registry.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H341E8DD72DE140F9BBDC951C046B2160"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Make elder abuse registries readily accessible to the public, including by—</text> <subparagraph id="HFB05E9C6B683453B887CBEEFCA73527E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>posting the information contained in the registry onto the Internet; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H15E8B70A61CA4A949B0C603DE8F151F1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>making the registry readily searchable.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFC00690ABEB7415B9C1AC14B4B13A354"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing such guidelines under subsection (a), the Attorney General shall consult with the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the appropriate public and private entities.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HDEAECFB16AE747DC9EDC8A48F9226E42"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grants</header>
 <subsection id="HF6896C2D446545B888113025D95545D2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General may make grants to States for establishing and operating elder abuse registries.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBE65A341EE294DBD9CF7BFE5E2B1D456"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State may apply for a grant under this section at such time and in such form as the Attorney General may require.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H94DB2FAA759E4787A3D0187211EA6EDB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of Funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The recipient of a grant under this section shall use the funds to—</text> <paragraph id="HD09E7C9B9B0440E4B2CFBCFE5F488CDE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish an elder abuse registry that substantially conforms to the guidelines established pursuant to section 2; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2B545B74226940E493C217A2E63A03C4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enact legislation requiring entities that provide health care services or long-term care to elders in the State to check the State elder abuse registry before hiring individuals for such services to ensure that such individuals have not been found by a State agency to have committed elder abuse.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H44D2CFC91E1F47F39CDEF8CE92222129"><enum>4.</enum><header>National elder Abuse Registry</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Beginning, not less than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall establish and maintain a national database of content from State elder abuse registries that substantially conforms to the guidelines established pursuant to section 2.</text>
 </section><section id="HF9B352E65DDD457082F54EE8E0AEF07A"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H82530FB551804BF08825C8D6DAD14BAE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>abuse</term> means the knowing infliction of physical or psychological harm or the knowing deprivation of goods or services that are necessary to meet essential needs or to avoid physical or psychological harm.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H548B53C3C9A5494DBE12A084E0A9E6F2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>caregiver</term> means an individual who has the responsibility for the care of an elder, either voluntarily, by contract, by receipt of payment for care, or as a result of the operation of law, and means a family member or other individual who provides (on behalf of such individual or of a public or private agency, organization, or institution) compensated or uncompensated care to an elder who needs supportive services in any setting.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H230D85F7C3A44E3AAD0F488259169CFE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>elder</term> means an individual aged 65 years or older.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2C0435C5A0AA4A2FADBEDCD373FA0E2E"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>elder abuse</term> means the abuse, neglect, mistreatment, or exploitation of an elder.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H46C8F7E01A684A29834912F9D1C14737"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <term>exploitation</term> means the fraudulent or otherwise illegal, unauthorized, or improper act or process of an individual, including a caregiver or fiduciary, that uses the resources of an elder for monetary or personal benefit, profit, or gain, or that results in depriving an elder of rightful access to, or use of, benefits, resources, belongings, or assets.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA1E2E82785304859A0ECDD34336D7F3A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The term <term>fiduciary</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="HBC2F7968BC33454D88F52DE53F9FBDDF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a person or entity with the legal responsibility—</text>
 <clause id="HE22E2D4B7B9E43898A60E2A5BB3FEBBC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to make decisions on behalf of and for the benefit of another person; and</text> </clause><clause id="H1A6C7B8961B14A7DAF347A548CA6BBE0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to act in good faith and with fairness; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H95D054122F274ED4A96143726F3C4F26"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a trustee, a guardian, a conservator, an executor, an agent under a financial power of attorney or health care power of attorney, or a representative payee.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD704D1A22E8642EF8F2FBB1921ABEECE"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The term <term>neglect</term> means the knowing failure of a caregiver or fiduciary to provide the goods or services that are necessary to maintain the health or safety of an elder.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3FD95396CE1244E2BACB0EB3AF76890B"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>mistreatment</term> means the inappropriate use of medications, isolation, or physical or chemical restraints.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H091738598A894517A382F95152AA2412"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means any of the 50 States, or the District of Columbia.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


