<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF74C9F13D0DC45D49196F37B5F1A2A99" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1162 : No Hero Left Untreated Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1162</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date date="20170524">May 24, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a pilot program to provide access to
			 magnetic EEG/EKG-guided resonance therapy to veterans.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H685212E647ED4528983654D51345E84D" style="OLC">
 <section id="HB0026646597240B2A499FF35BAA13F66" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Hero Left Untreated Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HEF38AE8A418043F6B70E04143F918ECF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H535477CF31F149F6BE9A07628AD9EC16"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Magnetic EEG/EKG-guided resonance therapy has successfully treated more than 400 veterans with post-traumatic stress disorder, traumatic brain injury, military sexual trauma, chronic pain, and opiate addiction.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1E8F12F69D594E3C9170B31F5CB0C987"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recent clinical trials and randomized, placebo-controlled, double-blind studies have produced promising measurable outcomes in the evolution of magnetic EEG/EKG-guided resonance therapy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA72EB241C32A4CBEB68602BC296E9079"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The outcomes described in paragraph (2) have resulted in escalating demand from returning members of the Armed Forces and veterans who are seeking access to magnetic EEG/EKG-guided resonance therapy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD9D782EB5B854ECA86050DCF04D816A6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Congress recognizes the importance of initiating innovative pilot programs that demonstrate the use and effectiveness of new treatment options for post-traumatic stress disorder, traumatic brain injury, military sexual trauma, chronic pain, and opiate addiction.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H6AB2159779A2458AA3012A5D1BD09DDB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Magnetic EEG/EKG-guided resonance therapy pilot program</header>
 <subsection id="H2BE457E6E93145B084CB9338F8A8E060"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Pilot program</header><text>Commencing not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall carry out a pilot program to provide access to magnetic EEG/EKG-guided resonance therapy to treat veterans suffering from post-traumatic stress disorder, traumatic brain injury, military sexual trauma, chronic pain, or opiate addiction.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFDB33A03E65C420FB5D0C71E96400135"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Locations</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out the pilot program under subsection (a) at not more than two facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB223E3B8662049959CDEBF6A3E7F3205"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Participants</header><text>In carrying out the pilot program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall provide access to magnetic EEG/EKG-guided resonance therapy to not more than 50 veterans.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2B27F271E4324EAEA80A3FFF58308437"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out the pilot program under subsection (a) for a 1-year period.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H7931C8927170488581AEAAE60E0DEAC0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the termination of the pilot program under subsection (d), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the pilot program.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFCB77A0C5CBB43F5AAB3A30E7F38491E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>No authorization of appropriations</header><text>No additional amounts are authorized to be appropriated to carry out the requirements of this section. Such requirements shall be carried out using amounts authorized under provisions of law other than this section.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20170523">Passed the House of Representatives May 23, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill>


