<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H332EDBA3E67D453397D68B80D4BB7439" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 575 IH: Cosmetic Modernization Amendments of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 575</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170113">January 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to establish new procedures and requirements for
			 the registration of cosmetic manufacturing establishments, the submission
			 of cosmetic and ingredient statements, and the reporting of serious
			 cosmetic adverse events, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H33F93485C3624CF59657611E1DE195F5" style="OLC">
		<section id="H0A0B70992DE04CC384D67C4995CBB869" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title and references</header>
 <subsection id="HEFAF73E8288547DAB4CAB013613CCB16"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cosmetic Modernization Amendments of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HAF61E4CE0DF143A59576025342014C80"><enum>(b)</enum><header>References to the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act</header><text>Except as otherwise specified, whenever in this Act an amendment is expressed in terms of an amendment to a section or other provision, the reference shall be considered to be made to a section or other provision of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/301">21 U.S.C. 301</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H4465B996E6C741908DE22A6FD81C8346"><enum>2.</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> <toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration"> <toc-entry idref="H0A0B70992DE04CC384D67C4995CBB869" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title and references.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H4465B996E6C741908DE22A6FD81C8346" level="section">Sec. 2. Table of contents.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H5EEFCF1D99E14FFF8D1CE9FA3C8E66F2" level="section">Sec. 3. Definitions.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HCCCFF95DE64241C4B3E3D17E3E2BFFBD" level="section">Sec. 4. Registration of cosmetic manufacturing establishments.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H4C6ADF014A2E4D4A9E816F45BE7706C4" level="section">Sec. 5. Cosmetic and ingredient statement.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HD35932CD9AAD43F0AE4AC9848519B230" level="section">Sec. 6. Serious and unexpected adverse event reporting for cosmetics.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H6579A1DBA4BD4F0AAF9B930FE1DA5C49" level="section">Sec. 7. Good manufacturing practice.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HE05EF8974C284D13A1A872DD09DC08A4" level="section">Sec. 8. Safety substantiation for cosmetic ingredients and nonfunctional constituents.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H8E2A6F5564F14CAD9F8468B2368535EC" level="section">Sec. 9. National Cosmetic Regulatory Databank.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HFBCCA86902C547DE908B5C616B57E530" level="section">Sec. 10. Special rules.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HDC5A250C05014876A3C71968CBDFC217" level="section">Sec. 11. Prohibited acts.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H213A84DC545849E18C5D313C1505EBE2" level="section">Sec. 12. National uniformity for cosmetics.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H5F91DF0E1B62438B8F61398E2E35B31C" level="section">Sec. 13. Importation.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H132E2F440EC34FCF85A9B87F7A802D78" level="section">Sec. 14. Effective dates.</toc-entry></toc> </section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5EEFCF1D99E14FFF8D1CE9FA3C8E66F2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Chapter VI (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/361">21 U.S.C. 361</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFD0E22F01DE847B187A8417843549CBF" style="OLC">
 <section id="H9A1F49D807674D33AD90767BADC8F322"><enum>604.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this chapter:</text> <paragraph id="HB912F8725B1149B9A90CFA3329C7227F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Cosmetic</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 201(i), for purposes of this section and sections 601(f), 605, 606, 607, 608, and 801(a), the term <term>cosmetic</term> includes only articles described in section 201(i)(1).</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="HF714C3AE74374ED2B4BA272CCDE0B622"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Establishment</header>
 <subparagraph id="H1B18BB8F43F24545A1B265B05B475034"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>establishment</term> means a place of business where a cosmetic is manufactured, without further processing outside or within the United States.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H18BD3EB58AE744A9B540F7A9EA9E9BF8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A cosmetic shall not be considered to have undergone further processing for purposes of subparagraph (A) solely on the basis that packaging or other labeling was added or changed or that any similar activity of a de minimis nature was carried out with respect to the cosmetic.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3AEEBF864DF4F58B94C7DE64336CB30"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>domestic establishment</term> means an establishment location in any State.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB10A0C5125FA4B8B8A0191ABDBD1A533"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>foreign establishment</term> means an establishment location outside the United States.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC7840D3FEFB44B8AF2BF2B3EAF07AC4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Safe; safety</header>
 <subparagraph id="H289CD593A38944CE97A657F78FAD608F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The terms <term>safe</term> and <term>safety</term>, with respect to a cosmetic, mean the cosmetic does not present a significant risk of serious illness or injury to humans under the conditions of use recommended or suggested in the labeling of the cosmetic, including the limitation of <quote>for professional use</quote> only.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE22985814CB486F9643FB48DCF782EE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term <term>professional</term> means an individual who—</text> <clause id="H8411A968871C41FEBA392E98F038F424"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is licensed by an official State authority to practice in the field of cosmetology, nail care, barbering, and or esthetics; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBEF0A79F9B9B461EB869A3CE37230E6A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is in compliance with all requirements of the State for such licensing.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section><section id="HCCCFF95DE64241C4B3E3D17E3E2BFFBD"><enum>4.</enum><header>Registration of cosmetic manufacturing establishments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Chapter VI (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/361">21 U.S.C. 361</external-xref> et seq.), as amended by section 3, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="HFBCDE20106DD4BEAB8DD412B7CB592D1" style="OLC">
				<section id="H82FE0B36588D48999434A3EFC09849B0"><enum>605.</enum><header>Registration of cosmetic manufacturing establishments</header>
					<subsection id="H321FA36824EB4920B040C8ECE9B2782D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <paragraph id="HB9B1910FFA16403D8A4BED266B733CD1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Registration</header><text>The Secretary shall by regulation require that every domestic and foreign establishment engaged in the manufacture of a cosmetic intended to be sold in the United States that is not exempt under subsection (e) be registered with the Secretary within 60 business days after the first commercial sale of a cosmetic in the United States. If a cosmetic is processed in more than one establishment, registration shall be required under this section only for the establishment that performs the final portion of the manufacturing operation. The single registration shall cover all such cosmetics manufactured by the establishment. The registration shall state only the name of the company or other organization name of the establishment, the city, street address, State, and country of the establishment, and the title, email address, and telephone number for the office within the establishment that is responsible for submitting and maintaining the registration. For a foreign establishment, the registration shall include the contact information for the initial United States agent of the establishment.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H73A8E9446ABF4E91AB634DBDC9F2D381"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Unique number</header><text>The Secretary shall establish and provide to each registrant under this section a unique cosmetic establishment registration number within 15 business days after receiving the registration. If the Secretary does not provide a unique cosmetic establishment registration number within such 15 business days, any requirement under this Act for such number shall be deemed to be inapplicable until 30 business days after such number is received by the person who submitted the registration. Where more than one person registers the same establishment, the Secretary shall provide only one unique establishment registration number for the establishment. The unique cosmetic establishment number shall not be required to be included in cosmetic labeling.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0487C0975BC445F4A7ABFC534709A050"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Maintenance</header><text>The information required in a registration under subsection (a) or in an existing registration under subsection (e)(1)(A) shall be maintained as current and accurate by the registrant by withdrawing or amending the registration within 60 business days after the information becomes no longer current and accurate.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD278D8FABEB14423BDD97E3D79EA4DC5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>The Secretary shall enforce this section under section 301(eee) and shall not suspend or revoke a registration under this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBF509F9C173540439A338BCB6F47879D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>List</header><text>The Secretary shall compile and maintain an up-to-date and publicly available electronic list of establishments that are registered under this section.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="HE88C07C9BDE942F5BF8A32E0114D98E8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Exemptions</header>
 <paragraph id="HDC14B9EEFBE4439495962B71C64BBD2F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Registration under subsection (a) shall not be required for any entity based on such entity operating as—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H88F86B83C6A74F80A0C64DFA37589C80"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an establishment that as of the date of enactment of this section is registered as a cosmetic establishment under part 710 of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on such date);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A11DA18632E4EA6B2AD467A48F51BEE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a beauty shop or salon or spa;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H716AC7BFDD564D9F828BF5AA91798F16"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a cosmetic retailer, including any such retailer that is—</text>
 <clause id="H1DDF206813904709830720F8D526A4D7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an individual sales representative;</text> </clause><clause id="HD048551F109B4EC2BF1690362415FB39"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a wholesale or retail distribution or sales facility; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAAB17D3D0D15408D80969557B1A1F050"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a pharmacy or other person or organization that—</text> <subclause id="HC3182486460D4FFEBFA6C46A6690CD39"><enum>(I)</enum><text>compounds cosmetics at a single location and administers, dispenses, or distributes such cosmetics at retail from that location; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H6F2116E012034712A7E7C6A176152BD0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>does not otherwise manufacture or package cosmetics from that location;</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7DAAF8C175F6422BB01E621FE08C5409"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a health care provider, including a hospital or clinic;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAAAD5008B26E4B4198897E407C33F076"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a public health agency or other nonprofit entity;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H60ECBE967891433DB457702116DC2DDE"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a hotel or other entity that provides complimentary cosmetics;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF36C768E53941309C8CD7422AA21110"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a trade show or other venue where cosmetic samples are provided;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDCCC357EA3BB489B845119CF4830BC0B"><enum>(H)</enum><text>an establishment that manufactures, prepares, compounds, or processes cosmetics for use in research, teaching, or chemical analysis or pilot plant production;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB95BA06F9DD546E489C5696FDBCE2D33"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a handcrafted soap or cosmetic made in a home, a community facility, or a similar establishment; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC7E14B130AC47C19DE832BFDF2FA363"><enum>(J)</enum><text>a business with less than $1,000,000 of annual net revenue from cosmetics.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE73AC2B7CCE742368934B3E1DC8822C5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional exemptions</header><text>The Secretary may supplement the list of exemptions under paragraph (1) with additional exemptions for persons and activities where the cost of compliance exceeds the safety benefit to the public.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H4C6ADF014A2E4D4A9E816F45BE7706C4"><enum>5.</enum><header>Cosmetic and ingredient statement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Chapter VI (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/361">21 U.S.C. 361</external-xref> et seq.), as amended by sections 3 and 4, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="H9819B26F5DF74A83B127E0BC15C73CEC" style="OLC">
				<section id="H5C05DC5FBC9941F094906D8CF5375049"><enum>606.</enum><header>Cosmetic and ingredient statement</header>
 <subsection id="HAD67846FA830428187C782C8D52FFB87"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall by regulation require that every domestic establishment and foreign establishment engaged in the manufacture of a cosmetic intended to be sold in the United States submit to the Secretary, for each cosmetic so manufactured in the establishment, except such cosmetics manufactured by entities exempted by section 605(e) from registration under section 605, within 60 business days after the first commercial sale of the cosmetic, a cosmetic and ingredient statement. The Secretary shall require the statement to contain only—</text>
 <paragraph id="HCC0CCA7AF0A24ACB997302C1D5CD28A5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the unique establishment registration number of the manufacturing establishment where the cosmetic is manufactured or, if the same cosmetic is manufactured in more than one establishment, the unique establishment registration number of each establishment where it is manufactured;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDD53742B41F149CCB75911396D157EB2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the brand name or names for the cosmetic;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8D388DDEF14342CB8694272E949BBAF8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the applicable cosmetic category or categories for the cosmetic;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7EB97DAE7CB74426BD9F0512929FD8CC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the ingredients in the cosmetic (in accordance with section 701.3 of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Cosmetic Modernization Amendments of 2017</short-title> and including any successor regulations), and using the name of each ingredient established under subsection (d), if any), in descending order of predominance by weight, except that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H772CC81AD7684079A78A132E595A2AF0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>flavors and fragrances may be designated as such; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC24DEF7B329B4D928DD12565176DACF4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>all variations in color, flavor, or fragrance may be included in one statement; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A75E163AC6243D3BFDA9FF75EA08A80"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the title, email address, and telephone number for the office within the establishment that is responsible for submitting and maintaining the statement.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H73FFBF08F8F446B593800F76A6EB1462"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Unique number</header><text>The Secretary shall establish and provide to the office submitting a statement required by subsection (a) a unique cosmetic and ingredient statement number within 15 business days after receiving the statement. If the Secretary does not provide a unique cosmetic and ingredient statement number within such 15-business-day period, any requirement under this Act for such number shall be deemed to be inapplicable until the date that is 30 business days after such number is received by the office that submitted the statement. The unique cosmetic and ingredient statement number shall not be required to be included in cosmetic labeling.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H70F659B421D942CCA7797A7DA67E64ED"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Change in labeling</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An establishment shall not be required to submit a new or revised statement under subsection (a) because of a change in labeling except to the extent necessary to maintain the accuracy of the information included in a statement under subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC498E85FDFF14FDD8D741B6ADAF97377"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Name of ingredient</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section and cosmetic ingredient labeling under section 701.3 of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Cosmetic Modernization Amendments of 2017</short-title> and including any successor regulations), the name of a cosmetic ingredient shall be the name, if any, in the most recent edition of the International Cosmetic Ingredient Dictionary, unless the Secretary by regulation establishes a different name for the ingredient.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6E708949379C48F4B0DF0CD221EA5F1D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Maintenance</header><text>The information required in a statement submitted to the Secretary under subsection (a) or in an existing statement under subsection (g)(1) shall be maintained as current and accurate by the office that filed the statement by withdrawing or amending the statement within 60 business days after the information becomes no longer current and accurate, except that no amendment shall be required for a change in the order of predominance of the ingredients or for any other type or category of change for which the costs of amending the statement exceed the safety benefit to the public.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAC1CD3E94A934FDFB0BFEA0EB8B6E391"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>The Secretary shall enforce subsections (a) and (e) under section 301(fff) and shall not suspend or revoke a cosmetic and ingredient statement.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H318DBD4A950F4716B76D0BA6C987651E"><enum>(g)</enum><header>List</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall compile and maintain an up-to-date and publicly available electronic list of cosmetics and ingredients for which statements are submitted under this section. A statement submitted pursuant to this section shall not be subject to disclosure under section 552 of title 5, United States Code. The Secretary may make publicly available information derived from such statements that discloses the names of ingredients used in cosmetics and the number of cosmetics in which a specific ingredient is used, but may not make publicly available any information that relates to any ingredient that is exempt from public disclosure under section 720.8 of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Cosmetic Modernization Amendments of 2017</short-title> and including any successor regulations), or that discloses at what establishment a cosmetic is manufactured. At the written request of the director of a State agency responsible for regulating the safety of cosmetics stating good cause therefor, the Secretary may disclose to such official confidential business and trade secret information contained in a statement and such official and other State employees who have access to such information shall then be subject to the provisions of section 301(j) of this Act, section 552(b) of title 5, United States Code, and section 1905 of title 18, United States Code, with respect to such information.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H36F64A4723924CEF81B83942F385C06C"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Exemptions</header><text>Submission of a statement under subsection (a) shall not be required—</text> <paragraph id="H875B5DECDCB044D6AE1A410D0D58393E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for a cosmetic for which as of the date of enactment of this section a cosmetic ingredient statement has been submitted to the Secretary under part 710 of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Cosmetic Modernization Amendments of 2017</short-title>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1C1BD7118C3443949D51E3C2F31D6107"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for a cosmetic ingredient exempt from public disclosure under section 720.8 of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Cosmetic Modernization Amendments of 2017</short-title> and including any successor regulations); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF7D8F928FC1B45E5B7F4935956481118"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by an entity to the extent such entity is exempted by section 605(e) from registration under section 605.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="HD35932CD9AAD43F0AE4AC9848519B230"><enum>6.</enum><header>Serious and unexpected adverse event reporting for cosmetics</header>
 <subsection id="H9850F95F439B479DB5E25020922D975D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chapter VI (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/361">21 U.S.C. 361</external-xref> et seq.), as amended by sections 3, 4, and 5, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HDCF29B14553744B79811CA53D0AA8485" style="OLC">
					<section id="H3697FD33088F47B395E55DFAA2C29554"><enum>607.</enum><header>Serious and unexpected adverse event reporting for cosmetics</header>
 <subsection id="H5810073742194B04B375C01A8772B8F5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall by regulation require that a domestic or foreign manufacturer, packer, or distributor whose name appears on the label pursuant to section 602(b)(1) of a cosmetic marketed in the United States submit to the Secretary under subsection (b) a report containing—</text>
 <paragraph id="H5C7F883702064D2F9118EB4692F93193"><enum>(1)</enum><text>information received concerning any serious and unexpected adverse event in the United States allegedly associated with the use of the cosmetic for which it is reasonably likely that the adverse event was caused by the cosmetic when used as recommended or suggested in the labeling; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3CB8DF9F25F0457193452030E4BC392B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a copy of the label for the cosmetic.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFCBEB8023CFA4BAF9FE2C7EB593C19C7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Submission of reports</header><text>A report on an adverse event under subsection (a) shall be submitted to the Secretary not later than 15 business days after information concerning the adverse event is received at the place of business labeled on the cosmetic pursuant to section 602(b)(1).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H763DC6CD31BC4E42BFC042329EE9BF5E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Required contents</header><text>A report under subsection (a) shall include all of the following information:</text> <paragraph id="H97700E631C8445638DE605C21ED48B0A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An identifiable patient.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6963C1828DE84486841674B0ED2C8F1B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An identifiable reporter.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2E6F5D4387E3429AADBDAA36434510FE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A suspect cosmetic or component thereof.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0D2F91F345FE453B81A279312EEE61F0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A serious adverse event.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2939C90CDC7D42FABAE59A163EEB4E55"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Additional contents; supplemental reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The person submitting a report under subsection (a) may—</text>
 <paragraph id="H06EC869E3001418C87EE9396259AFBFF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>include pertinent information in addition to the information listed in subsection (c); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9E1D40BC414443E49B1D845B84A1432C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>after submitting the initial report, supplement the report with additional information.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H21F52C53DB57446893F5B0A08AC8EBB9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Special rules</header>
 <paragraph id="HFFA474E50B3142D9BCF87D87D2486487"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Protected information</header><text>A serious and unexpected adverse event report (including all information submitted in the initial report or added later) submitted under subsection (a)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA331E1897E884DC5866338CA7A9A87F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be considered to be a safety report under section 756 that is subject to the provisions of that section; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDBA73B9A37E54A77958727D4942E9109"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be considered to be a record about an individual under section 552a of title 5, United States Code, and a medical or similar file the disclosure of which would constitute a violation of section 552 of such title 5, and shall not be publicly disclosed unless all personally identifiable information is redacted.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H22445491C3424B83AFD5588569C3D912"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No treatment as admission</header><text>The submission of a serious and unexpected adverse event report in compliance with subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="HC05A77526C3E409B8D0631D02063B2BA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall not be construed as an admission that the cosmetic involved caused or contributed to the adverse event; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H88FA844B25924ABB89007F2544F08169"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may be accompanied by a statement that denies that the report constitutes an admission that the cosmetic involved caused or contributed to the adverse event.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB9CF46932B8448AA3826ABDC278D07F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Inclusion of statement in public disclosure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In releasing any report under subsection (a) or portion thereof for public disclosure, the Secretary shall include any statement under paragraph (2)(B).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF798863209BD4C3D95508DA9AD315376"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Labeling</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The label of a cosmetic shall bear the domestic telephone number, email address, or mailing address through which the person whose name and place of business appear on the label may receive a report of a serious adverse event.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3A69B488F7394DF39A0F5A3C07A537C4"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may, by regulation, establish an exemption to the requirements under subsections (b) and (d) if the Secretary determines that such exemption would have no adverse effect on public health.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF9AAF9DE0B3542219AF94100ECC918E3"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H1F93031C3FC04C47AF8488050B2CA54C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>serious</term>, with respect to an adverse event, means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA82A75FEFD074F63A82157E15CD71327"><enum>(A)</enum><text>resulting in—</text> <clause id="H5F608DA812FF461C8F8979B6CC7CF9BE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>death;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0E18CDE5E4754292BE05A80DEC012659"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a life-threatening experience;</text> </clause><clause id="H42FA82EA8DC7486A841C748233FA7D13"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>inpatient hospitalization;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB8E1749AA8754AADB03B734BAE9F5CA3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a persistent and significant disability or incapacity;</text> </clause><clause id="H62E17D4F9431414EB60394D4B81629B7"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a congenital anomaly or birth defect; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H002ABCF8A4154CE8B738FC4AC092EC67"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>permanent disfiguration; or</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBBA6DDF22EA42E592A59FEE0DE5E762"><enum>(B)</enum><text>requiring, based on reasonable medical judgment, a medical or surgical intervention to prevent an outcome described under subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H49B8C7F9C0F245879D3A7F97BA701832"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>unexpected</term>, with respect to an adverse event, means not identified on the cosmetic label.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="HF6B1B5EE6BDF4CC38A87ACD4BDF5A18C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Misbranding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 602 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/362">21 U.S.C. 362</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H63A2DCC8BEE94BBD883052B094360ABF" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H967C3835B6464CDBAAFA8537C315E858"><enum>(g)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If it is a cosmetic that is marketed in the United States, unless the label of such cosmetic includes a domestic address or domestic phone number through which a report of a serious and unexpected adverse event (as such term is used in section 607) associated with the use of such cosmetic may be submitted to the person described in section 607(f).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H6579A1DBA4BD4F0AAF9B930FE1DA5C49"><enum>7.</enum><header>Good manufacturing practice</header>
 <subsection id="H325BD1718050428EA49CC59E57A3EE4F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 601 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/361">21 U.S.C. 361</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H5A2D734F2D1949BC97015A16B6CF2115" style="OLC"> <subsection commented="no" id="HB22711CC2D20429593829601BA3010B8"><enum>(f)</enum><text>If it has been manufactured under conditions that do not satisfy the principles and standards for good manufacturing practice established under section 608 and as a result presents a significant risk of serious adverse health consequences or death to humans.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF09DD070EC3E416196B5A829857DD0E5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Principles and standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chapter VI (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/361">21 U.S.C. 361</external-xref> et seq.), as amended by sections 3, 4, 5, and 6, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H225BB116E39947CE807E523514087EEC" style="OLC">
					<section id="HFAF59D2A81EC449DA780DE4C08C02A8C"><enum>608.</enum><header>Good manufacturing practice</header>
 <subsection id="H8C4E4C506E8D46CEA5606D2A21D247F6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may by regulation establish principles and standards for good manufacturing practice for the manufacture of cosmetics in accordance with paragraphs (a) and (d) of section 601.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBD5AAE21732149F1A9D9489B1BBAF4E9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notice and comment</header><text>A regulation under subsection (a) shall be promulgated only after providing notice and an opportunity for comment in accordance with <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0B1F36C7FEE6495BA19BA75475C31AC5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Good manufacturing practices of other parties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A manufacturer shall not be responsible under section 601(f) or this section for the good manufacturing practice of its suppliers. A distributor shall not be responsible under section 601(f) or this section for the good manufacturing practice of its manufacturers.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section commented="no" id="HE05EF8974C284D13A1A872DD09DC08A4"><enum>8.</enum><header>Safety substantiation for cosmetic ingredients and nonfunctional constituents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Chapter VI (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/361">21 U.S.C. 361</external-xref> et seq.), as amended by sections 3, 4, 5, 6, and 7, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="HDAC8E057DCB7425FA2F77EE2126EFE04" style="OLC">
				<section commented="no" id="H6208E71A7E174F599D84610041E26A39"><enum>609.</enum><header>Cosmetic ingredients and nonfunctional constituents that are safe for use in cosmetics</header>
 <subsection id="HBA0DEFEC228A4A1E9F321CF6E5160F8C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A manufacturer or distributor of a cosmetic may rely on this section to substantiate the safety of such cosmetic.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HF24FEC0267524ECCB4188C79ED3E7700"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Safe ingredients</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Unless and until prohibited or limited by the Secretary by regulation, the following ingredients are deemed to be adequately substantiated for safe use in cosmetics subject to the requirements of good manufacturing practice:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HC097EF6E3B7B4278B0824996E13A982E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Color additives approved by the Secretary for use in cosmetics, within any limits established in such approval.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8975A7D02E6F4941A3408884E80EB876"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Food additives approved by the Secretary for direct addition to food for human consumption, within any limits established in such approval.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF2DAFE2517F343308321DF3CB40D4129"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Food ingredients that have been determined by the Secretary to be generally recognized as safe for direct addition to food for human consumption, within any limits established in such determination.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HAA47B16F01C64ADBA801F0B469CC3613"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Food ingredients for which monographs have been included in the Food Chemicals Codex for direct addition to food for human consumption, within any limits established in such monographs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HEBD1A4B58B344F968542D6CCAF396AFB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Pharmaceutical excipients and inactive ingredients approved or permitted by the Secretary, listed on a Food and Drug Administration website for use in drugs for human consumption or for which monographs have been included in the Handbook of Pharmaceutical Excipients, within any limits established in such lists or monographs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H07EA0A2AC86D42C98BE2B5E26B77AE04"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Cosmetic ingredients that have been reviewed for safety by a qualified nongovernmental or governmental expert scientific body, including the Cosmetic Ingredient Review Expert Panel, and that are the subject of a monograph published in a peer-reviewed scientific journal, within any limits established in such monographs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HDF5BB7769CA0423EA7D98C4D9664A670"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Fragrance ingredients that have been reviewed for safety by a qualified nongovernmental or governmental expert scientific body, including the Research Institute of Fragrance Materials Expert Panel, and that are the subject of a monograph published in a peer-reviewed scientific journal, within any limits established in such monographs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3D9245D692AC48A2948B48F0318A2EC9"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Cosmetic ingredients approved or permitted for use in cosmetics by any of the countries listed in section 802(b)(1)(A) as having an adequate regulatory authority, within any limits established by such regulatory authority.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H1D7DE432490842DB9286003B0C68D958"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Safe nonfunctional constituents</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HED441DA390F2476492296C65E41B1F61"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>A nonfunctional constituent in a cosmetic is any substance that—</text> <subparagraph id="HB5F31B11DCED4B78860258B906F956EF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has not been intentionally added as a separate substance; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F740FA9063649F9A359BB3C38A959E6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>serves no technical or cosmetic function in the cosmetic.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HBE977FB3DCA84DAEAFEA48BB58A16681"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Adequate substantiation</header><text>The following nonfunctional constituents are deemed to be adequately substantiated for safe use in cosmetics, subject to the requirements of good manufacturing practice and any limits or bans established by the Secretary by regulation:</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H61ACE20CCE1F41309D45C3AAC06631C3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The levels approved or permitted for nonfunctional constituents by the Secretary for color additives for cosmetic use and for food additives and generally recognized as safe food ingredients for direct human consumption.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H931BD8C463A348409AB02E4F55DE70FC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The levels approved or permitted for nonfunctional constituents by the Secretary for cosmetics and for food and food ingredients for direct human consumption in compliance policy guides, guidance, and website statements.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H77A7189AFA3349BAA2246A2FD0E1FD43"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The levels approved or permitted for nonfunctional constituents by the Secretary or the United States Pharmacopeia for oral nonprescription drugs.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5AE4D63E6CA14AAEA2D1B9B07A4F9B36"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The levels approved or permitted for nonfunctional constituents by the Environmental Protection Agency for direct human consumption in drinking water.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8D6E766CE5D14A489670741D7E8F8102"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The levels for nonfunctional constituents approved or permitted in cosmetics and human food and food ingredients by any of the countries listed in section 802(b)(1)(A) as having an adequate regulatory authority.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H0B306B094C9D425A860C670D529A86DE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Center</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a program within the center of the Food and Drug Administration with primary responsibility for regulating cosmetics to evaluate and make determinations, by regulation, on the safe use of cosmetics and ingredients and nonfunctional constituents thereof.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H4BCD22E639D545EDA8E98E50E94C71A2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Application; preemption</header><text>A safety determination accepted or made by the Secretary or established under this section shall apply in every State. No State may establish or enforce a safety determination for a cosmetic or an ingredient or nonfunctional constituent of a cosmetic.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HED406058845149E8B518815F11DE9FB1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effective date of regulations</header><text>Any regulation or guidance by the Secretary pursuant to this section concerning the safety of a cosmetic or an ingredient or nonfunctional constituent of a cosmetic shall apply beginning no earlier than the date that is 2 years after the date on which such regulation or guidance is issued as final, unless the Secretary determines, after public notice and an opportunity for public comment, that an earlier date of applicability is required to prevent serious adverse health consequences or death to humans.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H8E2A6F5564F14CAD9F8468B2368535EC"><enum>9.</enum><header>National Cosmetic Regulatory Databank</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Chapter VI (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/361">21 U.S.C. 361</external-xref> et seq.), as amended by sections 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, and 8, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="H608806B04742418EBBBFFDB9685375AF" style="OLC">
				<section id="HA6EF1165D1884CCBAB3DFA842286B0FD"><enum>610.</enum><header>National Cosmetic Regulatory Databank</header>
 <subsection id="H3D3274DE4E0D48F796BB4F65B1C1AC36"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purpose of consolidating information pertaining to the regulation of cosmetic safety, the Secretary shall establish and maintain in the center of the Food and Drug Administration with primary responsibility for regulating cosmetics a database, to be known as the National Cosmetic Regulatory Databank, containing—</text>
 <paragraph id="HEF9EE704781F4CB792A9A46444373C7C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the information submitted to the Secretary under sections 605, 606, 607, and 609; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H000EEF74155F4D4591434FCD90FCB9A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such other information pertaining to the regulation of cosmetics as the Secretary deems appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H514EE81D1E9A42DFAC50FD18BE99B242"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>In the case of information in the National Cosmetic Regulatory Databank that is not subject to public disclosure under section 552 of title 5, United States Code, the Secretary may nonetheless disclose such information to the director of a State agency on written request by such director demonstrating good cause for the disclosure. A director receiving information pursuant to the preceding sentence shall agree to limit to the disclosure of such information by State officials and employees to the same extent such disclosure is limited with respect to Federal officials and employees under section 301(j) of this Act, section 552(b) of title 5, United States Code, and section 1905 of title 18, United States Code, with respect to such information.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2C6C75B0104B4421ACB40FD3755F752C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Preemption</header><text>No State or political subdivision thereof may require submission of information that is available in the National Cosmetic Regulatory Databank, whether in the same or a different format.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="HFBCCA86902C547DE908B5C616B57E530"><enum>10.</enum><header>Special rules</header>
 <subsection id="H79C7E7BB809F4A4A996830A3E1715C55"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Certain rules</header><text>Chapter VI (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/361">21 U.S.C. 361</external-xref> et seq.), as amended by sections 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, and 9, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HE671CB5FB3CC4B85AC277187D212105D" style="OLC">
					<section id="HD2FF71A1DA664F30BE32DA106E5E0B51"><enum>611.</enum><header>Special rules</header>
 <subsection id="HDA69FD3DC6B64DDCA53A28648B561C21"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Contractors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The person described in section 607(f) with respect to a cosmetic (referred to in this section as the <quote>responsible party</quote>) may, by agreement, authorize a manufacturer, distributor, or packer of the cosmetic or a third-party contractor to submit any required report of a serious and unexpected adverse event (as such term is used in section 607) so long as the responsible party directs to the manufacturer, distributor, packer, or third-party contractor all such adverse events associated with such cosmetic that are reported to the responsible party through the address or telephone number described in section 607(f).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7E20BCC41545479EB24426F90D690D0A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exemptions</header><text>The Secretary, on the Secretary’s own initiative or in response to a petition, may establish exemptions from the requirements of sections 601(f), 605, 606, 607, and 608—</text>
 <paragraph id="H90D66E9B5108472FBC3939284E71EFB5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for the efficient and cost-effective implementation of such requirements; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2DAFEF5367D84D47A3904E6464EC162F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>where the cost of compliance exceeds the safety benefit to the public.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE3EDE810AA7F454CA464039508C371DE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Cosmetic definition</header><text>Section 201(i) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/321">21 U.S.C. 321(i)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>An article described in subparagraph (1) that is intended only for topical external use to alter the appearance by temporarily affecting the structure or any function of the human skin, and that is not the subject of an approved new drug application under section 505, shall, for purposes of this Act, be treated only as a cosmetic and not a drug.</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6B51E58960174D2AAEC6D9318B149945"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Color Additives</header><text>Section 721(f) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/379e">21 U.S.C. 379e(f)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H048E48CF895647E5BDD502461C150CF5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(f) The Secretary shall</quote> and inserting <quote>(f)(1) The Secretary shall</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H16D55855A5924713B94DCD0BDCEC78C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HCF2B73860707441C9B5AADD5CC31FD90" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HF30D248840C34EC3B8E311AA42CA48B7" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A color additive, including mixtures thereof, intended for use in externally applied cosmetics and not in the area of the eye is exempt from the requirements of this section if it is generally recognized, among experts qualified by scientific training and experience to evaluate its safety, as having been shown through scientific procedures to be safe under the conditions of its intended use. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, the Secretary may by regulation require certification of batches under subsection (c) for any such color additive.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HDC5A250C05014876A3C71968CBDFC217"><enum>11.</enum><header>Prohibited acts</header>
 <subsection id="H6A2D026BD1A94E1D83500949FBD6422D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 301 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/331">21 U.S.C. 331</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF369DFCB70614F269373CFD044E641E1" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H86348D50D9FE43DB8B14E25988E87E5F"><enum>(eee)</enum><text>The failure to register a cosmetic establishment as required under section 605 or to maintain the registration current and accurate.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H49B84CF6637245D8A65397C2DBA7A055"><enum>(fff)</enum><text>The failure to submit a cosmetic and ingredient statement as required under section 606 or to maintain the statement current and accurate.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC00A6A564FF743E8935BE3C21F2B1334"><enum>(ggg)</enum><text>The failure to submit a serious and unexpected adverse event report, or to include on the label of a cosmetic the domestic telephone number, email address, or mailing address through which a report of a serious adverse event may be received, as required under section 607.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8C67A64D8B274663ADDB9EB6D2545CDF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information security</header><text>Section 301(j) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/331">21 U.S.C. 331(j)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>605, 606, 609,</quote> after <quote>573,</quote>.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H213A84DC545849E18C5D313C1505EBE2"><enum>12.</enum><header>National uniformity for cosmetics</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 752 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/379s">21 U.S.C. 379s</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H059E58BC8CE64FBC93518F8D68E6CB09"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by amending the section heading to read as follows: <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">National uniformity for cosmetics</header-in-text></quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFB18EFD4A0704E8681CC78EB82C8BBB9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by amending subsection (a) to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HDCD4A7E5E9F04CE3830A05BBBC29F6CE" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H0A7A54054D4A46B59C8132681BB48790"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b) or (d) of this section, no State or political subdivision of a State may establish or continue in effect any requirement for labeling or packaging of a cosmetic.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE5AA3887D373447BB5799188F35AC3FD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by amending subsection (c) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="HE75C2CCD7DF24D139E3C3B6A2929F77B" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HD49380D82B4543CB9E9B314E29E9FA1A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Cosmetic safety</header><text>No State or political subdivision of a State may establish or continue in effect any law, regulation, order, or other requirement—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6D297C488727425F9A0BA824804035B2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>relating directly or indirectly to, or relying upon, a human health or safety evaluation of a nonfunctional cosmetic constituent, cosmetic ingredient, or cosmetic (as defined in section 201(i)(1)), or relating in any way to the safety standard and the human health-based requirements, evaluations, and determinations under chapter VI, the Poison Prevention Packaging Act of 1970, or the Fair Packaging and Labeling Act; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF805AF724B144AD487F802AA9568389C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>relating directly or indirectly to registration or listing of cosmetic facilities, establishments, cosmetics, or cosmetic ingredients, reporting of any information relating to cosmetics including adverse event reporting, cosmetic manufacturing processes or standards including good manufacturing practice, cosmetic labels or labeling including any general or health related warnings or public statement, or the requirement of any fees on cosmetic establishments, cosmetics, ingredients, or nonfunctional constituents.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8E2C03152D314E5FBDC81E4C0C24CD4B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by repealing subsection (e).</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H5F91DF0E1B62438B8F61398E2E35B31C"><enum>13.</enum><header>Importation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 801(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/381">21 U.S.C. 381(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>If a cosmetic is being imported or offered for import into the United States and the importer does not present both the unique cosmetic establishment registration number required under section 605 for the establishment that performs the final portion of the manufacturing operation and the unique cosmetic and ingredient statement number required under section 606 for the cosmetic, or the registration or statement number is not correct and accurate, the cosmetic shall be denied entry.</quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="H132E2F440EC34FCF85A9B87F7A802D78"><enum>14.</enum><header>Effective dates</header>
			<subsection id="H9E5F5E6FF30C49A580D047BCF4981723"><enum>(a)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF6DE8C9F3FFE4A97921E2F2054E4EECB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The amendments made by sections 4, 5, 6, and 13 of this Act apply beginning on the later date of—</text> <subparagraph id="H162DC9F8BCF147179178DEDDCB8C7CB5" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the date that is one year after the Secretary of Health and Human Services promulgates final regulations implementing such amendments; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05A77882FCAE4D9887D156442C451E72" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date that is one year after the Secretary of Health and Human Services publishes a notice in the Federal Register determining that an effective electronic system has been established and is fully operational for—</text>
 <clause id="H175B6B9089B0465CA212AEC1CE6C27D7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the submission of cosmetic manufacturing establishment registrations, cosmetic and ingredient statements, and reports of serious cosmetic adverse events; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H06B60DD6670046D4A7F9082E50FFAE5A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the National Cosmetic Regulatory Databank.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCBE5137D7024401D9671EE16FEA4499D" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Until the date applicable under paragraph (1), the voluntary establishment registration and voluntary ingredient listing programs established in parts 710 and 720 of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act), shall remain effective and shall be fully implemented by the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H67549FA879CF49299F71C35595FA6D34"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The amendments made by sections 7 and 8 apply beginning on the date that is two years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDD577DB2546047D5B1182F7468CE5750"><enum>(c)</enum><text>Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (b), the amendments made by sections 5 and 7 shall not apply with respect to a cosmetic manufacturer with less than $5,000,000 of annual net sales of cosmetics until the later of—</text>
				<paragraph id="H01DE2D8FD159496290F28F16251C57FA"><enum>(1)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H79CA42FF5CD74C32A0C6DFDE3DF8425A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to the amendment made by section 5, the date that is 36 months after the date otherwise applicable under subsection (a); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCCCD60C08413402D884E1301FC67152A" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to the amendments made by section 7, the date that is 36 months after the date otherwise applicable under subsection (b); and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H259D62E7B1604517AB2DABEF2D552A70"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such later date as may be determined by the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD6667D26D7EF4E7282A1A5D9B74243EF"><enum>(d)</enum><text>Except as provided in subsections (a) through (c), this Act takes effect on the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


