<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H8C76A24830534FEFA07812A4662FD331" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4349 IH: Missed Opportunities in Student Debt and Possibilities Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4349</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171109">November 9, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000287">Mr. Lewis of Georgia</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require reporting by the Secretary of Education on missed opportunities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H3C41B0D4F596460B8764E716C6C3FF4A" style="OLC">
 <section id="H8A64918672B8423BA0C1BF63FB5CF347" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Missed Opportunities in Student Debt and Possibilities Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> <subsection id="H40083B779A39418D89917C16DBA122DE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than December 31 of each year, the Secretary of Education shall submit to Congress a report on missed opportunities for each competitive or discretionary grant program administered by the Department of Education in the preceding fiscal year that aims to make higher education more accessible or affordable in the United States or ease borrowers’ student debt burdens.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H82C278A2F11E44339431FD746B599E5B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>For each grant program described in subsection (a), the report shall detail the 10 individual applications, proposals, or requests for funding that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H73BAAA655AB4406685343EE7A75B67A3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>were not funded or awarded, completely or partially; but</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE680DFDBD8E24733B3F478027E23FC35"><enum>(2)</enum><text>showed the greatest potential, according to the selection criteria and established goals of that grant program, to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA001F63A01184CEA951270B2977157E0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>make higher education more accessible or affordable; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H605A5E82275340E2AEA7CEC4F411198B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ease borrowers’ student debt burdens.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3978A298DDAC4A63A571C250F5435798"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reporting date flexibility</header><text>If a law requires an annual report to Congress with respect to a grant program described in subsection (a), the report on missed opportunities required under this section for that program may—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4DA20DB0FE954092B1E57052A5DB7EC8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be included in that annual report; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H93470835CE4D4CE591FEA802B1E0A680"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be submitted on or before the date that annual report is due.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4602CEFA583D4C5581F9308F0E8B945F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Public transparency</header><text>Upon submission of a report on missed opportunities to Congress under this section, the Secretary shall make the report available to the public on an internet website of the Department of Education in a manner that is user friendly and able to be searched and downloaded by users of the website.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2900D9AA9E5440FFB0E553A3C61A6D07"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Trade secrets and confidential information</header><text>Nothing in this section authorizes the Secretary to disclose any information that is a trade secret or confidential information subject to section 552(b)(4) of title 5 or section 1905 of title 18.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


