<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Placed-on-Calendar-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB9A73CF6545B47CAA81214AF48AE3E0A" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2292 PCS: To extend a project of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission involving the Cannonsville Dam.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<calendar>Calendar No. 139</calendar><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2292</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date>June 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and placed on the calendar</action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To extend a project of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission involving the Cannonsville Dam.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HEF809342B45D4BE4A609F2F2EC63BE35" style="OLC">
		<section id="H1881C235B9B54D3DAD191D3DF2614F38" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Extension of time for a Federal Energy Regulatory Commission project involving Cannonsville Dam</header>
 <subsection id="H95F085CA823848ADBC976CBF992BF16B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding the time period specified in section 13 of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/806">16 U.S.C. 806</external-xref>) that would otherwise apply to the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission project numbered 13287, the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (referred to in this section as the <quote>Commission</quote>) may, at the request of the licensee for the project, and after reasonable notice, in accordance with the good faith, due diligence, and public interest requirements of that section and the procedures of the Commission under that section, extend the time period during which the licensee is required to commence construction of the project for up to 4 consecutive 2-year periods after the required date of the commencement of construction described in Article 301 of the license.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H044911AF68A5406298AAF08C02788FE1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reinstatement of expired license</header>
 <paragraph id="HE6AA59BFF9934FA1AB95FE9D27128839"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the required date of the commencement of construction described in subsection (a) has expired prior to the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission may reinstate the license effective as of that date of expiration.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4AE6B2E051A64508BE6AA65FE3394C05"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>If the Commission reinstates the license under paragraph (1), the first extension authorized under subsection (a) shall take effect on the date of that expiration.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20170613">Passed the House of Representatives June 12, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
	<endorsement display="yes"><action-date>June 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and placed on the calendar</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill>


