<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1E2C5E21D3B14AFEABC6859FE30CEF47" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 868 IH: National Museum of Asian Pacific American History and Culture Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>115th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 868</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20170203">February 3, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To establish within the Smithsonian Institution the National Museum of Asian Pacific American
			 History and Culture, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HFF26B49446624FA88D9A6FDF992DD854" style="OLC">
		<section id="H2B22173A71CA4CC6B0E6217A1D22E3AC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Museum of Asian Pacific American History and Culture Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="id372C8E0381754DEF8DD2C3AD68C39AE2" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="id66D3544C9C8E49EA90A1DFF8D5286718"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Board of Regents</header><text>The term <term>Board of Regents</term> means the Board of Regents of the Smithsonian Institution.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idF9418116317A400B8D75069B375F1885"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Council</header><text>The term <term>Council</term> means the National Museum of Asian Pacific American History and Culture Council established by section 4.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id74CCBBA8D4E447D78A801BFA71C0C4BE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Museum</header><text>The term <term>Museum</term> means the National Museum of Asian Pacific American History and Culture established by section 3.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idF732EFC8D8F943EF9FD1CF02D6280FC7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="id13451AC9A267496E90762749D5AFA01F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of Museum</header>
 <subsection id="id603287B244B34E94AC75497D10AE7B05"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established within the Smithsonian Institution a museum to be known as the <quote>National Museum of Asian Pacific American History and Culture</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="idB7243FD7158A4B42883ADC8269E5483C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the Museum shall be to provide for—</text>
 <paragraph id="idBAEB3ECC3A78439A91FD21AC02C12F5F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the collection, study, and establishment of programs relating to Asian Pacific American life, art, history, and culture;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id18A4F6339EEE43A8B462524B344FC675"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the creation and maintenance of permanent and temporary exhibits documenting the history of Asian Pacific American life, art, history, and culture;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id70F4D4624FF84A128FFBDDC02B449D65"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the collection and study of artifacts and documents relating to Asian Pacific American life, art, history, and culture; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id941627345EFC4C218B68FF5CAF069C8B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>collaboration between the Museum and other museums, Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institutions, historical societies, educational institutions, and other organizations that promote the study or appreciation of Asian Pacific American life, art, history, or culture, including collaboration concerning—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id46B300FBB3094664805C3803A6289E25"><enum>(A)</enum><text>development of cooperative programs and exhibitions;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id80C64DDDB0E54E86B0C0FE56E2BD6FAB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identification, management, and care of collections; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id21AE4AFAFCF641BC9A6FE2D8E8C42319"><enum>(C)</enum><text>training of museum professionals.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idA4D5601B3D0248608AF74983DC0A28E7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Council</header> <subsection id="id8DB5A326A94747A58D569107FD22AAEB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established within the Smithsonian Institution a council to be known as the <quote>National Museum of Asian Pacific American History and Culture Council</quote>.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id1385F03A5FFA4144B5E59C829EAAE84C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header>
 <paragraph id="idC497647FE4124C84A3AE1DD52CAF1D3C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Council shall—</text> <subparagraph id="id5D90BAACF6C544A58566579B996F8943"><enum>(A)</enum><text>make recommendations to the Board of Regents concerning the planning, design, and construction of the Museum;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id799931396E904B5D905947F3BAA9CB60"><enum>(B)</enum><text>advise and assist the Board of Regents on all matters relating to the administration, operation, maintenance, and preservation of the Museum;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8E469558783E446F9EFB20C3A9238AA7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recommend annual operating budgets for the Museum to the Board of Regents;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id421899F290C24031ADC99F73284DE82A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>report annually to the Board of Regents on the acquisition, disposition, and display of objects relating to Asian Pacific American life, art, history, and culture; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6D81BF561C684B82900331CDC22151C4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>adopt bylaws for the operation of the Council.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6497DD097B794D4A8071F674F5A84687"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Principal responsibilities</header><text>The Council, subject to the general policies of the Board of Regents, shall have sole authority to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idB0C451ACCFD748D48DBAA26B328A93CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>purchase, accept, borrow, and otherwise acquire artifacts for addition to the collections of the Museum;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD69BC3EB54714D82AFBE7A44649F3473"><enum>(B)</enum><text>loan, exchange, sell, and otherwise dispose of any part of the collections of the Museum, but only if the funds generated by that disposition are used for additions to the collections of the Museum; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2B9C1A9BF9C04741B4683BEE04A1070A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>specify criteria with respect to the use of the collections and resources of the Museum, including policies on programming, education, exhibitions, and research.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id047EF220EE7C452094AE473AA2C96A08"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Other responsibilities</header><text>The Council, subject to the general policies of the Board of Regents, shall have authority—</text> <subparagraph id="id91CDF04129C848B8A6E8BBE156745F6C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to provide for preservation, restoration, and maintenance of the collections of the Museum; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC24CD19E601042EC89917C1AEECD7116"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to solicit, accept, use, and dispose of gifts, bequests, and devises of personal property for the purpose of aiding and facilitating the work of the Museum.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id93AB604E0BDF42FE93823539C0AAA2B9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Composition and appointment</header>
 <paragraph id="id9DE3D32EE4274B969FF1D73F1113287D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Council shall be composed of 19 voting members as provided under paragraph (2).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idE57CA65D113C483A89D67BB8752B7916"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Voting members</header><text>The Council shall include the following voting members:</text>
 <subparagraph id="idC17BFA08EFEF42A1A7F0CD052FAF6898"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id47161D4E8F4445439BF1AEB37A1AAB61"><enum>(B)</enum><text>One member of the Board of Regents, appointed by the Board of Regents.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0E8429E5047B4C3DB4D17C44C67F84C0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Seventeen individuals appointed by the Board of Regents—</text> <clause id="idBE9A86B306724458AAA82FC10ED0AB4D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>taking into consideration individuals recommended by organizations and entities that are committed to the advancement of knowledge of Asian Pacific American life, art, history, and culture; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id24366E39B640427AB54F8CC4B18FD28A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>taking into consideration individuals recommended by the members of the Council.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idD47ED1B3479F46959676E11FBCE935BF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Initial appointments</header><text>The Board of Regents shall make initial appointments to the Council under paragraph (2) not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idD801D42B47854A959CEE38A3CD108F63"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Terms</header>
 <paragraph id="idF2CD6ECB007A4C31BF33B7259B561B64"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in this subsection, each appointed member of the Council shall be appointed for a term of 3 years.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0B16481495F646D9B5689B4836C7F738"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial appointees</header><text>As designated by the Board of Regents at the time of appointment, of the voting members first appointed under subsection (c)(2)(C)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id7FA04A2F9D5A45D3802F1F8E7C2A4A0C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>six members shall be appointed for a term of 1 year;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD87F27BC00304E0996E781964F39F3C7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>six members shall be appointed for a term of 2 years; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCD0EAA2097DC4F1191A03327A49C18ED"><enum>(C)</enum><text>five members shall be appointed for a term of 3 years.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7110C72ECFA545C7B1DF55659C7FCB1B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reappointment</header><text>A member of the Council may be reappointed, except that no individual may serve on the Council for a total of more than 2 terms. For purposes of this paragraph, the number of terms an individual serves on the Council shall not include any portion of a term for which an individual is appointed to fill a vacancy under paragraph (4)(B).</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="idF8AE7C5663474F198B5AB163AA5DF3D1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Vacancies</header>
 <subparagraph id="idEE5939AC30634FAE898186E75AA9FA7B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A vacancy on the Council—</text> <clause id="id9DFB9ADD5E344D04ADE893F22C4A1C87"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall not affect the powers of the Council; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id3B9F0FAD6FC6452E9EA766E667D9EFEF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment was made.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF50CD67812514C5692085E824629C954"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Term</header><text>Any member of the Council appointed to fill a vacancy occurring before the expiration of the term for which the member’s predecessor was appointed shall be appointed for the remainder of that term.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idFF3602A852B64607810E7632DEEB9E7E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Compensation</header>
 <paragraph id="id52CEF3B628464B0EA78BF842DE293D6B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), a member of the Council shall serve without pay.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idF3C8464C738246478A5235FA20615623"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text>A member of the Council shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for an employee of an agency under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, while away from the home or regular place of business of the member in the performance of the duties of the Council.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idD055B5C7B63945F78B009385FD75D25A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>By a majority vote of its voting members, the Council shall elect a chairperson from its members.</text> </subsection><subsection id="id5DAC1832530C4FED856DC7B799F3C373"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Meetings</header> <paragraph id="idC50DFB69283B4EDDB4F020904A727A4E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Council shall meet at the call of the chairperson or on the written request of a majority of the voting members of the Council, but not fewer than twice each year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6ADEB289267B4D31B48FD701E05292FF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial meetings</header><text>During the 1-year period beginning on the date of the first meeting of the Council, the Council shall meet not fewer than 4 times for the purpose of carrying out the duties of the Council under this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idC349F4162FC544328E017029BE390070"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>A majority of the voting members of the Council holding office shall constitute a quorum for the purpose of conducting business, but a lesser number may receive information on behalf of the Council.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="id6DF13B308405421FB63D1FA680E6D7E2"><enum>5.</enum><header>Director and staff of the Museum</header>
			<subsection id="id2B93EEE3DADC4635A44AB00B5A4C50C1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Director</header>
 <paragraph id="idF07E2116838143DEAABC352D2A2CB598"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Museum shall have a Director who shall be appointed by the Secretary, taking into consideration individuals recommended by the Council.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id92C8A3D8C49A4E0E9803B6CC5A68D6D0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Director shall manage the Museum subject to the policies of the Board of Regents.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4B75735C5C2D4F5C8A2556587AE6C854"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Staff</header><text>The Secretary may appoint two additional employees to serve under the Director, except that such additional employees may be appointed without regard to the provisions of title 5, United States Code, governing appointments in the competitive service.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id64F74FB981234465A7A2272CC499B807"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Pay</header><text>The employees appointed by the Secretary under subsection (b) may be paid without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, relating to classification of positions and General Schedule pay rates.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="id26115253529248779CFF9CC44EFFFD13"><enum>6.</enum><header>Educational and liaison programs</header>
			<subsection id="id243EC19845CB44E1BEE3C1F71FFF5CF5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <paragraph id="id1A9E15B770D04D28AA28D5F32AFF4C6E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Programs authorized</header><text>The Director of the Museum may carry out educational and liaison programs in support of the goals of the Museum.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idBB7EF6E9990F4525A578092274A016EC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Specific activities described</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Director shall—</text> <subparagraph id="id48D699EC0F0943B1AF9BFA12AE4971E2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>carry out educational programs relating to Asian Pacific American life, art, history, and culture, including—</text>
 <clause id="id940AFEF39B804283B4C082D9767F1282"><enum>(i)</enum><text>programs using digital, electronic, and interactive technologies; and</text> </clause><clause id="id18A4165ADA3C47B2BE4B0359888E90A6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>programs carried out in collaboration with elementary schools, secondary schools, and postsecondary schools; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id939EAD23D6C045149B46C1D72388CA04"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consult with the Director of the Institute of Museum and Library Services concerning the grant and scholarship programs carried out under subsection (b).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idC542F3CF8CFF4C14A0142AA3FA687515"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grant and scholarship programs</header><text>In consultation with the Council and the Director of the Museum, the Director of the Institute of Museum and Library Services shall establish—</text>
 <paragraph id="id77731651860D4D4F99CAC844F998865E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a grant program with the purpose of improving operations, care of collections, and development of professional management at Asian Pacific American museums;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id30E34C870F5B40CF8E2F5C20293218A5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a grant program with the purpose of providing internship and fellowship opportunities at Asian Pacific American museums; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idB972B890E1D641098293C938BA4967F7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a scholarship program with the purpose of assisting individuals who are pursuing careers or carrying out studies in the arts, humanities, and sciences in the study of Asian Pacific American life, art, history, and culture.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id92A18A7803264154B805F6EC289868CD"><enum>7.</enum><header>Building for the National Museum of Asian Pacific American History and Culture</header>
			<subsection id="id309F7306444149788258F9445DACFE07"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header>
				<paragraph id="idF8EC92285D494BC0BB3445B182DF7195"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Location</header>
 <subparagraph id="id7C069A9916CB413AA3F4A3A8453BDE6C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 12 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Board of Regents, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, the Commission of Fine Arts, the National Capital Planning Commission, and other Federal and local agencies, shall designate a site for the Museum.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE90E61BD75524DF589C97639E62BC7CB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Transfer to Smithsonian Institution</header><text>If the site designated for the Museum is in an area that is under the administrative jurisdiction of a Federal agency, as soon as practicable after the date on which the designation is made, the head of the Federal agency shall transfer to the Smithsonian Institution administrative jurisdiction over the area.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id95CD3F21E5A74A78A6E9D8882233BF46"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Board of Regents shall carry out its duties under this paragraph in consultation with the following:</text>
 <clause id="idBB09D0D9345E4847A80686E78610AEC9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Chair of the National Capital Planning Commission.</text> </clause><clause id="idC0A69533B94F4999B784A389913657E9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Chair of the Commission on Fine Arts.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idAEB34B2425334677B0EA270D4082EC5D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The Chair of the Presidential Commission referred to in section 8.</text> </clause><clause id="id1C118EA426174C949205BA2775393974"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The Chair and Ranking Member of each of the following committees:</text>
 <subclause id="id0BEE773C20AE493EA27861332778DA68"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate.</text> </subclause><subclause id="id9DE72E13DE8A42E88501375962DA3D01"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id770B13888C5046CFACD44CCA91C46CDC"><enum>(III)</enum><text>The Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives.</text> </subclause><subclause id="idB0BA472B005941C0B320535B2C35DE35"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>The Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id3B996893B6EB47F1BA48F2F5B103BF66"><enum>(V)</enum><text>The Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idC860B8D06FF446DFA20EE4C90B327AF2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Construction of building</header><text>The Board of Regents, in consultation with the Council, may plan, design, and construct a building for the Museum, which shall be located at the site designated by the Board of Regents under this paragraph.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idBCEBAD88513F4E6FB86F5913E403DAFB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Nonapplicability of provisions relating to monuments and commemorative works</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/89">Chapter 89</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code, shall not apply with respect to the Museum.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6686AC717A174FC68021C463E31225FF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Cost sharing</header><text>The Board of Regents shall pay—</text>
 <paragraph id="id47A88B161C834375AA71C31140D3199D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>50 percent of the costs of carrying out this section from Federal funds; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idF738D154FF144E029CDB6E3A559FD176"><enum>(2)</enum><text>50 percent of the costs of carrying out this section from non-Federal sources.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id35704E2B0C7C4B479898BBEA15C63268"><enum>8.</enum><header>Consideration of recommendations of Presidential Commission</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In carrying out their duties under this Act, the Council and the Board of Regents shall take into consideration the reports and plans submitted by the National Museum of Asian Pacific American History and Culture Plan for Action Presidential Commission.</text></section></legis-body>
</bill>


