<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HAC19163FFE9042279BD5D40CB099C086" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4673 IH: Promoting Women in the Aviation Workforce Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4673</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171218">December 18, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000293">Ms. Esty of Connecticut</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="W000813">Mrs. Walorski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000820">Mrs. Mimi Walters of California</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001286">Mrs. Bustos</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To create opportunities for women in the aviation industry.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H31595EB610EB4680A20F2E0FA54B23E6" style="OLC">
 <section id="HC13E8B40A815475EA2DED2864F44D7C4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Promoting Women in the Aviation Workforce Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HB42B95A7FD234AADA101CCA77453A65F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HB260D0ABD35E4245BE07883989A685AC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Women make up over 50 percent of the national workforce, but are significantly underrepresented in the aviation industry. Women represent only 2 percent of airline mechanics, 4 percent of flight engineers, 5 percent of repairmen, 26 percent of air traffic controllers, 18 percent of flight dispatchers, and 6 percent of pilots.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA67BB000FA244B7FA3E54F295BFCE3FC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>12 percent of students enrolled in AABI-accredited programs are women.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8D2732DD57B1453AB8A6C2C41575175D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Women have made tremendous contributions to aviation while under steep adversity. Courageous women like Blanche Scott, Amelia Earhart, Bessie Coleman, Ada Brown, and so many others paved the way for women in aviation and engineering. Their leadership shall be valued and remembered as we continue to grow the influence of women in aviation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBEA6E646073042EF97D1382252B8EDCD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Programs like the annual <quote>Girls in Aviation Day</quote> established by Women in Aviation International in September 2015 help young women be introduced to the different opportunities that are open to women in the aviation and aerospace industry. Support for these efforts will go a long way in supporting women’s aspirations in these fields.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HAACEFBBB60014D118A8080BAA7752D99"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress regarding women in aviation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the aviation industry should explore all opportunities, including pilot training, science, technology, engineering, and mathematics education, and mentorship programs, to encourage and support female students and aviators to pursue a career in aviation.</text>
		</section><section id="H1C16B235A52049D092C02FC9DBE19E6F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Supporting women’s involvement in the aviation field</header>
 <subsection id="H0A8473A8BDA042BA88C682B75B276E6F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Advisory Board</header><text>To encourage women and girls to enter the field of aviation, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall create and facilitate the Women in Aviation Advisory Board (referred to in this section as the <quote>Board</quote>), with the objective of promoting organizations and programs that are providing education, training, mentorship, outreach, and recruitment of women into the aviation industry.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2C055FF07EA0429CA5A76550462F1E88"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The Board shall consist of members whose diverse background allows them to contribute balanced points of view and ideas regarding the strategies and objectives set forth in section 4(f).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H377712482D504CFCBE7109E45C846650"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Selection</header><text>Not later than 9 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall appoint members of the Board, including representatives from the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HB283472E114848FD92A7E4EEA935C084"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Major airlines and aerospace companies.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0212A006CFF149298B0E9149224171C8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Nonprofit organizations within the aviation industry.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFB2E56EF9E4C4E15834A0B1A26C3082B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Aviation business associations.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6CCF41E7934D4CD59258237D22690660"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Engineering business associations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7EA248AB7AE74830ABE2F529B1E986FE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>United States Air Force Auxiliary, Civil Air Patrol.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4177CE3F5CFE4EC4A4670800A1F138CA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Period of Appointment</header><text>Members shall be appointed to the Board for the duration of the existence of the Board.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA8E19A741BF44178A4F0DB4BBA2DC3DD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>Board members shall serve without compensation.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H3F0B10E1E54045D98DB49E568F7DFFA4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Board shall present a comprehensive plan for strategies the Administration can take, which include the following objectives:</text>
 <paragraph id="H9EBCF7070AE34E2394C237323A29CF96"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Identifying industry trends that directly or indirectly discourage women from pursuing careers in aviation, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5EC79BA896B44870867B94510B106B9D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">possible differences between women minority groups; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE4206175A764E169B4457B7623AB9C0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>possible differences between women who live in rural, suburban, and urban areas.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC937EAB3D9794DF8AD0242924F4703B2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Coordinating the functions of airline companies, nonprofit organizations, and aviation and engineering associations to facilitate support for women pursuing careers in aviation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H86320F23DB0B45BBB0AA604EADCF83FC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Creating opportunities to expand existing scholarship opportunities for women in the aviation industry.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H642B178CFD54468D8A648AE54C5868D2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Enhancing aviation training, mentorship, education, and outreach programs that are exclusive to women.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H87BB2320A1724D3AB134C0956411275E"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reports</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H29E2051DAA294E00A9919B5E85CCC08C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit a report to—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H5CF470BF83C84267886092AC85A1276E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HCC3B77BC7EDC4FAF87ED02267BD595D0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE6D2F969EA824502B12F5E8AD926FE4F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability online</header><text>The Administrator shall make the report publicly available online and in print.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

