<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H4303D56908B649F8B077D1A86AE70EE0" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2776 RH: Workforce Democracy and Fairness Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
		<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 236</calendar>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2776</legis-num>
		<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 115–326]</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20170606">June 6, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000798">Mr. Walberg</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000450">Ms. Foxx</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000582">Mr. Roe of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001289">Mr. Byrne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000372">Mr. Allen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001201">Mr. Mitchell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<action><action-date>September 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="F000465">Mr. Ferguson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000607">Mr. Francis Rooney of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001189">Mr. Messer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action>
			<action-date>September 25, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the
			 Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
			<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction>
			<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on June 6, 2017</action-instruction>
		</action>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-desc display="yes"><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To amend the National Labor Relations Act with respect to the timing of elections and pre-election
			 hearings and the identification of pre-election issues.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body changed="added" committee-id="HED00" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H5A7CCA3D60C54247AA4F107852550C6A" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <section id="H9ADAC8B2FD794C09A6612E46E91C2572" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Workforce Democracy and Fairness Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HC8CB5F28F8AE4A2CB6583F2872A3BC0B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pre-election hearings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 9(c)(1) of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/159">29 U.S.C. 159(c)(1)</external-xref>) is amended in the matter following subparagraph (B)—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6917372BE77142C6B4586F414F6B10E8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, but in no circumstances less than 14 calendar days after the filing of the petition</quote> after <quote>upon due notice</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB4D498D0C1654D4CAB449C68E6A38846"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after <quote>with respect thereto.</quote> the following: <quote>An appropriate hearing shall be one that is non-adversarial with the hearing officer charged, in collaboration with the parties, with the responsibility of identifying any relevant and material pre-election issues and thereafter making a full record thereon. Relevant and material pre-election issues shall include, in addition to unit appropriateness, the Board’s jurisdiction and any other issue the resolution of which may make an election unnecessary or may reasonably be expected to impact the outcome of the election. Parties may independently raise any relevant and material pre-election issue or assert any relevant and material position at any time prior to the close of the hearing.</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB9AB06BC7E35463EBF72DD93FB1A00E9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and shall certify the results thereof</quote> and inserting <quote>to be conducted as soon as practicable but no earlier than 35 calendar days after the filing of an election petition. The Board shall certify the results of the election after it has ruled on each pre-election issue not resolved before the election and any additional issue pertaining to the conduct or results of the election</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HFD8FC04D2C29404BBB3A58EA6A19AC30"><enum>3.</enum><header>Determination of appropriate units for collective bargaining</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 9(b) of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/159">29 U.S.C. 159(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H8E41C83C30D24CDE9B8355714A00212F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1) through (3) as subparagraphs (A) through (C), respectively;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H557706845CB640DF8D63251743F3EC73"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>The Board shall decide</quote> and all that follows through <quote>or subdivision thereof:</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HED00" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H4C0F7992AF13488F855BBDD90D26AD4E" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"> <text>(1) In each case, prior to an election, the Board shall determine, in order to assure to employees the fullest freedom in exercising the rights guaranteed by this Act, the unit appropriate for the purposes of collective bargaining. Unless otherwise stated in this Act, and excluding any bargaining unit determination promulgated through rulemaking before August 26, 2011, the unit appropriate for purposes of collective bargaining shall consist of employees that share a sufficient community of interest. In determining whether employees share a sufficient community of interest, the Board shall consider—</text><subparagraph id="HFC89DDBB316D4A158284D11398DE5F74" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">similarity of wages, benefits, and working conditions;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H610AA06BC0C745EF80FEAEAFA7C3B301" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>similarity of skills and training;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BA0EF2B69FE4D48B754D726B962367E" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>centrality of management and common supervision;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E69CED16B3E4F27A71174A1AC139D9E" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>extent of interchange and frequency of contact between employees;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55E10D6F4B3B4AAEA7B3608B0D0DAA7B" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>integration of the work flow and interrelationship of the production process;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD3C6BE3E0D542BBA8B3E3C71F67892E" indent="up1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the consistency of the unit with the employer’s organizational structure;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBBBB1350650E4E21B2B6B67BB70479C4" indent="up1"><enum>(G)</enum><text>similarity of job functions and work; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H894952B08E824B858503A200ED5115DC" indent="up1"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the bargaining history in the particular unit and the industry.</text>
					</subparagraph><quoted-block-continuation-text quoted-block-continuation-text-level="subsection">To avoid the proliferation or fragmentation of bargaining units, no employee shall be excluded from
			 the unit unless the interests of the group seeking a separate unit are
			 sufficiently distinct from those of other employees to warrant the
			 establishment of a separate unit. Whether additional employees should be
			 included in a proposed unit shall be determined based on whether such
			 additional employees and proposed unit members share a sufficient
			 community of interest, with the sole exception of proposed accretions to
			 an existing unit, in which the inclusion of additional employees shall be
			 based on whether such additional employees and existing unit members share
			 an overwhelming community of interest and the additional employees have
			 little or no separate identity.</quoted-block-continuation-text><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA9F2870925CD47D49A64E095BDE587F5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote><italic>Provided, </italic>That the Board</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HED00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4AC54A47A8554DE7AE91F3D7722A5924" reported-display-style="italic" style="traditional"> <paragraph id="H041524210C21492CAB477D29FF0F89A6" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Board</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
	<endorsement display="yes">
		<action-date>September 25, 2017</action-date>
		<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the
			 Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill>


