<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H5C4F27AC41E14ACDA9B2522E3FB2C856" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4132 IH: Veterans Affairs Physician Recruitment Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4132</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171025">October 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000600">Mrs. Radewagen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001077">Mr. Coffman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000628">Mr. Dunn</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to make certain improvements in the Health Professionals
			 Educational Assistance Program of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H60260E95BF0743BE82123A9FDB9B3EB9" style="OLC">
 <section commented="no" id="HD0F38E5363944CC597B99E1BD1BC60C9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Affairs Physician Recruitment Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HBBD6D82D7C5745F0AD6A01061FC9434A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Designated scholarships for physicians and dentists under Department of Veterans Affairs Health Professional Scholarship Program</header> <subsection id="H3FCCEAFA623F4A0BBDAF45092F6B900C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Scholarships for physicians and dentists</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7612(b) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7A258ACE530746008AFD44BEE981866B" style="USC">
					<paragraph id="H77D44276AFD84AC7861F7EFB96CEA468" indent="up1"><enum>(6)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1EA4F9E6BE5A421586FF47F61DD75AD9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Of the scholarships awarded under this subchapter, the Secretary shall ensure that not less than 50 scholarships are awarded each year to individuals who are accepted for enrollment or enrolled (as described in section 7602 of this title) in a program of education or training leading to employment as a physician or dentist until such date as the Secretary determines that the staffing shortage of physicians and dentists in the Department is less than 500.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5002326D7B5A483E89BD6771DD513610" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>After such date, the Secretary shall ensure that of the scholarships awarded under this subchapter, a number of scholarships is awarded each year to individuals referred to in subparagraph (A) in an amount equal to not less than ten percent of the staffing shortage of physicians and dentists in the Department, as determined by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H16F33EB6C45B47EB86FBD228D03D7399" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Notwithstanding subsection (c)(1), the agreement between the Secretary and a participant in the Scholarship Program who receives a scholarship pursuant to this paragraph shall provide the following:</text>
 <clause id="H072922B7CE4C490CB9BE8317C8183F41"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary’s agreement to provide the participant with a scholarship under this subchapter for a specified number (from two to four) of school years during which the participant is pursuing a course of education or training leading to employment as a physician or dentist.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7B62BA70374C414D87FE82DB4E4A4337"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The participant's agreement to serve as a full-time employee in the Veterans Health Administration for a period of time (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as the <quote>period of obligated service</quote>) of 18 months for each school year or part thereof for which the participant was provided a scholarship under the Scholarship Program.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04E4ED37F99E4B99B9DBDA26551A45FE" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>In providing scholarships pursuant to this paragraph, the Secretary may provide a preference for applicants who are veterans.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H201F9FEF8DDC4A4391B81C599740F4F2" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>On an annual basis, the Secretary shall provide to appropriate educational institutions informational material about the availability of scholarships under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC87E557ADE394290AEA69402A7D56291"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Breach of agreement</header><text>Section 7617 of such title is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HBD752E5104764D1B9FD29A0BAC853D5C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (4) and (5) as paragraphs (5) and (6), respectively; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6E2DD125E19F4C21B57E4CA64CFC2FF1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (3) the following new paragraph (4):</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H84FC7E368CB24F18BA304CF74219DF0D" style="USC"> <paragraph id="HCAA1F95624EB4008AD6ED86A1A7FCD6B"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a participant who is enrolled in a program or education or training leading to employment as a physician, the participant fails to successfully complete post-graduate training leading to eligibility for board certification in a specialty.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1FA0F5AF68AB4B659A26C7C0FFD049C5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Extension of program</header><text>Section 7619 of such title is amended by striking <quote>December 31, 2019</quote> and inserting <quote>December 31, 2033</quote>.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H32CE17D7FB76417495E259C7C9542292" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishing the Department of Veterans Affairs Specialty Education Loan Repayment Program</header> <subsection id="H5CB6C13F91C34DA188B5F8A0B4DDEDC7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/76">Chapter 76</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting after subchapter VII the following new subchapter:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBE67674F1BE84E72A9D0474704D8861F" style="USC">
					<subchapter id="H08765ADD330A43058BB349BB6849385A"><enum>VIII</enum><header>Specialty Education Loan Repayment Program</header>
 <section id="H719F5A3AB378453CB076A53F9CADC583"><enum>7691.</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">As part of the Educational Assistance Program, the Secretary may carry out a student loan repayment program under section 5379 of title 5. The program shall be known as the Department of Veterans Affairs Specialty Education Loan Repayment Program (in this chapter referred to as the <quote>Specialty Education Loan Repayment Program</quote>).</text>
 </section><section id="H67EC65B838534691AACAE2CF963A7A29"><enum>7692.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of the Specialty Education Loan Repayment Program is to assist, through the establishment of an incentive program for certain individuals employed in the Veterans Health Administration, in meeting the staffing needs of the Veterans Health Administration for physicians in medical specialties for which the Secretary determines recruitment or retention of qualified personnel is difficult.</text>
						</section><section id="HE0C15F28049D4602926A2FC07A9F2CD4"><enum>7693.</enum><header>Eligibility; preference; covered costs</header>
 <subsection id="H01E8EB76F36444EBA592EDEF542238FC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>An individual is eligible to participate in the Specialty Education Loan Repayment Program if the individual—</text>
 <paragraph id="HCB5B4C915DB148298FB7D97812210F22"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is hired under section 7401 of this title to work in an occupation described in section 7692 of this title;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAFF3EBA7AAE54EE5837800556B11C620"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">owes any amount of principal or interest under a loan, the proceeds of which were used by or on behalf of that individual to pay costs relating to a course of education or training which led to a degree that qualified the individual for the position referred to in paragraph (1); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCBB00A53F0E44CBFA69BA70CE961227F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is—</text> <subparagraph id="H040D57120EF445AC90083C6D00C6F53F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>recently graduated from an accredited medical or osteopathic school and matched to an accredited residency program in a medical specialty described in section 7692 of this title; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC8A26DAB7E94A78A384BDF020A89FF4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a physician in training in a medical specialty described in section 7692 of this title with more than two years remaining in such training.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H790A1E28BC4E46C2988746B9AEEBA787"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Preference for veterans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In selecting individuals for participation in the Specialty Education Loan Repayment Program under this subchapter, the Secretary may give preference to veterans.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H763CEC69F5EB4AD993AD6C6CD5EC7285"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Covered costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (a)(2), costs relating to a course of education or training include—</text> <paragraph id="H35AF60F338154F68AE7C049BABC060F4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">tuition expenses;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7954E97A61AB40548AB0F8BE30153405"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all other reasonable educational expenses, including expenses for fees, books, equipment, and laboratory expenses; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3BFC662B6B6D40AF8B92393A8EF0BA6B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reasonable living expenses.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H60ECC653F3A540C8A052854DA709782E"><enum>7694.</enum><header>Specialty education loan repayment</header> <subsection id="HD670BD5EEAE54C899FA5E34A8CB924FA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Payments under the Specialty Education Loan Repayment Program shall consist of payments for the principal and interest on loans described in section 7682(a)(2) of this title for individuals selected to participate in the Program to the holders of such loans.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6A6F8997935049368A0C1BDB40EB9D78"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Frequency of payment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall make payments for any given participant in the Specialty Education Loan Repayment Program on a schedule determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="H3731CB9122B3485AA3F0C7F88FBBEFEE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Maximum amount; waiver</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE94FAC389E2C490688334337D67BF938"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of payments made for a participant under the Specialty Education Loan Repayment Program may not exceed $160,000 over a total of four years of participation in the Program, of which not more than $40,000 of such payments may be made in each year of participation in the Program.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="H510251C10D6B458CBAD077DE24C25D95" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H6AC63EC4160D42DFB43277A0AEA416D5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may waive the limitations under paragraph (1) in the case of a participant described in subparagraph (B). In the case of such a waiver, the total amount of payments payable to or for that participant is the total amount of the principal and the interest on the participant's loans referred to in subsection (a).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FC3132EEBD24E529C08CB95433EF76B" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A participant described in this subparagraph is a participant in the Program who the Secretary determines serves in a position for which there is a shortage of qualified employees by reason of either the location or the requirements of the position.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H518E6E82833D4EC6ADC69996560B32FE"><enum>7695.</enum><header>Choice of location</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Each participant in the Specialty Education Loan Repayment Program who completes residency may select, from a list of medical facilities of the Veterans Health Administration provided by the Secretary, at which such facility the participant will work in a medical specialty described in section 7692 of this title.</text>
						</section><section id="HDE331BF5C65C4FEEB1EA4D3045B83273"><enum>7696.</enum><header>Term of obligated service</header>
 <subsection id="H509241A7406C4C69A0FC270BF8F2286A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In addition to any requirements under section 5379(c) of title 5, a participant in the Specialty Education Loan Repayment Program must agree, in writing and before the Secretary may make any payment to or for the participant, to—</text>
 <paragraph id="HBA42C42E4BFF4B20A719FBCCC20026E8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>obtain a license to practice medicine in a State;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2BDBF1769D574A3DB795068968D8D94F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>successfully complete post-graduate training leading to eligibility for board certification in a specialty;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H70F8D2E53E6E43499C5713BECB1C5FC1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>serve as a full-time clinical practice employee of the Veterans Health Administration for 12 months for every $40,000 in such benefits that the employee receives, but in no case for fewer than 24 months; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5280E033A7E944B1B4868649C749EB9C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>except as provided in subsection (b), to begin such service as a full-time practice employee by not later than 60 days after completing a residency.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB9E69B78783A4B379D67AB4F5B0272E9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Fellowship</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a participant who receives an accredited fellowship in a medical specialty other than a medical specialty described in section 7692 of this title, the Secretary, on written request of the participant, may delay the term of obligated service under subsection (a) for the participant until after the participant completes the fellowship, but in no case later than 60 days after completion of such fellowship.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="HB9B983A19B9849EBB201C3C752BD74E0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Penalty</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H8ACE3130491442DAA50CDAD7A806941D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An employee who does not complete a period of obligated service under this section shall owe the Federal Government an amount determined in accordance with the following formula:</text><table align-to-level="section" blank-lines-before="1" colsep="0" frame="none" line-rules="no-gen" rowsep="0" rule-weights="0.0.0.0.0.0" table-template-name="Generic: 1 text" table-type=""><tgroup cols="1" grid-typeface="1.1" rowsep="0" thead-tbody-ldg-size="0.10.12"><colspec align="center" coldef="txt-no-ldr" colname="column1" colwidth="336pts" min-data-value="300" rowsep="0"></colspec><tbody><row><entry align="center" colname="column1" leader-modify="clr-ldr" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">A = B × ((T−S) ÷ T)).</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H0FC08BE1E32D42F6BD3643590837D96D" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the formula in paragraph (1):</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H6910E882CCF94C5484B33ECD0D9C53FB"><enum>(A)</enum><text><quote>A</quote> is the amount the employee owes the Federal Government.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0F99AB64FC67480B937562BD2E5DADEF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><quote>B</quote> is the sum of all payments to or for the participant under the Specialty Education Loan Repayment Program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1086656FF09A4BCD81EE325E1E5250F3"><enum>(C)</enum><text><quote>T</quote> is the number of months in the period of obligated service of the employee.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7BD5EEEF29C148B88DC908D3A7C86098"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><quote>S</quote> is the number of whole months of such period of obligated service served by the employee.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H225BB530EDE649C294477ED64064343D"><enum>7697.</enum><header>Relationship to Educational Assistance Program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Assistance under the Specialty Education Loan Repayment Program may be in addition to other assistance available to individuals under the Educational Assistance Program.</text></section></subchapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H67D9E91E94224C5187E32CB95BAB16F3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming and technical amendments</header>
				<paragraph id="H3201CBD5786345C1942CFEC3F6C2041E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <subparagraph id="H3F0DF62145534104B8386104FE81CB40"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7601(a) of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text> <clause id="HC6B60A16A74B42DBA2AB0D61C26483DD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>and</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H058A2FAD01964B68A134AF131018544F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="HA5EF8F6472BF48308378CEA2CBB0FC70"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7CC7ABEF79CF48CC8813EB41987199BC" style="USC">
 <paragraph id="H74C2A4A198DF4EAF962F37098877C78B"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the specialty education loan repayment program provided for in subchapter VIII of this chapter.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H567DFB253DD14C07ADBBFD38EBB56B3A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 7603(a)(1) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>or VI</quote> and inserting <quote>VI, or VIII</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB9AAB34B3E1410383EFA039C4865578"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Section 7604 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>or VI</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>VI, or VIII</quote>.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H307021C64AF140D2BC66F76782CC9084"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7631 of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <clause id="H9DF24E145C5A48B9874BD60E708C38B3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1)—</text> <subclause id="HE03602FC57D7441EBCB52BD4E6BEB9A1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> after <quote>scholarship amount</quote>; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE9A6BEA89C254BEC806C702695F3E30D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, and the maximum specialty education loan repayment amount</quote> after <quote>reduction payments amount</quote>; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H9EC44432CD734A909B7661B52E6957B6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subsection (b) by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2D0E51353E81406DAE319003A42D99DB" style="USC">
 <paragraph id="H3263E8CFD89F4057863D56604D60D212" indent="up1"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>specialty education loan repayment amount</quote> means the maximum amount of specialty education loan repayment payments payable to or for a participant in the Department of Veterans Affairs Specialty Education Loan Repayment Program under subchapter VIII of this chapter, as specified in section 7694(c)(1) of this title and as previously adjusted (if at all) in accordance with this section.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF602D7E688BC46C9AE1A83DB1F75287A"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7632 of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text> <clause id="H69FD66AF496A4DEE9E694A63B46525B1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>and the Education Debt Reduction Program</quote> and inserting <quote>the Education Debt Reduction Program, and the Specialty Education Loan Repayment Program</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC10C3E2FDE0541BA83F2AF6F73751427"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>and per participant in the Education Debt Reduction Program</quote> and inserting <quote>per participant in the Education Debt Reduction Program, and per participant in the Specialty Education Loan Repayment Program</quote>.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC1120397E8A1478BA4840B99DA79C6EE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Table of sections</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 76 of such title is amended by inserting after the items relating to subchapter VII the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBD4410765C0D4F02BC23E84FB4D2DFCE" style="USC">
						<toc regeneration="yes-regeneration">
							<toc-entry idref="H08765ADD330A43058BB349BB6849385A" level="subchapter">Subchapter VIII—Specialty Education Loan Repayment Program</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry level="section">Sec.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H719F5A3AB378453CB076A53F9CADC583" level="section">7691. Establishment.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H67EC65B838534691AACAE2CF963A7A29" level="section">7692. Purpose.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="HE0C15F28049D4602926A2FC07A9F2CD4" level="section">7693. Eligibility; preference; covered costs.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry level="section">7694. Specialty education loan repayment.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry level="section">7695. Choice of location.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="HDE331BF5C65C4FEEB1EA4D3045B83273" level="section">7696. Term of obligated service.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H225BB530EDE649C294477ED64064343D" level="section">7697. Relationship to Educational Assistance Program.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBE64933A3796450DA469DCA5338BBD44"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Needs of the VHA</header><text>In making determinations each year under section 7692 of title 38, United States Code, as enacted by subsection (a), the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall consider the anticipated needs of the Veterans Health Administration during the period two to six years in the future.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H57678235201D4C4C939FFB9FAFCCD3E3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Offer deadline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an applicant who applies before receiving a residency match and whom the Secretary of Veterans Affairs selects for participation in the Specialty Education Loan Repayment Program established by subsection (a), the Secretary shall offer participation to the applicant not later than 28 days after—</text>
 <paragraph id="HBC8019C5937A4EE3AC8DF0F46511D30A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the applicant matches with a residency in a medical specialty described in section 7692 of title 38, United States Code, as enacted by subsection (a); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H35FB184661FC44E08BAB1CBBF4A20B25"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such match is published.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE29B5879ED4B4A6FA9578381700243FE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Publicity</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall take such steps as the Secretary determines are appropriate to publicize the Specialty Education Loan Repayment Program established under subchapter VIII of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/76">chapter 76</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, as enacted by subsection (a).</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HC129821CEF514428817957AC9F0F79FF" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header>Veterans healing veterans medical access and scholarship program</header>
 <subsection id="H154A0792817842CF928DC4A81CF49337"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs, acting through the Office of Academic Affiliations of the Department of Veterans Affairs, shall carry out a pilot program under which the Secretary shall provide funding for the medical education of a total of ten eligible veterans. Such funding shall be provided for two veterans enrolled in each of the five Teague-Cranston medical schools in accordance with this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBA57169F7CEF482681A854DD7B1C4475"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible veterans</header><text>To be eligible to receive funding for medical education under this section, a veteran shall—</text> <paragraph id="H7CD27D2B264A48818F0222C12BB53184"><enum>(1)</enum><text>have been discharged from the Armed Forces not more than ten years before the date of application for admission to a Teague-Cranston medical school;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2587939997F3470BBEDED1932A7BDC1A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not be entitled to educational assistance under chapter 30, 31, 32, 33, 34, or 35 of title 38, United States Code, or chapter 1606 or 1607 of title 10, United States Code;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCEA430E6AC734B00BED0AF0BA049B8B6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>apply for admission to a Teague-Cranston medical school for the entering class of 2019;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEA0A758B9D254CF98240A412A73BECFC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>indicate on such application for admission that the veteran would like to be considered for an award of funding under this section;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBB329665E30C4BBB9226C039A1B20047"><enum>(5)</enum><text>meet the minimum admissions criteria for the Teague-Cranston medical school to which the veteran applies; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF727534544604371BD6D94EF204CB7BC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>enter into an agreement described in subsection (e).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H47128B0375A443DD97A3B03E7DC7CB37"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Award of funding</header> <paragraph id="H69F87CFC05FE4B779AE7327D99D03978"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each Teague-Cranston medical school that opts to participate in the program under this section shall reserve two seats in the entering class of 2019 for eligible veterans who receive funding under such program. Such funding shall be awarded to the two eligible veterans with the highest admissions rankings for such class at such school.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H24B563D40A124BF3BBDBD420B927A7C1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amount of funding</header><text>Each eligible veteran who receives funding under this section shall receive an amount equal to the actual cost of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAB2E7C75230A45C29BD8D25F182F80CC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>tuition at the Teague-Cranston medical school at which the veteran enrolls for four years;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H205D3230B8C844B280AFE1026183D443"><enum>(B)</enum><text>books, fees, and technical equipment;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E736CA7919047C19CFCAF7E808F247A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>fees associated with the National Residency Match Program;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F86AB3DC90F4371BC64FF2C8C2DCB35"><enum>(D)</enum><text>two away rotations performed during the fourth year at a Department of Veterans Affairs medical facility; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C1B10499E2249E1A7D0DA8F86F002BE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a monthly stipend for the four-year period during which the veteran is enrolled in medical school in an amount to be determined by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2D7083D88EC41FDAA24711DC03008AB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Distribution of funding</header><text>In the event that two or more eligible veterans do not apply for admission at one of the Teague-Cranston medical schools for the entering class of 2019, the Secretary shall distribute the available funding to eligible veterans who applied for admission at other Teague-Cranston medical schools.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBA903251A36049B2B362F35B5AFF73CD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Agreement</header>
 <paragraph id="HE18254F1C1ED4B4099623EFB71A5CE5F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Terms of agreement</header><text>Each eligible veteran who accepts funding for medical education under this section shall enter into an agreement with the Secretary that provides that the veteran agrees—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE88E34CFC6D34CDA8D63D277A2DF789E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to maintain enrollment and attendance in the medical school;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42C2E71394B0421B948FE38EFC778FFC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>while enrolled in such medical school, to maintain an acceptable level of academic standing (as determined by the medical school under regulations prescribed by the Secretary);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4857D045CC044D8E89E29FF214C777C6"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to complete post-graduate training leading to eligibility for board certification in a speciality applicable to the Department of Veterans Affairs, as determined by the Secretary;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H013D6DBB97C34369A93E0C83BC1019FC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>after completion of medical school, to obtain a license to practice medicine in a State; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFCE17D50480D44D984C1216911B24522"><enum>(E)</enum><text>after completion of medical school and post-graduate training, to serve as a full-time clinical practice employee in the Veterans Health Administration for a period of four years.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HABA782178E76475DB30BCC0DF534AD40"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Breach of agreement</header><text>If an eligible veteran who accepts funding under this section breaches the terms of the agreement described in paragraph (1), the United States shall be entitled to recover damages in an amount equal to the total amount of such funding received by the veteran.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE85A08B033484B0DA791862117CD2C70"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent any Teague-Cranston medical school from accepting more than two eligible veterans for the entering class of 2019.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HDA5F73F66FDA4CCEA5B3C8EC8E7D87F1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than December 31, 2020, and annually thereafter for the subsequent three years, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the pilot program under this section. Such report shall include the evaluation of the Secretary of the success of the pilot program, including the number of veterans who received funding under the program who matriculated and an evaluation of the academic progress of such veterans.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD00FF603C2AD48829ECB16C4573E44BB"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Teague-Cranston medical schools</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>Teague-Cranston medical school</quote> means any of the following:</text> <paragraph id="HBFD733D78F164467B6AE83962CB0BEB7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Texas A&amp;M College of Medicine.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H989E3F1736B546299C44582653527384"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Quillen College of Medicine at East Tennessee State University.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC19E0CA2649F4881BD4E5A330A7F987E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Boonshoft School of Medicine at Wright State University.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA51BADFD2C3B4F4A9C9D6ABB3AE04D6B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Joan C. Edwards School of Medicine at Marshall University.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC38ADABDA69D4CFCBD6469E68D51882A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>University of South Carolina School of Medicine.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


