<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2CAA0855C7844B51A3E460B4FA1AF849" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 272 IH: Back to Basics Job Creation Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 272</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170104">January 4, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000287">Mr. Lewis of Georgia</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XX of the Social Security Act to provide grants to support job creation initiatives,
			 and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H03DAD4C789CD4CD8B337D25312EE740E" style="OLC">
 <section id="H19F3583681554ECB935629A1998F6EF6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Back to Basics Job Creation Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H06706EC8984041758FD250C847941962"><enum>2.</enum><header>Back to Basics Job Creation grant program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subtitle A of title XX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397">42 U.S.C. 1397 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H73E658AF05CD4DF1B1A0FF559B62BD49" style="OLC">
				<section id="H5F7B9AE8F82140AC9810B2A331FE4038"><enum>2010.</enum><header>Back to Basics Job Creation grant program</header>
					<subsection id="H5A22BC4E741E4788A107B4A8A905A4F9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants</header>
 <paragraph id="H8D0302F82DA24ECC9567637DDAB83A6B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor and the Secretary of Commerce, shall make grants to eligible entities to assist low-income individuals and individuals who have been unemployed for at least 3 months in developing self-employment opportunities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC1E548F5D6F948908EE1BAF8F50CA73D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timing of grant awards</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall obligate not less than half of any funds appropriated for grants under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEE9B1AB23DD5439982F97657E4C1E810"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Preference</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give preference to eligible entities—</text> <subparagraph id="H5FF6B92385764A2CB0B72DD362C5A8BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that serve communities that have experienced high levels of poverty and unemployment and low levels of reemployment, as determined by the Secretary using data reported by the Census Bureau and the Bureau of Labor Statistics;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD53A1DF255D244EBB927EECB032BFF47"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that demonstrate an ability to administer activities using the grant funds without acquiring new administrative structures or resources, such as staffing, technology, evaluation activities, training, research, and programming; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9A62F2CB35542E08662A813BA7BC98A"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that have established partnerships with other government agencies, community based organizations, financial institutions, educational institutions, or business organizations.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H83D3DF312EAB4AC6987DFA18FA38CE12"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header>
 <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBDAD47164F55455C804E54DB3F45C98D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity awarded a grant under this section shall use the grant—</text> <subparagraph id="H9D1FF1A00A054850B72A7EF1D48CD547"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide education and training for business and financial literacy, certification, small business plan development, entrepreneurship, and patent and copyright processes; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H971F09F9084640E9BCD7D31286A6679E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to provide funding for new small businesses that pay employees at a living wage.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E8F866EE14D4B13867632F96539FEDE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity awarded a grant under this section may not use the grant—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD559B5FAD07B45BCBF4CFD320B8D6533"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to subsidize private or public employment; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4991BA94CA604CCA894DE40DA4F37B15"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for any activity in violation of Federal, State, or local law.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E1FEBE95DFA42548E5078CE0A4810C2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Administrative expenses</header><text>An eligible entity awarded a grant under this section may use not more than 10 percent of the grant funds for administrative expenses, except that none of the funds may be used for salaries.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD7066AB597F348CAAB43896C23A36F47"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Deadline on use of grant funds</header><text>An eligible entity awarded a grant under this section shall expend the grant funds before December 31, 2019, except that the Secretary may provide an extension.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD14F481D2A504589835C9CA479D5AA21"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No effect on means-Tested benefits</header><text>For purposes of determining eligibility and benefit amounts under any means-tested assistance program, any assistance funded by a grant under this section shall be disregarded.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA2B4C64FC44445099573ADC8C35A7BA9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall submit a report on the implementation of this section to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate whenever either committee shall so request.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD4083A1D04D44E06A8092AE377D27183"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated for grants under this section $5,000,000,000 for fiscal year 2018. The amounts appropriated under this section are authorized to remain available through December 31, 2018.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE9E728808FBD41839DA2FB6BB16E766E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H71610E6248634C4A816F7CF94B58C96F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <quote>eligible entity</quote> means a State, an Indian tribe, or a local government;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA82F16C1677A4AD3958FBE63CFB41440"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>Indian tribe</quote> has the meaning given such term by section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b</external-xref>); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC36FAC378E4A45D699E80BC3D17B6750"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <quote>means-tested assistance program</quote> means a benefit program for which eligibility is based on income.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section></legis-body></bill> 

