<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF7ADD4FD537D4F9799EDC3A850BBD8A5" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3612 IH: Prioritizing Education in Conflict Zones Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3612</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20170728">July 28, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To amend the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to provide assistance to expand, improve, support, and
			 promote primary and secondary education for displaced children, including
			 girls, from areas designated by the Department of State as areas of
			 conflict.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HAED74424A9E44772B7E891CC212FE6B9" style="OLC">
 <section id="HF597A3BF200C487480B4FE119EA0BC2C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prioritizing Education in Conflict Zones Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HC43CFD6EEB3E4E6F810B1030EFEB5DB5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Assistance to improve primary and secondary education for displaced children from areas of conflict</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 is amended by inserting after section 105 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151c">22 U.S.C. 2151c</external-xref>) the following new section:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5D3134DCE1BC4FD6A2DFF22DDE97CEFE" style="OLC">
				<section id="H8523DD161ABC40EDA0784B48BD9B121E"><enum>105A.</enum><header>Assistance to improve primary and secondary education for displaced children from areas of conflict</header>
 <subsection id="HB3C8F279710B4F8A8D66305C35F82421"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>The Secretary of State and Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, acting through the Director of Refugee Educational Assistance designated pursuant to subsection (c), is authorized to provide long-term assistance to expand, improve, support, and promote primary and secondary education for displaced children from areas of conflict.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDE7F79B22A8A48EFB212F2835816D8E0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Activities supported</header><text>Assistance provided under subsection (a) shall, to the maximum extent practicable, be used to—</text> <paragraph id="H854F125E118E494FBD29B242BBC3E80B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>build the capacity for private sector and civil society organizations with a stated purpose of educating children, including girls, in the areas of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDC73EA9CABA64A75946EFF2DCCA55D63"><enum>(A)</enum><text>development and strengthening of primary and secondary curricula;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H52B7BF4C409D40ADB92EF9E77184545A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>coordination with educational facilities of host countries; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8EDCAFE14CA4409DBBD4E57B90540A98"><enum>(C)</enum><text>technical capacities and expertise, including strategies for cost-effective procurement of science and technology equipment;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H74917950DAC2491788D7591DABB1EB11"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish, expand, and promote linkages and partnerships between host countries’ educational facilities, private sector and civil organizations, and United States colleges and universities education programs; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCD670B7EB999430698EBDA5212DF85DD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assist with efforts to educate women and girls.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4A7BB7ADCA8245B29798B7A68C894D81"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Director of Refugee Educational Assistance</header> <paragraph id="H3BACAA63E20941B19961358D7F8848FC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development shall designate a Director of Refugee Educational Assistance, who shall report directly to the Administrator, and who shall carry out the responsibilities described in paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB429348724B14EE3A63EE97A66B8CA30"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>The responsibilities referred to in paragraph (1) include—</text> <subparagraph id="H43E51FE34D8242BE8CC3742DB45C9239"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ongoing consultations with and the provision of technical advice to host country governments, particularly ministries of education, regional organizations, and public tertiary and related educational institutions, and education and educators’ organizations with respect to carrying out the activities described in subsection (b);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6B1742CE825489296A39EB8522F2A3A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>coordination and administration of long-term assistance authorized under subsection (a) in support of the activities described in subsection (b); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05ADC866BBC24FDDA67EBC51F984963E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>coordinating with other bureaus within the United States Agency for International Development, with other relevant United States Government agencies, with the United States and international private sectors, with the primary and secondary education community and relevant research organizations in the United States and host countries, and with other bilateral and multilateral development partners to maximize the gains and impact of activities carried out under subsection (b)(1).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H340F957CED804D5FBFA4FECE3D4A033E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Public-Private partnerships</header><text>The Director of Refugee Educational Assistance shall seek, to the extent practicable, to use any funding appropriated for the purpose of carrying out the duties, goals, and functions described in this section to leverage equal or greater sources of private sector funding for such purposes, and shall undertake and prioritize efforts to identify such sources of private sector funding.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA51BDA1C2D3D4023B6E543347210425C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>education</term> means primary and secondary academic training.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HF1EBBB3BC78E40938F3E044C41A1617D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $970,000,000 for fiscal year 2018 and such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2028.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


