<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD9DB73799E1B4626AB6A02FCD025032C" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1313 RH: Preserving Employee Wellness Programs Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
		<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 341</calendar>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1313</legis-num>
		<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 115–459, Part I]</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20170302">March 2, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000450">Ms. Foxx</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="W000798">Mr. Walberg</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20171211">December 11, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001201">Mr. Mitchell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001189">Mr. Messer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000580">Mr. Garrett</cosponsor></action-desc>
		</action>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20171211">December 11, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc>Reported from the Committee on <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Education and the Workforce</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc>
			<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction>
		</action>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20171211">December 11, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc>The Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name> and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to
			 be printed</action-desc>
			<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on March 2, 2017</action-instruction>
		</action>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-desc display="yes"><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To clarify rules relating to nondiscriminatory workplace wellness programs.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body changed="added" committee-id="HED00" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H9090A085423C42F58454449B7B597E7D" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <section id="H4BBEDCE755EA4C7A980F0ED999177BCF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preserving Employee Wellness Programs Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H9924B48FB85045298D69CA6E0D5A0FF7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H97BFEA5F947342BF80B5F664DA961CA1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Congress has a strong tradition of protecting and preserving employee workplace wellness programs, including programs that utilize a health risk assessment, biometric screening, or other resources to inform and empower employees in making healthier lifestyle choices;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H84DDEC6FC86B4E7AB19948CA91CE2ED8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>health promotion and prevention programs are a means to reduce the burden of chronic illness, improve health, and limit the growth of health care costs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7868692CF275478A9B15264A9843F693"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in enacting the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref>), Congress intended that employers would be permitted to implement health promotion and prevention programs that provide incentives, rewards, rebates, surcharges, penalties, or other inducements related to wellness programs, including rewards of up to 50 percent off of insurance premiums for employees participating in programs designed to encourage healthier lifestyle choices; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA473D841FC0046F689E27E5548D013D4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Congress has struck an appropriate balance among employees, health care providers, and wellness plan sponsors to protect individual privacy and confidentiality in a wellness program which is designed to improve health outcomes.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H148632384CF14505B8C33C84AD094557"><enum>3.</enum><header>Nondiscriminatory workplace wellness programs</header>
			<subsection commented="no" id="HF2C514B161BA49B0864FA76180365A08"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Uniformity across Federal agencies</header>
				<paragraph commented="no" id="H1B157445200741E59516D9E5620A9EA7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Programs offered in conjunction with an employer-sponsored health plan</header>
 <subparagraph id="HCCA709D1B7954219B4B613E25942F66E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a workplace wellness program and any program of health promotion or disease prevention offered by an employer in conjunction with an employer-sponsored health plan that complies with section 2705(j) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-4">42 U.S.C. 300gg–4(j)</external-xref>) (and any regulations promulgated with respect to such section by the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, or the Secretary of the Treasury) shall be considered to be in compliance with the following provisions (to the extent such programs are subject to the Acts described in such provisions):</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H7112458BCA5847F08934F4DF05C4DD71"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the acceptable examinations and inquiries set forth in section 102(d)(4)(B) of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12112">42 U.S.C. 12112(d)(4)(B)</external-xref>);</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HD7D2556946BB4A5EB8DE1A86F6FDF57F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 2705(d) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-4">42 U.S.C. 300gg–4(d)</external-xref>); and</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HD4B69F978199401BA9490AAF1CD6A3BE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 202(b)(2) of the Genetic Information Nondiscrimination Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000ff-1">42 U.S.C. 2000ff–1(b)(2)</external-xref>).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE895586903F94910BA782A92008C3722"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Safe harbor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, section 501(c)(2) of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12201">42 U.S.C. 12201(c)(2)</external-xref>) shall apply to any workplace wellness program or program of health promotion or disease prevention offered by an employer in conjunction with an employer-sponsored health plan.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA045858B3EB4CB39725F110E7027B5D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other programs offering more favorable treatment for adverse health factors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a workplace wellness program and a program of health promotion or disease prevention offered by an employer that provides for more favorable treatment of individuals with adverse health factors as described in section 146.121(g) of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations) shall be considered to be in compliance with—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HFCFE578F74094A0EB68DD76C9268A8A0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the acceptable examinations and inquiries set forth in section 102(d)(4)(B) of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12112">42 U.S.C. 12112(d)(4)(B)</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5929D7153414445A9C27582620B943F6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 2705(d) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-4">42 U.S.C. 300gg–4(d)</external-xref>); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0EEDAE72732A488A810E73835714FB7F"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 202(b)(2) of the Genetic Information Nondiscrimination Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000ff-1">42 U.S.C. 2000ff–1(b)(2)</external-xref>).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H36B966587F0C4D5081097E6619A38B0E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Programs not offered in conjunction with an employer-sponsored health plan</header>
 <subparagraph id="H06F37A71BE5B4FCAA50F670792357EBB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a workplace wellness program and any program of health promotion or disease prevention offered by an employer that are not offered in conjunction with an employer-sponsored health plan that is not described in section 2705(j) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-4">42 U.S.C. 300gg–4(j)</external-xref>) that meet the requirement set forth in subparagraph (B) shall be considered to be in compliance with—</text>
 <clause id="H98EBCA3E9C8646A09ADEE3878927A376"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the acceptable examinations and inquiries as set forth in section 102(d)(4)(B) of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12112">42 U.S.C. 12112(d)(4)(B)</external-xref>);</text>
 </clause><clause id="H21C07954664043BFAB4E082A457F0994"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>section 2705(d) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-4">42 U.S.C. 300gg–4(d)</external-xref>); and</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H28038EE077E140DEA9FD36A2A0D2A78D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>section 202(b)(2) of the Genetic Information Nondiscrimination Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000ff-1">42 U.S.C. 2000ff–1(b)(2)</external-xref>).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7B1ECE53B8C4433C81EFA48AA380B7B7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation on rewards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirement referenced in subparagraph (A) is that any reward provided or offered by a program described in such subparagraph shall be less than or equal to the maximum reward amounts provided for by section 2705(j)(3)(A) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-4">42 U.S.C. 300gg–4(j)(3)(A)</external-xref>), and any regulations promulgated with respect to such section by the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, or the Secretary of the Treasury.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6DF281FD1E194E61BFFD67BF7BE56748"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Collection of information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the collection of information about the manifested disease or disorder of a family member shall not be considered an unlawful acquisition of genetic information with respect to another family member as part of a workplace wellness program described in subsection (a) offered by an employer (or in conjunction with an employer-sponsored health plan described in section 2705(j) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-4">42 U.S.C. 300gg–4(j)</external-xref>)) and shall not violate title I or title II of the Genetic Information Nondiscrimination Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/233">Public Law 110–233</external-xref>). For purposes of the preceding sentence, the term <term>family member</term>has the meaning given such term in section 201 of the Genetic Information Nondiscrimination Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/233">Public Law 110–233</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6DA0F768EF954FDA99BAA354433B0F0F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in subsection (a)(1)(A) shall be construed to prevent an employer that is offering a wellness program to an employee from requiring such employee, within 45 days from the date the employee first has an opportunity to earn a reward, to request a reasonable alternative standard (or waiver of the otherwise applicable standard). Nothing in subsection (a)(1)(A) shall be construed to prevent an employer from imposing a reasonable time period, based upon all the facts and circumstances, during which the employee must complete the reasonable alternative standard. Such a reasonable alternative standard (or waiver of the otherwise applicable standard) is provided for in section 2705(j)(3)(D) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300">42 U.S.C. 300</external-xref> gg-4(j)(3)(D)) (and any regulations promulgated with respect to such section by the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, or the Secretary of the Treasury).</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
	<endorsement display="yes">
		<action-date date="20171211">December 11, 2017</action-date>
		<action-desc>Reported from the Committee on <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Education and the Workforce</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc>
		<action-date>December 11, 2017</action-date><action-desc>The Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name> and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to
			 be printed</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill>


