<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H4082FC62264641728A641D8102D8272E" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4608 IH: Securing Urgent Resources Vital to Indian Victim Empowerment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4608</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171211">December 11, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000171">Mr. O'Halleran</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001053">Mr. Cole</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001191">Ms. Sinema</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young of Alaska</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Victims of Crime Act of 1984 to secure urgent resources vital to Indian victims of
			 crime, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H3E1FE38559394DA2A20C495B9FF4A0C9" style="OLC">
 <section id="H0232A80334734F5AA423FC270DD6760A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Securing Urgent Resources Vital to Indian Victim Empowerment Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SURVIVE Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H3134133AAA7340A9B3245C088947B41B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Indian victims of crime</header> <subsection commented="no" id="H21CCAC78FC3E4759AD8A56F7A01F61D7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grant program for Indian crime victim services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Victims of Crime Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/20101">34 U.S.C. 20101</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by inserting after section 1404F the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC1275C604871492FB6BD33C8D4253EB2" style="traditional">
 <section id="H63663E74FA4C4905A18263A795F1918C"><enum>1404G.</enum><header>Grant program for Indian crime victim services</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H56B17DC86B5949BEBB2348AC18B0FD0E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H5E275A86E7FA4448910884F889A3148C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3F9342B8821F44A68CF006BBAA5CB55A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H235E23A2D4BD4FC58CD5BEF9A2EB6AA6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Subcommittee on Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs of the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6CACDF688D8244A39A8F1F6EB30D4770"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H310A39A44E664D01BB0D526F3F6A4A67"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD712012AB617416892CD654D3DA7D364"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered grant</header><text>The term <term>covered grant</term> means a grant under subsection (c).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H74B08B81FF5A41F59011DD3DDAAA5366"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible Indian tribe</header><text>The term <term>eligible Indian tribe</term> means an Indian tribe that submits a written proposal for a covered grant to the Director in accordance with subsection (c)(2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1AC5E81F287F40C1BE18A16A778BFFDB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Immediate family member</header><text>The term <term>immediate family member</term> has the meaning given the term in section 115(c) of title 18, United States Code.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8440CDEDF9C540498A655CD2E0C2C47E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Indian</header><text>The term <term>Indian</term> means a member of an Indian tribe.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3CF45F61C84341EA94E316822B19FF13"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Indian land</header><text>The term <term>Indian land</term> has the meaning given the term <term>Indian lands</term> in section 3 of the Native American Business Development, Trade Promotion, and Tourism Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4302">25 U.S.C. 4302</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3FA28E86F84C493AABED88C5C3CC66CE"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Indian tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDFA6178DEB0C40D795A09D804D7DAC91"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Personally identifying information</header><text>The term <term>personally identifying information</term> has the meaning given the term in section 40002(a) of the Violence Against Women Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/12291">34 U.S.C. 12291(a)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAA11F511D41B4F2CA580F0A2993535C4"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Services to victims of crime</header><text>The term <term>services to victims of crime</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="H7808D1BACA734E0597E493726ACDE94F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has the meaning given the term in section 1404; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34917223FE954D779C7BE507CA6546D3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes efforts that—</text> <clause id="H7E88C7E1EC4648ADA1CCC2035C9BD8DB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>respond to the emotional, psychological, or physical needs of a victim of crime;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5B91FACDB9A046D1B9B2C3B6C663A8F1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>assist a victim of crime in stabilizing his or her life after victimization;</text> </clause><clause id="HB1692E25A4004D3D8FADE63B879B7E14"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>assist a victim of crime in understanding and participating in the criminal justice system; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H31AFC1322A94414DB0A6972A5479A177"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>restore a measure of security and safety for a victim of crime.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H379BBEE483274C188521DE37EA76F100"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Victim of crime</header><text>The term <term>victim of crime</term> means an individual who has suffered direct physical, sexual, financial, or emotional harm as a result of the commission of a crime.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEBC6C491568E47CD81013185D08BDFBB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties of the Director</header><text>The Director shall—</text> <paragraph id="H2C346835027E445CA582DB39D53C1FAD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>administer the grant program described in subsection (c);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H08B9F2A143744A7FB2A07EF7603F3B0E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide planning, research, training, and technical assistance to recipients of covered grants; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7F685E1A45994FBA987B220B9DC43B6A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>coordinate with the Office of Tribal Justice, the Indian Health Service, and the Bureau of Indian Affairs in implementing the grant program described in subsection (c).</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE661FD32F5BB47B09A917C8B4F249B2D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant program</header>
 <paragraph id="H8346C38486A14DDDAEF486A6CE3279C5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On an annual basis, the Director shall make grants to eligible Indian tribes for the purposes of funding—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA3C2DFAEEA7E4001A9EFF7E8924AAC16"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a program, administered by one or more Indian tribes, that provides services to victims of crime, which may be provided in traditional form or through electronic, digital, or other technological formats, including—</text>
 <clause id="H9060557358D340EB86446383678A8580"><enum>(i)</enum><text>services to victims of crime provided through subgrants to agencies or departments of tribal governments or nonprofit organizations;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H445F4CA71104455D9A33BE608D93130C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>domestic violence shelters, rape crisis centers, child abuse programs, child advocacy centers, and elder abuse programs providing services to victims of crime;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H26E2E22A693A480CBFCDEA2E67B3252A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>medical care, equipment, treatment, and related evaluations arising from the victimization, including—</text>
 <subclause id="HC36EE6C299FF4834B2F5FD2F34ACE568"><enum>(I)</enum><text>emergency medical care and evaluation, nonemergency medical care and evaluation, psychological and psychiatric care and evaluation, and other forms of medical assistance, treatment, or therapy, regardless of the setting in which the services are delivered;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H5C6143D82E1D496FBF5CD9C896463420"><enum>(II)</enum><text>mental and behavioral health and crisis counseling, evaluation, and assistance, including outpatient therapy, counseling services, substance abuse treatment, and other forms of specialized treatment, including intervention and prevention services;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H45A2A6D3B6A346D3BA9F4FF25DEBA6FB"><enum>(III)</enum><text>prophylactic treatment to prevent an individual from contracting HIV/AIDS or any other sexually transmitted disease or infection; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H1EF6F249B7CF437DBB4E623C9553B26A"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>forensic medical evidence collection examinations and forensic interviews of victims of crime—</text> <item id="HDC9076D88D3E40AE848026C1E5815EE2"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>to the extent that other funding sources are unavailable or insufficient; and</text>
 </item><item id="HAE49D5489F6F4BB39E03B6FAA24897FB"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>on the condition that, to the extent practicable, the examiners and interviewers follow relevant guidelines or protocols issued by the State, unit of local government, or Indian tribe with jurisdiction over the area in which the examination or interview is conducted;</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause id="H51F3B127BB594137B310E5420E508283"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>legal services, legal assistance services, and legal clinics (including services provided by pro bono legal clinics and practitioners), the need for which arises directly from the victimization;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H632CDF4BABEA4AF0A38223901FC3B0AA"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the training and certification of service animals and therapy animals;</text> </clause><clause id="HC8575CC755B241BCB421A37C92A91B6A"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>equipment for Braille or TTY/TTD machines for the deaf necessary to provide services to victims of crime;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H777AA0268CE6406DA7289907309C2C25"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>restorative justice opportunities that allow victims of crime to meet with the perpetrators if the meetings are voluntarily agreed to by the victim of crime and are for therapeutic purposes; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB059BA10BE9148009E0802E7FDD331B3"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>training and related materials, including books, training manuals, and training videos, for staff and service providers to develop skills necessary to offer quality services to victims of crime;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB006183A3FB14706BB54DF5E3A0D17A1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>development or implementation of training, technical assistance, or professional development that improves or enhances the quality of services to victims of crime, including coordination between healthcare, education, and justice systems;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9BB628F9C45B4E33A38F00DFC8485E58"><enum>(C)</enum><text>transportation of victims of crime to—</text> <clause id="H380B0BC09DA7486680323E825C366FC0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>receive services; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H20EF38FA2F2C468EA87EF6313F47E94B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>participate in criminal justice proceedings;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D93BB22A50A457DB7119BB1023AD257"><enum>(D)</enum><text>emergency legal assistance to victims of crime that is directly connected to the crime;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0643650A89F44AA19B80FFB5E50EA5C8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>supervision of direct service providers and contracts for professional or specialized services that are related directly to providing services to victims of crime;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC0D9F89D3DB4D7FAAF28B5BFB70FEA2"><enum>(F)</enum><text>repair and replacement of essential items used during the provision of services to victims of crime to contribute to and maintain a healthy and safe environment for the victims;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H344D3958DC244F84A2A1354568C1F73A"><enum>(G)</enum><text>transitional housing for victims of crime, particularly victims who have a particular need for such housing and cannot safely return to previous housing, including travel, rental assistance, security deposits, utilities, and other related costs that are incidental to the relocation to transitional housing;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86E49EDD88454A52BAB86BB828EEBDA3"><enum>(H)</enum><text>relocation of victims of crime, particularly where necessary for the safety and well-being of the victim, including reasonable moving expenses, security deposits for housing, rental expenses, and utility startup costs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78848004EBF74FA7B58C58A4B58633D0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>coordination of activities that facilitate the provision of direct services to victims of crime;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD649A7FF49F4F8EBD018F6817DD1146"><enum>(J)</enum><text>multi-system, inter-agency, multi-disciplinary response to the needs of victims of crime; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD7046B62D1404709BC6C754AA800494D"><enum>(K)</enum><text>administration of the program and services described in this section.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H57EAAAB287B846DD85EA1049D4089BF9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>An Indian tribe seeking a covered grant shall, in response to a request for proposal, submit to the Director a written proposal for a covered grant, which shall include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9727C3B73CDB468F967AA6409FB13F2D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the need for services and the mission and goals of the activity to be carried out using the grant;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67922A870C4143D5B01E35F395C78E4A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of how amounts received under the grant would be used;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H375237F6580B4E5CA24C2894263D8DB0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the proposed annual budget for the activities for each fiscal year in which amounts received under the grant may be used;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D33087A1C1045B984598638A9F627B4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any qualifications, certifications, or licenses that may be required for individuals involved in administering the program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6AC9BECBB94347F6BEDD70465DEE0930"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a certification by the Indian tribe that, under the law of that Indian tribe or the law of a State to which the Act of August 15, 1953 (67 Stat. 588, chapter 505) (commonly known as <quote>Public Law 280</quote>), applies—</text>
 <clause id="H2730664CC46E496D9D97B5E8FD84BC07"><enum>(i)</enum><text>victims of crime are entitled to the rights and protections described in section 3771(a) of title 18, United States Code, or substantially similar rights and protections; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H724D57B012E14AA0BD654C1BB0059305"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>individuals who report crimes are protected by law from retribution and retaliation;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBAEECA88E2EE40ADB25E5CF4B32F4B9F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a certification by the Indian tribe that grant funds will be used to supplement and not supplant other Federal, State, local, and tribal funds that are used for the purposes described in paragraph (1);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H055662BE6E5B471CB397778C0999B268"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a description of any plans or agreements to coordinate services among Federal, State, local, and tribal governments; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9BA6D7F6AF7A410DA145B5C6C304CDD6"><enum>(H)</enum><text>any additional information required by the Director through written guidance, after consultation with Indian tribes.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE4B2150495F349F3A9ECC8894BFE24F5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>No matching requirement</header><text>A recipient or subrecipient of a covered grant shall not be required to make a matching contribution for Federal dollars received.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF5BA1F21820A448694DEB3B76FBB3AC2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Prohibited uses of funds</header><text>A recipient or subrecipient of a covered grant may not use the amounts of the grant for—</text> <subparagraph id="H0A6C526221934260BE49A6656E0F589F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>salaries, benefits, fees, furniture, equipment, and other expenses of executive directors, board members, and other administrators, except as specifically allowed under this section;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8434455BE9E34767AB330C3546FDF563"><enum>(B)</enum><text>lobbying and administrative advocacy; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC66707089E54CE8A7F30BB70E234B63"><enum>(C)</enum><text>fundraising activities.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC436A47768BA46B4B5FF6AC7E2188BED"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>A recipient of a covered grant shall, on an annual basis, submit to the Director an itemized budget with a report describing the purpose for which the grant was used, which shall include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8B7DA5FD652841F6B4FFC99C2C798F99"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the purpose for which grant funds were obligated or spent and the amount of funds obligated or spent by the recipient or subrecipient for each purpose, including, on a quarterly basis—</text>
 <clause id="H384EFD017A0D4DB2ACCD4F5692E268C3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount of grant funds obligated or spent by the recipient or subrecipient for administrative and operational costs; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3230AFF4284848C2B6055E7B0AB83DB2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount of grant funds obligated or spent by the recipient or subrecipient for direct services;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDED8084A09D4BAABC2F1F2BAD3FDECA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of individuals served as a result of the grant;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC7B060411634791B4A47B0920DD2FB0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description, in the aggregate, of the types of individuals served, including—</text> <clause id="H14F0477B1A7E43D8887AB748D37285BA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the alleged crime and injury involved;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEA87C4039A4F40B49A77D69E5EB465EA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>whether the victim is an Indian; and</text> </clause><clause id="H836375A375A043D2B85448D59AF0F8F0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the age, sex, and tribal affiliation of the victim, if applicable; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D24B0F60B18443D9FF060D0D86DF41D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a description, in the aggregate, of the general nature and location of the alleged crimes involved, including—</text>
 <clause id="H1DA8C72D54EF409AAD1BA60A8EBA510E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>whether the crime was committed on Indian land;</text> </clause><clause id="HB4CBEF6E68A2483CA3B77A96E24BEF7D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>whether the alleged perpetrator is an Indian;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF89A4DA46A444D64B396B4457A18AF29"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the disposition of the incident; and</text> </clause><clause id="H5D6A50BB638A4DC697E5ED9003EC7D21"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>all jurisdictions involved in any disposition.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA87066800A064C19B37CFB3BD70579B9"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Obligation to report fraud, waste, or abuse of grant funds</header><text>A recipient or subrecipient of a covered grant shall immediately report to the Director any finding of fraud, waste, or abuse of grant funds.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2B249C84A1804F0F9102B53154E4168D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Protection of crime victim confidentiality and privacy</header>
 <paragraph id="HCD2C03E9B29E457BAD0CAE5685047E63"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text>In order to ensure the safety of victims of crime and immediate family members of victims of crime, recipients and subrecipients of covered grants shall protect the confidentiality and privacy of individuals receiving services from the recipient or subrecipient.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="HDC972F10DDB74CC88D99AABB064990AC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nondisclosure</header>
 <subparagraph id="HEBA074CF338F4247867EEE7F8A1E1227"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraphs (3) and (4), a recipient or subrecipient of a covered grant shall not disclose, reveal, or release any personally identifying information collected in connection with any service requested, used, or denied through a program of the recipient or subrecipient or require the release of personally identifying information as a condition of eligibility for the services provided by the recipient or subrecipient—</text>
 <clause id="H66D5A6B1503547139E6C37374CB4FC54"><enum>(i)</enum><text>regardless of whether the information has been encoded, encrypted, hashed, or otherwise protected; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4D54EACE1A0B456FBC26468A8F1E7F2C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>subject to subparagraph (B) and the condition that consent for release may not be given by an abuser of the minor, an abuser of a parent or guardian of a minor, or an incapacitated individual, absent the informed, written, reasonably time-limited consent of—</text>
 <subclause id="H4F368576FF5741C28C6CC8BFA95DD11A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the individual about whom information is sought;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H04323C5337404FFCBFA87E2B9F8A4860"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the case of an emancipated minor, the minor, and the parent or guardian; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H3272C6A838024CEDB11FB67A79F431E9"><enum>(III)</enum><text>in the case of legal incapacity, a court-appointed guardian.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB82DD632778C433BBE788252FA88FA34"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Certain minors and other individuals</header><text>If a minor or individual with a legally appointed guardian may lawfully receive services without the consent of a parent or guardian, that minor or individual may consent to the release of information under subparagraph (A)(ii) without the additional consent of a parent or guardian.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB470655B963C4B8A9DB46A2D1993EB7F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Release</header><text>If the release of information described in paragraph (2) is compelled by a statutory or court mandate, a recipient or subrecipient of a covered grant shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA046A1F2958949D69C4FFC87D2F23172"><enum>(A)</enum><text>make reasonable attempts to provide notice to victims of crime affected by the disclosure of information; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF67F1E0A73B4427199C866C55AD6F12D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>take steps necessary to protect the privacy and safety of the individuals affected by the release of the information.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA77A6EA0E8C04EEEB03CB5EE18F7603E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Information sharing</header><text>A recipient or subrecipient of a covered grant may share—</text> <subparagraph id="H47DFDA0F5BC84011AE7D39B1DFE83FEA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>data in the aggregate that is not personally identifying information regarding services to clients and demographics in order to comply with Federal, State, tribal, or territorial reporting, evaluation, or data collection requirements;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3AF26AD749CD4E13A90236BB13A44188"><enum>(B)</enum><text>court-generated and law enforcement-generated information contained in secure, governmental registries for protection order enforcement purposes; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H46DFFB1D153546F6B3BB9DD7A91F482B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>law enforcement-generated and prosecution-generated information necessary for law enforcement and prosecution purposes.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC6CCF67BB15447659AF2DD2019BF3C08"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Statutorily mandated reports of abuse or neglect</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to prohibit a recipient or subrecipient of a covered grant from reporting suspected abuse or neglect of an individual.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H428E5479D33347A78541E62B03954A4A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Congressional oversight</header>
 <subparagraph id="H38A8A397C3D149B087046BBA0DDB6B4F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to prohibit the Director from disclosing grant activities authorized by this section to the appropriate committees of Congress.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75DD6E84B2F4413183F59A57FEA36F1F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The Director shall ensure that a disclosure under subparagraph (A) protects confidentiality and omits personally identifying information.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2521881B93824250BBFAB9F912C5C842"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Confidentiality assessment and assurances</header><text>A recipient or subrecipient of a covered grant shall document compliance with the confidentiality and privacy requirements of this subsection.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H09A9F750026D40F0A0C73235CD4BC3C4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Oversight and enforcement authority</header>
 <paragraph id="HAC47AD98A58048E88B3173C590A87E84"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>The Director shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H6D63C4DBDE9646D59AE307F814D685B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>regularly monitor and review covered grants awarded, which shall include evaluation of quarterly financial reports for victim services grants; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H690638DE109C44E28C7D7A08CACB086C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conduct investigations and audits—</text> <clause id="H8CBDA8C071CB428C9305912129E118B8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to ensure compliance with all applicable Federal law; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0955D09A439D4B979E78C118EEAEE8C5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to prevent duplication and redundancy in the awarding of covered grants.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C7CF305CBE6477D80DEF1CE03C43CC1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Performance measures and enforceable agreements</header><text>The Director shall ensure that all covered grants are subject to performance measures and enforceable agreements that allow for thorough program oversight.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC11DD94279DF44809BBBE4A959EDA144"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Compliance reports to Congress</header><text>For fiscal year 2017 and each fiscal year thereafter, the Director shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress an annual compliance report on all covered grants awarded.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA09C7DC30E084A09B008104F127C32D0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Violations</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE3D15A0617E74D28A8649C89C8B1802A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, after reasonable notice and opportunity for a hearing on the record (subject to subparagraph (B)), the Director finds that a recipient or subrecipient of a covered grant has failed to comply substantially with any provision of this section or a rule, regulation, guideline, or procedure issued under this section, or an application submitted in accordance with this section or the provisions of any other applicable law, the Director shall—</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7284DAE5550145CC8B87375F7125AB81"><enum>(i)</enum><text>terminate payments to the recipient;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H468EA03BB905460CBFD875FB452A9819"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>suspend payments to the recipient until the Director is satisfied that the noncompliance has ended; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H33AA07DBC6D9467BAA2DA4B86ABF2015"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>take any other action that the Director determines appropriate.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF3046A2B9F0F4BB89ABCCE2C0F70F207"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Subrecipients</header><text>A subrecipient of a covered grant may not request a hearing under subparagraph (A) but may assist a recipient in providing information during the hearing process.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H83E44B54E7B740F398169572E05FF025"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Timelines</header>
 <paragraph id="HBE42ADF486BD4551BE3A14872E73E7C0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Negotiated rulemaking</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Director shall publish a notice in the Federal Register to initiate the negotiated rulemaking described in section 3(b) of the <short-title>Securing Urgent Resources Vital to Indian Victim Empowerment Act</short-title>, which shall be completed not later than 180 days after that publication.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEDEB324AEB1047D1AB9F11ABCD69FBAF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Request for proposal</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the negotiated rulemaking described in paragraph (1) is complete, the Director shall publish a request for proposal in the Federal Register for covered grants.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6723F268B81544BD8586FF2A6C9BB2E2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Required disbursal</header><text>Not later than January 31 of each of the first 10 fiscal years beginning after the date of enactment of this section, the Director shall disburse competitive grants to Indian tribes in accordance with this section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9264AB93D0D0420FA75FBD5CE18B1DF3"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Availability of grant funds</header><text>Any amount awarded under a covered grant that remains unobligated at the end of the fiscal year in which the grant is made may be expended for the purpose for which the grant was made at any time during the 5 succeeding fiscal years, at the end of which period, any unobligated sums shall remain available to the Director for award under this section in the following fiscal year.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE6C0F7BEB3D44F45ABA33F7ADD4B19BC"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>Nothing in this section prohibits—</text> <paragraph id="H432DE88134774921A0956E2E635D4947"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an Indian tribe from contracting for the administration of a program or activity funded under this section; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF1009A395BA145D78A0B6264741A2FE2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>multiple Indian tribes or tribal organizations from forming a consortium for any of the purposes described in this section.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF54DB56A5DC748969D8BCF5940D88B83"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Funding</header>
 <paragraph id="H68973FC47E804225A3C274BAFB625D4C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The grant program established under this section shall be carried out using amounts made available under section 1402(d)(1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H790CD4A9B0B946E5B1C9A759BD4AF612"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative expenses</header><text>For each fiscal year in which a grant is made or grant funds may be obligated under this section, the Director may use not more than 4 percent of the amounts made available under this section for—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H845D3143DD874990BD28F575EEACD612"><enum>(A)</enum><text>administration and management of covered grants; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFFCFB720A94B4CE3BD0CB0553006B8A5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>training and technical assistance.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8FEC594FFAA94172BFE39EC965B99A56"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Term</header><text>This section shall be effective for the first 10 fiscal years beginning after the date of enactment of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HF56A37C7CAA748C2B61C073CE4883A7C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Funding for grants for tribal victims of crime</header><text>Section 1402(d) of the Victims of Crime Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/20101">34 U.S.C. 20101(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HB50A902E2C2F46F49595EE80F4282520"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting before paragraph (2) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H38CC564EE3684DEB9C44FA1CB7DC5020" style="OLC">
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HFC02A05BA3284C9E91F9CD274C7DA739"><enum>(1)</enum><text>For each of the 10 fiscal years beginning after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Securing Urgent Resources Vital to Indian Victim Empowerment Act</short-title>, 5 percent of the total amount in the Fund available for obligation during a fiscal year shall be made available to the Director to make grants under section 1404G.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8EF44241CA24416EB93BAD93650C4108"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(A), by inserting <quote>after compliance with paragraph (1)</quote> after <quote>deposited in the Fund</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H54AEAFAB66034C2FACB777D21F7F2A11"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(A), in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>paragraph (2)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (1) and (2)</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6A2E393CF1074B2D90364074BB5FB971"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)(A), by inserting <quote>(1),</quote> before <quote>(2)</quote> each place that term appears.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1C893677FB8549EFB3CCB787B290E873"><enum>3.</enum><header>Regulations regarding Indian tribes</header> <subsection id="HE53CA6A9705D4E8EA0FB50F4420BE698"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Existing regulations</header><text>Any regulation, rule, or guidance promulgated by the Director of the Office for Victims of Crime before the date of enactment of this Act shall have no force or effect with respect to section 1404G of the Victims of Crime Act of 1984, as added by section 2.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H07E3A04AD94E45BFAF70ACE52906BC36"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Negotiated rulemaking</header>
 <paragraph id="H01207CC7917E4DC4A202D21957E96CB5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office for Victims of Crime, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior and Indian tribes (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>)) and through notice and comment negotiated rulemaking, following the provisions of subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Negotiated Rulemaking Act of 1990</quote>), shall promulgate final regulations carrying out section 1404G of the Victims of Crime Act of 1984, as added by section 2.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3E1B6DAA8C554C8F9DF9B36E3DAC9DFB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The Director of the Office for Victims of Crime shall ensure that—</text> <subparagraph id="H4DE70C2B694C4BE6A7925D77564FC00C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not fewer than 2 Indian tribes from each Bureau of Indian Affairs region participate in the consultation; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H841F207293AB4EE5BD8634B9A3E0B746"><enum>(B)</enum><text>small, medium, and large land-based Indian tribes are represented.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

