<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0BF6285AD1984BD3B1C62C19F1D19D6D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3026 IH: Strengthening Loan Forgiveness for Public Servants Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3026</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170622">June 22, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Brendan F. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to provide for a percentage of student loan forgiveness for public service employment, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H02466C133D5C48CFBAD611CA65F757BF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6FA6756609B24DC590B6BBF4CFECDE0F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthening Loan Forgiveness for Public Servants Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H13A5AB8939734EC18FAC4CE63A7AD098"><enum>2.</enum><header>Public service loan forgiveness program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 455(m) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(m)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H688D722F86B34427BB892DD1C7F167EB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>, except as provided in paragraph (5),</quote> after <quote>on any eligible Federal Direct Loan not in default</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDB59FEDF4DD0435BB073C3C473E3FD54"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD699934D69B547ACBD4F3EC712FA90DB" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H017D0014838447E1B7D77982A1DEA143"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Loan cancellation for new loans</header> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5E0EF4FEAD02458BABF8B74C7F546CD6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Beginning after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Strengthening Loan Forgiveness for Public Servants Act</short-title>, after the conclusion of each employment period in a public service job, as described in subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall cancel the percent specified in such subparagraph of the total amount due on any eligible Federal Direct Loan made after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Strengthening Loan Forgiveness for Public Servants Act</short-title> for a borrower who is employed in such public service job and submits an employment certification form described in subparagraph (C).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5CB474C25A654994B465E62A55A094B9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Percent amount</header><text>The percent of a loan that shall be canceled under subparagraph (A) is as follows:</text> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDEFE3DE9B02F448DB0FC97A6C545F402"><enum>(i)</enum><text>In the case of a borrower who completes 2 years of employment in a public service job, 15 percent of the total amount due on the eligible Federal Direct Loan on the date the borrower commenced employment in such public service job.</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2D7BD724E6384856AE5CA6256B597672"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>In the case of a borrower who completes 4 years of employment in a public service job, 15 percent of the total amount due on the eligible Federal Direct Loan on the date the borrower commenced employment in such public service job.</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6AF81D98C3D340A9AE7DCCEA1378ED40"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>In the case of a borrower who completes 6 years of employment in a public service job, 20 percent of the total amount due on the eligible Federal Direct Loan on the date the borrower commenced employment in such public service job.</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE439414D5E6642D4AE8DFCC22746DDB2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>In the case of a borrower who completes 8 years of employment in a public service job, 20 percent of the total amount due on the eligible Federal Direct Loan on the date the borrower commenced employment in such public service job.</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H026352803E2249039314800D53FBFBB2"><enum>(v)</enum><text>In the case of a borrower who completes 10 years of employment in a public service job, 30 percent of the total amount due on the eligible Federal Direct Loan on the date the borrower commenced employment in such public service job.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H313EE991CDFB4A8C9C792E369D992E3F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Employment certification form</header> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H42AB074D7AA446AF9E85707489BBF6B7"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In order to receive loan cancellation under this paragraph, a borrower shall submit to the Secretary an employment certification form that is developed by the Secretary and includes self-certification of employment and a separate part for employer certification that indicates the dates of employment.</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBCB77F64246B4CCE9BE2B9CD094375C9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Deferment</header><text>If a borrower submits to the Secretary the employment certification form described in clause (i), during the period in which the borrower is employed in a public service job for which loan cancellation is eligible under this paragraph, the borrower's eligible Federal Direct Loan shall be placed in deferment.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD603A75972DF42B7B888EE1CAAE50BED"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Interest canceled</header><text>If a portion of a loan is canceled under this paragraph for any year, the entire amount of interest on such loan that accrues for such year shall be canceled.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

