<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H99DE989CE97248CEBCCDC5A9CB2150F3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1320 IH: Nuclear Utilization of Keynote Energy Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1320</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170302">March 2, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000378">Mr. Kinzinger</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000482">Mr. Michael F. Doyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990 related to Nuclear Regulatory Commission user fees and annual charges, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H336A61489AD14209917FA2B60BF72AFC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB9F0CB10732F40F2B4D5FE9FFFED4D13" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Nuclear Utilization of Keynote Energy Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HDEF129CFFAC34776AAAA1C12A505F782" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>2.</enum><header>Nuclear Regulatory Commission user fees and annual charges through fiscal year 2019</header> <subsection id="H42B0E9B420634E1A8DF602390A3CA8B9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 6101(c)(2)(A) of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2214">42 U.S.C. 2214(c)(2)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8D5EBD9FE21B4D079FEAFA00C8260A3F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB08456F3417B4321843CF16D2815F9FC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (iv), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H381FD85AF0E44FBEA75C4888DA19F618"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H28BA0AD3F3694B1AAD129E9F65D62332" style="OLC"> <clause id="H3A90B82B905B40EB94B81BFA39ABFFC6"><enum>(v)</enum><text>amounts appropriated to the Commission for the fiscal year for activities related to the development of a regulatory framework for advanced nuclear reactor technologies.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H12DD9E0E5609434FAF3D6659054210BF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Repeal</header><text>Effective October 1, 2019, section 6101 of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2214">42 U.S.C. 2214</external-xref>) is repealed.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HA8C1BE2A3CE4471FA860681EB3B882EC" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Nuclear Regulatory Commission user fees and annual charges for fiscal year 2020 and each fiscal year thereafter</header> <subsection id="H4DDB047C32CE4CE68C6282745BB95421"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual budget justification</header> <paragraph id="H2031891BCB144D55AB2C27B2B01B3612"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the annual budget justification submitted by the Commission to Congress, the Commission shall expressly identify anticipated expenditures necessary for completion of the requested activities of the Commission anticipated to occur during the applicable fiscal year.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H54CD98E1E04D47A38476E6C2E7FFBB3C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Restriction</header><text>Budget authority granted to the Commission for purposes of the requested activities of the Commission shall be used, to the maximum extent practicable, solely for conducting requested activities of the Commission.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8CC485E6C9264FD2B4BFE5AD145DA5E0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation on corporate support costs</header><text>With respect to the annual budget justification submitted to Congress, corporate support costs, to the maximum extent practicable, shall not exceed the following percentages of the total budget authority of the Commission requested in the annual budget justification:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3AE04DEBDBEE4AD3AA53F79201708329"><enum>(A)</enum><text>30 percent for each of fiscal years 2020 and 2021.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA8368866561F4FFFBB3519B5ABF9A211"><enum>(B)</enum><text>29 percent for each of fiscal years 2022 and 2023.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HABFFCB278E7A4AE1A0D2275A51990763"><enum>(C)</enum><text>28 percent for fiscal year 2024 and each fiscal year thereafter.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2A8075FE3A1C4B5C9531DC526E8F8B08"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Fees and charges</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB27934F72C964ABAB315A09D1CC9FBB5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Annual assessment</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE5F5B1A416D74052A9041E43173A984D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each fiscal year, the Commission shall assess and collect fees and charges in accordance with paragraphs (2) and (3) in a manner that ensures that, to the maximum extent practicable, the amount collected is equal to an amount that approximates—</text> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3ADC4DA6A1454E7894B47A73EB57A758"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total budget authority of the Commission for that fiscal year; less</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H04039F920A5B4647875891B2BB2F5F19"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the budget authority of the Commission for the activities described in subparagraph (B).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCE5D458146D04063B3FC1167B91BF73D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Excluded activities described</header><text>The activities referred to in subparagraph (A)(ii) are the following:</text> <clause id="HE39577E11E6241339443753E3C73042E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>An activity not attributable to an existing NRC licensee or class of licensee as identified by the Commission in Table III of the final rule of the Commission entitled <quote>Revision of Fee Schedules; Fee Recovery for Fiscal Year 2016</quote> (81 Fed. Reg. 41171 (June 24, 2016)).</text></clause> 
<clause id="HEAC8C96433DB42F081B5A71F157D7B2C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Amounts appropriated for a fiscal year to the Commission—</text> <subclause id="H7A15B4EEB8A24BFBB7F3A968DAACEF58"><enum>(I)</enum><text>from the Nuclear Waste Fund established under section 302(c) of the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/10222">42 U.S.C. 10222(c)</external-xref>);</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HC5462E0BEC7B4944A8A62E4A7771B1E0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for implementation of section 3116 of the Ronald W. Reagan National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/2601">50 U.S.C. 2601</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/375">Public Law 108–375</external-xref>);</text></subclause> <subclause id="H76E7247C77454341BFCF89B8BB62C32C"><enum>(III)</enum><text>for the homeland security activities of the Commission (other than for the costs of fingerprinting and background checks required under section 149 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2169">42 U.S.C. 2169</external-xref>) and the costs of conducting security inspections);</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HF58A7E9A2C574C41AAB3BAEA499959FE"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>for the Inspector General services of the Commission provided to the Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HE069B081FDC5442BB4A83CD4A5867ABE"><enum>(V)</enum><text>for research and development at universities in areas relevant to the mission of the applicable university;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H02071FF9285B42D5AF1488FB21B2D357"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>for a nuclear science and engineering grant program that will support multiyear projects that do not align with programmatic missions but are critical to maintaining the discipline of nuclear science and engineering; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HA9DF55A5A1A24F948584A27D8F9DA1CA"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>for any other fee-relief activity described in the final rule of the Commission entitled <quote>Revision of Fee Schedules; Fee Recovery for Fiscal Year 2016</quote> (81 Fed. Reg. 41171 (June 24, 2016)).</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H7D2B9451F07F4FA49B73234668BBEDDE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Costs for activities related to the development of regulatory infrastructure for advanced nuclear reactor technologies.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H0A1A05AD0A7D4D1A9FA25E0540C24FF7"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The exclusion described in subparagraph (B)(iii) shall cease to be effective on January 1, 2031.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDA271B22869D440C93374676D2065671"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than December 31, 2029, the Commission shall submit to the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report describing the views of the Commission on the continued appropriateness and necessity of the funding described in subparagraph (B)(iii).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB007DCF88D40496DAEF7EB870C37FB5C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Fees for service or thing of value</header><text>In accordance with section 9701 of title 31, United States Code, the Commission shall charge fees to any person who receives a service or thing of value from the Commission to cover the costs to the Commission of providing the service or thing of value.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H82C8BD23988D42BD9A31FD35BA0DF9EF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Annual fees</header> 
<subparagraph id="H2BF495FDBC98443AACBCBDA01CF49D2D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B) and except as provided in subparagraph (D), the Commission may charge to any licensee or certificate holder of the Commission an annual fee.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3BE409BA33924C7AA4ABC45C34EBB053"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Cap on annual fees of certain licensees</header> <clause id="HBC1332FA165F40EA9AF8F9DD679C66CE"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The annual fee under subparagraph (A) charged to an operating reactor licensee, to the maximum extent practicable, shall not exceed the annual fee amount per operating reactor licensee established in the final rule of the Commission entitled <quote>Revision of Fee Schedules; Fee Recovery for Fiscal Year 2016</quote> (81 Fed. Reg. 41171 (June 24, 2016)), as may be adjusted annually by the Commission to reflect changes in the Consumer Price Index published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor.</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF9703ABC0DAB4E62A35FA8C15A695712"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The Commission may waive, for a period of 1 year, the cap on annual fees described in clause (i) if the Commission submits to the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a written determination that the cap on annual fees may compromise the safety and security mission of the Commission.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB1442514042F4CFAA7F3E393C361A4B1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Amount per licensee</header> <clause id="H506307E252AB41638DC74D5052D44A65"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall establish by rule a schedule of fees fairly and equitably allocating the aggregate amount of charges described in subparagraph (A) among licensees and certificate holders.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H60A09C8C54BF437DA108DB107D257A55"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>The schedule of fees under clause (i)—</text> <subclause id="H82D6DE7F213C4D32B21BFC1B1DB58546"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to the maximum extent practicable, shall be based on the cost of providing regulatory services; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H0BB6CB825F9342CFB8EA658DA03099E6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>may be based on the allocation of the resources of the Commission among licensees or certificate holders or classes of licensees or certificate holders.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H192E9B888FAF4665931CB23CE6F6B429"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Exemption</header> <clause id="H85A04EB3C096492EB27B499C2A436E67"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definition of research reactor</header><text>In this subparagraph, the term <term>research reactor</term> means a nuclear reactor that—</text> 
<subclause id="HCF003DA6672348E594A1792FD766E1A0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is licensed by the Commission under section 104 c. of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2134">42 U.S.C. 2134(c)</external-xref>) for operation at a thermal power level of not more than 10 megawatts; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HE37F4914F3674F8D84186B4B8DC18BFB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if licensed under subclause (I) for operation at a thermal power level of more than 1 megawatt, does not contain—</text> 
<item id="HB04F81254FDE413DAA7D854B07B10833"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>a circulating loop through the core in which the licensee conducts fuel experiments;</text></item> <item id="H52DAFBCF6CC749EABBACDE61301E4989"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>a liquid fuel loading; or</text></item> 
<item id="H8D503B62891A46228ADB0DC6A370B58F"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>an experimental facility in the core in excess of 16 square inches in cross-section.</text></item></subclause></clause> <clause id="H5584DC9FCD034A64935B4792468B9408"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to the holder of any license for a federally owned research reactor used primarily for educational training and academic research purposes.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA049548E13F543D2B6F25C1B2715BA08"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Performance and reporting</header> 
<paragraph id="H6A74AA73726A41B081B9CE56256D0EB2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall develop for the requested activities of the Commission—</text> <subparagraph id="HE7BDD0088D934ED1B8E58C98C2C342F2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>performance metrics; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H89311CA4FC81414EB742FCDF0ABE30A1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>on each request, milestone schedules.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H39BC91ED20634919A6707B148A20D0C4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Delays in issuance of final safety evaluation</header><text>The Executive Director for Operations of the Commission shall inform the Commission of a delay in issuance of the final safety evaluation for a requested activity of the Commission by the completion date required by the performance metrics or milestone schedule under paragraph (1) by not later than 30 days after the completion date.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD81EF4D3EAF94811A0EB2C4035A72D5A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Delays in Issuance of final safety evaluation exceeding 180 days</header><text>If the final safety evaluation for the requested activity of the Commission described in paragraph (2) is not completed by the date that is 180 days after the completion date required by the performance metrics or milestone schedule under paragraph (1), the Commission shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a timely report describing the delay, including a detailed explanation accounting for the delay and a plan for timely completion of the final safety evaluation.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9B2CFFC685F5406988D4E35490A24CC7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Accurate invoicing</header><text>With respect to invoices for fees and charges described in subsection (b)(2), the Commission shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8B08701AFA8044DB9A8B7C3F9939B1CE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>ensure appropriate management review and concurrence prior to the issuance of invoices;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF55A91D1CF1C40F0952425B2EB4406A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop and implement processes to audit invoices to ensure accuracy, transparency, and fairness; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4FCC5B6B092146E097584E8A19A47D43"><enum>(3)</enum><text>modify regulations to ensure fair and appropriate processes to provide licensees and applicants an opportunity to efficiently dispute or otherwise seek review and correction of errors in invoices for fees and charges.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6F0EC9CACB9143C58AFB98189F83E60B"><enum>(e)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than September 30, 2021, the Commission shall submit to the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report describing the implementation of this section, including any impacts and recommendations for improvement.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H00FA85A7D695429390E621090CA0549E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H469E811CD9804935BB300E9D7CDD5C44"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Advanced nuclear reactor</header><text>The term <term>advanced nuclear reactor</term> means a nuclear fission or fusion reactor, including a prototype plant (as defined in sections 50.2 and 52.1 of title 10, Code of Federal Regulations), with significant improvements compared to commercial nuclear reactors under construction as of the date of enactment of this Act, including improvements such as—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBB972D58859A46999AA60B3F9D597382"><enum>(A)</enum><text>additional inherent safety features;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H891700D27FB64F36850DD53CC6BCE2E2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>significantly lower levelized cost of electricity;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC787CDD24EAF44D4ACE08D1D974F0811"><enum>(C)</enum><text>lower waste yields;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4854A7EFA57F4D8C96580217EE22D88F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>greater fuel utilization;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC01E7931F2664D8492AB4BC4DF5B8E60"><enum>(E)</enum><text>enhanced reliability;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H05E52210F3AC465F991E4A82AFEB227C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>increased proliferation resistance;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H78E82AF41A4B4C6DB40BC7DE4489E00F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>increased thermal efficiency; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAA455AFD5C96489AABFD523AAD94A23E"><enum>(H)</enum><text>ability to integrate into electric and nonelectric applications.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6ED0FB4A507C4B979326E93D1D09BB4B" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicant</header><text>The term <term>applicant</term> means an applicant for a license, certification, permit, or other form of approval from the Commission for a commercial advanced nuclear reactor or a research and test reactor.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6547D83665844A86948A086FD4032B8A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA1C0CD36B62B48918C4A1155AEFED178"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC081E47C71B3450C806FF757977B98A3" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Corporate support costs</header><text>The term <term>corporate support costs</term> means expenditures for acquisitions, administrative services, financial management, human resource management, information management, information technology, policy support, outreach, and training, as those categories are described and calculated in Appendix A of the Congressional Budget Justification for Fiscal Year 2017 of the Commission.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0FAD98C1BCDF4E40AB1DD46A3CD52FA5"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Requested activity of the Commission</header><text>The term <term>requested activity of the Commission</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H1868088E95774E609630D67D0A264222"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the processing of applications for—</text> 
<clause id="H8521C8CB44D049EBB5877724F6086473"><enum>(i)</enum><text>design certifications or approvals;</text></clause> <clause id="H65675D13FDB845DD8B3E0D639C6DA722"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>licenses;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H71F4244933264783963AB48E195185DF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>permits;</text></clause> <clause id="HCB86D7106B4A45959A1FCF32B67E4399"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>license amendments;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7278B226B5DE474590CF8BD6EF3CB34C"><enum>(v)</enum><text>license renewals;</text></clause> <clause id="H4718D3296BF140939D9EAFB94577EBD4"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>certificates of compliance; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE226318C6D50448A8183B10D48DDAD15"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>power uprates; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7537B66C45A0484ABC33F5FDC50A491E" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other activity requested by a licensee or applicant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAC7C91D3965648DBBAED018192F11646"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section takes effect on October 1, 2019.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H74A7B0A64729460396552E58EF4F9D0B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Study on elimination of foreign licensing restrictions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, shall transmit to Congress a report containing the results of a study on the feasibility and implications of repealing restrictions under sections 103d. and 104d. of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 on issuing licenses for certain nuclear facilities to an alien or an entity owned, controlled, or dominated by an alien, a foreign corporation, or a foreign government.</text></section> 
<section id="HA5D1A218DCBB429786AA15D6100249C5"><enum>5.</enum><header>Study on the impact of the elimination of mandatory hearing for uncontested licensing applications</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, shall transmit to Congress a report containing the results of a study on the impact of the elimination of mandatory hearings for uncontested licensing and construction permit applications under the Atomic Energy Act of 1954.</text></section> <section id="H796B2BB1A9F44EEF88F96B248634DFA1"><enum>6.</enum><header>Informal hearing procedures</header> <subsection id="HA21FA1107DD74D0287EFCEC907E6FE29"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text>Section 189 a. of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2239">42 U.S.C. 2239(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H7E2C5DA6F9704859817A21FFE35720DF" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H3387EC2659604A3A94AFA86BAC9160C9" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any hearing under this section shall be conducted using informal adjudicatory procedures in accordance with sections 553 and 555 of title 5, United States Code, unless the Commission determines that formal adjudicatory procedures are necessary—</text> <subparagraph id="HBF0FD9088F5F493390BCF04066A655A4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to develop a sufficient record; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H259319087E254929AE4BE1E111653C33"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to achieve fairness.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HDD1D4D5071A542E9B73CBF660E794287"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Hearings on licensing of uranium enrichment facilities</header><text>Section 193 b. of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2243">42 U.S.C. 2243(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2A3C3ECD4E0843DF83982BA54C96896C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>on the record</quote> and all that follows through <quote>and 63</quote> and inserting <quote>if a person the interest of whom may be affected by the construction and operation of a uranium enrichment facility under sections 53 and 63 has requested a hearing regarding the licensing of the construction and operation of the facility</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H19DD35A60354460594A4BA913FA23025"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>Such hearing</quote> and inserting <quote>If a hearing is held under paragraph (1), the hearing</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H018FCCB7EF2E4D24AED26CC57D1FBD5A"><enum>7.</enum><header>Application reviews for nuclear energy projects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 185 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2235">42 U.S.C. 2235</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="other" id="H9405AB9E4FCD490A843F41CA1F5E2D8A" display-inline="no-display-inline" other-style="nuclear"> <subsection id="H9F413337F97F4701810C410EB342BDE7"><enum>c.</enum><header>Application reviews for nuclear energy projects</header> <paragraph id="H310AAEC5783549F7B53AC41E524D016A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Streamlining license application review</header><text>With respect to an application that is docketed seeking issuance of a construction permit, operating license, or combined construction permit and operating license for a production or utilization facility, the Commission shall include the following procedures:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2C686E0FEA1E4AA89CC8CE32DAE35E0A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Undertake an expedited environmental review process and issue any draft environmental impact statement within 24 months after the application is accepted for docketing.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE37A591D2BA5431A82BF877886675C9C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Complete the technical review process and issue any safety evaluation report and any final environmental impact statement within 42 months after the application is accepted for docketing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6FF978CB7A334B17971E6EC6F59C9BB8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Early site permit</header> 
<subparagraph id="HF086443766A347D2AEDCDAF80352C9E7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Supplemental environmental impact statement</header><text>In a proceeding for a combined construction permit and operating license for a site for which an early site permit has been issued, any environmental impact statement prepared by the Commission and cooperating agencies shall be prepared as a supplement to the environmental impact statement prepared for the early site permit.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H476C53133A514F4280CE88212BD85245"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Incorporation by reference</header><text>The supplemental environmental impact statement shall—</text> 
<clause id="H651052CB60144C20A4A28BD017E46EB3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>incorporate by reference the analysis, findings, and conclusions from the environmental impact statement prepared for the early site permit; and</text></clause> <clause id="H7784EB17058741E787BFBB8E39EF8F6D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>include additional discussion, analyses, findings, and conclusions on matters resolved in the early site permit proceeding only to the extent necessary to address information that is new and significant in that the information would materially change the prior findings or conclusions.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB0E96970CA824281A0AE2E561D10BC69"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Production or utilization facility located at an existing site</header><text>In reviewing an application for an early site permit, construction permit, operating license, or combined construction permit and operating license for a production or utilization facility located at the site of a licensed production or utilization facility, the Commission shall, to the extent practicable, use information that was part of the licensing basis of the licensed production or utilization facility.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H33F49858F1624DD1B54F67D15F808F8C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Hearing on early site permit, construction permit, and combined construction permit and operating license</header><text>The Commission shall issue and make immediately effective an early site permit or construction permit for a production or utilization facility upon finding that the application therefor satisfies the requirements of this Act, notwithstanding the pendency before the Commission of a request for a hearing. Following completion of any required hearing, the Commission shall take any appropriate action with respect to the early site permit, construction permit, or combined construction permit and operating license to the extent necessary to account for the hearing results.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H41B1E88461F345128334A6AF5603782B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Commission shall initiate a rulemaking, to be completed 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Nuclear Utilization of Keynote Energy Act</short-title>, to amend the regulations of the Commission to implement this subsection.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA6E9A9613E314745B8B2725140C9ABA1"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Relationship to other law</header><text>Nothing in this subsection exempts the Commission from any requirement for full compliance with section 102(2)(C) of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4332">42 U.S.C. 4332(2)(C)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="HA64F717D462140FAA76983DC745B5842"><enum>8.</enum><header>Nuclear reactor decommissioning</header> 
<subsection id="H07191C6D5E4E465DB010C8D4F251DAB0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>Chapter 14 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2201">42 U.S.C. 2201–2210i</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block id="H6BD56628EF564168AE88A3EDF12EAFE3" style="other" other-style="nuclear"> <section id="H3DF0817DC8664D9C8EBC8C1E70BF9A09"><enum>170J.</enum><header>Decommissioning nuclear reactor rulemaking</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Commission shall, not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this section, initiate a rulemaking proceeding, including notice and opportunity for public comment, to be completed not later than 48 months after that date, to address the regulatory framework for decommissioning nuclear reactors licensed under section 103 or 104b.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H894EE4CF36FB412C97250CC9F583C0DA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of sections amendment</header><text>The table of sections for chapter 14 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF48BF4A8CD1C4EABBEC02C5271C171C8" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 170J. Decommissioning nuclear reactor rulemaking.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

