<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H912AFDAE4FB14B6C864BD70455D22029" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3690 IH: Preserving America’s Downtowns and Heritage Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3690</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170906">September 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to increase the rehabilitation credit for commercial
			 buildings and to provide a rehabilitation credit for principal residences.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H5E0EEEDA194048E1894CD1E2941BAC9B" style="OLC">
 <section id="H315C0C97401D4C8981725D00021E1A4D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preserving America’s Downtowns and Heritage Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H6A2904968DD946EDA7187F4B9907EE0E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Increased rehabilitation credit for commercial buildings</header> <subsection id="H809184B1029947E4A566786C4019D1B2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Buildings other than certified historic structures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/47">section 47(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (relating to rehabilitation credit) is amended by striking <quote>10 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>12.5 percent</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H14B340D6E1E445839498B9937537354A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certified historic structures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (2) of such section is amended by striking <quote>20 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>25 percent</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H959B90EF0C6048A697F4251E16C79387"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to rehabilitations the physical work on which begins after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H2FCEAFB92EAE4831909A74DCA6209118"><enum>3.</enum><header>Rehabilitation credit for historic principal residences</header>
 <subsection id="H99A406AF2B9D4F62A43E122865EC90E1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart A of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (relating to nonrefundable personal credits) is amended by inserting after section 25D the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H8C41271A579349ABBCB8A58DF5A361F9">
					<section id="H6813420D59A6433681230A6D4461CB24"><enum>25E.</enum><header>Rehabilitation of historic principal residences</header>
 <subsection id="HC8D8E8C333D74DFBA5B8F129FB6451A6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General rule</header><text>In the case of an individual, there shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by this chapter for the taxable year an amount equal to 20 percent of the qualified rehabilitation expenditures made by the taxpayer with respect to a qualified historic home.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H43B6D713FBEE434AAF8D29168B3A99CA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Qualified rehabilitation expenditure</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H259B1D1F1C174EFC81D0FD5CB50C8173"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>qualified rehabilitation expenditure</term> means any amount properly chargeable to capital account—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4E56F2B7D9E74700A1505709094E17D9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in connection with the certified rehabilitation of a qualified historic home, and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87990A9EA06E4CBDB7E6E572A5D21CD9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for property for which depreciation would be allowable under section 168 if the qualified historic home were used in a trade or business.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3394137477E44BC7B39DB3261227C3ED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certain expenditures not included</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rules similar to the rules of clauses (ii) and (iii) of section 47(c)(2)(B) shall apply.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H108572BC1BDC40EE8014EB5222070FB6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Mixed use or multifamily building</header><text>If only a portion of a building is used as the principal residence of the taxpayer, only qualified rehabilitation expenditures which are properly allocable to such portion shall be taken into account under this section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6B3A6046C43041379A3A314BC24145B1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Certified rehabilitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H4F1E21F5F0EA4FE4947039CEDB6CC9F0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>certified rehabilitation</term> has the meaning given such term by section 47(c)(2)(C).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB4D8E8EA6C9E4167A57826A5A1DABB18"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Approved State program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>certified rehabilitation</term> includes a certification made by—</text> <subparagraph id="HBD82D4EE811E4BA3B88220DD009E1A67"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State Historic Preservation Officer who administers a State Historic Preservation Program approved by the Secretary of the Interior pursuant to section 101(b)(1) of the National Historic Preservation Act, or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H583367D3701E4A98A9FC00BF267DE8E6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a local government, certified pursuant to section 101(c)(1) of the National Historic Preservation Act and authorized by a State Historic Preservation Officer, or the Secretary of the Interior where there is no approved State program, subject to such terms and conditions as may be specified by the Secretary of the Interior for the rehabilitation of buildings within the jurisdiction of such officer (or local government) for purposes of this section.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1F0783A04E234BD7B9ACA3A693905B9C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions and special rules</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="HF7B14A35149D487999C1E06443AA5A79"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Qualified historic home</header><text>The term <term>qualified historic home</term> means a certified historic structure—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H29027A7AA4144B5E9F4A8B366FE5512E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>which has been substantially rehabilitated, and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B5E6C69CD794443823111A43A6EDB81"><enum>(B)</enum><text>which (or any portion of which)—</text>
 <clause id="HC9E32A331F8748218E68AFF299D3539E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is owned by the taxpayer, and</text> </clause><clause id="H6FED9F350C3249E7AE3A1071D88CCFE9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is used (or will, within a reasonable period, be used) by such taxpayer as his principal residence.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9DB69F967C5F406D96F6CBEF1F87E54B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Substantially rehabilitated</header><text>The term <term>substantially rehabilitated</term> has the meaning given such term by section 47(c)(1)(C).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H50D425611F8D448CB4ECDC98953DFCC3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Principal residence</header><text>The term <term>principal residence</term> has the same meaning as when used in section 121.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H9119420D918849B7BD8C287310999D49"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Certified historic structure</header>
 <subparagraph id="HA090DEEA65CC46799FFE0E875EF401F7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>certified historic structure</term> means any building (and its structural components) which—</text> <clause id="H1B0D0CA4BF4743F1B663E01C6FF734BD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is listed in the National Register, or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBB52885D11704E7A95C91B7CF6C99BCE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is located in a registered historic district (as defined in section 47(c)(3)(B)) and is certified by the Secretary of the Interior as being of historic significance to the district.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8456B089FC59482E8A6A4E9DA10EAB8B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rehabilitation not complete before certification</header><text>A rehabilitation shall not be treated as complete before the date of the certification referred to in subsection (c).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1867B6CCC0434C77B6DD1F24ABC29B36"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Tenant-stockholder in cooperative housing corporation</header><text>If the taxpayer holds stock as a tenant-stockholder (as defined in section 216) in a cooperative housing corporation (as defined in such section), such stockholder shall be treated as owning the house or apartment which the taxpayer is entitled to occupy as such stockholder.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8AF607CA6AEB45C7B45EDEF5CBA820CF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Carryforward of unused credit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the credit allowable under subsection (a) exceeds the limitation imposed by section 26(a) for the taxable year reduced by the sum of the credits allowable under this subpart (other than this section and sections 25D and 1400C), such excess shall be carried to each of the 5 succeeding taxable years and, subject to rules similar to the rules of section 39(a)(2), shall be added to the credit allowable by subsection (a) for such succeeding taxable year.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H90B52D5F757C4FE29993D9F5ED4ACACE"><enum>(f)</enum><header>When expenditures taken into account</header><text>Qualified rehabilitation expenditures shall be treated for purposes of this section as made—</text> <paragraph id="HE88C0E91CC844CF28C7530B2A55A9A53"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on the date the rehabilitation is completed, or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6F0D749754E74D9492AF338832FD2DA3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to the extent provided by the Secretary by regulation, when such expenditures are properly chargeable to capital account.</text>
							</paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">Regulations under paragraph (2) shall include a rule similar to the rule under section 50(a)(2)
			 (relating to recapture if property ceases to qualify for progress
			 expenditures).</continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="HA1DF3D63676C4B98A214153748E5BE47"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Recapture</header>
 <paragraph id="H04EFAF87653D4E4FAA31616C8573715E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If, before the end of the 5-year period beginning on the date on which the rehabilitation of the building is completed—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H58E3AB6868CF4509B73A3B10309F5AB0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the taxpayer disposes of such taxpayer’s interest in such building, or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H808B1D74E5504619997A2AD8421C6841"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such building ceases to be used as the principal residence of the taxpayer or ceases to be a certified historic structure,</text>
								</subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">the taxpayer’s tax imposed by this chapter for the taxable year in which such disposition or
			 cessation occurs shall be increased by the recapture percentage of the
			 credit allowed under this section for all prior taxable years with respect
 to such rehabilitation.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD267DF9D4C543918E67973088B083F2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recapture percentage</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), the recapture percentage shall be determined in accordance with the table under section 50(a)(1)(B), deeming such table to be amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB9EE532CA4DD4CE68156CBE9E290FC8D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>If the property ceases to be investment credit property within—</quote> and inserting <quote>If the disposition or cessation occurs within—</quote>, and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H312361643E1E474C9715FD2CBDE2CDB3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (i) by striking <quote>One full year after placed in service</quote> and inserting <quote>One full year after the taxpayer becomes entitled to the credit</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2099F6C0B9CE4576869DD324691C6B50"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Transfer between spouses or incident to divorce</header><text>In the case of any transfer described in subsection (a) of section 1041 (relating to transfers between spouses or incident to divorce)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC33EE1E4DB354D4A9C92E9044F3155CC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the foregoing provisions of this subsection shall not apply, and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85C9158E567E43EEAE6E687C55110BC9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the same tax treatment under this subsection with respect to the transferred property shall apply to the transferee as would have applied to the transferor.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8727A64DF0D44F37B499CBFA2AB1A99B"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Basis adjustments</header><text>For purposes of this subtitle, if a credit is allowed under this section for any expenditure with respect to any property, the increase in the basis of such property which would (but for this subsection) result from such expenditure shall be reduced by the amount of the credit so allowed.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4CA6F6AE407641EAACB8B35F552B97D5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Processing fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any State may impose a fee for the processing of applications for the certification of any rehabilitation under this section provided that the amount of such fee is used only to defray expenses associated with the processing of such applications.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF7C0A1355C8A40608F0431A67AE1AE38"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Denial of double benefit</header><text>No credit shall be allowed under this section for any amount for which credit is allowed under section 47.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5129AFE3C5D24C208053E4D47AF7E561"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section, including regulations where less than all of a building is used as a principal residence and where more than 1 taxpayer use the same dwelling unit as their principal residence.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H19DF5EB86E074F52923588C4E375CF2A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="H198957D75C1242D4B2965CDD90770DA0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Subsection (a) of section 1016 of such Code is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (36), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (37) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new item:</text> <quoted-block id="H8340D069C6FA4B34A4FDE7DD3BEA4D7F"> <paragraph id="H0C4C98BBBAD540A4B12F6AC93A9171E5"><enum>(38)</enum><text>to the extent provided in section 25E(h).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H56947B23EF844EE7B4DEF38A3174973F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The table of sections for subpart A of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 25D the following new item:</text>
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section"><quote>Sec. 25E. Rehabilitation of historic principal residences.</quote>.</toc-entry></toc>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H30332B125DAD4331BFD47FCF028EC2B1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to rehabilitations the physical work on which begins after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


