<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HDF8B74BB1F4947D6833B03E2C4D76D57" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4515 IH: To amend title XXI of the Social Security Act to provide for a special rule during the first quarter of fiscal year 2018 for the redistribution of certain Children’s Health Insurance Program allocations for certain shortfall States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4515</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171201">December 1, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001106">Mr. Costello of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="E000294">Mr. Emmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000791">Mr. Walden</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XXI of the Social Security Act to provide for a special rule during the first
			 quarter of fiscal year 2018 for the redistribution of certain Children’s
			 Health Insurance Program allocations for certain shortfall States.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HD36F1E363B5B412B9BB95A5FAD39729F" style="OLC">
		<section id="HE95FAA064F234349B699F1B366E46A57" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>CHIP allocation redistribution special rule for certain shortfall States during first quarter of
 fiscal year <enum-in-header>2018</enum-in-header></header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2104(f)(2) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397dd">42 U.S.C. 1397dd(f)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HBA731D4F4D624DE6979C385FE75A964A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (B) to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H23B6654851A8417F91575FE29B4A7A1C" style="OLC">
					<subparagraph id="HA761B1C4EA444F6E8C11F0F619BE3518"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Determination of redistributed amounts if insufficient amounts available</header>
 <clause id="HF3553120AD794C489347B5076481D027"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Proration rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to clause (ii), if the amounts available for redistribution under paragraph (1) for a fiscal year are less than the total amounts of the estimated shortfalls determined for the year under subparagraph (A), the amount to be redistributed under such paragraph for each shortfall State shall be reduced proportionally.</text>
						</clause><clause id="H71C0FDAAF47F41F8BE787C7E96A3E053"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Special rule for first quarter of fiscal year <enum-in-header>2018</enum-in-header></header>
 <subclause id="H267D5BC73C9A4417BB74CDE1DA7EBC9E"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For the period beginning on October 1, 2017, and ending December 31, 2017, with respect to any amounts available for redistribution under paragraph (1) for fiscal year 2018, the Secretary shall redistribute under such paragraph such amounts to each emergency shortfall State (as defined in subclause (II)) in such amount as is equal to the amount of the shortfall described in subclause (II) for such State and period (as may be adjusted under subparagraph (C)) before the Secretary may redistribute such amounts to any shortfall State that is not an emergency shortfall State. In the case of any amounts redistributed under this subclause to a State that is not an emergency shortfall State, such amounts shall be determined in accordance with clause (i).</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HDA2F6CD9DE1B4194B29F3D8A9187FE0D"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Emergency shortfall State defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this clause, the term <quote>emergency shortfall State</quote> means, with respect to the period beginning October 1, 2017, and ending December 31, 2017, a shortfall State for which the Secretary estimates, in accordance with subparagraph (A) (unless otherwise specified in this subclause), that the projected expenditures under the State child health plan and under section 2105(g) (calculated as if the reference under section 2105(g)(4)(A) to <quote>2017</quote> were a reference to <quote>2018</quote> and insofar as the allotments are available to the State under this subsection or subsection (e) or (m)) for such period will exceed the sum of the amounts described in clauses (i) through (iii) of subparagraph (A) for such period, including after application of any amount redistributed under paragraph (1) before such date of enactment to such State. A shortfall State may be an emergency shortfall State under the previous sentence without regard to whether any amounts were redistributed before such date of enactment to such State under paragraph (1) for fiscal year 2018.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H99CB7F4E182F41E4B4C0386EA06BC1A9"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Application of qualifying State option</header><text>During the period described in subclause (I), section 2105(g)(4) shall apply to a qualifying State (as defined in section 2105(g)(2)) as if under section 2105(g)(4)—</text>
 <item id="H4E4B7C3720CA4CEA86FA34A935D45E82"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the reference to <quote>2017</quote> were a reference to <quote>2018</quote>; and</text> </item><item id="H679169256F5C4056849AF008774A424D"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the reference to <quote>under subsections (e) and (m) of such section</quote> were a reference to <quote>under subsections (e), (f), and (m) of such section</quote>.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBF9A3B8AF0E044EBBFD5692D86A94427"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6073E62F640B4EFD8DB727980E857CB2" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H57C5A57847CE4916A32898E2A020CDAE"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this paragraph may be construed as preventing a commonwealth or territory described in subsection (c)(3) from being treated as a shortfall State or an emergency shortfall State.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


