<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2E46EE1EA4E14A498591E4B7FF42B9DF" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1484 IH: Social Worker Safety Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1484</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170309">March 9, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001191">Ms. Sinema</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to award grants to States to provide safety
			 measures to social workers and other similar professionals who work with
			 at-risk populations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H009B2D4508B74DD3AA96F327D8DB7912" style="OLC">
 <section id="H600F9F56F9F34CF19B047CFF7F01ADB1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Social Worker Safety Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H9251E74229D04603B3086FA4AC809AA4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Social worker safety grant program</header> <subsection id="H70E5B1C5ED214E2BAF4DA2D72C959E50"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services may award grants to States to provide safety measures to social workers and other similar professionals (as designated by the Secretary) working with violent, illicit drug-using, or other at-risk populations.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0F139A04752D4750B3F0FC8654647ACD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Grants awarded pursuant to subsection (a) may be used to provide or support the following safety measures:</text>
				<paragraph id="HA504C300E1D645A995679F93387B61AE"><enum>(1)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H21E0F2D481754D6F92640E81A286B067"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The procurement and installation of safety equipment, including communications or recording systems, such as cell phones, wearable tracking devices with GPS/Bluetooth locator, or panic buttons used for supervised foster care visits and other client visits to assist agencies in locating staff.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB10299D0FF694F00BC239A51EFE350B8" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Technical assistance and training for safety communications.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3602A32C65CE423481FEB363E40305FE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Training sessions and exercises for self-defense and crisis, together with such organizations as local law enforcement.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5AD65602B5CB4243B5C151B13AB6A2CE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Facility safety improvements.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCE7C5EC43D714CB1BB549BC8683F1038"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Training in cultural competency, including linguistic training, and training on strategies for de-escalating a situation that could turn volatile.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H853CFAF06A8848729AFBBB38394CD23C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Training to help work with clients who—</text> <subparagraph id="H4E39CE8C8B2C4479A8714C8C7797351E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have serious mental and substance use disorders; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H39495050C1CB46EC96D10606DE3EE6DC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have behavioral problems and need help coping.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H860FDF544B1F444E94EF314847C4ABF7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Educational resources and materials to train staff on safety and awareness measures.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5920A42FE2E64B7A83D0892216ACF735"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Support services, counseling, and additional resources for social workers who have experienced safety issues or trauma-related incidents in the workplace.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H614C3CAF7F154D429FC1486E458A0F6A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Installation of a local data incident tracking system to monitor, prevent, and mitigate future offenses against social workers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H84EBE15043754146B4EB07DD1A94CFEC"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Other policy developments and implementation activities determined by the Secretary for social work safety training, resources, and support.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7CAAF311A612428392425DC7052D4D8E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header>
 <paragraph id="HBB78497B8EC14265BA09BB2C2CE27AFF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State seeking a grant under subsection (a) shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such additional information as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD778FBAA9C754ECCBAA52172DB2CD4CC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each application submitted pursuant to paragraph (1) shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H988F0E9E046E4BD7AD4E1BF7CF5EBD70"><enum>(A)</enum><text>describe the type of agencies that will receive funding through the grant and type of work to be done by such agencies;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE5B0E4B2F184A6F9C8F67A38BE69D2C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>describe the specific activities for which the grant is sought and include a program budget; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE7222E4A92C4DDE9714F302E2A9F3CC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>contain an assurance that the applicant will evaluate the effectiveness of the safety measures provided through the grant.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H07731618B5D44B56A7747F4465BC00B2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under subsection (a), the Secretary shall give priority to applicants that—</text> <paragraph id="HFE9083E650FD4475B0C63EF0D500ACA7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>demonstrate the greatest need based on documented incidents; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFBE5C2F92E324D1E9611B951B129E95A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>seek to provide assistance to multiple agencies.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0816AAF18FBC456CB927AB9C1BF10553"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Quality assurance and cost effectiveness</header><text>The Secretary shall establish guidelines for ensuring the quality and cost effectiveness of the safety measures funded under this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H815DB65E9A1A4A3E916AC88DE8131025"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary may provide technical assistance to recipients of a grant under this section with respect to planning, developing, implementing, and sustaining safety measures through the grant.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H913F334DDD0E4F76845F556141B03440"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Report requirement</header><text>States receiving a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary, not later than 2 years after such receipt, a report that includes—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA2021A9D882740CD8904D72189117480"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an assessment of the activities funded in whole or in part with the grant;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA69AFE8E041048809565B420DBA790A6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the range and scope of training opportunities provided through training programs funded in whole or in part through a grant under this section, including the numbers and percentages of social workers engaged in such training programs; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE80D6F80A95547A896A147CB95569CB8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the incidence of threats to social workers, if any, and the strategies used to address their safety.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD5F63DFE92904EE599105F7AD9B45502"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Non-Federal share</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the costs of safety measures to be provided pursuant to a grant under subsection (a), the State receiving the grant shall agree to make available (directly or through donations from public or private entities) non-Federal contributions toward such costs in an amount that is $1 for each $1 of Federal funds awarded through the grant.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8E3AE3A277AC4029B15172F2070DE67B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H4603923D664B470F9111FC6C1BA6EA68"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8BCBC5BB070F40CA9F88F9B8A1F1953B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>social work</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HF291D364458C46EA9AC2A2E4F13915EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the professional activity of helping individuals, groups, or communities to enhance or restore capacity for social and psychosocial functioning, and to create societal conditions favorable to such enhancement or restoration; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7578BCEE608D4FE2BA568F36AD1A9220"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the professional application of values, principles, and techniques related to the activities described in subparagraph (A), including—</text>
 <clause id="H0ECBA95B07AE45B39E41AEA7E653579C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>diagnosing mental and emotional disorders and treating individuals, families, or groups for such disorders; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5750CDD88CBF472A835C0752BE230CB6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>helping individuals, families, or groups to obtain tangible services, including personal, protective, informational, advisory, community, or maintenance services in order to improve the overall well-being of individuals.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD0CF5F9BA271455E8962ADEF14555DE1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>social worker</term> means an individual with a baccalaureate, master’s, or doctoral degree in social work from an institution of higher education who uses knowledge and skills to provide social work services for individuals, families, groups, communities, organizations, or society in general.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB1DB76D0F4F54C17A577C91ED26FD783"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


