<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H9AD7F41A2F7845D6A5FDE1E09D47874D" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4658 IH: Protecting Students from Worthless Degrees Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4658</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171214">December 14, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide consumer protections for students.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H095760767F1A4CC5BC0D2EDD45ED3EAF" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE9E9F73714494EFE9433037F25AC6CF1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Students from Worthless Degrees Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H144B4313EE5441FF95B05948CFCAF851"><enum>2.</enum><header>Consumer protections for students</header> <subsection id="H3EC41FFE83A14DBB9D56B67F567F5B40"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
 <paragraph id="H6F2625ECF14448CEA54DC86E59379E58"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal financial assistance program</header><text>The term <term>Federal financial assistance program</term> means a program authorized and funded by the Federal Government under any of the following provisions of law:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H70FCFDABA6894B83B901164FD6AD6D09"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070</external-xref> et seq.).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3648F384D1FE4481AB12BDFF586E7C09"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Title I of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3111">29 U.S.C. 3111</external-xref> et seq.) and title I of the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2801">29 U.S.C. 2801</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF6E9DFD55DD645428117FF812061E643"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Adult Education and Family Literacy Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3271">29 U.S.C. 3271</external-xref> et seq.).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DAD8ED15A5D4958B0D749D84A65ECEB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Chapter 30, 31, 32, 33, 34, or 35 of title 38, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA44F1B5D0AC44D43AC155F77E3047D2A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Chapter 101, 105, 106A, 1606, 1607, or 1608 of title 10, United States Code.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H47C8FB70179F408CB99A0E7085B18DDE"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Section 1784a, 2005, or 2007 of title 10, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEBC7B257528441BDB0BDBAEECB3E7634"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="HBB8493567EF04D94937E6B767FE6590A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to a program authorized under paragraph (1)(A), has the meaning given the term in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1E843BDDF514264A2FEBBF4B99681C7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to—</text> <clause id="H47829BDECF184A7692E8F5F1BEAD9011"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a program authorized under title I of the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2801">29 U.S.C. 2801</external-xref> et seq.), has the meaning given the term <term>postsecondary educational institution</term> as defined in section 101 of the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2801">29 U.S.C. 2801</external-xref>), on the day before the date of enactment of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/128">Public Law 113–128</external-xref>); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF97ABEC7084A42FE879C6B6BA186DBD9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a program authorized under title I of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3111">29 U.S.C. 3111</external-xref> et seq.), has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>);</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E67B90C427B4ABF8060E6A8E0AE277A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>with respect to a program authorized under paragraph (1)(C), has the meaning given the term <term>postsecondary educational institution</term> as defined in section 203 of the Adult Education and Family Literacy Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3272">29 U.S.C. 3272</external-xref>);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8178D27CA65C419FA9F0581EE0F3C9C3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>with respect to a program authorized under paragraph (1)(D), has the meaning given the term <term>educational institution</term> under section 3452 of title 38, United States Code;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84E6F540169F4AE4A860F4CC4752034D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>with respect to a program authorized under paragraph (1)(E), means an educational institution that awards a degree or certificate and is located in any State; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6896F7AE8CE44E85AEE49F9D1A88EA04"><enum>(F)</enum><text>with respect to a program authorized under paragraph (1)(F), means an educational institution that awards a degree or certificate and is located in any State.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H447440298B8A43B4B936B7DA1623DAD7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State</header>
 <subparagraph id="H1BF89087F6BB464EB68710A4828B4D66"><enum>(A)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> includes, in addition to the several States of the United States, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the District of Columbia, Guam, American Samoa, the United States Virgin Islands, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and the freely associated States.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C4AF4E39CF9418591BC67CC171029E4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Freely associated States</header><text>The term <term>freely associated States</term> means the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, and the Republic of Palau.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD4D350D481094CE7AFCB20CED905BAF0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consumer protections</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, an institution of higher education is not eligible to participate in a Federal financial assistance program with respect to any program of postsecondary education or training, including a degree or certificate program, that is designed to prepare students for entry into a recognized occupation or profession that requires licensing or other established requirements as a pre-condition for entry into such occupation or profession, unless, by not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act—</text>
 <paragraph id="HCE74CCF5D8AF40EEA19861E646031EE1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the successful completion of the program fully qualifies a student, in the Metropolitan Statistical Area and State in which the student resides (and in any State in which the institution indicates, through advertising or marketing activities or direct contact with potential students, that a student will be prepared to work in the occupation or profession after successfully completing the program), to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7A29D94C5B7843E9AE21B8F519221716"><enum>(A)</enum><text>take any examination required for entry into the recognized occupation or profession in the Metropolitan Statistical Area and State in which the student resides, including satisfying all Federal, State, or professionally mandated programmatic and specialized accreditation requirements, if any; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB34FF779A2284A1DAC897EAF61669355"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be certified or licensed or meet any other academically related pre-conditions that are required for entry into the recognized occupation or profession in the State; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5BA9C44E93454E2290CE70244BCF1770"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the institution offering the program provides timely placement for all of the academically related pre-licensure requirements for entry into the recognized occupation or profession, such as clinical placements, internships, or apprenticeships.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE3531AC31A004F68B71F93102867E3F1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Certification requirements for gainful employment programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 487 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1094">20 U.S.C. 1094</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H85E8EDD4CB6C4BDC89CA3FC9B653ED9D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD88EE634C407483CAF417387AD797357" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H1302B651AAA04C8EB3EED688521EA161"><enum>(30)</enum><text>The institution will provide to the Secretary not later than the first December 31 following the date of enactment of <short-title>Protecting Students from Worthless Degrees Act</short-title>, in accordance with procedures established by the Secretary, a certification signed by the most senior executive officer of the institution that each of the eligible gainful employment programs included on the eligibility and certification approval report of the institution meets the requirements of subsection (k).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFFF89294D2D84CDD92111ECCEC0D502F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD16CC057B362443ABE02EAAC03AD03FC" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HFED0AD057AB94F02B01623C0DD035FD1"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Certification requirements for GE programs</header><text>Each of the eligible gainful employment programs included on the eligibility and certification approval report of an institution of higher education shall comply with each of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HA59775FD2A9D4D2CA317D87D5C6FCB91"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The gainful employment program is approved by a recognized accrediting agency or is otherwise included in the institution's accreditation by its recognized accrediting agency, or, if the institution is a public postsecondary vocational institution, the program is approved by a recognized State agency for the approval of public postsecondary vocational education in lieu of accreditation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H014791866C5E42EBA868EC6AD75CF7BB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The gainful employment program is programmatically accredited, if such accreditation is required by a Federal governmental entity or by a governmental entity in the State in which the institution is located or in which the institution is otherwise required to obtain State approval pursuant to section 600.9 of title 34, Code of Federal Regulations, or a similar successor regulation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2E80FDFEA4AF41AD886D33BDD6BF64AE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The gainful employment program satisfies the applicable educational prerequisites for professional licensure or certification requirements in the State in which the institution is located or in which the institution is otherwise required to obtain State approval pursuant to section 600.9 of title 34, Code of Federal Regulations, or a similar successor regulation, so that a student who completes the program and seeks employment in such a State qualifies to take any licensure or certification exam that is needed for the student to practice or find employment in an occupation that the program prepares students to enter.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H742B8F3DB9464B348BABB28BC1EC7222"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The gainful employment program is not substantially similar to a program offered by the institution that, in any of the 3 years prior to the date of the determination, became ineligible for funding under this title due to the debt to earning rates measure or was failing, or in the zone with respect to, the debt to earning rates measure and was voluntarily discontinued by the institution. The institution shall include with its certification an explanation of how the gainful employment program is not substantially similar to any such ineligible or discontinued program.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


