<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H5DDAB9D166B0497285F73DB90C613E49" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1499 IH: Remedies for Refusal of Repatriation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1499</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170310">March 10, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001069">Mr. Courtney</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="W000810">Mr. Woodall</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide penalties for countries that systematically and unreasonably refuse or delay
			 repatriation of certain nationals, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H6C42C525AAA5456A9B219162AE985317" style="OLC">
 <section id="H24AE7784819B44A89DE0E1057868D316" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Remedies for Refusal of Repatriation Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H6EBCEB8CE5734DFEB5D7EFEAF871CEF3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="H4E6D2215303F4F178CE2361115BC3F9E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate committees of Congress</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H80A8F6CEBD3448E6BA9AB6A90D10CB59"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2919E2172F2F4BD79DDC30E5BC2C468E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate</committee-name>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF122BCF4B814466280B1BAC81156434F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate</committee-name>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD31CCE5418A74C5E96EB03DDB75D4259"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A1685A921D84A4582C877F5EDED8FA9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF76FB2BF985F4CF4AEF61D5AE7B17238"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF389E08EC36E4F488EAC77B86DDD4728"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Crime of violence</header><text>The term <term>crime of violence</term> has the meaning given that term in section 16 of title 18, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H707C0CDCC3A0498189B8D335BF671DF7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Felony</header><text>The term <term>felony</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H2B196983569C4305B106487E43A465BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a crime classified as a felony in the convicting jurisdiction, excluding State or local offenses for which an essential element was the alien’s immigration status; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H16502AACDB5546C6BC4B3F24B55C0617"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of an offense under section 276 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1326">8 U.S.C. 1326</external-xref>), or other Federal immigration-related offense that the Secretary may designate by regulation, an offense for which the term of imprisonment imposed on the defendant exceeded 1 year.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HC107774AAC424494AD58A7E3EB427BD9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Remedies for systematic refusal of repatriation</header>
 <subsection id="H0D1D673639E547DBAE1893561DAAC3C0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Criteria for systematic refusal or delay</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish procedures for determining whether the government of a foreign country systematically and unreasonably refuses or delays the repatriation of nationals of such country who—</text>
 <paragraph id="H537C6630A3534D5E9992B2AB7554D13A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>have been ordered removed from the United States; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H958B41E3FB7949F197A1808519808C15"><enum>(2)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0A26AE4F188D4FD9AAE1CFE6189B2C6A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have been convicted of a felony;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB087A9EB226841E4B4856DA6CC7872E8" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have been convicted of a crime of violence; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCAF5E1F34DF482DBB7B3E0588131FEE" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>are a threat to national security or public safety.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H90515C02CA4845C6AD20EA2D2E4B0F85"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements for inclusion on refusal or delay list</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A country shall be deemed to systematically and unreasonably refuse or delay the repatriation of its nationals if—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA4020638653E428FB7ED9FA824ED21A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the country refuses—</text> <subparagraph id="H23FFBED53CC44C62810D5E99896AE0DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to repatriate an individual described in subsection (a) who has been ordered removed notwithstanding the designation of such country as the place to which the individual is to be removed by the United States under section 241(b) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1231">8 U.S.C. 1231(b)</external-xref>); and</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H65F4D9D7F25F43699FD11C1725095A98"><enum>(B)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB4A4847CFB52456092874B0D9404FEAA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to secure and analyze all documents within its control that could tend to identify the nationality of such individual; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7CD2E676A2834CDC80804FE7321C8E7B" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to ensure that a government official capable of determining that such individual is a national of such country interviews such individual and, if additional evidence is needed, such individual’s family; or</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H374AF6BADD99471296BD33207F266FB0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>other factors indicate that the country systematically and unreasonably refuses or delays the repatriation of nationals of such country who are described in subsection (a) and have been ordered removed to such country by the United States.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H773634212F804F808662FC204B15373C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notification requirements</header><text>Upon determining that a country systematically and unreasonably refuses or delays repatriation of its nationals—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFA5606964B8C445389E415013486D7E7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary of Homeland Security shall notify the Secretary of State of such determination in writing not later than 5 days after such determination; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC60ED3783C314B058ECFE8B6DEE398FE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HC813923B60BD4B90879C3FDC847BD813"><enum>(A)</enum><text>meet concurrently with representatives of the foreign government in the United States and in the foreign country about such determination; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1D2B70DD772499BA6973E5116426760"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notify such representatives that the United States may discontinue issuance of visas to nationals of such country under section 243(d) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1253">8 U.S.C. 1253(d)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC24C41161FFE49698543D75C1BCA0313"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Discontinuance of visas</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In furtherance of section 243(d) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1253">8 U.S.C. 1253</external-xref>) and except as provided under subsection (e), if a country described in subsection (c) continues to systematically and unreasonably refuse or delay the repatriation of its nationals described in subsection (a) after receiving notification under subsection (c)(2)(B)—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2BC0EEF6B3D54952BBAA6B5E4E440D25"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary of Homeland Security shall notify the Secretary of State that the country meets the criteria described in section 243(d) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1253">8 U.S.C. 1253(d)</external-xref>); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEBBD728A5D41430D89BBD14CB6CBD98C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary of State shall discontinue the issuance of visas in accordance with such section.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9610E6AB53C94C1CA66EDEC56F2B3DF6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>If the Secretary of Homeland Security determines that it is not in the interests of the United States to discontinue the issuance of visas to nationals of a country described in subsection (d), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report documenting the reasons for such determination.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2591ED2478C94FC7ACD89BB90D916334"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Public dissemination of information</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security and the Secretary of State shall list countries that systematically and unreasonably refuse or delay repatriation of their nationals described in subsection (a) on the Web sites of their respective departments.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3CCBFA08D74241878DF6440F7F898526"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text>Not later than March 1 of each year, the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Secretary of State shall jointly submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7299C52E07F746E78A94E24DE27ABBCF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifies the countries that met the criteria developed pursuant to subsection (a) in the previous calendar year;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE2F6F54F30F7407CB6B976F675748F60"><enum>(2)</enum><text>describes the actions taken by the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Secretary of State after determining that a country met the criteria developed pursuant to subsection (a);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD42C20571DAC41F6A6C1AF267E98F255"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identifies the countries included in the notifications described in subsections (c) and (d) and the actions taken by the Secretary of State as a result of such notifications;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H749DCCFFB61541469EAE27500ABF4AF1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>identifies the countries that do not meet the criteria described in subsection (b), but have refused or delayed the repatriation of their nationals; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA1A19EADA8C94AA4854721C536D5D040"><enum>(5)</enum><text>describes the actions taken by the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Secretary of State with respect to the countries described in paragraph (4).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


