<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6A865CCF74B54DBD83896BD45CD41C6D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3603 IH: Stop Corporate Earnings Stripping Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3603</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20170728">July 28, 2017</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000263">Mr. Levin</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to prevent earnings stripping of corporations which are related to inverted corporations.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H071CFEC99ECE4A359ECB35B1A2753D3C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H733AB269B53F4E96955BBDE964E63265" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Corporate Earnings Stripping Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H83EE5ECA9DC44B59A9250FAA80266DEA" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prevention of earnings stripping of corporations which are related to inverted corporations</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H23BA4F9013A04369BD65DB66C69B7B28"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7874">Section 7874</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by redesignating subsection (g) as subsection (h) and by inserting after subsection (f) the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAF44E3EE414C43DA9CC279F6D38BF8E2" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H26F6743183E047619F66FA7FFC8BE6A0"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Special rules applicable to earnings stripping and related party transactions</header> 
<paragraph id="HF075C13A06F346B58B144EA77D199A20"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any corporation which is a related corporation for any taxable year, section 163(j) shall be applied with the following modifications:</text> <subparagraph id="HD8EBE7A34AA147AF91196F9CB2C7BB24"><enum>(A)</enum><header>5-year limitation on carryforward of disallowed amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of determining any amount carried to, or from, such taxable year under subparagraph (B) of section 163(j)(1), such subparagraph shall be applied by substituting <quote>in the 1st succeeding taxable and in the 2nd through 5th succeeding taxable years to the extent disallowed under subparagraph (A) in the preceding taxable year (determined on a first-in, first-out basis and by treating the amount carried forward under this subparagraph as allowed under subparagraph (A) before amounts otherwise taken into account under subparagraph (A))</quote> for <quote>in the succeeding taxable year</quote>. </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE624872411D94544A3F0D07F7C26F632"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rules for determining whether interest limitation rules apply</header><text>In applying section 163(j)(2) to determine whether section 163(j) applies to such related corporation for such taxable year—</text> <clause id="H7FAC629E4BC74954AA5F42496C3DDB4A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>subparagraph (A)(ii) shall be disregarded, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9DAD93B6D3F74FC09B07E09F01665E65"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>subparagraph (B)(i)(II) shall be applied by substituting <quote>25 percent of the adjusted taxable income of the corporation</quote> for <quote>the sum of 50 percent of the adjusted taxable income of the corporation plus any excess limitation carryforward under clause (ii)</quote> for purposes of determining the corporation's excess interest expense for such taxable year.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCB77245DDBE343A789282F2E1282D504"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Related corporation</header><text>For purposes of this subsection—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7D95750AEF20420F9EA4DE20983BCCDD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>related corporation</quote> means any corporation for any taxable year if, at any time during such taxable year, such corporation is a member of an expanded affiliated group which includes (at any time during such taxable year) an entity which—</text> <clause id="HF46F9B690C384209A9D089EF4205DD6E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is a surrogate foreign corporation, determined by applying subsection (a)(2)(B)—</text> 
<subclause id="H7BDE1E672DA841308077585B6337DCFA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by substituting <quote>on or after May 8, 2014</quote> for <quote>after March 4, 2003</quote> in clause (i) thereof, </text></subclause> <subclause id="H07888330476B4B908A64B6D2D2EDF3BE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by substituting <quote>more than 50 percent</quote> for <quote>at least 60 percent</quote> in clause (ii) thereof, and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H018BD511BA734BC6BDC249FE3BF3F3C1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>by disregarding the matter following clause (iii) thereof, and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HD8893AFBCE984D208644D324EE5B44CA" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is not treated as a domestic corporation by reason of subsection (b).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBF17F3115E8A49378369448CE98BB8FD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Special rule for inclusion of noncorporate entities</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), a partnership or other entity (other than a corporation) shall be treated as a member of an expanded affiliated group if such entity controls (as determined under section 954(d)(3)), or is controlled by (as so determined), members of such group (including any entity treated as a member of such group by reason of this sentence).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDDD5E00A38DF434CA824EE8658C3DBE0" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rules related to application of 5-year carryforward of disallowed amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of applying paragraph (1)(A)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2B5BBB7FEA984A96BA8DDF3F1396DD4A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Transition rule</header><text>For purposes of applying paragraph (1)(A), the term <quote>1st succeeding taxable year</quote> means the later of—</text> <clause id="H7D1BC956C6E14B1698BF6E04A089CD13" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the 1st succeeding taxable year after the taxable year in which the disqualified interest is paid or accrued (determined without regard to subsection (j)(1)(B)), or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HAC391F01C2A741218373294E87463476"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the 1st taxable year beginning after the date of the enactment of this subsection.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H53475B2779C34600819E23BECE33C165"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Amounts carried to taxable year for which corporation is a related corporation</header><text>Paragraph (1)(A) shall apply to amounts carried to a taxable year to which such paragraph applies without regard to whether such paragraph applied to the taxable year in which such amount was originally paid or accrued (or to any other taxable year).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H507ABC19968B4477BB336FD8732B8F39"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Amounts carried from taxable year for which corporation is a related corporation</header><text>Paragraph (1)(A) shall apply to amounts carried from a taxable year to which such paragraph applies (whether or not such amount was originally paid or accrued in such taxable year) without regard to whether such paragraph applies to the taxable year to which carried (or to any other taxable year).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD0DAC47328E24ED7BEE2EB83E61A8C39"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header> <paragraph id="H3658D6702B8F407D9DFAA463D8EBE0A1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0F03B5696B974FEB8DF7482CD839B6EC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation on carryforward of disallowed amounts</header><text>For purposes of determining any amount carried to a taxable year beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act, the amendments made by this Act shall apply to amounts paid or incurred before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

