<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCA7D75CD534344B788C30BFEC96129BD" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 497 RH: Santa Ana River Wash Plan Land Exchange Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
		<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 102</calendar>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 497</legis-num>
		<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 115–155]</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20170112">January 12, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001094">Mr. Cook</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="A000371">Mr. Aguilar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HII00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<action>
			<action-date>June 2, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc>Reported with amendments, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union,
			 and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
			<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction>
			<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on January 12, 2017</action-instruction>
		</action>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-desc display="yes"><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain public lands in San Bernardino County,
			 California, to the San Bernardino Valley Water Conservation District, and
			 to accept in return certain exchanged non-public lands, and for other
			 purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body changed="added" committee-id="HII00" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H38AA1820A3D94867AABEB4E01D621AAA" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <section id="H60ED01C2A43E4B5EA5AE04F7774E3A45" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Santa Ana River Wash Plan Land Exchange Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HE753646118FD493BB44B9A667F853FD9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="H297B973F66414A67811F826DA5753377"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Conservation District</header><text>The term <quote>Conservation District</quote> means the San Bernardino Valley Water Conservation District, a political subdivision of the State of California.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB54AEA9A75A94B8F8C327D4CAE73B0E2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Non-Federal Land</header><text>The term <quote>non-Federal Land</quote> means the approximately 310 acres of land owned by the Conservation District generally depicted as <quote>SBVWCD to BLM</quote> on the Map.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5326DE58042E4D71A4FBD68163D5F386"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Map</header><text>The term <quote>Map</quote> means the map titled <quote>Santa Ana River Wash Land Exchange</quote> and dated September 3, 2015.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H45FA6B0267F84231B4E78B0F20C8956E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Non-Federal exchange parcel</header><text>The term <quote>non-Federal exchange parcel</quote> means the approximately 59 acres of land owned by the Conservation District generally depicted as <quote>SBVWCD Equalization Land</quote> on the Map and is to be conveyed to the United States if necessary to equalize the fair market values of the lands otherwise to be exchanged.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDD55F3A758B848CDB9F99343E00D16B1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Federal exchange parcel</header><text>The term <quote>Federal exchange parcel</quote> means the approximately 90 acres of Federal land administered by the Bureau of Land Management generally depicted as <quote>BLM Equalization Land to SBVWCD</quote> on the Map and is to be conveyed to the Conservation District if necessary to equalize the fair market values of the lands otherwise to be exchanged.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA7F037CEA946474D9B228F4755FCF07B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Federal land</header><text>The term <quote>Federal land</quote> means the approximately 327 acres of Federal land administered by the Bureau of Land Management generally depicted as <quote>BLM Land to SBVWCD</quote> on the Map.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H07B31E20519B4242B41C6E67AC6D1118"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="HE843E7E6EEA443CF9B96C2DDCC15D94D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Exchange of land; equalization of value</header> <subsection id="H3606083A775F4043A173E9B2753F39E9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Exchange authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the land use planning requirements of sections 202, 210, and 211 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1712">43 U.S.C. 1712</external-xref>, 1720–21), subject to valid existing rights, and conditioned upon any equalization payment necessary under section 206(b) of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1716">43 U.S.C. 1716(b)</external-xref>), and subsection (b) of this Act, as soon as practicable, but not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, if the Conservation District offers to convey the exchange land to the United States, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HEE65E72096A24C628FDE561EA0B28434"><enum>(1)</enum><text>convey to the Conservation District all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the Federal land, and any such portion of the Federal exchange parcel as may be required to equalize the values of the lands exchanged; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF38DE419E4744A8D929D66FBA3C553F2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">accept from the Conservation District a conveyance of all right, title, and interest of the Conservation District in and to the non-Federal land, and any such portion of the non-Federal exchange parcel as may be required to equalize the values of the lands exchanged.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H692B8FD57E954E689ABD8F4B4F6E470F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Equalization payment</header><text>To the extent an equalization payment is necessary under section 206(b) of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1716">43 U.S.C. 1716</external-xref>), the amount of such equalization payment shall first be made by way of in-kind transfer of such portion of the Federal exchange parcel to the Conservation District, or transfer of such portion of the non-Federal exchange parcel to the United States, as the case may be, as may be necessary to equalize the fair market values of the exchanged properties. The fair market value of the Federal exchange parcel or non-Federal exchange parcel, as the case may be, shall be credited against any required equalization payment. To the extent such credit is not sufficient to offset the entire amount of equalization payment so indicated, any remaining amount of equalization payment shall be treated as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="H6962727901D54BC3A57764A575B5D5BE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>If the equalization payment is to equalize values by which the Federal land exceeds the non-Federal land and the credited value of the non-Federal exchange parcel, Conservation District may make the equalization payment to the United States, notwithstanding any limitation regarding the amount of the equalization payment under section 206(b) of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1716">43 U.S.C. 1716</external-xref>). In the event Conservation District opts not to make the indicated equalization payment, the exchange shall not proceed.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H70B6C9800D2F40CDA55D03D13AAE26A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>If the equalization payment is to equalize values by which the non-Federal land exceeds the Federal land and the credited value of the Federal exchange parcel, the Secretary shall order the exchange without requirement of any additional equalization payment by the United States to the Conservation District.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H552ED790DEC04516AC64C3477E970380"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appraisals</header>
 <paragraph id="H513F4EB68978463EA2413413D203B9C7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The value of the land to be exchanged under this Act shall be determined by appraisals conducted by 1 or more independent and qualified appraisers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE683888B9F81494787594DE36FBD6C31"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The appraisals shall be conducted in accordance with nationally recognized appraisal standards, including, as appropriate, the Uniform Appraisal Standards for Federal Land Acquisitions and the Uniform Standards of Professional Appraisal Practice.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4CCB64B4E03D44B394804FCEFD5E772C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Title approval</header><text>Title to the land to be exchanged under this Act shall be in a format acceptable to the Secretary and the Conservation District</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFC16D6D868B64049A66B93A3E694271A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Map and legal descriptions</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall finalize a map and legal descriptions of all land to be conveyed under this Act. The Secretary may correct any minor errors in the map or in the legal descriptions. The map and legal descriptions shall be on file and available for public inspection in appropriate offices of the Bureau of Land Management.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6F3B2F75628D4D02A9C2733389631BC1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Costs of conveyance</header><text>As a condition of conveyance, any costs related to the conveyance under this section shall be paid by the Conservation District.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H7E96292118684288A6483902076188F9"><enum>4.</enum><header>Applicable law</header>
			<subsection id="H35450DFB79DD4C9FA1D350DC8CC2840B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Act of February 20, 1909</header>
 <paragraph id="HA068D9956D0F46A38AB54186B7F562FB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Act of February 20, 1909 (35 Stat. 641), shall not apply to the Federal land and any public exchange land transferred under this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H839F358A35FA4CFABE795AD181301C2B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The exchange of lands under this section shall be subject to continuing rights of the Conservation District under the Act of February 20, 1909 (35 Stat. 641), on the non-Federal land and any exchanged portion of the non-Federal exchange parcel for the continued use, maintenance, operation, construction, or relocation of, or expansion of, groundwater recharge facilities on the non-Federal land, to accommodate groundwater recharge of the Bunker Hill Basin to the extent that such activities are not in conflict with any Habitat Conservation Plan or Habitat Management Plan under which such non-Federal land or non-Federal exchange parcel may be held or managed.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2610A5207D3446F38E8EF021C3A4049D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>FLPMA</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this Act, the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref>, et seq.), shall apply to the exchange of land under this Act.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H9AE52F71115A4A90A96A26100ECA8BB3"><enum>5.</enum><header>Cancellation of Secretarial Order 241</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Secretarial Order 241, dated November 11, 1929 (withdrawing a portion of the Federal land for an unconstructed transmission line), is terminated and the withdrawal thereby effected is revoked.</text>
		</section></legis-body><official-title-amendment>Amend the title so as to read: <quote>A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain Federal lands in San Bernardino
			 County, California, to the San Bernardino Valley Water Conservation
			 District, and to accept in return certain non-Federal lands, and for other
			 purposes.</quote>.</official-title-amendment>
	<endorsement display="yes">
		<action-date>June 2, 2017</action-date>
		<action-desc>Reported with amendments, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union,
			 and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill>


