<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H6DD5129C6C6F4C7F8FC2480717097545" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3224 IH: Critical Access and Rural Equity Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3224</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170713">July 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001045">Mr. Harper</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000565">Mr. Loebsack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000388">Mr. Kelly of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000601">Mr. Palazzo</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000258">Mr. Peterson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to clarify reasonable costs for critical access
			 hospital payments under the Medicare program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H50DD54084A734A46A1A64CF68CBEEF30" style="OLC">
 <section id="HEEFB2B390FAA48C1B97C451D7A2FA812" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Critical Access and Rural Equity Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CARE Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H2F1016C47DCD48ABA7A03CE9642A0877"><enum>2.</enum><header>Clarifying reasonable costs for critical access hospital Medicare payments</header> <subsection id="HA61852055F964491A8B046F218F825D6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Inclusion of certain costs as reasonable costs</header> <paragraph id="HB14EFEDADCB443FD818D3092A927F33C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Inpatient critical access hospital services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1814(l) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395f">42 U.S.C. 1395f(l)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9FE04BAE43EC4254AC2CEE1D2F8DD3A6" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HD3784223D0174C56A942034C95444E28"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining payment and reasonable costs under paragraph (1) for inpatient critical access services, the Secretary shall recognize as allowable costs of the critical access hospital at least the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H61C7DCB087BD45E0AAA2D0D3A75A2BA4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Costs of services that would be considered bona fide emergency services (as defined in section 1861(v)(1)(K)(ii)) if provided in a hospital emergency room, including professional services and any associated surgical on-call and standby costs.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BF2FA1B57304BC2B2F4302FFAE3DC41"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Costs of a test or procedure performed at a critical access hospital or an entity owned by the critical access hospital, including a clinical diagnostic laboratory test, mammogram (as defined in section 354(a)(5) of the Public Health Service Act), colonoscopy, cardiac stress test, pulmonary function test, echocardiogram, and bone density study.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H280689C5ACDD461C8AE0A89A641D63D2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Standby and on-call costs for certified registered nurse anesthetist services, regardless of the number of surgical procedures requiring anesthesia services and regardless of the number of full-time equivalent physicians.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H213ED97356D648D3BA4BD34D1C37BE99"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Costs of services provided by the critical access hospital or satellite facility of the critical access hospital that improve the total health of communities, including immunization programs, health clinics, and medical homes.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F4D52390F5741F09C65B77FD3903E5A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Costs of services provided by an off-campus provider-based clinic described in section 1820(c)(2)(F) of the critical access hospital, regardless of distance of such clinic from a hospital or another critical access hospital.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD9C0B72A9F664A81B7CBE53BF984633B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Outpatient critical access hospital services</header><text>Section 1834(g) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(g)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC112B756F39C4A9F9F46AAFC95CB2CA7" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H06863BABBE7D49D8A3DF0AE8C3E5726A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Coverage of certain additional costs as reasonable costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining the reasonable costs of outpatient critical access hospital services under paragraphs (1) and (2)(A), the Secretary shall recognize as allowable the costs described in paragraph (6) of section 1814(l).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H750AD93BAE224214887C09499E6D4074"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 1861(v)(7) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(v)(7)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB9FC781A2D0949D3B9B34B20E7A82942" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="HEB6296E7A4D2485E89227A365612A9E7" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For provisions further describing costs recognized as reasonable costs for inpatient and outpatient critical access hospital services, see sections 1814(l)(6) and 1834(g)(6).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3A5016BC42ED495AAABF035C84706284"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment of provider-Based clinics of critical access hospitals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1820(c)(2) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395i-4">42 U.S.C. 1395i–4(c)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H79E4F61AA38549D0B57781C188B8BCFF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)(i)(I), by striking <quote>is located</quote> and inserting <quote>subject to subparagraph (E), is located</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC792737BF77D48779ADC0FC63B9C2B82"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H88ECDBA12D6D4D98A6EFE53520292D11" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H9B017525BD7C4F50A757A6C17EBB20A1"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Treatment of off-campus pro­vider-based clinics</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (B)(i)(I) shall not apply to an off-campus provider-based clinic (as described in section 485.610 of title 45 of the Code of Federal Regulations) of a facility designated as a critical access hospital.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H15A6E54A42B14D89974D2E2AB62E98FD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Allowing coordination for provision of emergency services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1820(c)(2) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395i-4">42 U.S.C. 1395i–4(c)(2)</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (b), is further amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H80C9FBEEA742461191BD653C6C6B8CD1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)(ii), by striking <quote>makes</quote> and inserting <quote>subject to subparagraph (G), makes</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8405ABA5D54F499C8817986DD535FEF3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H442BE7682D6C432380573A3B4EEC50EB" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H19ACCFA8E4FD4BCFA8327B5EF7238C6B"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Allowing coordination for provision of emergency services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may waive the requirements under subparagraph (B)(ii), with respect to a facility, if such facility—</text>
 <clause id="H31CD8655BBB3447CBDBD376DCE41210D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is located not more than 15 miles of another facility or hospital that has an emergency department that satisfies the requirement of subparagraph (B)(ii); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H74F368DE44EF4366B847D11B66807E61"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>coordinates with such other facility or hospital with respect to furnishing 24-hour emergency care services described in such subparagraph to the area served by such facility.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H45F73205226043318195A56E7EB6D690"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Treatment of Medicaid provider taxes for critical access hospital reasonable costs</header>
 <paragraph id="HA1EAF343950C48C8BA733CEEA98447A2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Inpatient critical access hospital services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1814(l) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395f">42 U.S.C. 1395f(l)</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (a)(1), is further amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA38FE5A1F6AF4743993B3A878B8A216D" style="OLC">
						<paragraph id="HFCDA5AF106FD4676A65A99C234EB746F"><enum>(7)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H8935546C075142A1AB1ACCA13D7C5E07"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining payment and reasonable costs under paragraph (1) for inpatient critical access services—</text>
 <clause id="HC65A97247DDB450499EBA6A6F01A99E6" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with respect to a current permissible health care related tax imposed and paid by the critical access hospital for a cost reporting period beginning before the date of enactment of this paragraph, the Secretary shall not, through recoupment or otherwise, disallow payment to the critical access hospital under this subsection on the basis that payments to the critical access hospital under this subsection offset some or all of the costs of such tax; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H31C1BFAB1D5A40BF8DCF43B6B466E8F8" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a current permissible health care related tax imposed and paid by the critical access hospital for a cost reporting period beginning on or after the date of enactment of this paragraph, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <subclause id="H4BC270B147F04C3B90728F2EAD1AF0C0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>assess the percentage of individuals entitled to benefits under this part who are furnished inpatient critical access hospital services at such critical access hospital during such cost reporting period and who are also receiving medical assistance under the Medicaid program under title XIX during such period; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H10A9320B59C34FAAB306D55F072B9A20"><enum>(II)</enum><text>adjust payments under this subsection with respect to such services furnished during such period in a manner specified by the Secretary based on such percentage to take into account such tax.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H905CBF38417741BCAF876FBF9CCF4A60" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>For purposes of this paragraph and section 1834(g)(7), the term <term>current permissible health care related tax</term> means a broad-based health care related tax (as defined in paragraph (3)(B) of such section) that is in effect prior to enactment of this paragraph and for which there is not in effect a hold harmless provision described in paragraph (4) of such section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H35994774BA5C4358826E677123073518"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Outpatient critical access hospital services</header><text>Section 1834(g) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(g)</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (a)(2), is further amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4E6C0941E7EF45378670C602AE5930AF" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HBD7BBBB94F39454C8377294BE6A71B03"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Treatment of Medicaid provider taxes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining payment for outpatient critical access hospital services under paragraphs (1) and (2), the provisions of paragraph (7) of section 1814(l) shall apply to payment for such services under this subsection in the same manner as such provisions apply to payment for inpatient critical access hospital services under section 1814(l), except that in applying subparagraph (B) of such paragraph (7), the reference to <quote>individuals entitled to benefits under this part</quote> shall be deemed a reference to <quote>individuals enrolled under part B</quote>.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


