<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE83F4289126840A6BEE903A9D5DDD260" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2242 IH: Keep It in the Ground Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2242</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170428">April 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit drilling in the outer Continental Shelf, to prohibit coal leases on Federal land, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HBE96EF8BE4B147EB84F20B3F95999F40" style="OLC">
 <section id="H2D5C2D7BBF9C49D19923898EF2B4B0DD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Keep It in the Ground Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HA99435C31FBE42F3A9B25F2B6CBEB97B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; statement of policy</header> <subsection id="H08A6514D867D4225A28ABEB47111345C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H31402B54E0564A5F9445E969AE723423"><enum>(1)</enum><text>from 1880 through 2014, global temperatures have increased by about 0.9 degrees Celsius;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H31B176AAFDC24CD2AA7D8D0760E78E3A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the vast majority of global warming that has occurred over the past 50 years was due to human activities, primarily the burning of fossil fuels;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H25FFE3F262274AF4AB0CA0D39246188D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>emissions of greenhouse gases and atmospheric concentrations of greenhouse gases continue to rise, which results in a continued warming trend;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD5AD84BEEE034FBF934917A18B0C36C2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>global warming already has a significant impact on the economy, including the farming, fishing, forestry, and recreation industries;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDA24082EAC284C3D8EA0B7C646EA42E9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the significant impacts of global warming that are already occurring will be amplified by a global temperature increase of 2 degrees Celsius, which will lead to increased droughts, rising seas, mass extinctions, heat waves, desertification, wildfires, acidifying oceans, significant economic disruption, and security threats;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB1FBDCDFD2244764901FC198C591A0CB"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to avoid exceeding 2 degrees Celsius warming, at least 80 percent of carbon from proven fossil fuel reserves must be kept in the ground;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAF6D47472EEF49C89E437ACAFC2FB098"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the potential emissions resulting from extracting and burning all fossil fuels on Federal land and waters amounts to a significant percentage of the greenhouse gas emissions limit; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H637DB945411A43E0AA5AAA8A0A443D3B"><enum>(8)</enum><text>ending new leases for fossil fuels will prevent the release of 90 percent of the potential emissions from Federal fossil fuels.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0E25BD8CA3494FA7BFA8E8B8A0A9DCD6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text>It is the policy of the United States that—</text> <paragraph id="HB8B34DE737D84EBE95B72AAA7B9A225B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Federal land and waters should be managed for the benefit of the people of the United States—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDDCB1C6643F3431BB76779E271ED36E2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to avoid the most dangerous impacts of climate change; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEBC2BAD68AA247FB9418A054F6496BBA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to promote a rapid transition to a clean energy economy by keeping fossil fuels in the ground; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H24C52C7823F34DA3AF171F55B3EA61A5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Federal Government should pursue management of Federal land and waters for the benefit of the people of the United States by not issuing any new lease or renewing any nonproducing lease for coal, oil, or natural gas in any Federal land or waters.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HAF0D7C60716F4D8C92FE1AEC24509D0B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HDBE972285BB04A118FC0D71EE6CBC77C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Extend</header><text>The term <term>extend</term> means the act of extending a lease under the Mineral Leasing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/181">30 U.S.C. 181</external-xref> et seq.) beyond the existing term of the lease.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8860E568E7F24831B73BB120431E1D80"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nonproducing lease</header><text>The term <term>nonproducing lease</term> means any lease under which no coal, oil, gas, oil shale, tar sands, or other fossil fuel approved in the lease contract has been extracted for commercial use.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6653BC6FC41C4F108CB319A5EAACF5C4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reinstate</header><text>The term <term>reinstate</term> means the act of reinstating a lease under the Mineral Leasing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/181">30 U.S.C. 181</external-xref> et seq.) after a violation of any term of the lease that resulted in suspension or cancellation of the lease.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF36B78A080DF43BDA35F549E76F28E9C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Renew</header><text>The term <term>renew</term> means the act of renewing a lease under the Mineral Leasing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/181">30 U.S.C. 181</external-xref> et seq.) for a term that is not longer than the maximum renewal term for a lease under that Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7A51842A2DBB4E2C8E1B0A94788D572A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H2EB5BC41F3164CEA856833D653D80CCF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Stopping new offshore oil and gas leases in the gulf of mexico and the pacific, atlantic, and arctic oceans</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFDFD2C90291E4D528AF814CFD7F399B7"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prohibition on new oil and gas leasing on the outer continental shelf</header><text>Section 8 of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1337">43 U.S.C. 1337</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4204230299B44E158FFE40D3D340E32D" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="HB5C98F6F87DB48C1A3BBA082D738C70C"><enum>(q)</enum><header>Prohibition on new oil and gas leasing on the outer continental shelf</header>
 <paragraph id="H0D20A024D84B44ECBDC31EA8C5B37930"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="H26A62DA216FE415DB239A3CAE9D276C1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Extend</header> <clause id="H79D942F110A6457B82DDDE5215AB5AEE"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>extend</term> means the act of extending a lease under this Act beyond the existing term of the lease.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8DB2CF56154A4B3C8A14E052D7FCD68A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Inclusion</header><text>The term <term>extend</term> includes the act of extending a lease following a suspension under this Act.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7245902F54A447B98F398C5BB384D099"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Nonproducing lease</header><text>The term <term>nonproducing lease</term> means any lease under which any coal, oil, gas, oil shale, tar sands, or other fossil fuel approved in the lease contract has been extracted.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28ECA8880538404488F3D254E83C6164"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Reinstate</header><text>The term <term>reinstate</term> means the act of reinstating a lease under this Act after a violation of any term of the lease that resulted in suspension or cancellation of the lease.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE9FFC565BACF498FA09E8FD0CCD9C18B"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Renew</header><text>The term <term>renew</term> means the act of renewing a lease under this Act for a term that is not longer than the maximum renewal term for a lease under this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB93CEA3AEEDF4149A8C366758C9BAED9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act or any other law, the Secretary of the Interior shall not issue a new lease, renew, reinstate, or extend any nonproducing lease, or issue any other authorization for the exploration, development, or production of oil, natural gas, or any other fossil fuel in—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB116D3CB33E14D80B61FD1B2F253BCDD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Arctic Ocean;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H583F33BDB1D944D583103DC330BFB20E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Atlantic Ocean, including the Straits of Florida;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H873EF518C964491EB8309770439AD15D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Pacific Ocean;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94291C8664564DF084F8B94262E70260"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Gulf of Mexico; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20156E5F4B1F4E3E9AFCA8D0056D83E8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any other area of the outer Continental Shelf.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDB3D43F5D325497889635893F1BE73CF"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Cancellation of existing leases</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall cancel any lease issued under section 8 of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1337">43 U.S.C. 1337</external-xref>) on or before the date of enactment of this Act in the Beaufort Sea, Cook Inlet, or Chukchi Sea.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H8DA05AE65B3941C1A59A82B8397A3377"><enum>5.</enum><header>Stopping new coal, oil, tar sands, fracked gas, and oil shale leases on federal land</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary shall not conduct any lease sale, enter into any new lease, reoffer for lease any land covered by an expiring lease, or renew, reinstate, or extend any nonproducing lease in existence on or before the date of enactment of this Act for onshore fossil fuels, including coal, oil, tar sands, oil shale, and gas on land subject to the Mineral Leasing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/181">30 U.S.C. 181</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
		</section><section id="H61C1359498CF4F4DA9CE27C7FDB9BB37"><enum>6.</enum><header>Exceptions</header>
			<subsection id="HEE809EDFEC8140D2ABF60A5592360E9C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National security</header>
 <paragraph id="HCF82B11E7EF0492DA4194A58EE75A4E3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (2), the Secretary may exempt any provision of this Act or an amendment made by this Act for a lease if the Secretary determines, on the record and based on available information, that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8D47540EDA784D5BB7DD0544B31B9B5A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">there is an imminent national security threat; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4273E9C2316F4412AD287882541D5E5F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issuing an exemption for the lease would significantly reduce the imminent national security threat.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE413CA663EC948BEBD67D0FFB1A8486F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An exemption under paragraph (1) shall continue only for as long as the imminent national security threat persists.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9F26EFA3417F42DB9FAF3169CED7143A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Breach of contract</header>
 <paragraph id="HC2892F59D584403E84CF9D2C4F351330"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (2), the Secretary may allow a nonproducing lease to be renewed or extended if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFAA5A00CB9144D8BA5B8CD8EC3E6C2B5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the nonproducing lease contract was signed before the date of enactment of this Act; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE43DC3D77A814810BDA3F85CA8A80060"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary determines that giving effect to any provision of this Act or an amendment made by this Act is likely to lead to a court with jurisdiction ruling that there was a material breach of the nonproducing lease contract.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F511E1B096341548528936095E0B711"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>A renewal or extension under paragraph (1) shall be for the shortest time practicable, consistent with the terms of the nonproducing lease contract.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC89C026C9CBC41ABA85F31277D7FCADA" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>7.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, an amendment made by this Act, or the application of such a provision or amendment to any person or circumstance is held to be invalid or unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act, the amendments made by this Act, and the application of those provisions and amendments to any person or circumstance shall not be affected.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


