<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H666AE8B984DF4A3AA23549E8886A246E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><form><distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1028</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170213">February 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001165">Mr. Sires</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend titles 23 and 49, United States Code, with respect to congestion mitigation and metropolitan transportation planning, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAD45CA5485584B6794F7244A730169B7" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD7098FAA69AA464B9739392C92FC136A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Commute Less Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0EE2BE97FF8D4732BC470A7C81200C57"><enum>2.</enum><header>Metropolitan transportation planning</header> <subsection id="HE86D8DEBA0EA412885A4B4715B6F14CA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5303(b) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2FEC6DD4F1FD47A08D9401A8D03C546D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (7) as paragraph (9);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB650CBB53D1B420592AB9D0DA0910C38"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1) through (6) as paragraphs (2) through (7), respectively;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H08FC2B822CD74978A474F3F1EF4F4B73"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting before paragraph (2) (as so redesignated by paragraph (2) of this subsection) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H21E40A96A3194D43A08333F70682B034" style="USC"> <paragraph id="HB3C4AEEE08F84A7FA37E637E4777A5CF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Employer-based commuter program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>employer-based commuter program</term> means a program implemented by an employer that provides employees of that employer with alternatives to driving to and from work in a vehicle occupied by a single individual, including the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H81F3E8BBB7A540A49A446205D145B351"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A carpool program.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEAC24372CC8C4D0CB01D2D49721571A1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A vanpool program.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1854249A9B2242F59B1E2845A4DF8CBF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A transit benefit program.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE2660A24AC47411BBD7C611D3D8820B7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A parking cash-out program.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF3FB77A6956D43F6858F0C2501180770"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A shuttle program.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD74919AAB4FC4B39BD65662083BBE830"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A telework program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2BB8CE602D1645FBA77EFB0CB20D93D4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting before paragraph (9) (as so redesignated by paragraph (1) of this subsection) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBD8144AD77F54F20A1FC9B12D59120C1" style="USC"> <paragraph id="H4E87EE2E23434CE7B8ED6C8CA0D5482A"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Transportation management organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>transportation management organization</term> means a local, regional, or statewide association of employers established for the purpose of providing employees of those employers with alternatives to driving to and from work in a vehicle occupied by a single individual.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC63A45FBD7394DA7B8666483173FBE46"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Development of transportation plan</header> 
<paragraph id="H95E7EE574ED8460B982283B0389EF106"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Transportation plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5303(i)(2) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB06DB419D4CE48AEB041F8EFD602D1CE" style="USC"> <subparagraph id="H3937ACE05E7B4067AB299F86F38604F5"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Employer outreach activities and strategies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Proposed activities and strategies to provide outreach to employers and transportation management organizations to facilitate the creation and expansion of employer-based commuter programs.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H08E8CFAA99D7400EA4325C84B7A9E2D4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Participation by interested parties</header><text>Section 5303(i)(6)(A) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H6F1C6F3C1C0240FC80F42B75A8F163E5" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>, employer-based commuting programs, such as a carpool program, vanpool program, transit benefit program, parking cash-out program, shuttle program, or telework program</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB7A91A86C73B4E9888F5D6213C269219"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after <quote>the disabled,</quote> the following: <quote>representatives of employers, employer-based commuter programs, and transportation management organizations,</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDF7DABDABA724610BB1E6FFE9D988BCC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Metropolitan TIP</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5303(j)(2)(A) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>, including projects identified in a relevant commuter trip reduction plan developed under subsection (s).</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H65A2AF181BD748B696CF4D4B234DF2FC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Transportation management areas</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5303(k)(3) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H6F870887FCDC49429C151D7C4A38DE7E" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A) by striking <quote>operators, employer-based commuting programs, such as a carpool program, vanpool program, transit benefit program, parking cash-out program, shuttle program, or telework program</quote> and inserting <quote>operations and employer-based commuter programs</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H878F206FAE034D4F80B28EDB25CE1283" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subparagraphs (C) and (D); and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HE821BD5E5FA34EFB8DD574E6D182ED42"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFDE42DBE5EFB426AB900F5E14A760C81" style="USC"> 
<subparagraph id="H500AFE884DFF4EBF92F234E3EBB3FDCA"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Employer involvement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A process for addressing congestion management under subparagraph (A) shall be developed in coordination with any relevant employer advisory council established under subsection (s) and shall include projects identified in the commuter trip reduction plan of that council.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDDFCE3EFA6624EEF8303D1116BCEF439"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Employer advisory councils and information clearinghouse</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5303 of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBBE3EB85575B497AB696DDDA295268BB" style="USC"> 
<subsection id="H48C50C41AB9F4255A213D5FEF7E1ED84"><enum>(s)</enum><header>Employer advisory councils</header> 
<paragraph id="H18B4A9B6571F468D84D9497C85EF98B2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each metropolitan planning organization serving a transportation management area shall establish an employer advisory council that consists of representatives of employers in the area served by the metropolitan planning organization.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF56545D280784FC29801C847D6086E4C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header> <subparagraph id="H871193A6DE384165A9DA4F63C895399F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An employer advisory council shall consist of not less than 7 representatives of employers and representatives of identified transportation management organizations in the area served by the relevant metropolitan planning organization.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF196308836A7486FB72FA4C760C271AA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Ensuring a diverse cross-section of employers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In establishing an employer advisory council, a metropolitan planning organization, to the extent practicable, shall ensure that the membership of the council includes a diverse cross-section of employers from the area served by the organization.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H63D3E54DAF92478B89DB02C59D2E7335"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Commuter trip reduction plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An employer advisory council established under paragraph (1) shall develop and maintain a commuter trip reduction plan that identifies—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H52924173E6504E1FB31F60CCD413411E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">commuting patterns in the area served by the relevant metropolitan planning organization;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBF3E0479615B46158C2D907E5E69494D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>area goals for the reduction of vehicle miles traveled during peak commuting hours;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC89B319831E9484ABB8B0B1D09A8C2C0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>existing and proposed employer-based commuter programs in the area;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H010A91A4E9C24E458FF3E7B209783FEE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a series of projects and activities to facilitate achievement of the goals identified under subparagraph (B); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H681928D4F0304042A0E826D217ECEC06"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a financing plan for the projects and activities identified under subparagraph (D).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1CB399184789413EA89036AAF70DCC29"><enum>(t)</enum><header>Information clearinghouse</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary is authorized to make a grant to a national nonprofit organization engaged in efforts relating to employer-based commuter programs or another entity to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H85C1A18F18964BE48361D39092855172"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish and operate an information clearinghouse relating to employer investment in transportation and employer-based commuter programs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC451BC2F1F1D4AEE9B439AEE361589AF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop an education program with respect to employer investment in transportation and employer-based commuter programs; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8B3DB7246DEA474386829768E08D316A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide technical assistance relating to employer-based commuter programs and disseminate techniques and strategies used by successful employer-based commuter programs.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="H4808445C566D474881DDBCD0C8FFCEDC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Congestion mitigation during project construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 106 of title 23, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEB3183F76AF44B909BD2B899CDE9DF16" style="USC"> 
<subsection id="HA7F3C1717BDF4E69AD40E291E04F6908"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Congestion mitigation plans</header> 
<paragraph id="H01C635635A4449B3B75FDA6C4D767BD4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A recipient of Federal financial assistance under this title for a project with an estimated total cost of $75,000,000 or more or that will reduce traffic flow (as defined by the Secretary) for more than 120 days shall prepare a congestion mitigation plan for such project that includes funding for projects to reduce vehicle miles traveled during peak commuting hours along the impacted corridor.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF7AF26086DE4405E94B8344109B4E2C6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>A recipient shall prepare a congestion mitigation plan under paragraph (1) in coordination with any relevant employer advisory council established under section 5303(s) of title 49.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6401F8C568BF4203A8F454DDE3DF135C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Review by Secretary</header><text>A congestion mitigation plan prepared under paragraph (1) shall be made available to the Secretary for review upon the request of the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="HB81F3C8A71F2440AA22DA59B4CEF45C8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Employer-based commuter programs action plan</header> <subsection id="H756609453E1C465FA14AB6BAAA45CF82"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Transportation shall develop and implement a plan to expand and promote employer-based commuter programs (as defined in section 5303(b) of title 49, United States Code).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H549653BA99D74FABBD53F46F5AF53F2C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The plan developed under subsection (a) shall include plans—</text> <paragraph id="HFB7E57AA2CF34705874531F717AB531A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to amend existing regulations and guidance and, if necessary, develop new regulations and guidance to ensure that employer-based commuter programs are integrated, to the extent possible, into all appropriate Federal transportation programs;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDEF644BD1D0F4F529B6385D0E7900FCC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to identify best practices with respect to employer-based commuter programs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8AE2C9F3FA2D488882B82D212BA71BF6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to research the effectiveness and efficiency of employer-based commuter programs; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB450842EA9D04FDE9E671D96C66E1DC7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to create a national and regional peer exchange program to ensure that developments with respect to employer-based commuter programs are shared and issues are addressed.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H82B8D144CCC340DFBCEE2C3D6957FE11"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall finalize and begin implementation of the plan developed under subsection (a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3354C316D0604B7AACF1F76C2C706A9A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate a report on the implementation and impact of the plan developed under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> <section id="H5573A570B2FB424CA37ADC911D9226C2"><enum>5.</enum><header>Disaster preparedness report</header> <subsection id="H4031134CCA9F4AC4BA87248F59354396"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate a report with recommendations on how to better integrate employer-based commuter programs (as defined in section 5303(b) of title 49, United States Code) into emergency planning, preparedness, and response activities.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H56D5AF24647D4B16B995318144A4228D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In preparing the report under subsection (a), the Secretary shall consult with—</text> <paragraph id="H0E304AD5992F405DA7BF3813F61FD95F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF28FC9C6AB2F413D933D1D921B81E481"><enum>(2)</enum><text>stakeholders, including national and regional organizations and experts that promote employer-based commuter programs.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

