<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7C3B49A286EC494998ECA932C04CE201" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4013 IH: 2020 American Census Investment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4013</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20171011">October 11, 2017</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">Making appropriations for the Bureau of the Census for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2018.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HE94D18DAAAAE4F71AE56DD840A3C115B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCA6ECE5FE2B94435BA64F4C458A39882" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>2020 American Census Investment Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H8769BBA595C64C6FBE25CAF3A4612111"><enum>2.</enum><header>Appropriations for the Bureau of the Census</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The following sums are appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2018:</text><appropriations-intermediate id="H95FC9019BCC949DF9C29C29E96A83CE1"><header>Bureau of the Census</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H27B569D8376C4BCD8AFDA32B89AB24B5"><header>Current Surveys and Programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses for collecting, compiling, analyzing, preparing and publishing statistics, provided for by law, $300,000,000: <italic>Provided</italic>, That, from amounts provided herein, funds may be used for promotion, outreach, and marketing activities: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That the Bureau of the Census shall collect and analyze data for the Annual Social and Economic Supplement to the Current Population Survey using the same health insurance questions included in previous years, in addition to the revised questions implemented in the Current Population Survey beginning in February 2014.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HF6F00363F6C249AEA3901CB673841836"><header>Period censuses and programs</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H1BD6D738D5084A68A23A9A3B14D02758"><header>(Including transfer of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses for collecting, compiling, analyzing, preparing and publishing statistics for periodic censuses and programs provided for by law, $1,635,000,000: <italic>Provided</italic>, That, from amounts provided herein, funds shall be used for promotion, outreach, and marketing activities: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That within the amounts appropriated, $2,580,000 shall be transferred to the <quote>Department of Commerce—Office of Inspector General</quote> account for activities associated with carrying out investigations and audits related to the Bureau of the Census: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That not more than 50 percent of the amounts made available under this heading for information technology related to 2020 census delivery, including the Census Enterprise Data Collection and Processing (CEDCaP) program, may be obligated until the Secretary submits to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate a plan for expenditure that: (1) identifies for each CEDCaP project/investment over $25,000: (A) the functional and performance capabilities to be delivered and the mission benefits to be realized; (B) the estimated lifecycle cost, including estimates for development as well as maintenance and operations; and (C) key milestones to be met; (2) details for each project/investment: (A) reasons for any cost and schedule variances; and (B) top risks and mitigation strategies; and (3) has been submitted to the Government Accountability Office.</text></appropriations-small> </section> </legis-body> </bill> 

