<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H611CC4ACE3544674B3E5CCBFB8C2BFE0" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1630 IH: Columbia River In-Lieu and Treaty Fishing Access Sites Improvement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1630</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170320">March 20, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to assess sanitation and safety conditions at Bureau of
			 Indian Affairs facilities that were constructed to provide affected
			 Columbia River Treaty tribes access to traditional fishing grounds and
			 expend funds on construction of facilities and structures to improve those
			 conditions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H53BFCCB63DB540089C687E6AE7EB6158" style="OLC">
 <section id="H881D7420897F43D3983C8C34CFDF3054" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Columbia River In-Lieu and Treaty Fishing Access Sites Improvement Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H5A2C92F79F2E4429911F18F838646771"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sanitation and safety conditions at certain Bureau of Indian Affairs facilities</header> <subsection id="H9F8DB2A8F76F4B1D9F6F3892047F589A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Assessment of conditions</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Indian Affairs, in consultation with the affected Columbia River Treaty tribes, may assess current sanitation and safety conditions on lands held by the United States for the benefit of the affected Columbia River Treaty tribes, including all permanent Federal structures and improvements on those lands, that were set aside to provide affected Columbia River Treaty tribes access to traditional fishing grounds—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2127606445854C1AAE1FB2B3DCBCD28D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in accordance with the Act of March 2, 1945 (59 Stat. 10, chapter 19) (commonly known as the <quote>River and Harbor Act of 1945</quote>); or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H92722C6C2A844C558C0D2AF85C311E5F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in accordance with title IV of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/100/581">Public Law 100–581</external-xref> (102 Stat. 2944).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H13DE2D5C771D4E6C9CD5F175B65D9D9E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exclusive authorization; contracts</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Indian Affairs—</text> <paragraph id="H55543A3E48484E8FAEC301CEDE218A37"><enum>(1)</enum><text>subject to paragraph (2)(B), shall be the only Federal agency authorized to carry out the activities described in this section; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA11D74B931E942FB9587DEA7BEFBAFAF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may delegate the authority to carry out activities described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (c)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H368F7CE5C4534D48AD117D817AB492AE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>through one or more contracts entered into with an Indian tribe or tribal organization under the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5301">25 U.S.C. 5301</external-xref> et seq.); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H011594AA4E4543829E19169D475E9471"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to include other Federal agencies that have relevant expertise.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5922F852961D4F75A817F6455FFEB079"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition of affected Columbia river treaty tribes</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>affected Columbia River Treaty tribes</quote> means the Nez Perce Tribe, the Confederated Tribes of Umatilla Indian Reservation, the Confederated Tribes of the Warm Springs Reservation of Oregon, and the Confederated Tribes and Bands of the Yakama Nation.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0F6DF01A3F62437E9C022FFE1CC52E59"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of the Interior such sums as are necessary, to remain available until expended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H07B129FE274D456D80D60CC5E9F851C1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for improvements to existing structures and infrastructure to improve sanitation and safety conditions assessed under subsection (a); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9746EB95B9FA44A5B6AEF1E2C2C54024"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to improve access to electricity, sewer, and water infrastructure, where feasible, to reflect needs for sanitary and safe use of facilities referred to in subsection (a).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


