<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H71A309256381465E8F4663907B004A04" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2047 IH: Behavioral Health Infrastructure Improvement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2047</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170406">April 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000570">Mr. Ben Ray Luj&#225;n of New Mexico</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000379">Mr. Kennedy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to provide for behavioral health infrastructure improvements under the Medicaid program.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H52AD19509849468B921B5BFE898EDCC7" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD00839621E35476287CA2AA3E00A08E0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Behavioral Health Infrastructure Improvement Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H0235C1C3A4BA49F6BDC83F3E91FF0478"><enum>2.</enum><header>Behavioral health infrastructure improvements</header> <subsection id="H6C57699E8A76429AB8430579171D1FE8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Enhanced FMAP for infrastructure improvements</header> <paragraph id="H96792EE2F0084158A5E32DB55B85308F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1903(a)(3) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396b">42 U.S.C. 1396b(a)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text> 
<quoted-block style="traditional" id="H591A6B621095403B9CB6369309CF229C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="HF1D2114A01DC413FA3032F2EEDB112A2" indent="up1"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for calendar quarters beginning during the 5-year period beginning on or after the date of the enactment of this subparagraph, 90 percent of the sums expended during the quarter as are attributable to the design, development, implementation, or improvement of infrastructure and systems carried out for purposes of, with respect to behavioral health services and substance abuse treatment services, providing for enhanced data collection and reporting to the Secretary and tracking and ensuring access to such services by individuals eligible to receive medical assistance under the State plan under this title (or under a waiver of the plan); plus </text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAE66A429D7F6456B8542219EC07F2511"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each year during which subparagraph (I) of section 1903(a)(3) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396b">42 U.S.C. 1396b(a)(3)</external-xref>), as added by paragraph (1), applies, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to Congress a report on the affects of such subparagraph, including best practices for States receiving reimbursement for expenditures under such subparagraph and the effectiveness of such expenditures made by such States.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEBDB4393B41546E0B7B7F755564C7C4D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Behavioral health information for Medicaid beneficiaries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3C9AB923D6F1481D8DE43713564A4F78" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H310B691F3ECD43EC99D6B5694AC436A6"><enum>1947.</enum><header>Behavioral health information for Medicaid beneficiaries</header> <subsection id="H1DD96E31D90E4A02B9714AA6C3375045"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text>The Secretary shall award grants to States to enable such States to establish, expand, or provide support for—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5DF9FDCE37AA412E84D951C5A43055B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>offices of behavioral health assistance that provide assistance to individuals eligible to receive medical assistance under this title; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H561B3732C2C4470CAEEC77B0BA2EB669"><enum>(2)</enum><text>behavioral health ombudsman programs that are independent of any State agency,</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">in a manner that ensures coordination with other relevant programs of the State for assisting individuals receiving medical assistance under this title who have a broad range of health concerns, including relating to behavioral health and substance abuse treatment. </continuation-text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1D159631D8B543AFBFEB8101F8088F01"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header> 
<paragraph id="HA415425131E049CE8BF99058BFE8A4DB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a grant, a State shall designate an independent office of behavioral health assistance described in paragraph (1) of subsection (a), or an ombudsman described in paragraph (2) of such subsection, that—</text> <subparagraph id="H49C5E1A1E8DA4A458BF4E2D844E181F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has specialized knowledge of behavioral health and substance abuse and experience resolving inquiries and complaints described in subparagraph (B); and </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB91D45A268C548D48CE123BB486322BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>directly or in coordination with State Medicaid agencies, departments of insurance, and consumer assistance organizations, receives and responds to inquiries and complaints concerning access to behavioral health services and substance abuse treatment services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H71043408E4A34909901022D09B2D3AF2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>A State that receives a grant under this section shall comply with criteria established by the Secretary for carrying out activities under such grant.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H72C1ED9767FE45A691BD0B73E633F11D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Additional requirement</header><text>A State that receives a grant under this section, with respect to an office described in subsection (a)(1) or a behavioral health ombudsman program described in subsection (a)(2), shall coordinate such office or program with other programs of such State that serve individuals receiving medical assistance under this title, such as a consumer assistance program, long-term care ombudsman program, aging and disability resource center, a Medicaid managed care ombudsman program, or a mental health ombudsman program.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H06D9D2EA682B4435BB8F400167ADB48F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text>A grant provided to a State under subsection (a) may be used by the State to expand a program of such State that services individuals receiving medical assistance, such as a program described in paragraph (3), to include an office or program described in subsection (a) or a division that would provide for the functions that such an office or program would otherwise provide.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF94065BB7F8040A7A4FA7EA7D1C90DDB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The office of behavioral health assistance described in paragraph (1) of subsection (a), or an ombudsman referred to in paragraph (2) of such subsection shall—</text> <paragraph id="H87460AB1A1824897BAEEF35DB46419F0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>collect, track, and quantify problems and inquiries encountered by individuals eligible for medical assistance under this title with respect to access to behavioral health services and substance abuse treatment services;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE831B4FE171C43199573EFB9E02CB036"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">educate such individuals on the rights and responsibilities of such individuals with respect to such access and assist such individuals in the enforcement of such rights with respects to such access; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H06F195A8A2AD4E4DB3D77ECCC414252B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assist such individuals with accessing behavioral health services and substance abuse treatment services by providing information, referral, care coordination, and other assistance.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2E99FC41C82E43CF9957D33583A1E2CD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Data Collection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a condition of receiving a grant under subsection (a), an office of behavioral health assistance described in paragraph (1) of subsection (a), or an ombudsman described in paragraph (2) of such subsection shall be required to collect and report data to the Secretary, State legislature, relevant State agencies, including the departments of insurance and the State attorney general, on the types of problems and inquiries encountered by individuals with respect to access to behavioral health services and substance abuse treatment services. </text></subsection> <subsection id="H970FE73AEF324EA88EAA921788FBA26F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the data collected under subsection (d).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7772ACE32AC543BB92BC4AEBD5352A1D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Funding</header> 
<paragraph id="H7DECBB81C0B74951AAA302C8025AD1F8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial funding</header><text>There is hereby appropriated to the Secretary, out of any funds in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $30,000,000 for the first fiscal year for which this section applies to carry out this section. Such amount shall remain available without fiscal year limitation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H450E1EF2CC924B2A9F8FAF42C7859AA2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization for subsequent years</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for each fiscal year following the fiscal year described in paragraph (1), such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H57B87434AC47406484FCDF3F1544954F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>State Medicaid agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>State Medicaid agency</term> means the State agency administering the State plan under this title (or a waiver of such plan).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

