<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H73857DAFB09A4316AA4EDE3C3E361A7C" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4707 IH: Procure PGMS For Israel Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4707</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171221">December 21, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Brendan F. Boyle of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000560">Mr. Graves of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize a joint assessment of quantity of precision guided munitions for use by Israel, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H6010CC9960934CA3986962D9B613EB53" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE234E983721D41A0924D8B4137998DA7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Procure PGMS For Israel Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H28CF83AD0BA8461C8FA833253191E5E8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HF9571F439FCA4E0EB58F558B3063D13F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Hezbollah constitutes a major threat.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H71462974DBAC458AA7DBE883BEC008EA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Israel uses precision guided munitions to save civilian lives.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1180B40F7B804278AECCF5D2D7D17C12"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress authorized the War Reserves Stockpile-Israel primarily for use by United States Armed Forces to address regional contingencies.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7C36D75BF3BC4AF081C043F4AE165E95"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Israeli supplies of precision guided munitions dwindled during the 2006 Lebanon War.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0825A5028C6C4AD6B70636D42A99F7C6"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Given the enhanced threat of Hezbollah to Israel, there is a need to ensure the War Reserves Stock Allies-Israel is sufficiently large to meet the threat while ensuring adequate supplies for the United States.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HB5CF44686ED4427E88CC6D57173C83C5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Joint assessment of quantity of precision guided munitions for use by Israel</header>
 <subsection id="H47BCB5F30A024EA5AD8BB0ECACEBF064"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President, acting through the Secretary of Defense, is authorized to conduct a joint assessment with the Government of Israel with respect to the matters described in subsection (b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8556A241D4CB4A59AE63A742232B7A21"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters described</header><text>The matters described in this subsection are the following:</text> <paragraph id="H3C860BBDE9AE49BEABCD3E7FF5FC59EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The quantity and type of precision guided munitions that are necessary for Israel to combat Hezbollah in the event of a sustained armed confrontation between Israel and Hezbollah.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3C950CBC73D6404996B90D0C1146E589"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The plan of the Government of Israel to acquire such precision guided munitions.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3B376413C88F40F3A5FE15657F8177CB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The role of the United States to assist the Government of Israel in carrying out the plan described in paragraph (2), if any.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3134DB060C3445E89DC6D1ABEEB21B8C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 15 days after the date on which the joint assessment authorized under subsection (a) is completed, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that contains the joint assessment.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HD8AEFFE89C4B4469837A12243514F304"><enum>4.</enum><header>Amendment to Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2005</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 12001 of the Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/287">Public Law 108–287</external-xref>; 118 Stat. 1011) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0F769210772540EAA1F508696B503905"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(2), by inserting <quote>(other than precision guided munitions)</quote> after <quote>and other munitions</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3C68DC2FDAFE46728354D2AC29FF8928"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by striking <quote>this section</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (a)</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC5E29F81E5F842289F28F0D59547FE52"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (d) as subsection (e); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6FD021C733424ADFA248C7BE5EFE3090"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (c) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H29AC9686687849AA899EA2AF9E805C0F" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H78BBA0519F4A4B2BB99EB892EB72F4EB"><enum>(d)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H92F93CB4C0714121844FC4387E4DBC08"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Notwithstanding section 514 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2321h">22 U.S.C. 2321h</external-xref>), the President is authorized to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBB76205DF3E148BEBD33E3AB96653F03" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>add precision guided munitions to reserve stocks for Israel; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED88D3A3F1784ACA8554A2D3474F60DC" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">transfer precision guided munitions from reserve stocks for Israel to or for use by the Government of Israel for the purpose of assisting Israel defend itself against rockets fired by Hezbollah or other terrorist organizations within the prior 30 days and with the likely possibility of a sustained conflict between Hezbollah and Israel.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA955E13258F4795B76D212772439D8B" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 5 days before making a transfer under paragraph (1), the President shall certify to the Committees on Foreign Relations and Armed Services of the Senate and the Committees on Foreign Affairs and Armed Services of the House of Representatives that the transfer of the precision guided munitions—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9DBB1A4DE35F46AD85A24ECB87E0C5D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>meets the requirements described in paragraph (1)(B);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05225FD64F3748D491D70131950824A8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not affect the ability of the United States to maintain a sufficient supply of precision guided munitions; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F3995C9754F434BB52F2B417FCAC602"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not harm the combat readiness of the United States or the ability of the United States to meet its commitment to allies for the sale of such munitions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H39C088D14E1D4ED5ACA817310B3C20F4"><enum>5.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that Department of Defense should work with the defense industrial base to ensure it is able to produce precision guided munitions with greater rapidity in order to resupply United States efforts to combat the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant (ISIL) and to assist allies such as Israel in their fight against Hezbollah.</text>
		</section><section id="H10E7F279658440719BA2E82D36D71942"><enum>6.</enum><header>Modification of rapid acquisition and deployment procedures</header>
			<subsection id="H2CFAED6CE39641179623B06DD5FBD119"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement To establish procedures</header>
 <paragraph id="HF57EE01EB07F4D34AA369A771554B036"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 806(a) of the Bob Stump National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/2302">10 U.S.C. 2302</external-xref> note; 116 Stat. 2607) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDE9B79115F1346EC8D408871BFC3FDC7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(C), by striking <quote>; and</quote> at the end;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D8038D457F446608AC5BC8A36806670"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BC8F1E36B3D4BF89BB740F731367FB1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H90D8F588C06A4254AD47A19932651C96" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H5D9AB41251144C9EB98A1F4A13541B6C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">urgently needed to support production of precision guided munitions—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1314C192180E4D5EB2E5B6146780F67D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for United States counterterrorism missions; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H48755A27FC0140E2814A0164F5D4E481"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to assist an ally of the United States under direct missile threat from an organization the Secretary of State has designated as a foreign terrorist organization pursuant to section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H56F16B656257474F966AB01280AD1D2F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prescription of procedures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe procedures for the rapid acquisition and deployment of supplies and associated support services for purposes described in paragraph (3) of section 806(a) of the Bob Stump National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2003, as added by paragraph (1) of this subsection, not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H618BA4BCA8A74AE681F7BED22A3CD9D7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of amounts in Special Defense Acquisition Fund</header><text>Section 114(c)(3) of title 10, United States Code, is amended by inserting at the end before the period the following: <quote>or to assist an ally of the United States that is under direct missile threat, including from a terrorist organization supported by Iran, and such threat adversely affects the safety and security of such ally</quote>.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


