<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1A925941029046BBB17F2761AEA149C3" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1899 IH: Protecting Data at the Border Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1899</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170404">April 4, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000460">Mr. Farenthold</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To ensure the digital contents of electronic equipment and online accounts belonging to or in the
			 possession of United States persons entering or exiting the United States
			 are adequately protected at the border, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H20BFFFA242F946828C0FB57741ECE800" style="OLC">
 <section id="H2F5FF076C8EB4DCB82551F706F9374E3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Data at the Border Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H4FDE0053975D4CBCACFF4D402922DC4B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H7D6C647BD9444808819A2DBA0D05712B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>United States persons have a reasonable expectation of privacy in the digital contents of their electronic equipment, the digital contents of<short-title><?xm-replace_text Type new short-title here ?></short-title> their online accounts, and the nature of their online presence.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HADBA11679D7E4F9EB2BDC41D939ED8D3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Supreme Court of the United States recognized in Riley v. California, 134 S. Ct. 2473 (2014) the extraordinary privacy interests in electronic equipment like cell phones.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAFA6793043264B65BD1AC781319FC0F0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The privacy interest of United States persons in the digital contents of their electronic equipment, the digital contents of their online accounts, and the nature of their online presence differs in both degree and kind from their privacy interest in closed containers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7D364E2213394756A8B05A5ADB5E43F5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Accessing the digital contents of electronic equipment, accessing the digital contents of an online account, or obtaining information regarding the nature of the online presence of a United States person entering or exiting the United States, without a lawful warrant based on probable cause, is unreasonable under the Fourth Amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H75D40088CA784B0A996F0AEA18496A5E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Scope</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to—</text> <paragraph id="H828241D68E054B45B48E32286A3F0AFE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prohibit a Governmental entity from conducting an inspection of the external physical components of the electronic equipment to determine the presence or absence of weapons or contraband without a warrant, including activating or attempting to activate an object that appears to be electronic equipment to verify that the object is electronic equipment; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9C35FF0BEE24470591D92DDDCAE53E69"><enum>(2)</enum><text>limit the authority of a Governmental entity under the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1801">50 U.S.C. 1801</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H88E76AA44DC14AF6A6C102253F863487"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">As used in this Act—</text> <paragraph id="H9561FF59761D45F9B95A897AE94B12F1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>access credential</term> includes a username, password, PIN number, fingerprint, or biometric indicator;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6AD9B5065A26454DB64D8C5AC126A5E7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>border</term> means the international border of the United States and the functional equivalent of such border;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE9BEBCC20364300B4E0F64677140E2E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>digital contents</term> means any signs, signals, writing, images, sounds, data, or intelligence of any nature transmitted in whole or in part by electronic equipment, or stored in electronic equipment or an online account;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2F18E9A83D6D47DBAFED0BC823122568"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>electronic communication service</term> has the meaning given that term in section 2510 of title 18, United States Code;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H61C947F7965145038951D01B27465847"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>electronic equipment</term> has the meaning given the term <term>computer</term> in section 1030(e) of title 18, United States Code;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H06CDE7383A1B4C2CAFD7395815BBBCEA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the term <term>Governmental entity</term> means a department or agency of the United States (including any officer, employee, or contractor or other agent thereof);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H36DAEF853B504569AA32A7CD17EBD611"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the term <term>online account</term> means an online account with an electronic communication service or remote computing service;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD8E4F349B7654246AB0FB01C43226FF8"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the term <term>online account information</term> means the screen name or other identifier or information that would allow a Governmental entity to identify the online presence of an individual;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5C42ACD8003641858FCFB95A1B15CA6C"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the term <term>remote computing service</term> has the meaning given that term in section 2711 of title 18, United States Code; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H50CFF35B46B8434F98D157CF89F08D8A"><enum>(10)</enum><text>the term <term>United States person</term> means an individual who is a United States person, as defined in section 101 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1801">50 U.S.C. 1801</external-xref>).</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H80F8DF22FA0047DFB8A478526816218B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Procedures for lawful access to digital data at the border</header>
 <subsection id="H702C1AE8AC4D43E492991555EA3AFCA8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Standard</header><text>Subject to subsection (b), a Governmental entity may not—</text> <paragraph id="H0F72DC4AEDFF4668A8D316B7D4FA73E7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>access the digital contents of any electronic equipment belonging to or in the possession of a United States person at the border without a valid warrant supported by probable cause issued using the procedures described in the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure by a court of competent jurisdiction;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H596EBD90C6CB46ED98EA61F602672D2D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>deny entry into or exit from the United States by a United States person based on a refusal by the United States person to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF8AB49894A974BEEB71D761EA4816CD9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>disclose an access credential that would enable access to the digital contents of electronic equipment or the digital contents of an online account;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF968D08DAE84FABA861BF21A1F7C1C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide access to the digital contents of electronic equipment or the digital contents of an online account; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB591E702861C47EDBF9AE10A094A8299"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide online account information; or</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2809DCEB7C8942B9959E81388F44E4A3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>delay entry into or exit from the United States by a United States person for longer than the period of time, which may not exceed 4 hours, necessary to determine whether the United States person will, in a manner in accordance with subsection (c), consensually provide an access credential, access, or online account information, as described in subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) of paragraph (2).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC35BF9373AF243E4B38385C4AE76A990"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Emergency exceptions</header>
				<paragraph id="H06BA85686E0C4D0C91C66014C4C242EE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Emergency situations generally</header>
 <subparagraph id="H6C153BE618B048309C4B318011DCF2A5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An investigative or law enforcement officer of a Governmental entity who is designated by the Secretary of Homeland Security for purposes of this paragraph may access the digital contents of electronic equipment belonging to or in possession of a United States person at the border without a warrant described in subsection (a)(1) if the investigative or law enforcement officer—</text>
 <clause id="H86F0DB59274145A4816156171FF0959A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>reasonably determines that—</text> <subclause id="H1BF3126A687F459888348017DA5ECAEA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an emergency situation exists that involves—</text>
 <item id="HB01FF1AA75B44858B49DD13828BCB0B0"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>immediate danger of death or serious physical injury to any person;</text> </item><item id="H1729A52B51A943749A658E1CC59333B8"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>conspiratorial activities threatening the national security interest of the United States; or</text>
 </item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBE67C9E051494A93A4CDD2DBED729A3C"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>conspiratorial activities characteristic of organized crime;</text> </item></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H76A04A3DCD0F4B1CBB87F591F5E88CCD"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the emergency situation described in subclause (I) requires access to the digital contents of the electronic equipment before a warrant described in subsection (a)(1) authorizing such access can, with due diligence, be obtained; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HF2F762E5A66F48CDBB2ED0385808A66B"><enum>(III)</enum><text>there are grounds upon which a warrant described in subsection (a)(1) could be issued authorizing such access; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H0FD7634A3C8443C69B000DDD77538050"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>makes an application in accordance with this section for a warrant described in subsection (a)(1) as soon as practicable, but not later than 7 days after the investigative or law enforcement officer accesses the digital contents under the authority under this subparagraph.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F9E2BB7A5C142F2A3FC414CE1E70FA4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Warrant not obtained</header><text>If an application for a warrant described in subparagraph (A)(ii) is denied, or in any other case in which an investigative or law enforcement officer accesses the digital contents of electronic equipment belonging to or in possession of a United States person at the border without a warrant under the emergency authority under subparagraph (A) and a warrant authorizing the access is not obtained—</text>
 <clause id="HBBF834B63A3D4D348BB483A6D17799C8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any copy of the digital contents in the custody or control of a Governmental entity shall immediately be destroyed;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF9CCCBF77A424011ABC828D5F9B04BB4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the digital contents, and any information derived from the digital contents, may not be disclosed to any Governmental entity or a State or local government; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H77F96707D0E847B2A970BCC4148CB426"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Governmental entity employing the investigative or law enforcement officer that accessed the digital contents shall notify the United States person that any copy of the digital contents has been destroyed.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H226FDD42FB1F44DFA5F6F615593B98A0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Protection of public safety and health</header><text>A Governmental entity may access the digital contents of electronic equipment belonging to or in possession of a United States person at the border without a warrant described in subsection (a)(1) if the access is—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDE2242AAB8BD47218ECB68AE4B36AF66"><enum>(A)</enum><text>necessary for the provision of fire, medical, public safety, or other emergency services; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E8963B2415644538D681233895130B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>unrelated to the investigation of a possible crime or other violation of the law.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H58537A89D75A4DB897DBC4B7318DEA55"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Informed consent in writing</header>
				<paragraph id="H17ACB11FFC194046AF2371791A289D9A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice</header>
 <subparagraph id="H21FC4B4AEFB7488F9729EC8EF045FB01"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A Governmental entity shall provide the notice described in subparagraph (B) before requesting that a United States person at the border—</text>
 <clause id="HECDC76C1BEBA4C91821BC0DD360FE985"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide consent to access the digital contents of any electronic equipment belonging to or in the possession of or the digital contents of an online account of the United States person;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7758483188374809856D7FE2BF321005"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>disclose an access credential that would enable access to the digital contents of electronic equipment or the digital contents of an online account of the United States Person;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H926D10922C664B85AFA8ADB0848C060C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provide access to the digital contents of electronic equipment or the digital contents of an online account of the United States Person; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H899D0997DCF64262931540CE0F5603EB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>provide online account information of the United States Person.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0A5BB9D84D90411C9E349AD28C17984D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The notice described in this subparagraph is written notice in a language understood by the United States person that the Governmental entity—</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H273A6EF722BB4826BBB89845A1C5EAF3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>may not—</text> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2CF5313A5E3444E9BF44C167F89164A5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>compel access to the digital contents of electronic equipment belonging to or in the possession of, the digital contents of an online account of, or the online account information of a United States person without a valid warrant;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H0DE1FE713DF04C669CDF5F2F2EBE6B09"><enum>(II)</enum><text>deny entry into or exit from the United States by the United States person based on a refusal by the United States person to—</text>
 <item id="HE1157C0516374CE18E880A4E1551348C"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>disclose an access credential that would enable access to the digital contents of electronic equipment or the digital contents of an online account;</text>
 </item><item id="H90E3944F7C434D3D8D59878751A219E8"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>provide access to the digital contents of electronic equipment or the digital contents of an online account; or</text>
 </item><item id="H684A8522EB384D32880A2159A07D0275"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>provide online account information; or</text> </item></subclause><subclause id="HB869638D8D6A4E34B6162BC36C8F166E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>delay entry into or exit from the United States by the United States person for longer than the period of time, which may not exceed 4 hours, necessary to determine whether the United States person will consensually provide an access credential, access, or online account information, as described in items (aa), (bb), and (cc) of subclause (II); and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H40576114AFD94598B1F148B4BB81CF94"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the Governmental entity has probable cause that the electronic equipment contains information that is relevant to an allegation that the United States person has committed a felony, may seize electronic equipment belonging to or in the possession of the United States person for a period of time if the United States person refuses to consensually provide access to the digital contents of the electronic equipment.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D89CEB15B2D4AA196F17F37C6E532BE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consent</header>
 <subparagraph id="H5F2AEB180833424FA8B4A850653A5F07"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A Governmental entity shall obtain written consent described in subparagraph (B) before—</text> <clause id="H2456267B65F84949A87B3E2838E7D870"><enum>(i)</enum><text>accessing, pursuant to the consent of a United States person at the border the digital contents of electronic equipment belonging to or in the possession of or the digital contents of an online account of the United States person;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA6F285FDFD4141249A4252F52389DD09"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>obtaining, pursuant to the consent of a United States person at the border, an access credential of the United States person that would enable access to the digital contents of electronic equipment or the digital contents of an online account; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE02F698C631147C29B5206C57BABEEC7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>obtaining, pursuant to the consent of a United States person at the border, online account information for an online account of the United States person.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC607D747AE544268F52607A57BE705F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents of written consent</header><text>Written consent described in this subparagraph is written consent that—</text> <clause id="H24EE0221053B43C3982AD22486AB4F96"><enum>(i)</enum><text>indicates the United States person understands the protections and limitations described in paragraph (1)(B);</text>
 </clause><clause id="H87BD1F6E9B5A4EC59B29D61229B3639D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>states the United States person is—</text> <subclause id="H3E7014DB00714E94BFE570BD8E218793"><enum>(I)</enum><text>providing consent to the Governmental entity to access certain digital contents or consensually disclosing an access credential; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H4A5157181BEA465C9C7E4C4242C6B916"><enum>(II)</enum><text>consensually providing online account information; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H6021CCA4260E46DE98E92B9DAA5595A5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>specifies the digital contents, access credential, or online account information with respect to which the United States person is providing consent.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9B2C62F16BAC40E08E1939F03D0510A5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Retention of digital contents</header>
 <paragraph id="H3F02ABA971824975A915ED156C2B586D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Lawful access</header><text>A Governmental entity that obtains access to the digital contents of electronic equipment, the digital contents of an online account, or online account information in accordance with this section may not make or retain a copy of the digital contents or online account information, or any information directly or indirectly derived from the digital contents or online account information, unless there is probable cause to believe the digital contents or online account information contains evidence of, or constitutes the fruits of, a crime.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC63DEC24DD144BEB0A0A15E735BE0A6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Unlawful access</header><text>If a Governmental entity obtains access to the digital contents of electronic equipment, digital contents of an online account, or online account information in a manner that is not in accordance with this section, the Governmental entity—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2EE90E6A65D645A08A855A6252A13C60"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall immediately destroy any copy of the digital contents or online account information, and any information directly or indirectly derived from the digital contents or online account information, in the custody or control of the Governmental entity;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6B0F9EDDCB242788841C04F9564AAC0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may not disclose the digital contents or online account information, or any information directly or indirectly derived from the digital contents or online account information, to any other Governmental entity or a State or local government; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H63279B24B73A4C668953C510193AA83B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>shall notify the United States person that any copy of the digital contents or online account information, and any information directly or indirectly derived from the digital contents or online account information, has been destroyed.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H361BD94DEFA84A1993F9A7FFCC3C763E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Recordkeeping</header><text>A Governmental entity shall keep a record of each instance in which the Governmental entity obtains access to the digital contents of electronic equipment belonging to or in the possession of an individual at the border, the digital contents of an online account of an individual who is at the border, or online account information of an individual who is at the border, which shall include—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0925C8CE98EB48508D6390B04363A460"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the reason for the access;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6E39C22E8E91484D9BE8F2C20469D899"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the nationality, immigration status, and admission category of the individual;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H294E26845A3D4CDFACA5D581A3BE5190"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the nature and extent of the access;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6799507BA4204643BAB8A1DFC03A2C78"><enum>(4)</enum><text>if the access was consensual, how and to what the individual consented, and what the individual provided by consent;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0FF2A0E6A65F475790BE91426ACDE6B8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>whether electronic equipment of the individual was seized;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2F4A7D991C06415FB71D39B88477F8FD"><enum>(6)</enum><text>whether the Governmental entity made a copy of all or a portion of the digital contents or online account information, or any information directly or indirectly derived from the digital contents or online account information; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H42F7BE47EED14B8B94609FE4B91E35C0"><enum>(7)</enum><text>whether the digital contents or online account information, or any information directly or indirectly derived from the digital contents or online account information, was shared with another Governmental entity or a State or local government.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1C9148EED89F445895F5CC7EC5E41846"><enum>6.</enum><header>Limits on use of digital contents as evidence</header>
 <subsection id="HABF1E0B9E6274AF8916B0F3BB3B54FE0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whenever any digital contents or online account information have been obtained in violation of this Act, no part of the digital contents or online account information and no evidence derived therefrom may be received in evidence in any trial, hearing, or other proceeding (including any proceeding relating to the immigration laws, as defined in section 101(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)</external-xref>)) in or before any court, grand jury, department, officer, agency, regulatory body, legislative committee, or other authority of the United States, a State, or a political subdivision thereof.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD151206FB02E4FE6898872863DE0CC3A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To the maximum extent practicable, the limitations under subsection (a) shall be applied in the same manner as the limitations under section 2515 of title 18, United States Code.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H521C7459F2C24F81B883F0B909915DA8"><enum>7.</enum><header>Limits on seizure of electronic equipment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A Governmental entity may not seize any electronic equipment belonging to or in the possession of a United States person at the border unless there is probable cause to believe that the electronic equipment contains information that is relevant to an allegation that the United States person has committed a felony.</text>
 </section><section id="H0D242E54B8654E59A52F3B7602A0E587"><enum>8.</enum><header>Audit and reporting requirements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In March of each year, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to Congress and make publicly available on the Web site of the Department of Homeland Security a report that includes the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H7DB94FEBCF814470A5AE32743F2BC6F4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of times during the previous year that an officer or employee of the Department of Homeland Security did each of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H58B1F258ADA54684A2DEB7C9620B1DE1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Accessed the digital contents of any electronic equipment belonging to or in the possession of or the digital contents of an online account of a United States person at the border pursuant to a warrant supported by probable cause issued using the procedures described in the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure by a court of competent jurisdiction.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7FE9D75F64864FAF9DD2B0D8862C608E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Accessed the digital contents of any electronic equipment belonging to or in the possession of a United States person at the border pursuant to the emergency authority under section 5(b).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A925F2DC817481A870598090EE74462"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Requested consent to access the digital contents of any electronic equipment belonging to or in the possession of, the digital contents of an online account of, or online account information of a United States person at the border.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDAE2B5EED6FE49BE8FBD038182F96664"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Accessed the digital contents of any electronic equipment belonging to or in the possession of, the digital contents of an online account of, or online account information of a United States person at the border pursuant to written consent provided in accordance with section 5(c).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6E1C0380F7E143559C80861AE12729FB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Requested a United States person at the border consensually disclose an access credential that would enable access to the digital contents of electronic equipment or the digital contents of an online account of the United States person.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8F4F5F2B21A54A1E915C4151A882ACFD"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Accessed the digital contents of electronic equipment or the digital contents of an online account of a United States person at the border using an access credential pursuant to written consent provided in accordance with section 5(c).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7C3C3FD40782400B9B0404E4BC36D87C"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Accessed the digital contents of any electronic equipment belonging to or in the possession of, the digital contents of an online account of, or online account information of a United States person at the border in a manner that was not in accordance with section 5.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEEF353C61ACB47AC8C71B2ECB6AD12BB"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Accessed the digital contents of any electronic equipment belonging to or in the possession of, the digital contents of an online account of, or online account information of an individual who is not a United States person at the border.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4F42C08A7B23468EB693BF31F6433D2A"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Accessed the digital contents of any electronic equipment belonging to or in the possession of an individual at the border, the digital contents of an online account of an individual at the border, or online account information of an individual at the border (regardless of whether the individual is a United States person) at the request of a Governmental entity (including another component of the Department of Homeland Security) that is not the Governmental entity employing the individual accessing the digital contents or online account information.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2CC68C6D3DDF4253897E4ABEA5A682A1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Aggregate data on—</text> <subparagraph id="HD91C18DA360448D99A80D06CD79E1514"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of United States persons for which a Governmental entity obtains access to—</text>
 <clause id="HDA4A701B37A2440184037AA83443D344"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the digital contents of electronic equipment belonging to or in the possession of the United States person at the border;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H45D4643F37584EDC80EFCBA05BC444AF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the digital contents of an online account of the United States person while at the border; or</text> </clause><clause id="H730A2EB8AC884D73A2253AE18A0E1A7F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>online account information of the United States person while at the border;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA294729AEDD644FFAD2D959F511EE41B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the country from which United States persons departed most recently before arriving in the United States for the United States persons for which a Governmental entity obtains access to—</text>
 <clause id="H8B813958EF704CA5BE2D84E18847EE34"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the digital contents of electronic equipment belonging to or in the possession of the United States person at the border;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3AC9046CE32A419393E63ABFDD3B8BB1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the digital contents of an online account of the United States person while at the border; or</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H91121DC049C54D7299B619627D6DE3B5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>online account information of the United States person while at the border;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7AB9AEE81A544FCBA8A92964F5B864DE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number and nationality of individuals who are not United States persons for which a Governmental entity obtains access to—</text>
 <clause id="H443289A208CB40149F0A1BBBA2A6CBA4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the digital contents of electronic equipment belonging to or in the possession of the individuals at the border;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDE709BBB79244D708698C7F34E8A4236"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the digital contents of an online account of the individuals while at the border; or</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H48194EB37DCE48E78233F4B049818555"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>online account information of the individuals while at the border; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5AAB61888A647879BEDDE97757656FC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the country from which individuals who are not United States persons departed most recently before arriving in the United States for the individuals for which a Governmental entity obtains access to—</text>
 <clause id="HD550FB57A93A4082915C9DCCCE06B9D7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the digital contents of electronic equipment belonging to or in the possession of the individuals at the border;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC30687362FF843A59559A2DF7F8C3B32"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the digital contents of an online account of the individuals while at the border; or</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H50E902901B4D412284C35208942B3D94"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>online account information of the individuals while at the border.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE201AF67AFA243DCABCCFED635BAF5F2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Aggregate data regarding the perceived race and ethnicity of individuals for whom Governmental entity obtains access to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H038C799243324268A0B4E35DE14C704E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the digital contents of electronic equipment belonging to or in the possession of the individuals at the border;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H612B46B9D36448F8A9D51CE2EB7BCEA5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the digital contents of an online account of the individuals while at the border; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H07DD2A6943C747D394591BD401C81A23"><enum>(C)</enum><text>online account information of the individuals while at the border.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


