<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H86A2E9A74EFF483F863FA9BB6DCA50DB" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3961 IH: Kissimmee River Wild and Scenic River Study Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3961</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171004">October 4, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate segments of the Kissimmee River and its
			 tributaries in the State of Florida for study for potential addition to
			 the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HD8A747B876C8408D8C65EEFCEED8C16E" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE0E74DB281404B4FBF157B0110B1379A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Kissimmee River Wild and Scenic River Study Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H533D36817C9E41AB8E20B16CE3AAEE54" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H5F179BE55B9F43A9992F11F8A68C5051"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Kissimmee River has undergone, over the course of two decades, the largest river restoration effort in the world.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H66F95D0DCDEC45E2A69FB5ACCFF8BF25"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Extending approximately 105 miles from Orlando to Lake Okeechobee, the Kissimmee River forms the headwaters of Lake Okeechobee and the Everglades and serves as a vital component of ecosystem restoration in South Florida as a whole.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H22FA12CF2F3C4755ABFB4687978A3B3A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Kissimmee River Restoration Project has significantly improved approximately 63,000 acres of wetlands within the Kissimmee River watershed and reestablished an environment suitable for fish, wildlife, and the wetland plants that existed prior to the Kissimmee River’s channelization in the 1960s.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4C4D46A7C4B946BDBDF8EA9AD9F67F9E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Kissimmee River Restoration Project is expected to be completed in 2020, at which point it is expected to reestablish historic hydrologic conditions, recreate historic river and floodplain con­nect­i­vi­ty, recreate the historic mosaic of wetland plant communities, and restore historic biological diversity and functionality.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3868D612D83142079252F8CDBA691556"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After decades of restoration efforts and the expenditure of nearly a billion dollars, upon completion of the Kissimmee River Restoration Project, a study should be conducted to determine the eligibility of including the fully restored Kissimmee River into the National Wild and Scenic River program to preserve the fully restored free-flowing condition and immediate environment of the river for the benefit and enjoyment of present and future generations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2A472FD8859C43C080C131CE11EC025D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Inclusion of the Kissimmee River into the National Wild and Scenic River program would be a fitting tribute to the hard work of the Army Corps of Engineers and the South Florida Water Management District’s restoration work.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H8609FDCBA2024D60BC8AC7D9B9BB0AD9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Designation for study</header>
 <subsection id="H8EEAA34DCC3D4165A3187ABF30BFD9B0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation for potential addition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5(a) of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1276">16 U.S.C. 1276(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8BE771D1687344898E26E2A2E437BB97" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H1F115F84B91C4507BE93E651D939A1CF"><enum>(__)</enum><header>Kissimmee River, Florida</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment from the southern shore of Lake Kissimmee to its confluence with Lake Okeechobee.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="HA79052CDF68745DBBAFDA4311075A968"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5(b) of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1276">16 U.S.C. 1276(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAEB5BB7DCAC447609B8E157F951D963D" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="HFE90B80DD33C4D5B99ECF18FA2FCDDDD"><enum>(__)</enum><header>Kissimmee River, Florida</header>
 <subparagraph id="H60C240F0E5304E32A496D9BEEA5A98F9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date on which funds are made available to carry out this paragraph, the Secretary of the Interior shall complete a study of the Kissimmee River, as described in subsection (a)(__), and submit a report describing the results of such study to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F453E57C44B4450AF25247B6BEA452E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required under subparagraph (A) shall—</text> <clause id="HBC74F4B7E0064D8FAE24F0356AB68646"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include a discussion of the effect of the designation of the segment to be studied under subsection (a)(__) on—</text>
 <subclause id="H399C4DAFC3D24B3EA303E23F0310D00C"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">existing commercial and recreational activities, such as cattle ranching, dairy production, hunting, fishing, trapping, recreational shooting, motor boat use, or bridge construction;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H51A0463C5C73456C871012C2FD9B01BA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the authorization, construction, operation, maintenance, or improvement of energy production and transmission infrastructure; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H2EF558E215924286A323729B6B99804B"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the authority of State and local governments to manage the activities described in subclauses (I) and (II); and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="HC30CCAEA34B64DF3A1156B935A7F4E7E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify—</text> <subclause commented="no" id="HF3CA956214B54AC99FD884778B023DFC"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all authorities that will authorize or require the Secretary of the Interior to influence local land use decisions (such as zoning) or place restrictions on non-Federal land if the area studied under subsection (a)(__) is designated under the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H65DC292192DE43FF9653E8094410624E"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all authorities that the Secretary of the Interior may use to condemn property if the area studied under subsection (a)(__) is designated under the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H6EA7D208BA4F4FEBAA01A1FBE5434827"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all private property located in the area to be studied under subsection (a)(__).</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97F7338B3E6D4804BA5985833CD4D2D6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Noninterference</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This study shall not interfere with the Kissimmee River Restoration Project authorized under section 101(8) of the Water Resources Development Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/102/580">Public Law 102–580</external-xref>).</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


