<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H164F66CA87254F7DA4FC096BF7A531BB" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1742 IH: Article V Records Transparency Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1742</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170327">March 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001189">Mr. Messer</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Archivist of the United States to compile all applications, and rescissions of
			 applications, made to the Congress to call a convention, pursuant to
			 article V of the Constitution, and certain related materials, and to
			 transmit them to Congress, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H175B6645F1E04101B506A876EE78C17B" style="OLC">
 <section id="H351F482DCFAD43419830C86DA6AF7E18" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Article V Records Transparency Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HFD022752A6DF475C9766B7D1EBD57B09"><enum>2.</enum><header>Compilation and transmission to Congress of applications and rescissions of applications to call a convention for proposing amendments to the Constitution and rescissions of those applications</header> <subsection id="HE5A48C9282BF4D389566854B91B6D139"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Compilation and transmission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Archivist of the United States (hereinafter in this Act referred to as the <quote>Archivist</quote>) shall, in accordance with this Act—</text>
 <paragraph id="H462CE4E9C5E24E95893E72EB2C019CA5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>make an organized compilation, to the extent feasible, of all applications and rescissions of applications, ever made by States under article V of the Constitution, to call a convention for proposing amendments to the Constitution; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H51C62C00FE054DE2BF7F5616CFBC550D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>transmit to Congress and transmit to the chairmen of the Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and Senate that compilation, together with both physical and electronic copies of each such application and rescission.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2F50B9D368264B5B94FC4682CF8CCC48"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sources for compilation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In complying with subsection (a) the Archivist shall use the records contained in the National Archive and Records Administration, and take other appropriate action, including using outside resources, to obtain an official copy of any application or rescission that may not be in such records.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7063D98D1A32457F8518869842799060"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Timing of transmittal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Archivist shall transmit the compilation, containing all the known applications or rescissions according to the following schedule:</text>
				<table align-to-level="section" blank-lines-before="1" colsep="1" frame="all" line-rules="all-gen" rowsep="1" rule-weights="4.4.4.4.4.0" table-template-name="Generic: 2 text, even cols" table-type="">
					<tgroup cols="2" grid-typeface="1.1" rowsep="1" thead-tbody-ldg-size="10.10.12"><colspec coldef="txt" colname="column1" colwidth="163pts" min-data-value="150"></colspec><colspec coldef="txt-no-ldr" colname="column2" colwidth="163pts" min-data-value="150"></colspec><thead>
							<row><entry align="center" colname="column1" morerows="0" namest="column1"><bold>Year After Enactment</bold></entry><entry align="center" colname="column2" morerows="0" namest="column2"><bold>Applications and Rescissions Required to be Submitted</bold></entry></row></thead>
						<tbody>
							<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" leader-modify="force-ldr-bottom" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">1 Year after enactment </entry><entry align="left" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr">Applications and rescissions 1970 and later</entry></row>
							<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" leader-modify="force-ldr-bottom" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">2 Years after enactment </entry><entry align="left" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr">Applications and rescissions 1920 through 1969</entry></row>
							<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" leader-modify="force-ldr-bottom" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">3 Years after enactment</entry><entry align="left" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr">Applications and rescissions 1870 through 1919</entry></row>
							<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" leader-modify="force-ldr-bottom" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">4 Years after enactment</entry><entry align="left" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr">Applications and rescissions 1820 through 1869</entry></row>
							<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" leader-modify="force-ldr-bottom" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1"> 5 Years after enactment</entry><entry align="left" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr">Applications and rescissions before 1820</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table>
 </subsection><subsection id="H46EAD8CDA19A444BA32549E8D5CACB07"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report on extent of missing applications or rescissions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Archivist shall submit to Congress a report detailing the extent of suspected missing applications or rescissions not included in each compilation under subsection (c), to accompany each transmittal required under subsection (c).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3038D2B0BFBF4F1795C16A512D015C5F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Cataloging applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Archivist shall, in compiling the applications and rescissions, catalog them by year of submission and State, and include that information in the material transmitted to Congress.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H04C16808AD8044CF8F8A0E6A644434D3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text>Nothing contained within the transmittal required under subsection (a) or in the report required by subsection (b) shall be considered an official source or designation of valid state applications and rescissions under article V of the Constitution.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H094C35AEA68F4E4BB245B77D4112308D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Duties of the Committees on the Judiciary</header>
 <subsection id="H01B36477C56846E7B261466F40190F6E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation of applications and rescissions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon receipt by Congress of the compilation described in section 2(a), the respective committees on the judiciary in each House of Congress shall designate the applications and rescissions contained in such compilation for public availability on a publicly accessible website not later than 6 months after receiving such compilation as required under section 2(c).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H567F22010A5C466ABEADB13D5039E521"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Continuing Designations of Applications and rescissions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The respective committees on the judiciary in each House of Congress shall update the compilation in the public websites maintained by them under subsection (a) by designating the receipt of any application or rescission submitted under article V of the Constitution to call a convention for proposing amendments to the Constitution that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H04FADF3DE0BA4993A313DB4A6982E207"><enum>(1)</enum><text>was not included in the initial compilation as transmitted under section 2; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7A6D7079DE2149EBA369E35D79AAD818"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is a new application or rescission or otherwise comes to the attention of the committee.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3388E74BA308485C85E64CACFC7734BA"><enum>4.</enum><header>Recommended procedures for transmission of applications and rescissions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress recommends the following procedures to make uniform and simplify the process by which State legislatures make an application, or a rescission of an application, under article V of the Constitution to call a convention for proposing amendments to the Constitution:</text>
 <paragraph id="H7C97B83020CE4A65AA611D954B090110"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Officers to transmit and receive applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After the adoption by the legislature of a State of an application or rescission, the secretary of state of the State, or if there be no such officer, the person who is charged by the State law with such function, should submit to Congress at least two copies of the resolution or other measure containing the application or rescission, one copy addressed to the President of the Senate, and one copy to the Speaker of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7A9A0719DF1C474CA26C58A104949E81"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents of resolution or measure</header><text>Each copy of the resolution or measure should contain—</text> <subparagraph id="HADB90CEE73E1452193C5EE8BC2585B63"><enum>(A)</enum><text>its exact text, with the authenticating signature of the relevant officer of the legislature; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB0A57AEC170464D951130F10FD61B57"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date on which the legislature adopted the resolution or measure.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H37070EE633FA4D6B9B5782323BB30E22"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Other forms of Application or recision</header><text>If a State submits an application or rescission in a manner that is inconsistent with this section, and the application or rescission does not have an authenticating signature of a member of the respective states legislature, the Clerk of the House or the Secretary of the Senate shall confirm the authenticity of the application or rescission through a search of public records. If unable to confirm through a public records search, the Clerk of the House or Secretary of the Senate shall notify the appropriate State official and request a letter from that State official, with the authenticating signature of that State official, confirming the application or rescission’s authenticity.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HF7707BF40CEC4BC1A4CF2F6D58345924"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Noncompliance with the recommendations of this section not a basis for Congress to refuse to accept
 an application or rescission</header><text>The failure of a State legislature to comply with any of the procedures recommended in this section is not a basis for a refusal by Congress to accept or count an application or rescission.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H318B03ECC957450A8B2CB7639BFC262B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be interpreted to expand in any way the specific, limited duties assigned to Congress under article V of the Constitution.</text>
 </section><section id="H3E1CD367A41A4FECABD6917784581F05"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act—</text> <paragraph id="H9806690551684FE3B00274EF70C95083"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the terms <quote>transmit to Congress</quote> and <quote>submit to Congress</quote> mean transmission or submission, as the case may be, to the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the President of the Senate;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC3F45974CBD44FE699AD5224AEFBBB2D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>application</quote> means any resolution or other measure, agreed upon by a State legislature, that purports to be a request to Congress to call a convention pursuant to article V of the Constitution; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE04B8059232142AD92020A6DBF2B98F9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>rescission</quote> means any resolution or other measure, agreed upon by a State legislature, that purports to make null and void an application previously submitted by the State legislature.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H2B915C21E88F44A0A15DD58FEF70B73A"><enum>7.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations.</header>
 <subsection id="H7CDB51FEA3C844D194C65E1FA3546F43"><enum>(a)</enum><header>For carrying out this Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the National Historical Publications and Records Commission $2,000,000 for the purposes of carrying out this act for each of the fiscal years 2018 through 2023.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H28F7A86553344CFFBD8D094AF7B072F0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Historical record grant program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2504(g)(1) of title 44, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAE69464762B446A192B2F747492383CC" style="USC"> <subparagraph id="H7241E5F6EBEA4674A87BBE444DBE651A" indent="up1"><enum>(T)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$3,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2018 through 2023.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


