<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HAA857E40BF594B008DE2B7C844FE9358" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2323 IH: San Gabriel Mountains Foothills and Rivers Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2323</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170503">May 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001150">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the San Gabriel National Recreation Area as a unit of the National Park System in the
			 State of California, to modify the boundaries of the San Gabriel Mountains
			 National Monument in the State of California to include additional
			 National Forest System land, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HFAED88A70F3049A2993C64A9ADD1D920" style="OLC">
		<section id="HD655DFC0271C4631AD90561A6BDDE5C7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="HB48526CF43DF4572B8A297E26AF5D665"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>San Gabriel Mountains Foothills and Rivers Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H71E405BC3B0440C28872647EFEC1F39B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
					<toc-entry idref="HD655DFC0271C4631AD90561A6BDDE5C7" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HAF51852DCBCD45C2B265BEF8015C54EA" level="title">Title I—San Gabriel National Recreation Area </toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HB2E51B8DAF234C52A636DA791DE6CFFC" level="section">Sec. 101. Definitions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H30EDBBBE21924F57A89F4DD5C5B5708A" level="section">Sec. 102. Establishment of San Gabriel National Recreation Area.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H1DCFFCC7F49946C6AAB173B58103E519" level="section">Sec. 103. Management.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H2FAF7177820140C0BE4B4017D7BDFFD1" level="section">Sec. 104. Acquisition of non-Federal lands within the recreation area.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H883EC938A7394072951DD65D3549DD82" level="section">Sec. 105. Water rights; water resource facilities; public roads; utility facilities.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H576F4519C4C1485D87DEB9ECE4732B8E" level="section">Sec. 106. San Gabriel National Recreation Area Public Advisory Council.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HDD450DAE52C74526AA676ED4204A1555" level="section">Sec. 107. San Gabriel National Recreation Area Partnership.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HCE4DA7A8B0DD4C20937A5A5744C84062" level="section">Sec. 108. Visitor services and facilities.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H0DABC2E7F15B4FFDBFEE1ECE59B3666C" level="title">Title II—San Gabriel Mountains National Monument</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H0C2C5FE7D79746F5B607B75012DABAB0" level="section">Sec. 201. Boundary modification, San Gabriel Mountains National Monument.</toc-entry></toc>
			</subsection></section><title id="HAF51852DCBCD45C2B265BEF8015C54EA"><enum>I</enum><header>San Gabriel National Recreation Area </header>
 <section id="HB2E51B8DAF234C52A636DA791DE6CFFC"><enum>101.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text> <paragraph id="HA8C0D5772DD94A38A5E019061B21BD75"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Adjudication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>adjudication</term> means any final judgment, order, ruling, or decree entered in any judicial proceeding adjudicating or affecting water rights, surface water management, or groundwater management.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8265540125ED43458A01202A299DF907"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Advisory council</header><text>The term <term>advisory council</term> means the San Gabriel National Recreation Area Public Advisory Council established by section 106(a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0678199CDA194A70826CC0EE24134548"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federal lands</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Federal lands</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HA1AC4A9CC3A24536945A6D1037761BBA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>public lands under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC57B8C97FF7840AC88A4B1B582E9D5E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>lands under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Defense, acting through the Army Corps of Engineers.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBBBE1D89B5EB47A0BB82225117D66EC2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Management plan</header><text>The term <term>management plan</term> means the management plan for the recreation area required by section 103(e).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5F81AD46F1354A3892521EADAB7AF91C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Public lands</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>public lands</term> has the meaning given that term in section 103(e) of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1702">43 U.S.C. 1702(e)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF838F49F53404D47954F7FB5C4E11914"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Partnership</header><text>The term <term>partnership</term> means the San Gabriel National Recreation Partnership established by section 107(a).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H496E24AE7D074646BBD85CF7A1BADB7B"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Recreation area</header><text>The term <term>recreation area</term> means the San Gabriel National Recreation Area established by section 102(b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD599880F29E1479ABDDA5DB193253DDA"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4078E2FA70B44EDD875693C081ECB410"><enum>(9)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of California.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H703AB0FC4A404C0B804EACCDAAC2D04F"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Utility facility</header><text>The term <term>utility facility</term> means electric substations, communication facilities, towers, poles, and lines, ground wires, communication circuits, and other structures, and related infrastructure.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9472D6C536CE4F7CBBF0C709DA17387F"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Water resource facility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>water resource facility</term> means irrigation and pumping facilities, dams and reservoirs, flood control facilities, water conservation works, including debris protection facilities, sediment placement sites, rain gauges, and stream gauges, water quality facilities, recycled water facilities and water pumping, conveyance distribution systems, and water treatment facilities, aqueducts, canals, ditches, pipelines, wells, hydropower projects, and transmission and other ancillary facilities, groundwater recharge facilities, water conservation, water filtration plants, and other water diversion, conservation, groundwater recharge, storage, and carriage structures.</text>
				</paragraph></section><section id="H30EDBBBE21924F57A89F4DD5C5B5708A"><enum>102.</enum><header>Establishment of San Gabriel National Recreation Area</header>
 <subsection id="HDC8620CF1818487E9EFF8C2AF1E2F526"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this title are—</text> <paragraph id="HA134BE96F30B4B5990C5854BE009193C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to conserve, protect, and enhance for the benefit and enjoyment of present and future generations the ecological, scenic, wildlife, recreational, cultural, historical, natural, educational, and scientific resources of the recreation area;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF4B09C1487D44EFBBA3B8502519BB067"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to provide environmentally responsible, well-managed recreational opportunities within the recreation area, and improve access to and from the recreation area;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFDD9F182FE1F496A9CB6B59684526E03"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to provide expanded educational and interpretive services that will increase public understanding of and appreciation for the natural and cultural resources of the recreation area;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5F58E85BF54B44DE963630DEAE6203AF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to facilitate the cooperative management of the lands and resources within the recreation area, in collaboration with the State and political subdivisions of the State, historical, business, cultural, civic, recreational, tourism and other nongovernmental organizations, and the public; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA9B2572AC20C428BB6640B986D15ED2A"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to allow the continued use of the recreation area by all persons, entities, and local government agencies in activities relating to integrated water management, flood protection, water conservation, water quality, water rights, water supply, groundwater recharge and monitoring, wastewater treatment, public roads and bridges, and utilities within or adjacent to the recreation area.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H181266276BA847F7939AD92AFEC957A1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment and boundaries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to valid existing rights, there is hereby established the San Gabriel National Recreation Area as a unit of the National Park System in the State of California, which shall consist of approximately 51,107 acres of Federal lands and interests in land in the State depicted as the <quote>Proposed San Gabriel Mountains National Recreation Area</quote> on the map titled <quote>San Gabriel Mountains National Recreation Area and National Monument Expansion Proposal</quote> and dated October 5, 2015.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="H4A0D010F746B4CBAA91917CC2BB0FC32"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Map and legal description</header>
 <paragraph id="H7BD64BD55CBC4361AE9B99A76FF3354A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall file a map and a legal description of the recreation area with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H90620BB8A2C64C328F85D266F3F36ED0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC41AD2F2039E4F7F87DA67CACCAB99E1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H15EA7FDAB3E840DB91B8A67732E62673"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Force of law</header><text>The map and legal description filed under paragraph (1) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act, except that the Secretary may correct any clerical and typographical errors in the map and legal description.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H679520800D87492E83DBBFB68D45609B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The map and legal description filed under paragraph (1) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6EEF568EB691438B95FF1197CC9DF6C4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Administration and jurisdiction</header>
 <paragraph id="H74FE0378B98449008B95DF0B5F982F8E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Public lands</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The public lands included in the recreation area shall be administered by the Secretary, acting through the National Park Service.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H170B837A478646ACB31FC601A8F2D3C0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Department of defense lands</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Although certain Federal lands under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Defense are included in the recreation area, nothing in this title transfers administrative jurisdiction of such Federal lands from the Secretary of Defense or otherwise affects Federal lands under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Defense.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFF5FB8E8764A4FF6AD192ACA0757A855"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State and local jurisdiction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this title alters, modifies, or diminishes any right, responsibility, power, authority, jurisdiction, or entitlement of the State, any political subdivision of the State, or any State or local agency under existing Federal, State, and local law (including regulations).</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1DCFFCC7F49946C6AAB173B58103E519"><enum>103.</enum><header>Management</header>
 <subsection id="H7E388B3D09DD46ADA517E97C5CDB63B8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National park system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to valid existing rights, the Secretary shall manage the public lands included in the recreation area in a manner that protects, and enhances the natural resources and values of the lands, in accordance with—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8840B3E743F1432685352994A1B463F3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>this title;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H355BA40B6AE846CAB97EA7C484134AF1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the laws generally applicable to units of the National Park System; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H58F71301302249EB8BA8369D6A02754D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>other applicable law (including Federal, State, or local law, and regulations).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H178589B026644839A3DD2B959197B2BC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Cooperation with Secretary of Defense</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall cooperate with the Secretary of Defense to develop opportunities for the management, to the maximum extent practicable, of the Federal lands under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Defense included in the recreation area in accordance with the purposes described in section 102(a).</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="H120D9533887B4F64BE01C9C310316250"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Treatment of Non-Federal lands and related provisions</header>
 <paragraph id="HCEA5F871FCE142779CBBA6DD0223706C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in this title—</text> <subparagraph id="H6AC368D901994561A7DF6A7D467057A1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>authorizes the Secretary to take any action that would affect the use of any land not owned by the United States;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08A369B70F8341C0A50E36F8F3810810"><enum>(B)</enum><text>affects the use of, or access to, any non-Federal land within the recreation area;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8D652B2801744B6B2FB26E90BA2EA55"><enum>(C)</enum><text>modifies any provision of Federal, State, or local law with respect to public access to or use of non-Federal land;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9ED68B89643642048624A76ED0F6E3F4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>requires any owner of non-Federal land to allow public access (including Federal, State, or local government access) to private property or any other non-Federal land;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69B84A064A3B480CA87709ACBBCEEB16"><enum>(E)</enum><text>alters any duly adopted land use regulation, approved land use plan, or any other regulatory authority of any State, or local agency, or tribal government;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C7366EB6EBC45E3B1C5AFF09430C0EA"><enum>(F)</enum><text>creates any liability, or affects any liability under any other law, of any private property owner or other owner of non-Federal land with respect to any person injured on private property or other non-Federal land;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B745AAC559B4357B7440E37360C3B6B"><enum>(G)</enum><text>conveys any land use or other regulatory authority to the partnership;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H385985F7B08A43AEA14AE260C257C131"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be construed to cause any Federal, State, or local regulations or permit requirements, which are intended to apply to units of the National Park System, to affect the Federal lands under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Defense or non-Federal lands within the boundaries of the recreation area; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8B861BD3BC84D7490E27701D20C4416"><enum>(I)</enum><text>requires any local government to participate in any program administered by the Secretary.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C2341E4759248618E4CE3CF75C42731"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cooperation</header><text>The Secretary is encouraged to work with owners of non-Federal land who have agreed to cooperate with the Secretary to further the purposes of this title.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="HCB42BA3953F24E93A0BE55CC2789BE54"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Buffer zones</header>
 <subparagraph id="H96ABC558A6D64B1FA643177F8A0EABB7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Congress does not intend the establishment of the recreation area to lead to the creation of protective perimeters or buffer zones around the recreation area.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA340A4025C043B589BD63D46EFC014D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Activities or uses up to boundaries</header><text>The fact that certain activities or land can be seen or heard from within the recreation area shall not, of itself, preclude the activities or land uses up to the boundary of the recreation area.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3AC6B9F9E6C842ACA53FDB6934F6948A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Facilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this title shall affect the operation, maintenance, modification, construction, or expansion of any water resource facility or any solid waste, sanitary sewer, water or wastewater treatment, groundwater recharge or conservation, hydroelectric, conveyance distribution system, recycled water facility, or utility facility located within or adjacent to the recreation area.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB73888FEF9C64086AE3573CC37D37CF3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 100903 of title 54, United States Code, shall not apply to the Puente Hills landfill, materials recovery facility, or intermodal facility.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4BEAA10387B246E484946DC88956DC92"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Management plan</header>
 <paragraph id="H10F7CFE50A894067B84E4B909A190E58"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary and the advisory council shall create a comprehensive management plan for the recreation area that fulfills the purposes described in section 102(a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF425E3E3673945518802A4BF8DEE645A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of existing plans</header><text>In developing the management plan, and to the extent consistent with this section, the Secretary may incorporate any provision from a land use plan or any other plan applicable to the public lands included in the recreation area.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBA2E7E83CB4B4461925908D275C0503A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Incorporation of visitor services plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall incorporate the visitor services plan required by section 108 into the management plan.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H11C0416E8F1D47A59D13F30F6EF00B9A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Partnership</header><text>In developing the management plan, the Secretary shall consider recommendations of the partnership. To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall incorporate recommendations of the partnership into the management plan if the Secretary determines that the recommendations are feasible and consistent with the purposes in section 102(a), this title, and applicable laws (including regulations).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H41A602E095E14427895188F85DF977FA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Fish and wildlife</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this title affects the jurisdiction of the State with respect to fish and wildlife located on public lands in the State.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H2FAF7177820140C0BE4B4017D7BDFFD1"><enum>104.</enum><header>Acquisition of non-Federal lands within the recreation area</header>
 <subsection id="HC04BBBB6B74047DBA0FA013DED196BD7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Limited acquisition Authority</header><text>The Secretary may acquire non-Federal land within the boundaries of the recreation area only through exchange, donation, or purchase from a willing seller.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8DADB50871B74EEB9C03610986B51659"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on use of Eminent domain</header><text>Nothing in this title authorizes the use of eminent domain to acquire land or interests in land.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HEAEB130C968D477BB47F52913415EE18"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Treatment of acquired lands</header><text>Any land or interest in land acquired by the United States and located within the boundaries of the recreation area shall be—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB5685A1C9A8F4A92B6176DCFD7A6E558"><enum>(1)</enum><text>included in the recreation area; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H359B11963866493B973D0CC7CA6D69B9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>administered by the Secretary in accordance with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD78B0F27D143478E842628E5D8896461"><enum>(A)</enum><text>this title; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD75E3C8105234E61B591CF296B8A4E97"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other applicable law (including regulations).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H08F40BA774C84B67AA8B5A8D4354374C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Additional Requirement</header><text>As a further condition on the acquisition of land or interests in land under this section, the Secretary shall make a determination that the land contains important biological, cultural, historic, or recreational values.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H883EC938A7394072951DD65D3549DD82"><enum>105.</enum><header>Water rights; water resource facilities; public roads; utility facilities</header>
 <subsection id="HABC7E52E978444F788E7A26AA90DC1EE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>No effect on water rights</header><text>Nothing in this title—</text> <paragraph id="HE22FBA6D9B5C44FB9F71249B4D060500"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall affect the use or allocation, in existence on the date of the enactment of this Act, of any water, water right, or interest in water (including potable, recycled, reclaimed, waste, imported, exported, banked, stored water, surface water, groundwater, and public trust interests);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H71A4BC0C3762468DB5495A0DC4066459"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall affect any public or private contract in existence on the date of the enactment of this Act for the sale, lease, or loan of any water (including potable, recycled, reclaimed, waste, imported, exported, banked, stored water, surface water, and groundwater);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H443F8CDF283C4B68AF3E5FE08311E65C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>shall be considered to be a relinquishment or reduction of any water rights reserved or appropriated by the United States in the State on or before the date of the enactment of this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H55DEED352D8143CFA4C7A673BFBDA8BC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>authorizes or imposes any new reserved Federal water rights or expands water usage pursuant to any existing Federal reserved riparian or appropriative rights;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3DDB95DB465E44828A4549B199B3A7C5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>shall be considered to be a relinquishment or reduction of any water rights (including potable, recycled, reclaimed, waste, imported, exported, banked, stored water, surface water and groundwater) held, reserved or appropriated by any public entity, or other person or entities, on or before the date of the enactment of this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6764DBF468A5453BA424F195151D2308"><enum>(6)</enum><text>shall be construed to, or shall interfere or conflict with the exercise of the powers or duties of any watermaster, public agency, or other body or entity responsible for groundwater or surface water management or groundwater replenishment as designated or established pursuant to any adjudication, or Federal or State statute including, without limitation, the management of the San Gabriel River watershed and basin, to provide water supply and other environmental benefits;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H91831E54C5434FF88EE0C7C83708F9BC"><enum>(7)</enum><text>shall be construed to impede or adversely impact any previously adopted Los Angeles County Drainage Area project, as described in the report of the Chief of Engineers dated June 30, 1992, including any supplement or addendum to that report, or any maintenance agreement to operate the project;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE8D8DCA43B2F48A681A555CD35FC2651"><enum>(8)</enum><text>shall interfere or conflict with any action by a watermaster or public agency that is authorized pursuant to Federal or State statute, water right or adjudication, including actions relating to water conservation, water quality, surface water diversion or impoundment, groundwater recharge, water treatment, conservation or storage of water, pollution, waste discharge, the pumping of groundwater; the spreading, injection, pumping, storage, or the use of water from local sources, storm water flows, and runoff, or from imported or recycled water, that is undertaken in connection with the management or regulation of the San Gabriel River;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC975F3FBB8A843E890A56393D0F65EE1"><enum>(9)</enum><text>shall interfere with, obstruct, hinder, or delay the exercise of, or access to, any water right by the owner of a public water system, or other person or entity, including, but not limited to, the construction, operation, maintenance, replacement, repair, location, or relocation of any well; pipeline; or water pumping, treatment, diversion, impoundment, or storage facility; or other facility or property necessary or useful to access any water right or operate any public water system;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H65CCC32624804CA5A91CA0F2E14A671A"><enum>(10)</enum><text>shall require initiation or reinitiation of consultation with the United States Fish and Wildlife Service under, or the application of provisions of, the Endangered Species Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531</external-xref> et seq.) concerning any action or activity affecting water, water rights or water management or water resource facilities in the San Gabriel River watershed and basin; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9F700E768A9B4DBF80EE1F656AB8A3AF"><enum>(11)</enum><text>authorizes any agency or employee of the United States, or any other person, to take any action inconsistent with a preceding paragraph.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC22F4E3800354740894EECBE96B225F7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Water resource facilities</header>
 <paragraph id="H4A58ACFBC0414CD789794CA5DA77514C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>No effect on existing water resource facilities</header><text>Nothing in this title shall affect—</text> <subparagraph id="H6A77626C9A7B4ED4AB29725B8D195339"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the use, operation, maintenance, repair, construction, reconfiguration, expansion, or replacement of a water resource facility within or adjacent to the recreation area; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0869B766CC7468A99F32C447C58235F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>access to a water resource facility within or adjacent to the recreation area.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A824972EA15477DA3C017A4020356B6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No effect on new water resource facilities</header><text>Nothing in this title shall preclude the establishment of new water resource facilities (including instream sites, routes, and areas) within the recreation area if such facilities are necessary to preserve or enhance the health, safety, water supply, or utility services to residents of Los Angeles or San Bernardino Counties.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H506E434154044E008DF1914716F7AFD0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Flood control</header><text>Nothing in this title shall be construed to—</text> <subparagraph id="H0B9CAE3393BE4429A842AA8EA0F74C49"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">impose new restrictions or requirements on flood protection, water conservation, water supply, groundwater recharge, water transfers, or water quality operations; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A42483314A64AB9A4F5A9604930FCCE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increase the liability of agencies carrying out flood protection, water conservation, water supply, groundwater recharge, water transfers, or water quality operations.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H48F8DE69FA4647AB90D3C3785ECA1D96"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Diversion or use of water</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this title shall authorize or require the use of water in or the diversion of water to the recreation area.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9CB2E08FF2C844E7A91510ACE1152A95"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Utility facilities and rights of way</header><text>Nothing in this title shall—</text> <paragraph id="H9FFBB79296954BDE888A69A8B74A7742"><enum>(1)</enum><text>affect the use, operation, maintenance, repair, construction, reconfiguration, expansion, inspection, renewal, reconstruction, alteration, addition, relocation, improvement, removal, or replacement of utility facilities or appurtenant rights of way within or adjacent to the recreation area;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1E23C3FE4B324C2BB9E595F7F9826F7D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>affect access to utility facilities or rights of way within or adjacent to the recreation area; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF1FA3EECA9CD4F67ABEF3C602149C224"><enum>(3)</enum><text>preclude the establishment of new utility facilities or rights of way (including instream sites, routes, and areas) within the recreation area if such facilities are necessary for public health and safety, electricity supply, or other utility services.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H26ED74CFE0564D619BFE13778E2BA89F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Roads; public transit</header>
 <paragraph id="H4988238E00404B0092654FD3BAD725A4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="H30F02153676A4A61B5CF3B7640653779"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Public roads</header><text>The term <term>public roads</term> means any paved road or bridge (including any appurtenant structures and rights of way) that is operated or maintained by a non-Federal entity and is—</text>
 <clause id="H2DCEBB73F0534BB498723DAB94466229"><enum>(i)</enum><text>open to vehicular use by the public; or</text> </clause><clause id="HD1F7ABCC4113473DB81AF03324E878B7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">used by public agencies or utilities for the operation, maintenance, repair, construction, and rehabilitation of infrastructure, utility facility, or right-of-way.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B67CCB61A1C43569C4A96726D646BA3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public transit</header><text>The term <term>public transit</term> means transit services (including operations and rights of way) that are operated or maintained by a non-Federal entity and are—</text>
 <clause id="H54B85595254E487FA79035A5CF428467"><enum>(i)</enum><text>open to the public; or</text> </clause><clause id="H6E25FD52D47645E59A8F2186D42D3FA8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">used by public agencies or contractors for the operation, maintenance, repair, construction, and rehabilitation of infrastructure, utility facility, or right-of-way.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C21076002E64338A7039C2F799A123F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No effect on public roads or public transit</header><text>Nothing in this title—</text> <subparagraph id="H38C9EBC4BC5C448C946DE5E44053BF8F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>authorizes the Secretary to take any action that would affect the operation, maintenance, repair, and rehabilitation of public roads or public transit (including activities necessary to comply with Federal and State safety standards or public transit); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7245435AA274414985044E41DCCFBDCC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>creates any new liability, or increases any existing liability, of any owner or operator of public roads.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H576F4519C4C1485D87DEB9ECE4732B8E"><enum>106.</enum><header>San Gabriel National Recreation Area Public Advisory Council</header>
 <subsection id="HD83A93FF46D74690BAAE62018837D529"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish the San Gabriel National Recreation Area Public Advisory Council.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2FA732E4E6FE4B348B19A6FAE997D42E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The advisory council shall advise the Secretary on the development and implementation of the management plan and the visitor services plan.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEDBB9F51AA4246CDA529FADF58774CBC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicable law</header><text>The advisory council shall be subject to—</text> <paragraph id="H7FDF5BFB15D74BFA91EB6F224F451740"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H887B60CD3B264C20A29E8212FF9AD69A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>all other applicable law (including regulations).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H96C49862600944B4867562791E9E0464"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Members</header> <paragraph id="HA9E081B79CCE43E8BA6732391D60DDE7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Size of advisory council</header><text>The advisory council shall include 21 members.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H297C5FD9DD3B4B6AB6E5A8B15C2C06CF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Makeup of advisory council</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After considering the recommendations of the partnership, the Secretary shall appoint members of the advisory council to represent the following interests:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H284C07C503844C0A8FA4F46D46E03DAA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Two members to represent local, regional, or national environmental organizations.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H282854DADE5B4B22B424B159F6BD2A96"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Two members to represent the interests of outdoor recreation, including off-highway vehicle recreation, within the recreation area.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E5B87486CA24F378ADF3C21D7B31B11"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Two members to represent the interests of community-based organizations whose mission includes expanding access to the outdoors.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7158853193104573AF5E87175182A0DC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Two members to represent business interests.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H447089C401AB4541A867F6BD6B3BC8BA"><enum>(E)</enum><text>One member to represent Native American tribes within or adjacent to the recreation area.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F864BA9ACE542FFA730DBD7D2C9BCC2"><enum>(F)</enum><text>One member to represent the interests of homeowners’ associations within the recreation area.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H604A27E1A6484AB69AF7F0212A26CB4D"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Three members to represent the interests of holders of adjudicated water rights, water agencies, wastewater and sewer agencies, recycled water facilities, and water replenishment entities.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41BF9DD08CFF4C5C89E6F9BFB47A4B06"><enum>(H)</enum><text>One member to represent energy and mineral development interests.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5EE186239B0D4D72AC6FDC3B1ACA2CD4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>One member to represent owners of Federal grazing permits, or other land use permits within the recreation area.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A4E276583BF4D42A57C2E1C2D0D35E9"><enum>(J)</enum><text>One member to represent archaeological and historical interests.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB22EDBBE79B4862A5E774DD6086E4E2"><enum>(K)</enum><text>One member to represent the interests of environmental educators.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE734BBB8DF45437EA2AE3F9A4C312DB5"><enum>(L)</enum><text>One member to represent cultural history interests.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5C8860770F44389A00B031D9EBDB20A"><enum>(M)</enum><text>One member to represent environmental justice interests.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF18AD711C0CE444B88E4D8FFAD25D6D0"><enum>(N)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">One member to represent electrical utility interests.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED989DA987424F3EAD446C5F1C933F79"><enum>(O)</enum><text>Two members to represent the affected public at large.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H17F9E8E5E00B48559874D1F4888E996A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Terms</header>
 <paragraph id="HFDD23FCDE85344189B0B178BCD133B08"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Staggered terms</header><text>Members of the advisory council shall be appointed for terms of 3 years, except that, of the members first appointed, 6 of the members shall be appointed for a term of 1 year and 6 of the members shall be appointed for a term of 2 years.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HECBF24CC278845E9A59272293A71C7EB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reappointment</header><text>A member may be reappointed to serve on the advisory council upon the expiration of the member’s current term.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAF3E5AB405FE4E4CA4DEEDBFECBFAD10"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Vacancy</header><text>A vacancy on the advisory council shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2630733322684D378040A69A2A1D01F0"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>A quorum shall be ten members of the advisory council. The operations of the advisory council shall not be impaired by the fact that a member has not yet been appointed as long as a quorum has been attained.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA8381274C8B348F08F7D9A9FB6F6025C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Chairperson and procedures</header><text>The advisory council shall elect a chairperson and establish such rules and procedures as the advisory council considers necessary or desirable.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFE6902E0F2D8496F9ABEB509EF542CF3"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Service without compensation</header><text>Members of the advisory council shall serve without pay.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H856D403FA28F4A2AA15BB3517E2BA8C1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The advisory council shall cease to exist—</text>
 <paragraph id="HBEE270A59F2D4005AD3A255D21682E32"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on the date that is five years after the date on which the management plans are officially adopted by the Secretary; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8F2A01C493A94511806D8EACC713ABB3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>on such later date as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HDD450DAE52C74526AA676ED4204A1555"><enum>107.</enum><header>San Gabriel National Recreation Area Partnership</header> <subsection id="H86D19E968CAD436EBEC7FEFE26340AB6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is hereby established the San Gabriel National Recreation Area Partnership.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H47CA576C9DAF434F8D5AB06EDCB533E6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of the partnership are to—</text> <paragraph id="HAA1D7445359D4C31B56BFFD7BEA3B4E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>coordinate the activities of Federal, State, tribal, and local authorities, and the private sector, in fulfilling the purposes of this title; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC26A650A39B142E88B79BF33E2F873A9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>use the resources and expertise of each agency in improving the management and recreational opportunities within the recreation area.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1442A7633EE14A0CAEC5C06AD5B45682"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The members of the partnership shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="H415A5AE6299D4BA78050733B2720FC25"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary, or a designee of the Secretary, to represent the National Park Service and Bureau of Land Management.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H30B25CCA9DAD4949BA017DBC16447F89"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary of Defense, or a designee of the Secretary, to represent the Army Corps of Engineers.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8D4F98A1539D448392A3EC9A1591083B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Secretary of Agriculture, or a designee of the Secretary, to represent the Forest Service.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H70DC2734E6DF488C9D46401042F753DC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Secretary of the State Natural Resources Agency, or a designee of the Secretary, to represent the California Department of Parks and Recreation and the Rivers and Mountains Conservancy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA0597BDE5E15418EB21262C06E608B2A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A designee of the Los Angeles County Board of Supervisors.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6266B6C4A2BC4583BB32301F659F9CDD"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A designee of the Puente Hills Habitat Preservation Authority.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H028ECC73AE3D4BE5ACDD303B449651DA"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Four designees of the San Gabriel Council of Governments, one of whom is to be elected from a local land conservancy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H917C4060BB724709A5BCAFDA56E8E0FB"><enum>(8)</enum><text>One designee of the San Bernardino Associated Governments.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE307F67F3FDB4195B10E87FBF2BEB6A4"><enum>(9)</enum><text>A designee of the San Gabriel Valley Economic Partnership.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB7AC96A20937416C895E023DA79CDBC4"><enum>(10)</enum><text>A designee of the Los Angeles County Flood Control District.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9E400C9E7CC04915BD3A38A310E7F13D"><enum>(11)</enum><text>A designee of the San Gabriel Valley Water Association.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC2D046B1C0234DA6BEAE4FA4A625681D"><enum>(12)</enum><text>A designee of the Central Basin Water Association.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H71772309D63F420AA21C606CC5CE6518"><enum>(13)</enum><text>A designee of the Six Basins Watermaster.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8D55FEECE0FE4C05B7BF697F26E72DF5"><enum>(14)</enum><text>A designee of a public utility company, to be appointed by the Secretary.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H83B49610195743A084A8E69676CD3E92"><enum>(15)</enum><text>A designee of the Watershed Conservation Authority.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H49513098AE9B45E8BF614E1EDED53729"><enum>(16)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A designee of the public advisory council so long as the public advisory council remains in effect.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H554334EFCD2541F58FDA5EC0567E7995"><enum>(17)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">One designee of San Gabriel Mountains National Monument Community.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD464868EFC68463A84D2C396FF93FA30"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To further the purposes described in section 102(a), and in a manner consistent with such purposes, the partnership shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H21C550DC21D84B27B381820B658EF418"><enum>(1)</enum><text>make recommendations to the Secretary on the development and implementation of the management plan;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H21349A9CD01D4C938AEA1BEC000E078E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>review and comment on the visitor services plan required by section 108;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H01CF580F3F2941DC89B6B6130EDDA91B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>seek opportunities to facilitate the implementation of the visitor services plan;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4518605883FC45EB8183A8FBCD854BEE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>assist units of local government, regional planning organizations, and nonprofit organizations in fulfilling the purposes of the recreation area by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB8B268F7A91E452BAA9B016BE0C5139F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>carrying out programs and projects that recognize, protect, and enhance important resource values within the recreation area;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66DD7E0BF22147B18B3D5A9106E75F6A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establishing and maintaining interpretive exhibits and programs within the recreation area;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB92F1FE2B1C40D0B4BF519D4682A8C2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>developing recreational and educational opportunities in the recreation area, consistent with the purposes of this title;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD542AE4A9715464993D1CF109A15E4C2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>increasing public awareness of, and appreciation for, natural, historic, scenic, and cultural resources of the recreation area;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92CE2FC0DE8D4DC083B4F73CDEF961EC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>ensuring that signs identifying points of public access and sites of interest are posted throughout the recreation area;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA696C77BD324D34A7D98BC6FA01C6B5"><enum>(F)</enum><text>promoting a wide range of partnerships among governments, organizations, and individuals to further the purposes of the recreation area; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD94B9FB15E4413AA65E8A44CB9C8FA2"><enum>(G)</enum><text>ensuring that management of the recreation area takes into account local ordinances and land-use plans, as well as adjacent residents and property owners;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD22018B2A1AD4E5B8B35AA1B6B7ECDDE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>make recommendations to the Secretary regarding the appointment of members to the advisory council; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H358EFC74EDD74692BF7FEACF9FB4C0A8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>undertake any other action necessary to fulfill the purposes of this title.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7F1C764FD79D4AE08537C299E5165CCB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the prior approval of the Secretary, for the purposes of preparing and implementing the management plan, the partnership may use Federal funds made available under this section—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8510E2F9DA9445E8A0661F46C5259D7B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to make grants to the State, political subdivisions of the State, nonprofit organizations, and other persons;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD2742EC3F2F64A9F871064BCFD88F026"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to enter into cooperative agreements with, or provide grants or technical assistance to, the State, political subdivisions of the State, nonprofit organizations, Federal agencies, and other interested parties;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H061C02155C7E4E14BDDB23F3F6DBB7F6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to hire and compensate staff;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9E0840B88FCC4099A086C6DD894BAE88"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to obtain funds or services from any source, including funds and services provided under any other Federal law or program;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCC948FE5EA1F4CF193233EB4074A08AB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to contract for goods or services; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF1C756DB3E9C44AFA6620223846CCD85"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to support activities of partners and any other activities that further the purposes of the recreation area and are consistent with the management plan.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4F3C3295D21540ED8577869B2105CC26"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Terms of office; reappointment; vacancies</header>
 <paragraph id="HE558C178951F451E9F053D48BAD397B5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Terms</header><text>Members of the partnership shall be appointed for terms of 3 years.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0190E10996BD44EF928294C03CD66BB4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reappointment</header><text>A member may be reappointed to serve on the partnership upon the expiration of the member’s current term.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H73A6D0F82D464F81B9E77EC6BA695C38"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Vacancy</header><text>A vacancy on the partnership shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H28DA103E24EF4870B9A50BE1B1BFFF0C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>A quorum shall be eleven members of the partnership. The operations of the partnership shall not be impaired by the fact that a member has not yet been appointed as long as a quorum has been attained.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3464B29112E24904B0BF304B4553D1D7"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Chairperson and procedures</header><text>The partnership shall elect a chairperson and establish such rules and procedures as it deems necessary or desirable.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB2C493434C6844BFB8AD34B6EFFA5DA2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Service without compensation</header><text>Members of the partnership shall serve without pay.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H85C0F9F8F8574DCD93AE7C559415C942"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Duties and authorities of the secretary</header> <paragraph id="H0C96F858B0A14DC99F1F578F16AA0E31"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall convene the partnership on a regular basis to carry out this title.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE319543C88584B9D8381E7DB6E641ADA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Visitor services plan</header><text>The Secretary may carry out the visitor services plan required by section 108.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB4354B0B8F6C4293BF82B1D50A253E79"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Technical and financial assistance</header><text>The Secretary may provide technical and financial assistance, on a reimbursable or non-reimbursable basis, as determined by the Secretary, to the partnership or any members of the partnership to carry out this title.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCF0CF0F7A02C4CBEBBD732BB48B442FB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Cooperative agreements</header><text>The Secretary may enter into cooperative agreements with the partnership, any members of the partnership, or other public or private entities to provide technical, financial or other assistance to carry out this title.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H1C7366CDE89143A9AB2A7F23A2C9F7B5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Construction of facilities on non-Federal lands</header>
 <subparagraph id="H7C9751A3969941C89760BCACECB6ABD7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to facilitate the administration of the recreation area, the Secretary is authorized, subject to valid existing rights, to construct administrative or visitor use facilities on non-Federal public lands within the recreation area.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6938B8DE3F534E58AF8720BB9479E20D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional requirement</header><text>Such facilities may only be developed—</text> <clause id="H141EA132807443E8868BEFE060805581"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with the consent of the owner of the non-Federal public land; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC838141E2BBE4B76A70DDCC07DEF047A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in accordance with applicable Federal, State, and local laws, regulations, and plans.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H98C79B09D5444BC7920EB2A49E1303F1"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>The Secretary shall give priority to actions that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4E1E783E8AE24D0F9771AD690F16AC2B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conserve the significant natural, historic, cultural, and scenic resources of the recreation area; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06F4052EB7F840839CBC1EAF97114986"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide educational, interpretive, and recreational opportunities consistent with the purposes of the recreation area.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6C97ECB6770347F08000C42FCBFC2A23"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Committees</header><text>The partnership shall establish—</text> <paragraph id="H7F389F568775486FAD56F23136835AA5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a Water Technical Advisory Committee to advise the Secretary on water-related issues relating to the recreation area; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4E99FBE95F314C5ABDB4AF2A8EAF00D6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a Public Safety Advisory Committee to advise the Secretary on public safety issues relating to the recreation area.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HCE4DA7A8B0DD4C20937A5A5744C84062"><enum>108.</enum><header>Visitor services and facilities</header>
				<subsection id="HB3B639AF4C0D4E249B7E9BDDF023F9A4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Visitor services</header>
 <paragraph id="H153ADB0216294A88AA731F85AEC3CCF5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this subsection is to facilitate the development of an integrated visitor services plan that will improve visitor experiences in the recreation area through expanded recreational opportunities, and increased interpretation, education, resource protection, and enforcement.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF77F560CEC1C4AC2980426C472B6A3BF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Plan required</header><text>Not later than three years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and in accordance with this subsection, the Secretary shall develop an integrated visitor services plan for the recreation area.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCA0C09672E734D34B5E3F8BF0483E414"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The visitor services plan shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H7F6C165603E3479699E8DFA7E0AA8367"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assess current and anticipated future visitation to the recreation area, including recreation destinations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20D8FA2637BF4412A5E682F1FECE5C2D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consider the demand for various types of recreation (including hiking, picnicking, horseback riding, and the use of motorized and mechanized vehicles) where permissible and appropriate;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H71A6007886534554B84A3A1C0CB6CC48"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluate the impacts of recreation on natural and cultural resources, water resource facilities, public roads, adjacent residents and property owners, and utilities within the recreation area, as well as the effectiveness of current enforcement efforts;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A6EE25BEAAD4C65B4A10FCC4B832F76"><enum>(D)</enum><text>assess the current level of interpretive and educational services and facilities;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H792485E346DE4FCC84877343A08B4526"><enum>(E)</enum><text>include recommendations to—</text>
 <clause id="H059BF54EB46F4862A6D942B2706D49A8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>expand opportunities for high-demand recreational activities, consistent with the purposes described in section 102(a);</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAF4E753AC7414281A92BAD5956169F0A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>better manage recreation area resources and improve the experience of recreation area visitors through expanded interpretive and educational services and facilities, and improved enforcement; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8D373A57033E4006A3DD7E0C0AB1D070"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>better manage recreation area resources to reduce negative impacts on the environment, ecology, and integrated water management activities in the area;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E1E68A85A2D41DD905F44FE2854A010"><enum>(F)</enum><text>in coordination and consultation with owners of non-Federal land, assess options to incorporate recreational opportunities on non-Federal land into the recreation area—</text>
 <clause id="H0B55AD5049604234AFA46A588FC75B2F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in a manner consistent with the purposes and uses of the non-Federal land; and</text> </clause><clause id="H9A7590312FDA4ABB9860E683BA244A7D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with the consent of the non-Federal land owner;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H59A04AFC900B40F8B0C95F2243706D3D"><enum>(G)</enum><text>assess opportunities to provide recreational opportunities that connect with adjacent National Forest System lands; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE39C91F424E640A5B89F42AF95BF5234"><enum>(H)</enum><text>be developed and carried out in accordance with applicable Federal, State, and local laws and ordinances.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0AC4D10DA50544E38A14F0E58A08EC20"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the visitor services plan, the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H04DBD7EA1C784AAF87016566A2FA8D9C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consult with—</text>
 <clause id="H549E2C31944B48F1B7C923BBD982BE57"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the partnership;</text> </clause><clause id="HA15452AF7D5644CEBADA4D140D961DC0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the advisory council;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8F74228416A44F39A6475795BC16EAE8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>appropriate State and local agencies; and</text> </clause><clause id="H028AD67F7A2048C997DB62D8208BC582"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>interested nongovernmental organizations; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC80CEC76B5B04ED5A6E838961FB557E3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>involve members of the public.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HADB2B130FE51431FAA2549674CA197EE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Visitor facilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may construct visitor use facilities in the recreation area. Such facilities shall be developed in conformance with all existing Federal, State, and local laws (including regulations) and applicable Federal, State, and local plans.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="H78DC1C8BBB464B718A3502A5075D84C4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Donations</header>
 <paragraph id="HDF4A3F409CD34B7CA56B897EAF4742B8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may accept and use donated funds, property, in-kind contributions, and services to carry out this title.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8A0FFB9DF20B498BABAF4B6F7344D588"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not use the authority provided by paragraph (1) to accept non-Federal land that has been acquired, after the date of the enactment of this Act, through use of eminent domain.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE754FA5071D1493792324B0F0785F45F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Cooperative agreements</header><text>In carrying out this title, the Secretary may make grants to, or enter into cooperative agreements with, State, tribal, and local governmental entities and private entities to conduct research, develop scientific analyses, and carry out any other initiative relating to the management of and visitation to the recreation area.</text>
				</subsection></section></title><title id="H0DABC2E7F15B4FFDBFEE1ECE59B3666C"><enum>II</enum><header>San Gabriel Mountains National Monument</header>
			<section id="H0C2C5FE7D79746F5B607B75012DABAB0"><enum>201.</enum><header>Boundary modification, San Gabriel Mountains National Monument</header>
 <subsection id="H3E79CB973CA547AB949E700E7B190821"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Modification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Agriculture shall modify the boundaries of the San Gabriel Mountains National Monument in the State of California to include the approximately 109,143 acres of additional National Forest System land depicted as the <quote>Proposed National Monument Expansion</quote> on the map titled <quote>San Gabriel Mountains National Recreation Area and National Monument Expansion Proposal</quote> and dated October 5, 2015.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDC3583A4A4CC442B8ED62D1129C6B25B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon inclusion of the National Forest System land identified in subsection (a), the Secretary of Agriculture shall administer those lands as part of the San Gabriel Mountains National Monument in accordance with the laws generally applicable to the monument.</text>
				</subsection></section></title></legis-body></bill>


