<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H58C33ED1F8004E94B5706769CFA0C36F" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4086 IH: Rim of the Valley Corridor Preservation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4086</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171019">October 19, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001150">Mr. Schiff</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To adjust the boundary of the Santa Monica Mountains National Recreation Area to include the Rim of
			 the Valley Corridor, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H9A169CA6EF0343EC8A33F69CCE1BC56D" style="OLC">
 <section id="H492A0F9B43DA48A887FA973F0175D08A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rim of the Valley Corridor Preservation Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HCEA66635C9024886A3DEAC6C8491C459"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="HE129014126964B34810DD69142896EBF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Santa Monica Mountains National Recreation Area was authorized as a unit of the National Park System on November 10, 1978.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H51D836D9371F4A0C874796245DAD9B24"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Santa Monica Mountains and the Rim of the Valley Corridor include—</text> <subparagraph id="H561EFB648FE54CEABF94537B01935E3C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>nationally significant resources—</text>
 <clause id="H77ECFEF551D84D9C9EB3D568761CF3ED"><enum>(i)</enum><text>outstanding examples of geologic history, including the evolution of the Transverse Ranges Province;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFF48354E710B43B5B34D971513778220"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a diversity of well-preserved marine and terrestrial paleontological resources; and</text> </clause><clause id="H707AA3514BB5414C866091DDEF8A8DBC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>high biodiversity, including outstanding examples of native grasslands, coastal sage scrub, chaparral, dry coniferous forests, and alluvial fan sage scrub; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H498D870457BC42E3BCEFED311D655BE8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>nationally significant cultural resources that represent a wide range of themes related to human use and settlement in the region—</text>
 <clause id="HB1D8E941BBBE4992A7EA7BF8D0AACBC1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>high concentrations of archeological resources that provide insight into more than 10,000 years of Native American history; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE53A85B850C6455781742FBA60BEAB90"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>landmarks that represent topics such as architecture, recreation, and space exploration.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H730CED89699B4F259BD432B4F2E0DEE2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Expanding the Santa Monica Mountains National Recreation Area would provide new opportunities for the National Park Service to serve a broad range of urban communities, including many that are underrepresented in national parks and underserved by State and local parks.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HDBBE832A6CF94CCD956BB584538DF774"><enum>3.</enum><header>Boundary adjustment; land acquisition; administration</header>
 <subsection id="HAC2DF2CCD44A40F49E2A0E24F9F16320"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Boundary adjustment</header><text>Section 507(c)(1) of the National Parks and Recreation Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/460kk">16 U.S.C. 460kk(c)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote><quote>Santa Monica Mountains National Recreation Area and Santa Monica Mountains Zone, California, Boundary Map</quote>, numbered 80,047–C and dated August 2001</quote> and inserting <quote><quote>Rim of the Valley Unit—Santa Monica Mountains National Recreation Area</quote> and dated October 2017</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDF601FE1DC1F4C9D9A187F1DEFF537B5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rim of the Valley Unit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 507 of the National Parks and Recreation Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/460kk">16 U.S.C. 460kk</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4A0058347B9049CEBDCE6B981F34DC8E" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="HEB36C25B7C8D4C02BC1C322A0B0E241B"><enum>(u)</enum><header>Rim of the Valley Unit</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HEFA0BA90DC174971B225187D9F80A2BB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Secretary shall update the general management plan for the recreation area to reflect the boundaries designated on the map referred to in subsection (c)(1) as the <quote>Rim of the Valley Unit</quote> (hereafter in the subsection referred to as the <quote>Rim of the Valley Unit</quote>). Subject to valid existing rights, the Secretary shall administer the Rim of the Valley Unit and any land or interest in land acquired by the United States and located within the boundaries of the Rim of the Valley Unit, as part of the recreation area in accordance with the provisions of this section and applicable laws and regulations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC19CE94194E34012ADB5C794AF144DAC" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may acquire non-Federal land within the boundaries of the Rim of the Valley Unit only through exchange, donation, or purchase from a willing seller. Nothing in this subsection authorizes the use of eminent domain to acquire land or interests in land.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8CFA48FDCA6B4584B20AB7C18F6298D8" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Nothing in this subsection or the application of the management plan for the Rim of the Valley Unit shall be construed to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H64DEF353A9AB4CB3B69815F4E2B8C665"><enum>(A)</enum><text>modify any provision of Federal, State, or local law with respect to public access to or use of non-Federal land;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75C12B8CA0AB4C68A1A68EB11ACDEFC8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>create any liability, or affect any liability under any other law, of any private property owner or other owner of non-Federal land with respect to any person injured on private property or other non-Federal land;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B5E20428D6746338C7622CAAC9154D2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>affect the ownership, management, or other rights relating to any non-Federal land (including any interest in any non-Federal land);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0A8E5AA3040456F91E9FCFBB245A948"><enum>(D)</enum><text>require any local government to participate in any program administered by the Secretary;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50261A61AD3F4B548E4252AA62C08D1E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>alter, modify, or diminish any right, responsibility, power, authority, jurisdiction, or entitlement of the State, any political subdivision of the State, or any State or local agency under existing Federal, State, and local law (including regulations);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8FF7A8FE24EA49D3A92418621CE25470"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require the creation of protective perimeters or buffer zones and the fact that certain activities or land can be seen or heard from within the Rim of the Valley Unit shall not, of itself, preclude the activities or land uses up to the boundary of the Rim of the Valley Unit;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A0F34B703C844C6BA14E1B7E545B614"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require or promote use of, or encourage trespass on, lands, facilities, and rights-of-way owned by non-Federal entities, including water resource facilities and public utilities, without the written consent of the owner;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73F78934C64A429EA09D052B8DB59F63"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">affect the operation, maintenance, modification, construction, or expansion of any water resource facility or utility facility located within or adjacent to the Rim of the Valley Unit;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2FF9A92CC87485EA181DFDED3280FDC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>terminate the fee title to lands or customary operation, maintenance, repair, and replacement activities on or under such lands granted to public agencies that are authorized pursuant to Federal or State statute;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5C61E842A0545C7ACE561AE910765AF"><enum>(J)</enum><text>interfere with, obstruct, hinder, or delay the exercise of any right to, or access to any water resource facility or other facility or property necessary or useful to access any water right to operate any public water or utility system; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5B0F139AE8C4A8097EF0EFB90B234C3"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require initiation or reinitiation of consultation with the United States Fish and Wildlife Service under, or the application of provisions of, the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531</external-xref> et seq.), the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.), or division A of subtitle III of title 54, United States Code, concerning any action or activity affecting water, water rights or water management or water resource facilities within the Rim of the Valley Unit.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H35CA04FBFEBD414C8DCEE839903C914A" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The activities of a utility facility or water resource facility shall be conducted in a manner to reasonably avoid or reduce the impact on the resources of the Rim of the Valley Unit.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H53C41BD2052749C59E6340D431374DA3" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>For the purposes of paragraphs (4) and (5)—</text> <subparagraph id="HE68E60078C0A4895A3B3532C05A6269A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>utility facility</term> means electric substations, communication facilities, towers, poles, and lines, ground wires, communications circuits, and other structures, and related infrastructure; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7557C3246D9C4228BF6499536D9A36FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <term>water resource facility</term> means irrigation and pumping facilities; dams and reservoirs; flood control facilities; water conservation works, including debris protection facilities, sediment placement sites, rain gauges, and stream gauges; water quality, recycled water, and pumping facilities; conveyance distribution systems; water treatment facilities; aqueducts; canals; ditches; pipelines; wells; hydropower projects; transmission facilities; and other ancillary facilities, groundwater recharge facilities, water conservation, water filtration plants, and other water diversion, conservation, groundwater recharge, storage, and carriage structures.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


