<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H7BD1C8DA81DC4946BAA5D4A087BB88CE" key="H" public-private="public">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3572 IH: Making College More Affordable Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3572</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20170728">July 28, 2017</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To carry out an income-contingent repayment program for Federal Interest Free Education Loans for undergraduate students, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form> 
<legis-body id="HCCC79ACBB5024279970F1E10B8D14976" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6CDCAD8E160A4D1FB88187ECD9762087" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Making College More Affordable Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="HE3044331BC7E44FA9447B36AD2F010B9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Direct Federal Undergraduate Loans and repayment plan</header> <subsection id="HCA3EFCC12D9541439DE5E555E5D20B08"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Interest rates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 455(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEE5C83FD3AF54A1383B662A008159276" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H216B801D15B9409EACF194F703E102EC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Undergraduate loans on or after the date of enactment of the Making College More Affordable Act</header> 
<subparagraph id="H281D706D000948EE8D17FA1BF15781B6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, a new borrower on or after the date of enactment of the Making College More Affordable Act may only borrow a Federal Interest Free Education Loan for the undergraduate course work being pursued by such borrower.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC03287796A30422498A17DB36D81D721"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Terms, conditions, and benefits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Federal Interest Free Education Loan shall have the same terms and conditions, and benefits to borrowers as Federal Direct Stafford Loans with respect to undergraduate borrowers, except that—</text> 
<clause id="HF99ECC09DA714FF29AA19C0FA7C29EB3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a Federal Interest Free Education Loan shall have an applicable rate of interest of 3.76 percent for the term of the loan;</text> </clause> <clause id="H03151BEED87C4203AACB88F2EE2F98DF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the aggregate maximum amount of Federal Interest Free Education Loan that may be awarded to a borrower shall be $90,000, for not more than a 4-year academic period;</text> </clause>
<clause id="H313D664E36364E318AE5BF845D1B3D7B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">interest on a Federal Interest Free Education Loan shall only accrue during periods when a borrower is not earning taxable income due to professional negligence, professional incompetence, or malicious action on the part of the borrower;</text> </clause> <clause id="H3E5AAD01CE4743348125E3B8ADBF99C5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a borrower may consolidate any loan under section 428B, or a Federal Direct PLUS Loan, that is made, insured, or guaranteed on behalf of such borrower with the Federal Interest Free Education Loan of such borrower;</text> </clause>
<clause id="H9933B4500A694087A7F2DF4E2393D27A"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a Federal Interest Free Education Loan may only be repaid under the income-contingent repayment plan under subsection (r); and</text> </clause> <clause id="H67B03D0D2A4640D9A1809CECA63C24A1"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary may determine other terms and conditions, and benefits to borrowers of a Federal Interest Free Education Loan.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection>
<subsection id="H84DEFC4AEFFA47598EC2D4B188C3F1DB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Income-Contingent repayment plan for undergraduate loans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 455 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e</external-xref>) is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD4EB2B44FB4F4C96AECFBB4B9CEFA295" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HED3E5FC1597E4D04A0A8BBC9BA18567B"><enum>(r)</enum><header>Income-Contingent repayment plan for undergraduate loans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, the Secretary shall carry out a program under which—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC1EB228AF84847C0B9EACCB6DBCB29AD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a borrower of a Federal Interest Free Education Loan—</text> <subparagraph id="HF96473EC41D148319D52364B3032CEAD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall have an aggregate monthly payment for the outstanding balance of principal and interest due on all such loans automatically withheld from the pre-tax income of the borrower by the employer of the borrower in a manner which—</text> 
<clause id="HE239CE66B62C4A8791EE1CAF99D6BAED"><enum>(i)</enum><text>prohibits employers from using any information about an employee’s outstanding balance or principal and interest due on such loans for any purpose of use as an advantage against the employee;</text> </clause> <clause id="H34A1D849C38141F9B70C2BD5CEDF7028"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is determined by the Secretary, in coordination with the heads of other appropriate Federal agencies (including the Secretary of the Treasury and the Commissioner of the Social Security Administration); and</text> </clause>
<clause id="H488B99FFBF78491F83311ABA6E8031F3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is an amount equal to—</text> <subclause id="H630FC2E079B548AA970F5D4A745DEAF2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>if the borrower’s gross income is less than 337 percent of the poverty line applicable to the borrower’s family size as determined under section 673(2) of the Community Services Block Grant Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9902">42 U.S.C. 9902(2)</external-xref>), $0;</text> </subclause>
<subclause id="H3CA22C65BFDE4A3D9323BF473F0B2DEC"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the borrower’s gross income is equal to or greater than 337 percent, but not more than 841 percent of such poverty line; 4 percent of the borrower’s gross income;</text> </subclause> <subclause id="HC329A4DA71844903B61DA267A7B1FC86"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the borrower’s gross income is equal to or greater than 842 percent, but not more than 925 percent of such poverty line, 5 percent of the borrower’s gross income;</text> </subclause>
<subclause id="HBEBB5EF3D71B49C3B324F786B7C94E17"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the borrower’s gross income is equal to or greater than 926 percent, but not more than 1,010 percent of such poverty line, 6 percent of the borrower’s gross income;</text> </subclause> <subclause id="H66F10DAA60AA420B8B1464581E01BC92"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the borrower’s gross income is equal to or greater than 1,011 percent, but not more than 1,094 percent of such poverty line, 7 percent of the borrower’s gross income;</text> </subclause>
<subclause id="H456A229538D4495D92ABD4C5DEC83089"><enum>(VI)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the borrower’s gross income is equal to or greater than 1,095 percent, but not more than 1,178 percent of such poverty line, 8 percent of the borrower’s gross income;</text> </subclause> <subclause id="H69A889E7783143489AD5E923605F6EB9"><enum>(VII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the borrower’s gross income is equal to or greater than 1,179 percent, and 1,262 percent of such poverty line, 9 percent of the borrower’s gross income; and</text> </subclause>
<subclause id="HA128D8B309AE4521BA323D6DFC991C12"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the borrower’s gross income is equal to or greater than 1,263 percent of such poverty line, 10 percent of the borrower’s gross income;</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H82FBD6200B6745C9AB0F8A770DEEEC1A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may elect to have any payments made under subparagraph (A) that exceed the amount owed by the borrower on such loans for a calendar year be refunded to the borrower or applied to the amount owed by the borrower on such loans for the succeeding calendar year;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4CFECAD594F946F1B9A6298F8F4E4ABB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary will cancel any outstanding balance of principal or interest due on all Federal Interest Free Education Loans made to a borrower who has made 300 monthly payments under this subsection; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H3DBD48120A554FC9A8298ACE892FAEBB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a borrower will be taxed on the amount cancelled under paragraph (2), which taxes shall be applied to carry out the Federal Direct Loan program under this part.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection></section>
</legis-body>
</bill> 


