<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H25303B2CD1794F9C8F319DEC0D53D078" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3359 : Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3359</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date date="20171212">December 12, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to authorize the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure
			 Security Agency of the Department of Homeland Security, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HD3D63EC8C5D64F82AEB92363E34F2B56" style="OLC">
 <section id="H483DB096B988457CBF86E4020CCCFD6F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HA1E16EBD43F3499D89DD89E54219DF34"><enum>2.</enum><header>Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency</header> <subsection id="H3DD377F202B246858D099FD6DCC6F9D1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended by adding at the end the following new title:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H8473D7BC14B54AAA83FC76E31D903FB2" style="OLC">
					<title id="H5786C25FE5714889ADD5ED0421EB3863"><enum>XXII</enum><header>Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency</header>
						<subtitle id="H411E20690B9C46DB9A773331E3CCC6EC"><enum>A</enum><header>Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security</header>
 <section id="H4A3EEED3CF2C46528808B5752808A6E9"><enum>2201.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this subtitle:</text> <paragraph id="HB1654AC2DB314D05B7985EAEAC345872"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Critical infrastructure information</header><text>The term <quote>critical infrastructure information</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 2215.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC7D079EC9DB64CE68F85A5F9CDA9A2A6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cybersecurity risk</header><text>The term <quote>cybersecurity risk</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 2209.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4A9E1AE5BDD24994A181F7E203B55931"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cybersecurity threat</header><text>The term <quote>cybersecurity threat</quote> has the meaning given such term in paragraph (5) of section 102 of the Cybersecurity Act of 2015 (contained in division N of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/113">Public Law 114–113</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/1501">6 U.S.C. 1501</external-xref>)).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H86885767B8D14422AD6A85D7A4899267"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Federal entity</header><text>The term <quote>Federal entity</quote> has the meaning given such term in paragraph (8) of section 102 of the Cybersecurity Act of 2015 (contained in division N of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/113">Public Law 114–113</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/1501">6 U.S.C. 1501</external-xref>)).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA6D2358CEEEE4381969BC2AE02F73EC5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Non-Federal entity</header><text>The term <quote>non-Federal entity</quote> has the meaning given such term in paragraph (14) of section 102 of the Cybersecurity Act of 2015 (contained in division N of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/113">Public Law 114–113</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/1501">6 U.S.C. 1501</external-xref>)).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H61737E3688044660806F5A09CE07B9BB"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Sector-Specific Agency</header><text>The term <quote>Sector-Specific Agency</quote> means a Federal department or agency, designated by law or presidential directive, with responsibility for providing institutional knowledge and specialized expertise of a sector, as well as leading, facilitating, or supporting programs and associated activities of its designated critical infrastructure sector in the all hazards environment in coordination with the Department.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H510533B8DE7349A083CFBC27EC4D88F2"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Sharing</header><text>The term <quote>sharing</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 2209.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H880009174FAC4FB3B902EBDBE8DB0211"><enum>(8)</enum><header>National cybersecurity asset response activities</header><text>The term <quote>national cybersecurity asset response activities</quote> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC112DBA2E29441C3ACF345C8B6349274"><enum>(A)</enum><text>furnishing cybersecurity technical assistance to entities affected by cybersecurity risks to protect assets, mitigate vulnerabilities, and reduce impacts of cyber incidents;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9375C8ED70E045D18851B8B15625B34C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identifying other entities that may be at risk of an incident and assessing risk to the same or similar vulnerabilities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H155CA889418F4C8D88DD49520BA3D015"><enum>(C)</enum><text>assessing potential cybersecurity risks to a sector or region, including potential cascading effects, and developing courses of action to mitigate such risks;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87D109C988C4428FA2D9D170309C3185"><enum>(D)</enum><text>facilitating information sharing and operational coordination with threat response; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H773EA051873242088410E5E4E3F673DA"><enum>(E)</enum><text>providing guidance on how best to utilize Federal resources and capabilities in a timely, effective manner to speed recovery from cybersecurity risks.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HFDE317D3C5364C9E9B5F6E2507C0AC0E"><enum>2202.</enum><header>Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency</header>
								<subsection id="H7312AB580C074DB98CF85FF329C9E2AC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Redesignation</header>
 <paragraph id="H497BD57E389D4856833839D0C9C09633"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The National Protection and Programs Directorate of the Department shall, on and after the date of the enactment of this subtitle, be known as the <quote>Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency</quote> (in this subtitle referred to as the <quote>Agency</quote>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H669E77BA4D4D496FAC943C588CBD2A7E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>References</header><text>Any reference to the National Protection and Programs Directorate of the Department in any law, regulation, map, document, record, or other paper of the United States shall be deemed to be a reference to the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency of the Department.</text>
									</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H19EE276C97CD46DEBCB946C1E9D6026B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Director</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HC8C05F8728AE4C939B6D5E6D18BE6ADB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Agency shall be headed by a Director of Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security (in this subtitle referred to as the <quote>Director</quote>), who shall report to the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H63918FDD4A0941BBA5C2B1BEA0334B33"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reference</header><text>Any reference to an Under Secretary responsible for overseeing critical infrastructure protection, cybersecurity, and any other related program of the Department as described in section 103(a)(1)(H) as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this subtitle in any law, regulation, map, document, record, or other paper of the United States shall be deemed to be a reference to the Director of Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security of the Department.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD9BA4ED5072A48D5B990485341F42185"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>The Director shall—</text> <paragraph id="H2FE8806865B9458893248CF4236245E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>lead cybersecurity and critical infrastructure security programs, operations, and associated policy for the Agency, including national cybersecurity asset response activities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H10270308949A40369B210F52F74C6D62"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinate with Federal entities, including Sector-Specific Agencies, and non-Federal entities, including international entities, to carry out the cybersecurity and critical infrastructure activities of the Agency, as appropriate;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H36B8E27D674F44C497B1B6CE7182CBF2"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">carry out the Secretary’s responsibilities to secure Federal information and information systems consistent with law, including subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code, and the Cybersecurity Act of 2015 (contained in division N of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/113">Public Law 114–113</external-xref>));</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC26DD79ECBA5413FA3338EC3EBD1D7B5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>coordinate a national effort to secure and protect against critical infrastructure risks, consistent with subsection (e)(1)(E);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBBBF790FB8DB48EA8C9D57AB08879495"><enum>(5)</enum><text>upon request provide analyses, expertise, and other technical assistance to critical infrastructure owners and operators and, where appropriate, provide such analyses, expertise, and other technical assistance in coordination with Sector-Specific Agencies and other Federal departments and agencies;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2B62EEFDFC6A4E7C8BB0BCFEBCF9AD49"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop and utilize mechanisms for active and frequent collaboration between the Agency and Sector-Specific Agencies to ensure appropriate coordination, situational awareness, and communications with Sector-Specific Agencies;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H68CC9F9BA8384E3F8A2650E8596BCE68"><enum>(7)</enum><text>maintain and utilize mechanisms for the regular and ongoing consultation and collaboration among the Agency’s Divisions to further operational coordination, integrated situational awareness, and improved integration across the Agency in accordance with this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HED96327A0B044436ADD3889A4E3D96FF"><enum>(8)</enum><text>develop, coordinate, and implement—</text> <subparagraph id="H1F5FB30C9EF74FD0BEED8117F18EEBF6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>comprehensive strategic plans for the activities of the Agency; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22FA6DE22672461AB187B835703C72B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">risk assessments by and for the Agency;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF64C187361040D699FDB23056B1317E"><enum>(9)</enum><text>carry out emergency communications responsibilities, in accordance with title XVIII;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H175FF4442DE84F8E8AC92F9EE275E938"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">carry out cybersecurity, infrastructure security, and emergency communications stakeholder outreach and engagement and coordinate such outreach and engagement with critical infrastructure Sector-Specific Agencies, as appropriate; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF4FE3AD22EB54E85B138BFF9A5725B37"><enum>(11)</enum><text>carry out such other duties and powers prescribed by law or delegated by the Secretary.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H41B5EC5F35E14D7FB7F4B41499751DFE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Deputy director</header><text>There shall be in the Agency a Deputy Director of Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security who shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE3B45B2E8B014BC081589F8C1CA6C348"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assist the Director in the management of the Agency; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA7D63033366A400FB2CB7B4F0D39AAA5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>report to the Director.</text>
									</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HD9968D7986284F4AB0D3E0DEE4C80D9D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Cybersecurity and infrastructure security authorities of the Secretary</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H40A1C61F643E430F80CBBB92BE8215AC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The responsibilities of the Secretary relating to cybersecurity and infrastructure security shall include the following:</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HA8A02301C3F149F49BDB719CEE946AAE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>To access, receive, and analyze law enforcement information, intelligence information, and other information from Federal Government agencies, State, local, tribal, and territorial government agencies (including law enforcement agencies), and private sector entities, and to integrate such information, in support of the mission responsibilities of the Department, in order to—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H26F7AFF2FED742F4ABD7ACE2B9FA6312"><enum>(i)</enum><text>identify and assess the nature and scope of terrorist threats to the homeland;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H759E062D4C1549A19C05D17420B513A3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>detect and identify threats of terrorism against the United States; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HFAEF1DE8428848EEBFC1D738432546FF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>understand such threats in light of actual and potential vulnerabilities of the homeland.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA25F55FAC2DB43B289DE4852DADB6635"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out comprehensive assessments of the vulnerabilities of the key resources and critical infrastructure of the United States, including the performance of risk assessments to determine the risks posed by particular types of terrorist attacks within the United States (including an assessment of the probability of success of such attacks and the feasibility and potential efficacy of various countermeasures to such attacks). At the discretion of the Secretary, such assessments may be carried out in coordination with Sector-Specific Agencies.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H60C7A11B5C624FA98D4C09628868806D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To integrate relevant information, analysis, and vulnerability assessments (regardless of whether such information, analysis, or assessments are provided or produced by the Department) in order to make recommendations, including prioritization, for protective and support measures by the Department, other Federal Government agencies, State, local, tribal, and territorial government agencies and authorities, the private sector, and other entities regarding terrorist and other threats to homeland security.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7FBECE160CD14F90B1F66A689975F47C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>To ensure, pursuant to section 202, the timely and efficient access by the Department to all information necessary to discharge the responsibilities under this title, including obtaining such information from other Federal Government agencies.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0F4818CDD823419996464F1C2A58F629"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To develop, in coordination with the Sector-Specific Agencies with available expertise, a comprehensive national plan for securing the key resources and critical infrastructure of the United States, including power production, generation, and distribution systems, information technology and telecommunications systems (including satellites), electronic financial and property record storage and transmission systems, emergency communications systems, and the physical and technological assets that support such systems.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HEDD284F92E8A42C8B4FFC513088B9C05"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To recommend measures necessary to protect the key resources and critical infrastructure of the United States in coordination with other Federal Government agencies, including Sector-Specific Agencies, and in cooperation with State, local, tribal, and territorial government agencies and authorities, the private sector, and other entities.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4C59834581A7444596AECFC2F921CD6E"><enum>(G)</enum><text>To review, analyze, and make recommendations for improvements to the policies and procedures governing the sharing of information relating to homeland security within the Federal Government and between Federal Government agencies and State, local, tribal, and territorial government agencies and authorities.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6F4237CBC5EE46FD9E1942BCAB025904"><enum>(H)</enum><text>To disseminate, as appropriate, information analyzed by the Department within the Department, to other Federal Government agencies with responsibilities relating to homeland security, and to State, local, tribal, and territorial government agencies and private sector entities with such responsibilities in order to assist in the deterrence, prevention, preemption of, or response to, terrorist attacks against the United States.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4A1324FCDBF94E8880CB3E4D5FD15D82"><enum>(I)</enum><text>To consult with State, local, tribal, and territorial government agencies and private sector entities to ensure appropriate exchanges of information, including law enforcement-related information, relating to threats of terrorism against the United States.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD15B9AAEE9B54DF4AAF0FFF2F7DDEB67"><enum>(J)</enum><text>To ensure that any material received pursuant to this Act is protected from unauthorized disclosure and handled and used only for the performance of official duties.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HCF3902FF1EF74A8F8943694E8D321C45"><enum>(K)</enum><text>To request additional information from other Federal Government agencies, State, local, tribal, and territorial government agencies, and the private sector relating to threats of terrorism in the United States, or relating to other areas of responsibility assigned by the Secretary, including the entry into cooperative agreements through the Secretary to obtain such information.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H30194E14CC3649BDA437110BD54E49B1"><enum>(L)</enum><text>To establish and utilize, in conjunction with the chief information officer of the Department, a secure communications and information technology infrastructure, including data-mining and other advanced analytical tools, in order to access, receive, and analyze data and information in furtherance of the responsibilities under this section, and to disseminate information acquired and analyzed by the Department, as appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H44868BDAF3224A42A34A4CB5A225E64B"><enum>(M)</enum><text>To coordinate training and other support to the elements and personnel of the Department, other Federal Government agencies, and State, local, tribal, and territorial government agencies that provide information to the Department, or are consumers of information provided by the Department, in order to facilitate the identification and sharing of information revealed in their ordinary duties and the optimal utilization of information received from the Department.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HEB1B1EDF3E0F415D8C0EF537FE44E4DF"><enum>(N)</enum><text>To coordinate with Federal, State, local, tribal, and territorial law enforcement agencies, and the private sector, as appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5BFCA673C0B5402090A9D4DF49A72FA0"><enum>(O)</enum><text>To exercise the authorities and oversight of the functions, personnel, assets, and liabilities of those components transferred to the Department pursuant to section 201(g).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2470F5FA35674C478FCE1944BDDF8335"><enum>(P)</enum><text>To carry out the functions of the national cybersecurity and communications integration center under section 2209.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0ED9CF39DF44252B972F6D1DA9C8404"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>To carry out requirements of the Chemical Facilities Anti-Terrorism Standards Program established under title XXI and the secure handling of ammonium nitrate established under subtitle J of title VIII.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC57030F6F34C445CA99160D838E169A8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reallocation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may reallocate within the Agency the functions specified in sections 2203(b) and 2204(b), consistent with the responsibilities provided in paragraph (1) of this subsection, upon certifying to and briefing the appropriate congressional committees, and making available to the public, at least 60 days prior to any such reallocation that such reallocation is necessary for carrying out the activities of the Agency.</text>
									</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H829E13D7E2974A14980394D27DBF854C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Staff</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HE81F2F85F746441EB7FB9CD4A84A60FB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide the Agency with a staff of analysts having appropriate expertise and experience to assist the Agency in discharging its responsibilities under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4BC234C014CF4C5CA803511A9EF4E642"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Private sector analysts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Analysts under this subsection may include analysts from the private sector.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H637BFC611B964B64BE3131F2AB2EBBBC"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Security clearances</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Analysts under this subsection shall possess security clearances appropriate for their work under this section.</text>
										</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H1402034B8FD84DBE9201D0E3938FE617"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Detail of personnel</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HD9BF2E966E664A1F8CE5ADE0E2D5F120"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to assist the Agency in discharging its responsibilities under this section, personnel of the Federal agencies referred to in subparagraph (B) may be detailed to the Agency for the performance of analytic functions and related duties.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H520EFA8BD62842059385097B6CB710EA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Agencies specified</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal agencies referred to in subparagraph (A) are the following:</text> <clause commented="no" id="HF53595AF76F241008FE054DEF7BBE117"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Department of State.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HCEFA60C18CDB4A44AACAC7AC3C35A711"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Central Intelligence Agency.</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HA8BDAD18F6F241F3872DDC4B3788683E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The Federal Bureau of Investigation.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H1AA454237EA14986AA65D17873BC1723"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The National Security Agency.</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HE077B5F1BCE54481A8236113A82CB6AE"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H6B650B68631C4009B414691437FFD0BC"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The Defense Intelligence Agency.</text> </clause><clause id="H111903A8288449A7AF3F6DA12B9D16B4"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sector-Specific Agencies.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HFF02CEBCE126440B8CF98BE4089FCA5D"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Any other agency of the Federal Government that the President considers appropriate.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H826AD110AE9D47389F5715CED70B0281"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Interagency agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary and the head of an agency specified in subparagraph (B) may enter into agreements for the purpose of detailing personnel under this paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H528884BFE82E4BEDB7AFA5B0655FF8BA"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Basis</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The detail of personnel under this paragraph may be on a reimbursable or non-reimbursable basis.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H89E5E6455FBB4986AADB441AB4B555A6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The Agency shall be composed of the following divisions:</text>
 <paragraph id="H05ADD09579124473A013095333431280"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Cybersecurity Division, headed by an Assistant Director.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6F8EEE2316444B93AE9374C5AEC51E70"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Infrastructure Security Division, headed by an Assistant Director.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0B26E4128AC8486E9099BB5D0ABAAD3A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Emergency Communications Division under title XVIII, headed by an Assistant Director.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0673AB5223134608990B8063D4577ADA"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Co-Location</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the maximum extent practicable, the Director shall examine the establishment of central locations in geographical regions with a significant Agency presence. When establishing such locations, the Director shall coordinate with component heads and the Under Secretary for Management to co-locate or partner on any new real property leases, renewing any occupancy agreements for existing leases, or agreeing to extend or newly occupy any Federal space or new construction.</text>
								</subsection><subsection id="H53C91EDBD1D7467587546DFA7833167B"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Privacy</header>
 <paragraph id="H5204772B085D4310B39FC9498D7C5329"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There shall be a Privacy Officer of the Agency with primary responsibility for privacy policy and compliance for the Agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2B18A314D63C4E2D8F6C2C72896CA9FC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>The responsibilities of the Privacy Officer of the Agency shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="H8D9715B943684A0FAC4F4BAD36825E3A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assuring that the use of technologies by the Agency sustain, and do not erode, privacy protections relating to the use, collection, and disclosure of personal information;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5F6770F47914E8C9EC71212251E61B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assuring that personal information contained in Privacy Act systems of records of the Agency is handled in full compliance with fair information practices as specified in the Privacy Act of 1974;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE6BB3A822FB04E1095844A920CE7F957"><enum>(C)</enum><text>evaluating legislative and regulatory proposals involving collection, use, and disclosure of personal information by the Agency; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4D9EB43C84274F1D802724646A2ADAC8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>conducting a privacy impact assessment of proposed rules of the Agency on the privacy of personal information, including the type of personal information collected and the number of people affected.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCC6ACFFCB2A3487DA5105AD6DB7CDDF2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Savings</header><text>Nothing in this title may be construed as affecting in any manner the authority, existing on the day before the date of the enactment of this title, of any other component of the Department or any other Federal department or agency.</text>
								</subsection></section><section id="H5E099062DF0A4955A395D970CB192AA0"><enum>2203.</enum><header>Cybersecurity Division</header>
								<subsection id="H775E7E66C6334959989F2FE54BC456DD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header>
 <paragraph id="H1104C0308CA0496B9FBD140CB1B3C0D6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established in the Agency a Cybersecurity Division.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H05CFB26E653E4A0FA8A3FE54FFDBE147"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assistant Director</header><text>The Cybersecurity Division shall be headed by an Assistant Director for Cybersecurity (in this subtitle referred to as the <quote>Assistant Director</quote>), who shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H548C6AEE9AED48FF81EC4B660B96B555"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be at the level of Assistant Secretary within the Department;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE8FBC25CDAC54050A2FFAD28917E1466"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be appointed by the President without the advice and consent of the Senate; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6050A410DE0D4F0B9D7E71673C6AFF91"><enum>(C)</enum><text>report to the Director.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H109FBB9ADD35400F99EB0C94F1C549AF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reference</header><text>Any reference to the Assistant Secretary for Cybersecurity and Communications in any law, regulation, map, document, record, or other paper of the United States shall be deemed to be a reference to the Assistant Director for Cybersecurity.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HDA1BC4E852684895975B3654609C2F43"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The Assistant Director shall—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H2A2B5EDDE66743FA97029679E7743E54"><enum>(1)</enum><text>direct the cybersecurity efforts of the Agency;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA59056AF56784048B0A0945F51CB596E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>carry out activities, at the direction of the Director, related to the security of Federal information and Federal information systems consistent with law, including subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code, and the Cybersecurity Act of 2015 (contained in division N of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/113">Public Law 114–113</external-xref>));</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H28A1FE7D683246D8B6F45EBB331CAD3F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>fully participate in the mechanisms required under subsection (c)(7) of section 2202; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA9FA9B115BEA4E2C8E48A1C7784E30DA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>carry out such other duties and powers as prescribed by the Director.</text>
									</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HDCD56BD6268344C3B501794584901E18"><enum>2204.</enum><header>Infrastructure Security Division</header>
								<subsection id="H7DED6B65FF114A87A14121D00CAA7E8A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header>
 <paragraph id="H0C2B0E3B03854791AE746123D7E4BC63"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established in the Agency an Infrastructure Security Division.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H58C8634DF25D4BA1976C7EA3F4AE8683"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assistant Director</header><text>The Infrastructure Security Division shall be headed by an Assistant Director of Infrastructure Security (in this section referred to as the <quote>Assistant Director</quote>), who shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3F6987A6B1E842F39D11628A3EBB4999"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be at the level of Assistant Secretary within the Department;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HABA7F051968346C4A4A7C8C3A5991184"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be appointed by the President without the advice and consent of the Senate; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F6790996CA14D709211E69F2B08D78C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>report to the Director.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H774CA835C24F46BD92DEC9971D9A0AED"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reference</header><text>Any reference to the Assistant Secretary for Infrastructure Protection in any law, regulation, map, document, record, or other paper of the United States shall be deemed to be a reference to the Assistant Director for Infrastructure Security.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC01D91CA915D4BEBAAF855CD2C5C7D3A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The Assistant Director shall—</text> <paragraph id="HD7BF99D3399D4CF0BF049F7E08C95FDC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>direct the critical infrastructure security efforts of the Agency;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFEBDF12900E7447F89FBF4876DB09B68"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">carry, at the direction of the Director, the Chemical Facilities Anti-Terrorism Standards Program established under title XXI and the secure handling of ammonium nitrate established under subtitle J of title VIII or successor program;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7B5A1AA24E7E454C82BBE7C0E5642156"><enum>(3)</enum><text>fully participate in the mechanisms required under subsection (c)(7) of section 2202; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5DEE547D78694DCFB448AB91021E5E3E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>carry out such other duties and powers as prescribed by the Director.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></subtitle></title><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H793A6A6A7804478FAD9F11AE8B8635B2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment of certain positions</header>
 <paragraph id="H3FD2541C5CA84ACC9609D746A9CFB146"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Under Secretary</header><text>The individual serving as the Under Secretary appointed pursuant to section 103(a)(1)(H) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/113">6 U.S.C. 113(a)(1)</external-xref>) of the Department of Homeland Security on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act may continue to serve as the Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency of the Department on and after such date.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8DCAF03D869E4441A2586623F9610D03"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Director for Emergency Communications</header><text>The individual serving as the Director for Emergency Communications of the Department of Homeland Security on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act may continue to serve as the Assistant Director for Emergency Communications of the Department on and after such date.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2C66F30DA6314C4E972522744F158882"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Assistant Secretary for Cybersecurity and Communications</header><text>The individual serving as the Assistant Secretary for Cybersecurity and Communications on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act may continue to serve as the Assistant Director for Cybersecurity on and after such date.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H05C118D94AF24C84BEAB4E9831AE47C2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Assistant Secretary for Infrastructure Security</header><text>The individual serving as the Assistant Secretary for Infrastructure Protection on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act may continue to serve as the Assistant Director for Infrastructure Security on and after such date.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF3876D0C51DD427D86E9A458C66A2846"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reference</header><text>Any reference to—</text> <paragraph id="HE7CAD0C1B1744DACBC8D6FB3EC3376F9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Office of Emergency Communications in any law, regulation, map, document, record, or other paper of the United States shall be deemed to be a reference to the Emergency Communications Division; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBA26080248A44B9F8EAC7C64673BB337"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Director for Emergency Communications in any law, regulation, map, document, record, or other paper of the United States shall be deemed to be a reference to the Assistant Director for Emergency Communications.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H34EB405E7D8E4368BB668F100D1F2D91"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Oversight</header><text>The Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency of the Department of Homeland Security shall provide to Congress, in accordance with the deadlines specified in paragraphs (1) and (2), information on the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H097230616CE142E5A8A422447A16F2E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, a briefing on the activities of the Agency relating to the development and use of the mechanisms required pursuant to section 2202(c)(6) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (as added by subsection (a) of this section).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBAB7BF75BF58436C8A172BC9C16CD3DF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, a briefing on the activities of the Agency relating to its use and improvement of the mechanisms required pursuant to section 2202(c)(6) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 and how such activities have impacted coordination, situational awareness, and communications with Sector-Specific Agencies.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4EB130D5E4724C42BBF1AD4AC01F3868"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, information on the Agency’s mechanisms for regular and ongoing consultation and collaboration, as required pursuant to section 2202(c)(7) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (as added by subsection (a) of this section).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H45895B10DA78416BA719527F75D18BBA"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the activities of the Agency’s consultation and collaboration mechanisms as required pursuant to section 2202(c)(7) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, and how such mechanisms have impacted operational coordination, situational awareness, and integration across the Agency.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H6EEB92BD19EE42BDA11AFD7D60FC137D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Cyber workforce</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this subtitle, the Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency of the Department of Homeland Security shall submit to Congress a report detailing how the Agency is meeting legislative requirements under the Cybersecurity Workforce Assessment Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/246">Public Law 113–246</external-xref>) and the Homeland Security Cybersecurity Workforce Assessment Act (enacted as section 4 of the Border Patrol Agent Pay Reform Act of 2014; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/277">Public Law 113–277</external-xref>) to address cyber workforce needs.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HF1F307F5F3E042C293DBEB295D684852"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Facility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency of the Department of Homeland Security shall report to Congress on the most efficient and effective methods of consolidating Agency facilities, personnel, and programs to most effectively carry out the Agency’s mission.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H25A9C655DDD746CA8A95D842FBEDEE6A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Conforming amendments to the Homeland Security Act of 2002</header><text>The Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H8E5B19E9AC6F42C690497A31A05509D3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in title I, by amending subparagraph (H) of section 103(a)(1) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/113">6 U.S.C. 113(a)(1)</external-xref>) to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block id="HEEA28249192842F9802C146226DAA046" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H386DCC854D244B9AB36AD7506DBD3EC0"><enum>(H)</enum><text>A Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H31E3961F0BBA43A6BFECFB9B6B18B822"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in title II (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/121">6 U.S.C. 121</external-xref> et seq.)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4C9D115BDAD44F2A97DE064F2A0068CD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the title heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="title" style="OLC">and infrastructure protection</header-in-text></quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H30672793502340119B9E25C3275D7484"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the subtitle A heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subtitle" style="OLC">and infrastructure protection</header-in-text></quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H545E84BE77924C84B8341212358AAE1B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in section 201 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/121">6 U.S.C. 121</external-xref>)—</text> <clause id="H320AE184B82E4C37B683014D273F27FD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the section heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">and infrastructure protection</header-in-text></quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2A197442ED184BC988D9217D56673547"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <subclause id="H97985A1C5A3B4EE1B70B25445EB0BCBE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">and infrastructure protection</header-in-text></quote>; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H9BD96996EFB944C0A6D7D2B93DB31E8E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and an Office of Infrastructure Protection</quote>;</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H7154B511BD2643E295A54882AE38B6CC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text>
 <subclause id="H507CDDCB3C1740F4A8FB35B68F1CA190"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">and Assistant Secretary for Infrastructure Protection</header-in-text></quote>; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HCA95164553BC4B02AF17C6FAF3E1BBF5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (3);</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HCC120A832B3D4CD4BB0930FFC3BE4805"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text> <subclause id="H65B1E0B8FF5F447BB6C949C69B14D8D3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and infrastructure protection</quote>; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB5B2C3ED89E846C78B28C67D1014BE39"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or the Assistant Secretary for Infrastructure Protection, as appropriate</quote>;</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HD5EB5F975C9F4D768A6A6527BFA09638"><enum>(v)</enum><text>in subsection (d)—</text>
 <subclause id="HFF0FC6F96CD84D518158E37A4DE23F5F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">and infrastructure protection</header-in-text></quote>;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H4AB3DB5260A94A27BFBD656C7F0FEA04"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>and infrastructure protection</quote>;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H7D8806CC6CA0461587BCB306E67DA3F2"><enum>(III)</enum><text>by striking paragraphs (5) and (6) and redesignating paragraphs (7) through (26) as paragraphs (5) through (24), respectively;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HC4020A03EE7C4D58B43471DC5AD3AEC8"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (23), as so redesignated; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H91D372967EE7469E9A816F9CFBAE3428"><enum>(V)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (24), as so redesignated, as paragraph (23);</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HEBEA845B1A7A41859B3E6477E2D0E2F9"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>in subsection (e)(1), by striking <quote>and the Office of Infrastructure Protection</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H0E79ACE163B2419F94CE8BC4D0B6B823"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>in subsection (f)(1), by striking <quote>and the Office of Infrastructure Protection</quote>;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22B4C354C22E48B5A589E592C788D38F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in section 204 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/124a">6 U.S.C. 124a</external-xref>)—</text> <clause id="H357C357DC2E34B1C9D0FF2EAB1ECB969"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(1), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>Assistant Secretary for Infrastructure Protection</quote> and inserting <quote>Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE9F3D92B927B4CD98EF9EF570E8340F5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(1), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>Assistant Secretary for Infrastructure Protection</quote> and inserting <quote>Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency</quote>;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72516C24FB954B138CD73DBC7FD8EF30"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B) of section 210A(c)(2) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/124h">6 U.S.C. 124h(c)(2)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>Office of Infrastructure Protection</quote> and inserting <quote>Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC062E964F9F74BD095C44AC922F5BC74"><enum>(F)</enum><text>by transferring section 210E (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/124">6 U.S.C. 124</external-xref>) to appear after section 2213 (as redesignated by subparagraph (H) of this paragraph) and redesignating such section 210E as section 2214;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H689B2F397FE540538A47CF5DA202E5B3"><enum>(G)</enum><text>in subtitle B, by redesignating sections 211 through 215 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/101">6 U.S.C. 101</external-xref> note through 134) as sections 2221 through 2225, respectively, and inserting such redesignated sections, including the enumerator and heading of subtitle B (containing such redesignated sections), after section 2214, as redesignated by subparagraph (F) of this paragraph; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7CF110F0A8794CDF81BF29BEA472C831"><enum>(H)</enum><text>by redesignating sections 223 through 230 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/143">6 U.S.C. 143</external-xref> through 151) as sections 2205 through 2213, respectively, and inserting such redesignated sections after section 2204, as added by this Act;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1BD43909FCE4000B8B40765C39A0C00"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in title III, in paragraph (3) of section 302 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/182">6 U.S.C. 182</external-xref>), by striking <quote>Assistant Secretary for Infrastructure Protection</quote> and inserting <quote>Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3C19559DE7B64F65A16D7105B7CFC393"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in title V—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7E35D2AC2E5E4456AC76147EC4571B65"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in section 514 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/321c">6 U.S.C. 321c</external-xref>), by—</text> <clause id="HCBCA9AB040A541ACA2E12374BCCE8505"><enum>(i)</enum><text>striking subsection (b); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H47999F3FFDE5489F8A5B67DE4901C4BC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>redesignating subsection (c) as subsection (b);</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4AEE2CE0A6174A39A17D13D7FC2FEB17"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in section 523 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/321l">6 U.S.C. 321l</external-xref>)—</text>
 <clause id="HE22B62F2FE6F4751AEA558CA2482D8AD"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a), in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>Assistant Secretary for Infrastructure Protection</quote> and inserting <quote>Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H24AC1DC810FE4792957E500DBF130D2E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c), by striking <quote>Assistant Secretary for Infrastructure Protection</quote> and inserting <quote>Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency</quote>; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D381064A86E4FA7AF6B2B00BE7AA5AE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in section 524(a)(2)(B) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/321m">6 U.S.C. 321m(a)(2)(B)</external-xref>), in the matter preceding clause (i)—</text> <clause id="H2B02347928D04F3E98475695E8A72539"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Assistant Secretary for Infrastructure Protection</quote> and inserting <quote>Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC9E6C3F6A5E942D6B5F386A5817F59FD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>of the Assistant Secretary</quote> and inserting <quote>of the Director</quote>;</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HABB0633D66F54D73B118E06DC8D2FD0E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in title VIII, in section 899B(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/488a">6 U.S.C. 488a(a)</external-xref>), by inserting at the end the following new sentence: <quote>Such regulations shall be carried out by the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency.</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3F3482FE258C4AE3BBE29584D8AB53AC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in title XVIII (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/571">6 U.S.C. 571</external-xref> et seq.)—</text> <subparagraph id="HDA45752BDA7A4DE597AA2B310355BCF0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in section 1801 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/571">6 U.S.C. 571</external-xref>)—</text>
 <clause id="H382658F0AB1C4306BCE5EAD60E197DFB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the section heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Office of Emergency Communications</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Emergency Communications Division</header-in-text></quote>;</text> </clause><clause id="H59859802BAEA42CAB2CC8989BC969D96"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text>
 <subclause id="H2743C5E95A304E1EACDEE4CB0383AC4C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Office of Emergency Communications</quote> and inserting <quote>Emergency Communications Division</quote>; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H26D1AFE526D64D8FA492048F997ADC5F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>The Division shall be located in the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency.</quote>;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HD8AC2E1C390B4158819D3535CB714114"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by amending subsection (b) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H22B3C8AC2A0B4F5A8432D4382F7AF154" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HD1D28EE39D30440AA324FCFFF16029A1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Assistant Director</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of the office shall be the Assistant Director for Emergency Communications. The Assistant Director shall report to the Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency. All decisions of the Assistant Director that entail the exercise of significant authority shall be subject to the approval of the Director.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause><clause id="H4BCBCDA17DCA4237965D040237948761"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text> <subclause id="HF4130DF8F1454F6FAC5CC7E742E8A992"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>Assistant</quote> before <quote>Director</quote>;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H55A3595B12174ABE80A20175ECCD3C20"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in paragraph (14), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HA5145073EFCA425986EF47D62043AFFB"><enum>(III)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (15) as paragraph (16); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HC8F8AA5296974E43805000A9192E78BD"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (14) the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block id="HB1DB432378494B72B49488652117056B" style="OLC"> <paragraph commented="no" id="H9E74C86C780349079253747468FF45C6"><enum>(15)</enum><text>fully participate in the mechanisms required under subsection (c)(7) of section 2202; and</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H679CEE9D9C2B472FB9223AA160B750B7"><enum>(v)</enum><text>in subsection (d), by inserting <quote>Assistant</quote> before <quote>Director</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="HF3F34A7446CE48D89B090415ECEF5094"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>in subsection (e), in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>Assistant</quote> before <quote>Director</quote>;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E901D54A0294B91B5FAB57B4120BA5F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in sections 1802 through 1805 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/575">6 U.S.C. 575</external-xref>), by striking <quote>Director for Emergency Communications</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>Assistant Director for Emergency Communications</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38AF2D77FAE5467282C7D41BE4F03C43"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in section 1809 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/579">6 U.S.C. 579</external-xref>)—</text>
 <clause id="H35400D1DDDAD41EEB2B96FC06DEF4065"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Director for Emergency Communications</quote> and inserting <quote>Assistant Director for Emergency Communications</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H02DC4FBBB0654B97A2255CB2B0E53633"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Office of Emergency Communications</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>Emergency Communications Division</quote>; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB691D86664DB42AAB24DA2FC3C6C4C5C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in section 1810 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/580">6 U.S.C. 580</external-xref>)—</text> <clause id="H7DA8E72B51B645AD9BBE9093E6302163"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1), by striking <quote>Director of the Office of Emergency Communications (referred to in this section as the <quote>Director</quote>)</quote> and inserting <quote>Assistant Director for the Emergency Communications Division (referred to in this section as the <quote>Assistant Director</quote>)</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H29C02E0FF9DA43FEAABAEE566D84F28B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by striking <quote>Office of Emergency Communications</quote> and inserting <quote>Emergency Communications Division</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="HF7AD2E8F4E65494E9B4D50675A79A27B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Director</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>Assistant Director</quote>;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8105E25133EA4E95AA0A502D61F7E9F9"><enum>(7)</enum><text>in title XXI (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/621">6 U.S.C. 621</external-xref> et seq.)—</text> <subparagraph id="H16DCB3CA0C8446FDB2EF86FB0A8F4D4E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in section 2101 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/621">6 U.S.C. 621</external-xref>)—</text>
 <clause id="HF3BFCE82C6A64520A5877315BA8E18B3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (4) through (14) as paragraphs (5) through (15), respectively; and</text> </clause><clause id="H8708C353CC1143F589F230F2F7440F46"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (3) the following new paragraph:</text>
							<quoted-block id="H5A251C4B2BBE4450BA32E173A525BB2B" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HEA8D0F1C10554D61B459404821C5EF55"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <quote>Director</quote> means the Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE0CD452BFC142BD8E3A386D0D1AE72B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (1) of section 2102(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/622">6 U.S.C. 622(a)</external-xref>), by inserting at the end the following new sentence: <quote>Such Program shall be located in the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency.</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3C4F60C21E049D0A151F4C1772BA16D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (2) of section 2104(c) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/624">6 U.S.C. 624(c)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>Under Secretary responsible for overseeing critical infrastructure protection, cybersecurity, and other related programs of the Department appointed under section 103(a)(1)(H)</quote> and inserting <quote>Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency </quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0FF459AD8E042F69D5D5914707152FB"><enum>(8)</enum><text>in title XXII, as added by this Act—</text> <subparagraph id="HB65013AD808E46C68346CA806AAFBB44"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in section 2205, as so redesignated, in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>Under Secretary appointed under section 103(a)(1)(H)</quote> and inserting <quote>Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HAB2011C7E7564D1A9DEE279AABF067F2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in section 2206, as so redesignated, by striking <quote>Assistant Secretary for Infrastructure Protection</quote> and inserting <quote>Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4D3BD8C22FD24EA2A63822B40D78277B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in section 2209, as so redesignated—</text>
 <clause id="H2C888CE74F234B528EFD90D22A810FDD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Under Secretary appointed under section 103(a)(1)(H)</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency</quote>;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H226BF24DB4054298BDBC503270E6C83B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by adding at the end the following new sentences: <quote>The Center shall be located in the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency. The head of the Center shall report to the Assistant Director for Cybersecurity.</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8DC140AE3EDD4985AA1AAD6273648566"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(11), by striking <quote>Office of Emergency Communications</quote> and inserting <quote>Emergency Communications Division</quote>;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C89F5ADBE324F0599666B84AC77B98A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in section 2210, as so redesignated—</text>
 <clause id="HDD689CC61C6D424EAF244CF6F3CE8C9E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>section 227</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>section 2209</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H4BEFCF41A8814CA6A4C7871B4BF9FEB4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text>
 <subclause id="H50305AF8CAFA4C708EE5FCCFD5400A50"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Under Secretary appointed under section 103(a)(1)(H)</quote> and inserting <quote>Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency</quote>; and</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HB060698FD614490594267C804FF842B0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>section 212(5)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 2225(5)</quote>;</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD67619BA6AAC49299DB3BD84B19CC51C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(2)(A) of section 2211, as so redesignated, by striking <quote>section 227</quote> and inserting <quote>section 2209</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF68F1A1A14454FB393D8CEE64A24740E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>in section 2212, as so redesignated, by striking <quote>section 212(5)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 2225(5)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8DB9C0FA65014703A3EB0A2AB054123C"><enum>(G)</enum><text>in section 2213, as so redesignated, in subsection (a)—</text> <clause id="HE179CBCF0E0B46C1B789F9A8DE1E6B08"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>section 228</quote> and inserting <quote>section 2210</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6112D6A1BE534D19A7EC170E242151D9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>section 227</quote> and inserting <quote>section 2209</quote>.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF2E5454E592544719E95BA6E3A03CDFE"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Conforming amendment to title 5, United States Code</header><text>Section 5314 of title 5, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <quote>Under Secretaries, Department of Homeland Security.</quote> the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCAE5E72548854DEF8D8C038AB7186FA4" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H59BD758D055243C0A7812F1999D58666"><enum></enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Director, Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H9FC27699C49340B699547B11CB5F38ED"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDEA9DEA238014B8392F1A81241D34BA7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in title II—</text> <subparagraph id="HBEBF68DBA03F4D5DA30A63E607C4D81D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the item relating to the title heading, by striking <quote>AND INFRASTRUCTURE PROTECTION</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05A600F41A254951A5778D7F7132E14B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the item relating to the heading of subtitle A, by striking <quote>and Infrastructure Protection</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7AA8D6318C94C79A557C272226A0591"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the item relating to section 201, by striking <quote>and Infrastructure Protection</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2974865802F6411AA17241A0303BA474"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by striking the item relating to section 210E;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HBC541F7AA5564796A433EABBB4EFF917"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by striking the items relating to subtitle B of title II; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2AE21889AE3849E5B052EC0A28D5DC33"><enum>(F)</enum><text>by striking the items relating to section 223 through section 230;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD477662C62846E4BD5DA67BEF37C2A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in title XVIII, by amending the item relating to section 1801 to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7A6A0489B1164B159E873DE7D5AAD36D" style="OLC">
						<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
							<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 1801. Emergency Communications Division.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC455BCE9FC91487B917AE90323FA5C73"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following new items:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0BE59DBF963D4C37B7581C7A1A8BAE50" style="OLC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="title">TITLE XXII—CYBERSECURITY AND INFRASTRUCTURE SECURITY AGENCY</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="subtitle">Subtitle A—Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2201. Definitions.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2202. Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2203. Cybersecurity Division.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2204. Infrastructure Security Division.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2205. Enhancement of Federal and non-Federal cybersecurity.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2206. Net guard.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2207. Cyber Security Enhancement Act of 2002.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2208. Cybersecurity recruitment and retention.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2209. National cybersecurity and communications integration center.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2210. Cybersecurity plans.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2211. Cybersecurity strategy.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2212. Clearances.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2213. Federal intrusion detection and prevention system.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2214. National Asset Database.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="subtitle">Subtitle B—Critical Infrastructure Information</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2221. Short title.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2222. Definitions.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2223. Designation of critical infrastructure protection program.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2224. Protection of voluntarily shared critical infrastructure information.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2225. No private right of action.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HDDEA943E6DB145DEB4A90E31F744D762"><enum>3.</enum><header>Transfer of other entities</header> <subsection id="HAC447824203645F9B750338DE7FE3B70"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Office of Biometric Identity Management</header><text>The Office of Biometric Identity Management of the Department of Homeland Security located in the National Protection and Programs Directorate of the Department of Homeland Security on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act is hereby transferred to the Management Directorate of the Department.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2F88A4A9DDFA47DE97E10BD76431B079"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Federal Protective Service</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security is authorized to transfer the Federal Protective Service, as authorized under section 1315 of title 40, United States Code, to any component, directorate, or other office of the Department of Homeland Security that the Secretary determines appropriate.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HC071CC278F264C1BA52C67B089D7A2DB"><enum>4.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed as—</text> <paragraph id="HB36153FB5933492685E7991258719B0C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conferring new authorities to the Secretary of Homeland Security, including programmatic, regulatory, or enforcement authorities, outside of the authorities in existence on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6392FAD528144EE2BD729D20CA27C9EE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reducing or limiting the programmatic, regulatory, or enforcement authority vested in any other Federal agency by statute; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H43D492B062E1461085B191CE8E931183"><enum>(3)</enum><text>affecting in any manner the authority, existing on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act, of any other Federal agency or component of the Department of Homeland Security.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H8A9FA65B4CCE4A06965D5099EE5D7C1C"><enum>5.</enum><header>Prohibition on additional funding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act or the amendments made <pagebreak></pagebreak>by this Act. This Act and such amendments shall be carried out using amounts otherwise authorized.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
	<attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20171211">Passed the House of Representatives December 11, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill>


