<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2313C88CA0454040B78E24112012CFC2" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2859 IH: Advancing Competency-Based Education Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2859</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170608">June 8, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001189">Mr. Messer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000598">Mrs. Davis of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001177">Mr. Sablan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to establish demonstration projects for competency-based
			 education.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HE510440AD9FD455C8CBF0D258B140F0A" style="OLC">
 <section id="H285E329D6FF04E4BB7C996EDDCC909F3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Advancing Competency-Based Education Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HB7B9F428D2DE40A89005233C943CC7F3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Competency-based education demonstration projects</header> <subsection id="H38D88BB2852D40969767154EA2A30D4B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Projects</header><text>Part G of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1088">20 U.S.C. 1088</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by inserting after section 486A the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H64F1AD49E58D40848FED95040210687B" style="OLC">
					<section id="HD7F98F90F0D54CC8A00E4AF0A8004EB4"><enum>486B.</enum><header>Competency-based education demonstration projects</header>
 <subsection id="H62AF41DBB7F043D5B545ED1ADF608B55"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Demonstration projects authorized</header><text>The Secretary shall select, in accordance with subsection (d), eligible entities to voluntarily carry out competency-based education demonstration projects and receive waivers or other flexibility described in subsection (e) to carry out such projects.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H71C86C9C93064B9082049CFF1CC36A2C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header>
 <paragraph id="HD5432F2A58BC416F8C86EB2A7A1E7EE3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each eligible entity desiring to carry out a demonstration project under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary, at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB2CEA61B4871492EAA65218DC54947B9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Outreach</header><text>The Secretary shall, prior to any deadline to submit applications under paragraph (1), conduct outreach to historically Black colleges and universities, Hispanic-serving institutions, Native American-serving, nontribal institutions, institutions serving students with special needs, and institutions located in rural areas to provide those institutions with information on the opportunity to apply to carry out a demonstration project under this section.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H5B8C99C2F2044918A3F7565EAB9A4289"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Amendments</header>
 <subparagraph id="HFFCA9B4F955A4006AA8F6862A261A240"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity that has been selected to carry out a demonstration project under this section may submit to the Secretary amendments to the eligible entity’s approved application under paragraph (1), at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may require, which the Secretary shall approve or deny within 30 days of receipt.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67CE3D7C0D0C403F98AAE726E30EEB26"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Expanding enrollment</header><text>Notwithstanding the assurance required with respect to maximum enrollment under paragraph (4)(I)—</text> <clause id="H696BA343B88D4B84867829000EA332FD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an eligible entity whose demonstration project has been evaluated under subsection (g)(2) not less than twice may submit to the Secretary an amendment to the eligible entity’s application under paragraph (1) to increase enrollment in the project to more than 3,000 students, but not more than 5,000 students, and which shall specify—</text>
 <subclause id="H75009ABC52874036A33EAB98982CE17D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the proposed maximum enrollment or annual enrollment growth for the project;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H82BA4016B5C8428B8C9B4E90EB4C872F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>how the eligible entity will successfully carry out the project with such maximum enrollment or enrollment growth; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H6C63198B17D74AAEA7A518842F804832"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any other amendments to the eligible entity’s application under paragraph (1) that are related to such maximum enrollment or enrollment growth; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H70AF6D5198EA4C62A0426DB25F2D97A6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Secretary shall determine whether to approve or deny an amendment submitted under clause (i) for a demonstration project based on the project’s evaluations under subsection (g)(2).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H117BFCEEE0B74506921C2DB781A73FAC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each application under paragraph (1) shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="HC5AF525D854942EF860918B07DBF0C87"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of each competency-based education program to be offered by the eligible entity under the demonstration project;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6976A7D707DB4591B5F072A8A3BDE9EE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of the proposed academic delivery, business, and financial models for the demonstration project, including explanations of how each competency-based education program offered under the demonstration project will—</text>
 <clause id="H585530D3AB244E6081F9E4C8AFCFB16C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>result in the achievement of competencies;</text> </clause><clause id="H30732671BC64423991151A5291247BA5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>differ from standard credit hour approaches, in whole or in part; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA94639720DDE46EAA86C3FFE8AA41B62"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>result in lower costs or shortened time to the completion of a recognized educational credential;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F73685629BD4FF5AE02743552B5545F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of how each competency-based education program offered under the demonstration project will progress a student toward completion of a recognized educational credential;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CEBDC6D6C4D4E0BA4825F5977B15AB1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the meaningful role of the appropriate faculty of the eligible entity in the development, design, implementation, delivery, and evaluation of each such competency-based education program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H590E3CB444C34C9989D3E62BFD943741"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of how each such competency-based education program will provide strong post-enrollment earnings and loan repayment outcomes;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBED54F5323C04E12854C82435EA7A4C5"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a description of how the eligible entity will articulate the transcript from a competency-based education program offered under the demonstration project to another program at the eligible entity or at another institution of higher education;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4EFFAAE414944BD980F49446CE10AA40"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a description of the statutory and regulatory requirements described in subsection (e) for which the eligible entity is seeking a waiver or other flexibility, and why such waiver or flexibility is necessary to carry out the demonstration project;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A109809B57847D6A6298B7AA3ABF6FC"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of how a third party will assess student learning for each competency-based education program offered under the demonstration project;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H075F8C5AC5A942508D037F93E8321E29"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a description of how the eligible entity will develop and evaluate the competencies and assessments of student knowledge administered as part of the demonstration project, including how such competencies and assessments are aligned with workforce needs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC83729C120C54AA19DD457948BDFE240"><enum>(J)</enum><text>a description of the proposal for determining a student’s Federal student aid eligibility under this title for participating in the demonstration project, the award and distribution of such aid, and the safeguards to ensure that students are making satisfactory progress that warrants the disbursement of such aid;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA62BBAD90B44CA6BCBA3DDE722DAF39"><enum>(K)</enum><text>an assurance that the demonstration project will enroll a minimum of 25 students and a maximum of 3,000 students or, in the case of an eligible entity with an application amendment approved under paragraph (3)(B), the maximum enrollment approved under such paragraph;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E7A570A674F4C1785738E6A7EBC7EB3"><enum>(L)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the population of students to whom competency-based education under the demonstration project will be offered, including demographic information and prior educational experience, disaggregated by students who are Federal Pell Grant recipients, students of color, students with disabilities, students who are veterans or members of the Armed Forces, and first generation college students, and how such eligible entity will, when appropriate, address the specific needs of each such population of students when carrying out the demonstration project;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97EE4F425DF6461A9AF17BF8DB788054"><enum>(M)</enum><text>an assurance that students participating in the demonstration project will not, on average, be eligible for more Federal assistance under this title than such students would have been eligible for under a traditional program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6BD6A6D17CB14D6D944D875B48009322"><enum>(N)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the cost of attendance for each competency-based education program offered under the demonstration project, disaggregated by each of the applicable costs or allowances described in paragraphs (1) through (13) of section 472, and the estimated amount of the cost of attendance of each such program to be covered by need-based grant aid and merit-based grant aid from Federal, State, institutional, and private sources;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE03D4A2B1DAD47E1AD3DEFDA00DA2EED"><enum>(O)</enum><text>an assurance that the eligible entity will identify and disseminate best practices with respect to the demonstration project to other eligible entities carrying out a demonstration project under this section;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FA44E17AC8C4076B45A12BA35446769"><enum>(P)</enum><text>a description of other competency-based education the eligible entity offers or plans to offer outside of the demonstration project;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB1C9FE7F39854CA69BBDBC19DF63178B"><enum>(Q)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assurance that the eligible entity will use data to—</text> <clause id="H23619A024F8B47E996BC07668870C980"><enum>(i)</enum><text>ensure that each competency-education program under the demonstration project meets the benchmarks established in accordance with subsection (c)(2)(E); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8921A8C6AAA541719E6D4D7D36349B1C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>improve each such program;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7E403A5E1AF459DBC5BD1306FD13FB6"><enum>(R)</enum><text>an assurance that the eligible entity has an agreement with the accrediting agency or association of the eligible entity to establish the standards described in subsection (c); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD401E80CCE6A40CB9E1AD6FE7D8F8752"><enum>(S)</enum><text>such other elements as the Secretary may require.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF3C0A2EC34B84FA6883BE9F01B82ECF9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Recognition by accrediting agency or association</header><text>To carry out a competency-based education program under a demonstration project under this section, an eligible entity shall ensure that before, on, or after the date of approval of the eligible entity’s application under subsection (b), the accrediting agency or association of the eligible entity will establish the following standards with respect to such competency-based education program:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HECB5E1377C4F43328B1BDAD271CD4E5E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Standards for determining whether the eligible entity or the program requires students to demonstrate competencies that are—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HF13411F50225413796A986964349C30F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>capable of being validly and reliably assessed; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC9070CA65B554049BA8BC5B9B51D366D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>appropriate in scope and rigor for the award of the relevant recognized educational credential.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H795D3F1A4A0C436482ADAFF9FF73CBC3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Standards for determining whether the eligible entity or the program demonstrate—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H19C36093FC564553B4ECF1AF428670DF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the administrative capacity and expertise that will ensure—</text>
 <clause id="HE577C03D96AC4D45AAB9714D52835EF8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the validity and reliability of assessments of competencies; and</text> </clause><clause id="HD9581AB843D44380AB5BEB8F3B008A88"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>good practices in assessment and measurement;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H76EE45D2C1064CC8BA0BD7CF7A0BE302"><enum>(B)</enum><text>sufficient educational content, activities, and resources (including faculty support)—</text> <clause id="HB7ABDD54BF474742A3DC45887BB0B215"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to enable students to learn or develop what is required to demonstrate or attain mastery of competencies; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H439ED744112F4ADD83CA62D342044069"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that are consistent with the qualifications of graduates of traditional programs;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H21B29430089C44499B634E97D4EDC762"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that the quality of demonstration of competence is judged at mastery for each competency that is assessed for the award of a recognized educational credential;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HFFAA33FECB84474A97F0E220D64A11D6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a standard for the amount of learning that is included in a unit of competency;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD991AEA8459D42E1BAE8926A83A3F40C"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reasonable benchmarks for graduation rates and the employment and earnings of graduates, including placements in a field for which the program prepares students, debt-to-earnings ratios, loan repayment rates, and student satisfaction; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A241008FF67464885D54CBDFB03CC9D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>regular evaluation of whether the program meets the benchmarks under subparagraph (E).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2CD9A73262C44308ADB5417FF10D5AA"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Standards for determining when to deny, withdraw, suspend, or terminate the accreditation of the program if the benchmarks under paragraph (2)(E) are not achieved, including standards for providing sufficient opportunity—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1FE11BA44EA74BF2B14DEC30894041C8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for the eligible entity or program to provide a written response regarding the failure to achieve such benchmarks be considered by the agency or association in the manner described in section 496(a)(6)(B); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H288711CF2A8246E698A67D5D5465C45B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for the eligible entity or program to appeal any adverse action under this subparagraph before an appeals panel that meets the requirements of section 496(a)(6)(C).</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H74E4687F4D504F2E89E66766AC967FFB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Selection</header>
 <paragraph id="H3C48A7785E744CEB9966BE89CC4ED050"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 9 months after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Advancing Competency-Based Education Act of 2017</short-title>, the Secretary shall select not more than 100 eligible entities to carry out a demonstration project under this section under which at least 1 competency-based education program is offered.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5F40E567768F49F29F4BACABCE922AA3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In selecting eligible entities under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H56411CD1A7744E599F4EA81361BAF910"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consider the number and quality of applications received;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A422F0361694319A21B906ACCE573BC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consider an eligible entity’s—</text> <clause id="H39885B7BDB2142E392D4EF299A91FF9A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>ability to successfully execute the demonstration project as described in the eligible entity’s application under subsection (b);</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEFE5C8540BD34A72B8D1570A022E3E1D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>commitment and ability to effectively finance the demonstration project;</text> </clause><clause id="HE3605EF13B77436A82121F9FF4C329F2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>ability to provide administrative capability and the expertise to evaluate student progress based on measures other than credit hours or clock hours;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6C5CD000859E4B6C9897DEA263FDC4A1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>history of compliance with the requirements of this Act;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H8F0B00C9AC30487AB68DA7651414B6AD"><enum>(v)</enum><text>commitment to work with the Director of the Institute of Education Sciences and the Secretary to evaluate the demonstration project and the impact of the demonstration project under subsection (g)(2); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3B9D52FBFD934CD389651507C19DE1AE"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">commitment and ability to assess student learning through a third party;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FB526689F49458B9ED9060B722D169E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure the selection of a diverse group of eligible entities with respect to size, mission, student population, and geographic distribution;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7164E3957DC949AAA088BA5385C56BB1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>not limit the types of programs of study or courses of study approved for participation in a demonstration project; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13417613DB0A43F5BD51B7A0BDA5207B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>not select an eligible entity that has had, for 1 of the preceding 2 fiscal years, a cohort default rate (defined in section 435(m)) that is 30 percent or greater.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H829FEDE5A47C49EE88BF1E72AB3538B0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Waivers and other flexibility</header>
 <paragraph id="H1360D404EAAA478DA0181E6E04986FC2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>With respect to any eligible entity selected to carry out a demonstration project under this section, the Secretary may—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H54F218DE1CDD4783A20065DA89D0ADCA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">waive any requirements of the provisions of law (including any regulations promulgated under such provisions) listed in paragraph (2) for which the eligible entity has provided a reason for waiving under subsection (b)(4)(F); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9BDFC316B30F4B84B331B6579FD09ADB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide other flexibility, but not waive, any requirements of the provisions of law (including any regulations promulgated under such provisions) listed in paragraph (3) for which the eligible entity has provided a reason for such flexibility under subsection (b)(4)(F).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H75BBD128F19C4480B47CA70E1F299D4A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Provisions eligible for waivers</header><text>The Secretary may waive the following under paragraph (1)(A):</text> <subparagraph id="H54AEA6B9A8014876B12366D087D805E2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Subparagraphs (A) and (B) of section 102(a)(3).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H15BA95FDDD0747A0AC699BC189694043"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 484(l)(1).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE3B4BB9C85904E17858EE7A1A5D6761B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Provisions eligible for flexibility</header><text>The Secretary may provide the flexibility described in paragraph (1)(B) with respect to the requirements under provisions in title I, part F of this title, or this part, that inhibit the operation of a competency-based education program, relating to the following:</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H642EB738D56E4DB487F148D7FDDCEB2E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Documenting attendance.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB16DB2BF7ECE4138B68D37D9D900F338"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Weekly academic activity.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HCEA81435AEB3445EACD4BDA3C0A0AE0C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Minimum weeks of instructional time.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H023A14F509C84A779C9F3AD42BF25F29"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Requirements for credit hour or clock hour equivalencies.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE08448B7E55E4190A64313A0B53E62F5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Requirements for substantive interaction with faculty.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD84E29AA61A24896882478F39DF5AACF"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Definitions of the terms <term>academic year</term>, <term>full-time student</term>, <term>term</term> (including <quote>standard term</quote>, <quote>non-term</quote>, and <quote>non-standard term</quote>), <quote>satisfactory academic progress</quote>, <quote>educational activity</quote>, <quote>project of study</quote>, and <quote>payment period</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H321886E56CB343B08769B44038ADA0DD"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Methods of disbursing student financial aid by institutions of higher education selected, as of the date of enactment of the <short-title>Advancing Competency-Based Education Act of 2017</short-title>, as experimental sites under section 487A(b)(3) to carry out competency-based education programs.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H03A61F72DB324DA48CD67168A68BB063"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>Not later than 9 months after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Advancing Competency-Based Education Act of 2017</short-title>, the Secretary shall make available to the authorizing committees and the public a list of eligible entities selected to carry out a demonstration project under this section, which shall include for each such eligible entity—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC51D07F43DCB4D1C9B985A525108285C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the specific waiver or other flexibility from statutory or regulatory requirements offered under subsection (e); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5098C357FE93407C923A3107D7EF06B9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of the competency-based education programs to be offered under the project.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEB1B97CA918F4C739BBADB34E6964742"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Information and evaluation</header> <paragraph id="H7ED39C2808034FDE9F2D031D90A19AB0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Information</header> <subparagraph id="HBE9A8E4A703E4CF5ABFDC1930DA26617"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Student-level data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each eligible entity that carries out a demonstration project under this section shall provide to the Director of the Institute of Education Sciences the student-level data for the students enrolled in a program described in subparagraph (C)(i)(I), the student-level data for the students enrolled in a program described in subparagraph (C)(i)(II), and the student-level data for students enrolled in a program described in subparagraph (C)(i)(III) to enable the Director—</text>
 <clause id="H6ACF8695863147D29478A04A35C760D7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to determine the aggregate information described in subparagraph (B) with respect to each such program; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H18F817ABB9074DE297EE7ADE15F53558"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the extent practicable, to compare the programs using a rigorous evaluation, such as propensity score matching.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92A950DE95F64E4C89F555CA053F6372"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Aggregate information</header><text>For purposes of the evaluation under paragraph (2), the Director shall use the student-level data provided under subparagraph (A) by an eligible entity to determine the following information with respect to each program described in subparagraph (C)(i) offered at such eligible entity:</text>
 <clause id="HD7C54B61449A4B7DB8DFB779776B191E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The average number of credit hours students earned prior to enrollment in the program, if applicable.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA9982610537B47819E52AFB7FFE34011"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The number and percentage of students enrolled in a competency-based program that are also enrolled in programs of study or courses of study offered in credit hours or clock hours, disaggregated by student status as a first-year, second-year, third-year, fourth-year, or other student.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFA1043AD63E441649C2599556F135382"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The average period of time between the enrollment of a student in the program and the first assessment of student knowledge of such student.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H66A970C4F39042559F3F4DDCE3932935"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The average time to 25 percent, 50 percent, 75 percent, 100 percent, 150 percent, and 200 percent completion of a recognized educational credential.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H562EB23CAE454C889049CF04FE36967A"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The percentage of assessments of student knowledge that students passed on the first attempt during the period of enrollment in the program.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCFFB167842CF4A4081A6C1E30CE4E59A"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The percentage of assessments of student knowledge that students passed on the second attempt and the average period of time between the first and second attempts during the period of enrollment in the program.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H558E3DF1702E48A98F5D143C08DCFFDD"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>The average number of competencies a student acquired while enrolled in a program and the period of time during which the student acquired such competencies.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H787434C191BC45ED8BD56E3331A8E8D0"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number and percentage of students completing the program who find employment, disaggregated by number and percentage of such students finding employment in a field related to the program.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6D431BCFC60D48BAA9ABCA372D580CD8"><enum>(ix)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The median student earnings 1, 3, and 4 years after graduating from the program, if available.</text> </clause><clause id="H4DAD283C30824D86A6AB82CD41EA9538"><enum>(x)</enum><text>Such other information as the Director may reasonably require.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D486CEA7C2542FF8AE638CEF6383F5E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Disaggregation</header><text>The information determined under subparagraph (B) shall be disaggregated as follows, provided that the disaggregation of the information does not identify any individual student:</text>
 <clause id="H920FB743210540E69047D58744D15578"><enum>(i)</enum><text>For each eligible entity that carries out a demonstration project under this section, disaggregation by—</text>
 <subclause id="HFA03E438A0364AE6AC58E5E5CB94FDAB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the students enrolled in each competency-based education program under the project;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H7B82BB668A404DD39CFE9317DF8DE6DA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the students enrolled in each competency-based education program not being carried out under the project; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H99085846EE5A466388A6D6354206E1B5"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the students enrolled in a program not described in subclause (I) or (II).</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HC067B54BDB554C5FB04910132FE425BB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>For each group of students described in clause (i), disaggregation by age, race, gender, disability status, students who are Veterans or servicemembers, first generation college students, and status as a recipient of a Federal Pell Grant.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01A4C322848D4129A9F478598D3E5466"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Council</header><text>The Director shall provide to the Competency-Based Education Council any information described in subparagraph (A) or (B) (other than personally identifiable information) that may be necessary for the Council to carry out its duties under section 3(e) of the <short-title>Advancing Competency-Based Education Act of 2017</short-title>.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B841AB96B8045288060CF6E90097CE0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Evaluation</header>
 <subparagraph id="HD8BBF94FC33F468E8387C09F155B48A1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director, in consultation with the Secretary and using the information determined under paragraph (1), shall annually evaluate each eligible entity carrying out a demonstration project under this section. Each evaluation shall be disaggregated in accordance with subparagraph (B) and include—</text>
 <clause id="H5446138E56844930B5EB583C688EE037"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the extent to which the eligible entity has met the elements of its application under subsection (b)(4);</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDE3306AB2F274988AC4FEC4BB0F32F2F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>whether the demonstration project led to reduced cost or time to completion of a recognized educational credential, and the amount of cost or time reduced for such completion;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA7E57BB25BC245FCA689DC2E78181032"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>obstacles related to student financial assistance for competency-based education;</text> </clause><clause id="H7E1DEB57530A46C2A0C6974C45A304AF"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the extent to which statutory or regulatory requirements not waived or for which flexibility is not provided under subsection (e) presented difficulties or unintended consequences for students or eligible entities;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1DBD82378ED44A6697A9CF0CC56939FB"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a description of the waivers or flexibility provided under subsection (e) that were most beneficial to students or eligible entities, and an explanation of such benefits;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H69C28035B5C04EDCB6498021F194444D"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the percentage of students who received each of the following—</text> <subclause commented="no" id="H9F6591C7FE79419088D6A30146C39359"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a grant under this title;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H1F6B79192CF445D88CD831AC99AB3147"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a loan under this title;</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HCAACBE12ECD34B2CBC465D7882313490"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a State grant;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H9F0C1851A7E44E2D945B03D23A208E3B"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>a State loan;</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H45568FDE3E1946539EDCC5C7B9937889"><enum>(V)</enum><text>an institutional grant;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H530035B2ED514EE39317FA75AA9F8FF4"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>an institutional loan; and</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HC37470F002174D71B3167F14D7DC6ACE"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>a private loan;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HE16144B46FB84AE198F9AC2239470AF2"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>total cost and net cost to the student of the program;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HB68AEE95398A43439F4ADAD8683C09EA"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the average outstanding balance of principal and interest on loans made under this title that students have upon graduation;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HC53D634709884509B1D38DE863B4A979"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>the 3-year cohort default rate;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H170A8555CBF44D34BCCC6DAE5DAA8C9A"><enum>(x)</enum><text>the 1- and 3-year repayment rate of loans made under this title;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H671553CAD0404595924834067AF8CF20"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>the median student earnings 1, 3, and 4 years after graduation;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HEFF664DD8B164C848D7A98DD1E7BC7BE"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>enrollment data, disaggregated by—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" id="H8CAF9387414847E9834A4BCD93062C5F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>enrollment status, retention rates, credit accumulation, and completion rates for—</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HD8B8626C8189441780C1AF18D45DB3E2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>first-time, full-time students;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HBB46D4642B6F42C196CD5BD187946244"><enum>(III)</enum><text>first-time, part-time students;</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H929E3CE9630B45A9BCF196C8556EAA70"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>nonfirst-time, full-time students;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H5295FCBA7E364432B973EF2740214C10"><enum>(V)</enum><text>nonfirst-time, part-time students;</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H46B1367FB06C4565B3664E3CB49F9B1F"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>eligibility for Federal Pell grants;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H184EE04EE17949F7BED6F4C6B59CA05E"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>race and ethnicity; and</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H965612B38B52437C860DB9B75E39EDE2"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>transfer rates;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H7EA445FA0F6B4F5DB4E8EE259C541EDE"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>a description of the assessments of student knowledge and the corresponding competencies;</text> </clause><clause id="H16EA64090D664DBDA4E6DA28B8F543A4"><enum>(xiv)</enum><text>a description of the role of faculty and faculty involvement; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC4C0300CF24E4FA9BCDE3B4A5CCA9BF8"><enum>(xv)</enum><text>outcomes of the assessments of student knowledge.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H373029B5398949C5993124C422560971"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Disaggregation</header><text>The data collected under clauses (vi) through (xii) shall be disaggregated by each group of students described in paragraph (1)(C)(i).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB52A426070B84F8AB511CD45B3242CE6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>The Director, in consultation with the Secretary, shall annually provide to the authorizing committees a report on—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBE80CC0F51D0455C9255EC399CC4756C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the evaluations required under paragraph (2);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA9DA128590B46D98CD2504229CA0741"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number and types of students receiving assistance under this title for competency-based education programs offered under projects under this section;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2884C7EF9F9F414F9FBC17602EBB10E4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any proposed statutory or regulatory changes designed to support and enhance the expansion of competency-based education programs, which may be independent of or combined with traditional credit hour or clock hour projects;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H15D122A99F38453381FE1F8112BCB13B"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the most effective means of delivering competency-based education programs through projects under this section; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56F46BA92CF24F6F8FAF16ACE7A36AF6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the appropriate level and distribution methodology of Federal assistance under this title for students enrolled in a competency-based education program.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9220F7FFD7F94E1A9EBCBE8ACC236BEE"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>An eligible entity or the Director shall consult with the Secretary of Education or the Secretary of the Treasury to obtain the employment, earnings, and loan information that may be necessary for purposes of subsection (c)(2)(F) or subsection (g), respectively.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC588AC37A2854A0DBB18544C88CEBAD0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Oversight</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall, on a continuing basis—</text> <paragraph id="H3B71CD0AF6524F3CA738A1F5C3CF1544"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assure compliance of eligible entities with the requirements of this title (other than the provisions of law and regulations that are waived under subsection (e));</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3E2AC30E655B4F5F825B14AA544D5BE5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide technical assistance;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC6D3FD1744A84D07BCAC2670AA18F5A6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>monitor fluctuations in the student population enrolled in the eligible entities carrying out the demonstration projects under this section;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1F953A3753BE43F6B69E3D3B7F16C86D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>consult with appropriate accrediting agencies or associations and appropriate State regulatory authorities for additional ways of improving the delivery of competency-based education programs; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA0F9DB754DDD43519CC1AE2E2857A998"><enum>(5)</enum><text>collect and disseminate to eligible entities carrying out a demonstration project under this section, best practices with respect to such projects.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE7C5836D667B49F5B7A03206F002AD37"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Data privacy</header>
 <paragraph id="H34D008CF7F144DBFBB6788345A19D907"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be unlawful for any person who obtains or has access to personally identifiable information in connection with this section to willfully disclose to any person (except as authorized in this Act or any Federal law) such personally identifiable information.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB351253FD93E4501A9E311A51589ED74"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person who violates paragraph (1) shall be fined not more than $5,000, imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both, together with the costs of prosecution.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6CEB432CCD1D4EC98A0D84E8FC0674BA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Employee or officer of the United States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a violation of paragraph (1) is committed by any officer or employee of the United States, the officer or employee shall be dismissed from office or discharged from employment upon conviction for the violation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4FCE804C532744E7815E4D4E21FCE19C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Sale of data prohibited</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Data collected under this section shall not be sold to any third party by the Director, any postsecondary institution, or any other entity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE2CA4634EB7445489457BB499735436"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Limitation on use by other Federal agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall not allow any other Federal agency to use data collected under this section for any purpose except as explicitly authorized by this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDE4CA5F08213421D8365D3275EA9AC7B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Law enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Personally identifiable information collected under this section shall not be used for any law enforcement activity or any other activity that would result in adverse action against any student, including debt collection activity or enforcement of the immigration laws.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD69235819B3049CAA96DCC2BFE4F196B"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 to carry out this section.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H4112AF7893C34A9CB45DC2E87693FC05"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For the purpose of this section:</text>
 <paragraph id="H8872D00C17A246839061AEF351A0C9D7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Competency-based education program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>competency-based education program</term> means a program that provides competency-based education for which the accrediting agency or association of the institution of higher education offering such program has established or will establish the standards described in subsection (c) and, in accordance with such standards—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HA2C008ABE4CC4C39971DDB06D127678A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>measures academic progress and attainment by the assessment of student learning in lieu of, or in addition to, credit or clock hours;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD590653A0BB94B65AD13E6E51B6564FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>measures and assesses such academic progress and attainment in terms of a student’s mastery of competencies by identifying what students know and the skills mastered through rigorous assessment;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H989512F204C0453C8406C7968C9440D8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>determines and reports to the Secretary the number of credit or clock hours that would be needed for the attainment of a similar level of knowledge, skills, and characteristics in a standard credit or clock hour program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H932B249232974100BF6B44473C745A37"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provides the educational content, activities, support, and resources necessary to enable students to attain the knowledge, skills, and characteristics that are required to demonstrate mastery of such competencies, including—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H047B05E4D96E4BAFBCB17C310A129066"><enum>(i)</enum><text>ready access to academic assistance from faculty who meet the standards of the agency or association for providing instruction in the subject area; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H807F3EABA7CA4E719CA98034507A83C8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a system for monitoring a student’s engagement and progress in each competency, in which faculty are responsible for providing proactive academic assistance, when needed, on the basis of such monitoring; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0E5ABE9ACDB64BE6952CDB7896FCB8C9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>upon a student’s demonstration or mastery of a set of competencies identified and required by the institution, leads to or results in the awarding of a recognized educational credential.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H48A5AB22229E47A5A6FD1D5F585B0842"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means an institution of higher education, which may be an institution of higher education that offers a dual or concurrent enrollment program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H468878D6F50840138BCB80F66537ED9F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 102, except that such term does not include institutions described in section 102(a)(1)(C).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H688C3C8AE9D74A678C64F968EA487073"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Dual or concurrent enrollment program</header><text>The term <term>dual or concurrent enrollment program</term> has the meaning given the term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H58AA3A2050FA47BC9B13786277964638"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Director</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Institute of Education Sciences.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7E29123943FF48D8AF55DF6263D3CFD6"><enum>(6)</enum><header>First generation college student</header><text>The term <term>first generation college student</term> has the meaning given the term in section 402A(h)(3).</text>
							</paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4B9C09B3B6DA4F488BD9B1BA7F6910C8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception to student unit record ban</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 134(b) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1015c">20 U.S.C. 1015c(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HCACF33AF0AEB4B7E82937ACA221185DE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF963CB429DAE40D9A81D2462D7726E41" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H8765C414D2BA4D589B8708F16CDB3CB8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is necessary</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and inserting the following:</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H92FD283C8DC44835A56E871E39461051" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H63E6B99EE22443F7912346FF7BD5B6F3"><enum>(1)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H006A174CBC0046188CBF3A371DB90635"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is necessary</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H06E7B3B7085A4908915C0D67D86A9160"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H12AF74EF2467454FA4FD4D3D89664F75" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HF975B697D52B470BB2131B41D3389BF2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">was in</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and inserting the following:</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC43C4EA235FC4907BB7597BEFC4D7C10" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H61D1A61F787E44C2AEF5C67D7CAAB921"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">was in</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFD399F8EA93847298F404FA59C6B28F9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBF48ADBD67A24032A2BB9B0DFD87ADA2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE20BB6E14BEF4689BA2D9C1A9E38B805" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H0C39F040850545068747C042139E811D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is necessary for the operation of section 486B.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB7F72AA953E74F52A3CEF0B74553F3F2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act or the amendments made by this Act shall be construed to alter the authority of the Secretary of Education to establish experimental sites under any other provision of law.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H4F9DC6F6E7DB418E95DD5FCE01809D8E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Competency-based education council</header>
 <subsection id="H629D19B1711E46209887F060EA3A383C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of a committee on competency-Based education</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, there shall be established the Competency-Based Education Council (referred to in this section as the <quote>Council</quote>).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H7E3528DF01EA42DFB3F6EDC83CBA5BE4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header>
 <paragraph id="HEB58CEC5E54F4FE891A1AD1019E61C42"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The Council shall be composed of—</text> <subparagraph id="HC63E92C0BBDC4CE8A783C32E9AE2E665"><enum>(A)</enum><text>3 individuals appointed by the Secretary of Education;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8104261967B34A51937AD93D4E5679C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>2 individuals appointed by the Director of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8960B65411E44BA4948E562FC922B5AB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not less than 8 and not more than 13 individuals appointed by the Comptroller General of the United States, representing—</text>
 <clause id="HF419C24BAB094BDC9CC9C6F1C175116B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>experts in competency-based education;</text> </clause><clause id="H738B2BE021A14B4FADB96E05F24F2B11"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>faculty members in competency-based education programs;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBD8252307A37467FB62981736FF95A70"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>administrators at institutions that offer competency-based education programs;</text> </clause><clause id="HA9B07B629BBD4D13B721D6B815C6C57E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>individuals currently enrolled in or graduated from a competency-based education program;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H18B482A6A2534BDF965CFC02D6D99DB3"><enum>(v)</enum><text>accrediting agencies or associations that recognize competency-based education programs; and</text> </clause><clause id="H89E2130D5EB043A4B01071F7D1F5B7FB"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>experts from the State education agency;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE76BCB15C9EB41FB9C783D8F4E5E174C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>4 members appointed by—</text> <clause id="H348C99DFC5AE42BC900FD2F6F1C3535C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the majority leader of the Senate;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5734EF214CB34FC6B582E4B180B813C1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the minority leader of the Senate;</text> </clause><clause id="H5E44F52DAC5B4CD09284E5C514A1712B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Speaker of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA087C7B547354CD384072BD3DB491F08"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the minority leader of the House of Representatives.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F415F1A6D754D1C9CD0E8F77A1CA0CF"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>The Council shall select a Chairperson from among its members.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A7F321E44554E67B1998AFA8F72147C"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>Any vacancy in the Council shall not affect the powers of the Council and shall be filled in the same manner as an initial appointment.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H97D4C7A8A6FB4B70818B198859DA73CD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Council shall hold, at the call of the Chairperson, not less than 6 meetings before completing the study required under subsection (e) and the report required under subsection (f).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HBC6B78AE1141492A88A401386C27CDB3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Personnel matters</header>
 <paragraph id="HEC3B129C03FE4C4AB7AC1ADB16461DAA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Compensation of members</header><text>Each member of the Council shall serve without compensation in addition to any such compensation received for the member’s service as an officer or employee of the United States, if applicable.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1315AEBC10154406B5B8228DD2E34C38"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text>The members of the Council shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter 1 of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the Council.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA7949315AEAE4552879ABBF353C1C2C5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Duties of the council</header>
 <paragraph id="H61C5FB4D71954CE0B0221EAE088F1A6F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Council shall conduct a study on the ongoing innovation and development of competency-based education programs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE6EE2BEF10F14397AA25230D37DBA645"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text>Based on the findings of the study under paragraph (1), the Council shall develop recommendations for the authorization of competency-based education under the Higher Education Act of 1965, including recommendations that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8A571D581A9348019E0971A68458A180"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide or update standard definitions, if needed, for relevant terms, including—</text> <clause id="H7636F9ADFF4E44CCADAE4DE4D2B9AA24"><enum>(i)</enum><text>competency-based education; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4129C0567A4242EB83FE8178E1BA7B68"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>competency-based education program; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H43DBA6E19A344F509DE59248A4E86BBC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>address—</text>
 <clause id="H364B6889A420438E90441EB941E5EB24"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount of learning in a competency unit;</text> </clause><clause id="H928E7E199F6E4EF6A803B8107FE0FE73"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the transfer of competency-based education credits to other institutions or programs;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H168B9B60D07D4C639B3ED6D66068DD4F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the minimum amount of time in an academic year for competency-based education programs, for financial aid purposes;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H68C8636D54374D3A9AC246B3689D3AEB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>considerations for accreditation agencies before recognizing competency-based education programs;</text> </clause><clause id="H09C92CADF3E5497D9491FCB14BE20FBD"><enum>(v)</enum><text>address the role of faculty and faculty involvement in competency-based education programs; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H71F072235F6E456CB6DB60D524CD801C"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>additional resources that may be needed for adequate oversight of competency-based education programs.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8FBF4DCF19724A3FBF314686EB97157D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 6 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Council shall prepare and submit a report to the Secretary of Education and to Congress containing the findings of the study under subsection (e)(1) and the recommendations developed under subsection (e)(2).</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


