<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HED859DF3ED144344A32B4DDAB98E6335" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1621 IH: Protecting Seniors from Health Care Fraud Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1621</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170317">March 17, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to distribute additional information to Medicare
			 beneficiaries to prevent health care fraud, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HA2DBD5CBC290495BA38A9409B4548359" style="OLC">
		<section id="H08EAEC97D0374221B8E1B0EF820F1A89" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; findings</header>
 <subsection id="HAB1C83D6828D4E26A40D8671616A4A38"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Seniors from Health Care Fraud Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HB6C5D84F04564AFFAEB87705AC68E46C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H9E780C048C5B49FABCA3950F4045A65B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Seniors are more vulnerable to fraud than the general population.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H38A0D3B3BB1A49199199F2276A2F7353"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Because seniors require more health care services than the general population, they need more information on health care schemes so they can protect themselves.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H5198092D0F1545A7867950F9AAA9D10D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Department of Health and Human Services should provide more up-to-date information in order to educate seniors on health care scams.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H47B542A73823474E9CACC3FD97D86BA4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Distribution of additional information to seniors to prevent health care fraud</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1804 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395b-2">42 U.S.C. 1395b–2</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDA586C7B1E5B41B3AF7A9613735D8089" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="H28705D9DB6104E309EB3BF1A18385AB1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Distribution of additional information on health care fraud</header>
					<paragraph id="HB03B3BB569B0442DA04A1ED604F00950"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Annual reports on health care fraud schemes</header>
 <subparagraph id="H051786944A4E4A3BA600661D9DDB65C3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In connection with the Health Care Fraud and Abuse Control Program established under section 1128C, the Secretary, acting through the Office of the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services, and the Attorney General, shall transmit to Congress, and make available to the public, an annual report on health care fraud schemes that are targeted to seniors and steps that are being taken to combat such schemes and to educate seniors concerning such schemes. The first such report shall be transmitted and made available not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this subsection.</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE217740B9E0746028C181670ECC78853"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents of reports</header>
 <clause id="HA6AC5DCDCF15484799C542313BD93FC8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to clause (ii), each annual report under subparagraph (A) shall include the following information:</text>
 <subclause id="HFE40B7B98FE048B1AF79A6D051AC570E"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Identification of most prevalent fraud schemes</header><text>The identification of the 10 most prevalent health care fraud schemes that are targeted to seniors and the prevalence and trends in such schemes.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD159067EF4FF4811B566530EB539DEE3"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Protection of seniors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Actions that seniors and law enforcement and government agencies are taking and can take to combat such schemes and to protect seniors against health care fraud schemes.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H41EC758C5D6F47CC99BB91F494FAA7F1"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Additional suggestions</header><text>Policy suggestions to improve protections for seniors, including whether the additional information provided under this subsection is helping seniors in protecting them against fraud.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H69EB2C366C7E48578F50DD5C0871C68B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may—</text> <subclause id="H05A46FB788D640DBBAB9C35A79CD12C4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>omit information from an annual report on fraud schemes targeting seniors if public disclosure of the information would compromise an ongoing investigation; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA4C8AC28D399415CAB67D8E91B721D1B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>report information on fraud schemes by categories in an annual report if a more detailed disclosure of such a scheme would educate criminals rather than seniors.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HE8699D034589406CBE41BFFB53678B60"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Private-public partnership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Office of the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services and the Attorney General, may enter into an arrangement between public and private partners to develop the report that identifies the top 10 most prevalent health care fraud schemes and the associated report information.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H155E8085ECDC4788A1B6443825EA08E0"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Quarterly updating</header><text>The information described in clauses (i) and (ii) of subparagraph (B) shall be updated quarterly to reflect changes in fraud schemes and methods to combat and educate seniors concerning such schemes.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5182F9DCD7C45ECA538C886C18F89DF"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Languages</header><text>Such reports, as updated, shall be available in English and Spanish.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDDA3EB6C99174A4FB66FC8C789E044B9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Dissemination of reports and top 10 list</header> <subparagraph id="HA00705F067C343688ACADB8A440B53E5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text>
 <clause id="H40A2DC95AAB64B7F91A3E8EB613CF349"><enum>(i)</enum><text>disseminate the reports under paragraph (1) to Medicare beneficiaries through mechanisms that reach the most Medicare beneficiaries; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD279466FA596440EAF69772C75328E78"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide for the mailing to each Medicare beneficiary of a list of the top 10 most prevalent health care fraud schemes.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H982ACB4FD19F4747AE2EA3067EE90B46"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Quarterly updates of top 10 list included with Medicare summary notices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall include an updated list of the top 10 most prevalent health care fraud schemes under paragraph (1)(C) with the quarterly Medicare summary notices mailed to Medicare beneficiaries.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD748D3C30A144C698A8D842B472BAB46"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Posting of reports and quarterly updates on websites</header><text>The annual reports, and quarterly updates, under this subsection shall be posted on the website of the Health Care Fraud and Abuse Control Program and on other websites maintained or supported by the Secretary relating to the Medicare program, the State Health Insurance Assistance Program, and Senior Medicare Patrol of the Administration on Aging.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0EEA0C4C01C04D17B6EEC45A8940D307"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Sources of information for reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information for the reports and updates under paragraph (1) shall be gathered from at least the following sources:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H25BE4C31D1BC47538CA6CB872F70F2F5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Department of Health and Human Services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following sources within the Department of Health and Human Services:</text> <clause id="HE3E3A6B03C794E918BA7A440373276D0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Medicare hotlines, including 1–800–MEDICARE, 1–800–HHSTIPS, and Medicare fraud toll-free hotlines and websites (such as www.stopmedicarefraud.gov) established by the Office of the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services and the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H22E0E3B9C94444D29BE40873FA0A9517"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>State Health Insurance Assistance Programs (SHIPs).</text> </clause><clause id="H0C7B917DCADA46AC9ADF82FF039F7C4F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The Administration on Community Living, including—</text>
 <subclause id="H28218BE431C144568AC8EC14E7A65145"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Senior Medicare Patrol (SMP) of the Administration on Aging; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H7A665A6E664344C0AFBE2A9557FA256E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Aging and Disability Resource Centers.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H35FA44D441704AA2AA4A6B9C8B0A7C63"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Medicare administrative contractors, fiscal intermediaries, and other contractors with the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services performing functions which may relate to fraud and abuse under the Medicare program.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE11619F0258E42E8AF470476C1100105"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The Indian Health Service.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HCE87B7FC2E044D8E86187781572BE791"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Department of Justice</header><text>The Department of Justice, including the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE1BF0321F044D49A06EA49C945218B5"><enum>(C)</enum><header>SSA</header><text>The Social Security Administration.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C1586005B2B4B639DB56BC8979A792B"><enum>(D)</enum><header>FTC</header><text>The Federal Trade Commission.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF99C09891424409BAFF12579F90A3EBA"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Optional additional sources</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the option of the Secretary—</text> <clause id="HAE8EAB8F49EF4FA9A974B3EE7E80B260"><enum>(i)</enum><text>State agencies that deal with elder abuse; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD470BBA9ACAD4870B22DD88EAFFF7A63"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>other governmental and nongovernmental entities with expertise in the protection of seniors from health care fraud as deemed appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


