<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H8D3B6A0A72AF4BBAA5177C0A86B47F11" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1130 IH: Fair Medicare Hospital Payments Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1130</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170216">February 16, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001273">Mrs. Black</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001243">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000582">Mr. Roe of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001289">Mr. Byrne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000591">Mrs. Roby</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000575">Mr. Rogers of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001274">Mr. Brooks of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000533">Mr. Duncan of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000754">Mr. Cooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000616">Mr. DesJarlais</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000459">Mr. Fleischmann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000392">Mr. Kustoff of Tennessee</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="A000055">Mr. Aderholt</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to ensure fairness in Medicare hospital payments by
			 establishing a floor for the area wage index applied with respect to
			 certain hospitals.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H2B8A817E5A8A47E6BACBCCC167E0680B" style="OLC">
 <section id="H27E7FED5DB1144758E75FE914771FAB1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fair Medicare Hospital Payments Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H2BA951C150FF4998BEED8A3490DB7A62"><enum>2.</enum><header>Ensuring fairness in Medicare hospital payments in a budget neutral manner</header> <subsection id="H525B1B6CFE084EFFAD2526C7B1A1A2B6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Hospital inpatient services</header><text>Section 1886(d)(3)(E) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395www">42 U.S.C. 1395www(d)(3)(E)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H096672EFA32F434BA9CE49BB92F2886E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>clause (ii) or (iii)</quote> and inserting <quote>clause (ii), (iii), or (iv)</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2BBAE71C696F4D2DBFDFB4758DF50854"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text>
					<quoted-block id="HA4EDB1C3263E45C8A823645254749DE7" style="OLC">
						<clause id="H77F4185635B648A99254861EA74CB8FE" indent="up2"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Floor on area wage index for hospitals in certain other areas</header>
 <subclause id="H74211B278C544FA2B3C14F1154A63DC7"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For discharges occurring on or after October 1, 2017, the area wage index applicable under this subparagraph to any hospital which is not located in a frontier State (as defined in clause (iii)(II)) may not be less than 0.874.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H13E643A6DCB84E588ACD9D19DB6B005F"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Ensuring budget neutrality</header><text>In order to ensure that the aggregate payments made under this subsection for a fiscal year (beginning with fiscal year 2018) are not greater than the aggregate payments that would have been made under this subsection for such fiscal year without the application of subclause (I), as estimated by the Secretary, the Secretary shall establish pursuant to rulemaking a maximum area wage index to apply under this subparagraph to any hospital which is not located in a frontier State (as defined in clause (iii)(II)).</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE5130129CDAF4EB29E0CD5544D45DA44"><enum>(III)</enum><header>No impact for hospitals with an area wage index between the floor and the maximum index</header><text>Subclauses (I) and (II) shall have no effect on the area wage index applicable in a fiscal year to a hospital with an area wage index that is greater than the floor under subclause (I) but less than the maximum area wage index established under subclause (II) for the fiscal year.</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5C2AD4DB436C44F5B0C8F4B564805779"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Hospital outpatient department services</header><text>Section 1833(t) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l(t)</external-xref>), is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HFA660170AD7E4795895A7046B3CD7B68"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(D), by striking <quote>paragraph (19), the Secretary</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (19) and (22), the Secretary</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H40F8B134D8E84938AC6C6017AE3EEBAD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block id="H968F1AB6B4454E1CA38D39D448D3388F" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HA0373D710A4448F4A63AB2171518290A"><enum>(22)</enum><header>Floor on area wage adjustment factor for hospital outpatient department services in areas other than in frontier States</header> <subparagraph id="H7FF063420BC64AADBE0FD960A4FFE504"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>With respect to covered OPD services furnished on or after January 1, 2018, the area wage adjustment factor applicable under the payment system established under this subsection to any hospital outpatient department which is not located in a frontier State (as defined in section 1886(d)(3)(E)(iii)(II)) may not be less than 0.874.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H26BA612C8AE446E1AE2CF9D04A1C4C0F"><enum>(B)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ensuring budget neutrality</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to ensure that the aggregate payments made under this subsection for a year (beginning with 2018) are not greater than the aggregate payments that would have been made under this subsection for such year without the application of subparagraph (A), as estimated by the Secretary, the Secretary shall establish pursuant to rulemaking a maximum area wage adjustment factor to apply under the payment system established under this subsection to any hospital outpatient department which is not located in a frontier State (as defined in clause (iii)(II)).</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAE4C0392C3304AE19E3F4454F562ADD6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>No impact for hospitals with an area wage adjustment factor between the floor and the maximum
 factor</header><text>Subparagraphs (A) and (B) shall have no effect on the area wage adjustment factor applicable in a year to a hospital with an area wage adjustment factor that is greater than the floor under subparagraph (A) but less than the maximum area wage adjustment factor established under subparagraph (B) for the year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


