<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HDD2758C1E2AB490EA7A4B44910E9E443" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4436 IH: Caguana Indigenous Ceremonial Park and Tibes Indigenous Ceremonial Center Study Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>115th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4436</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20171116">November 16, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000582">Miss González-Colón of Puerto Rico</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to study the suitability and feasibility of designating
			 Caguana Indigenous Ceremonial Park and Tibes Indigenous Ceremonial Center,
			 as units of the National Park System.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H71896168B0854951B1C525A67B728924" style="OLC">
		<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB932DF9D6A564BF18C5FAC08838BC281" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; findings</header>
 <subsection id="idF006E00AFE604D9ABAE52BDB815BC786"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Caguana Indigenous Ceremonial Park and Tibes Indigenous Ceremonial Center Study Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="idBCCC4FC9761845FAB69320DF7A4D9286"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds as follows:</text>
				<paragraph id="ida5c6ffda56564e0b96536341c2b4cc2d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Caguana indigenous ceremonial park</header>
 <subparagraph id="idD5E5B89D96374278968434D9F7A3ED8B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Caguana Indigenous Ceremonial Park is comprised of approximately 13.5 acres located at the center of Puerto Rico, in the Caguana Ward at the Municipality of Utuado.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEE43AEB2B9A34696B5EC10A485AF9DF0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The park is visited by approximately 60,000 students and tourists every year.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id117A2AAABF134BB888C7020C5B12234D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Efforts to protect the park began in 1915, when archeologist John Alden Mason, together with Robert T. Aitken, started research on this archeological site. A final report was issued in 1941.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1E75EFF439CE4CA8AFBEEA42F14FB27E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>In 1949, the Puerto Rican anthropologist and archeologist, Ricardo E. Alegría started a series of excavations and, in 1964, as Director of the Institute of Puerto Rican Culture, ordered the restoration of the park.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id95A30F24D1D3499EA9B8A57ABBAE2D69"><enum>(E)</enum><text>During 1992, after years of studies and investigations, the National Park Service included the park in the National Register of Historic Places. In 1993, the park received the distinction of a National Historic Landmark.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDE6EB5E55771404CB5A731B42B6993DB"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The park has one of the most surprising archeological sites of the Antilles, including 22 petroglyphs on calcareous slates, monoliths located in its main square, and the Cemí Mountain as sentinel.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id99D75930E6A94D45BB524FC62F99687C"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The park museum has a permanent exhibition of more than 80 archeological pieces from the Taíno ancestors. Other pieces are exhibited at the University of Puerto Rico Museum, the Puerto Rico Historical Archives, the National Museum of American Indians in New York City, and at Yale University, among other private collections.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA627660318A949FABDDF1D842E21B09E"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The Caguana Indigenous Ceremonial Park has unique pieces belonging to precolonial culture, from Puerto Rico and from the Caribbean, and the best way to ensure their protection of these treasures may be the inclusion of the park as a unit of the National Park Service.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id829A942F0DC14553B1C9980DD98AE515"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Tibes indigenous ceremonial center</header>
 <subparagraph id="idCD76354B26E24FD19388414105074198"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Tibes Indigenous Ceremonial Center is located between the wards of Tibes and Portugués in the municipality of Ponce, and is considered one of the most significant indigenous sites in the Caribbean. The center is visited by approximately 80,000 students and tourists every year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id76529E4492DA48259CF2344BFE56FFE8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In 1975, Don Luis Hernández—a sugar cane worker—discovered the remnants of indigenous cultures after the massive flooding caused by Hurricane Eloísa.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id894DEDDA4CD747B6908219E089652542"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Just after the discovery, the Guaynia Society of Archeology and History from the Pontifical Catholic University of Puerto Rico started the excavations and restoration on the site. The group was assisted by the renowned Antillean archeologist, Ricardo Alegría.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id59EF23A0B0374137899BD39B3C90C64E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>After months of excavations, the Society had discovered the oldest Antillean indigenous ceremonial site in Puerto Rico, including the largest indigenous cemetery on the Island with more than 186 human remains from the Igneri and Pre-Taíno cultures.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC6DFB143EEC0401B82F13586497FBAE9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Additionally, the Society discovered nine plazas used by the indigenous to dance the areyto, play ball and celebrate ceremonies of great importance. The plazas varied in size from 42 feet long by 35.8 feet wide to 115 feet long by 30.5 feet wide, and were named as follows: Horseshoe Ball Court, Cemí Ball Court, Santa Elena Ball Court, One Row Ball Court, Principal Plaza, Oval or Elliptical Plaza, Bat Ball Court, and Chief Ball Court. The ninth court remains unnamed.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id42298CD529FC40C1AFB1723A6623FE68"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The Tibes Indigenous Ceremonial Center is key in the education of the current and next generations of Puerto Ricans about our indigenous roots. Thus, the best way to preserve our heritage may be the inclusion of the center as a unit of the National Park Service.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id60C4D242356A436CB7868ECDFA6662B3"><enum>2.</enum><header>National park service study</header>
 <subsection id="id7299812B114A491DA3B0D03693D865FA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior shall—</text> <paragraph id="id700047FE3D7A4772830FD2F0B1B0D280"><enum>(1)</enum><text>carry out a study regarding the suitability and feasibility of designating Caguana Indigenous Ceremonial Park and Tibes Indigenous Ceremonial Center as units of the National Park System; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id48AB437E5E4949F4ACC92C9FB961E023"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consider management alternatives for the Caguana Indigenous Ceremonial Park and Tibes Indigenous Ceremonial Center.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idBFC714965B5E442CA2A90CB8B6BB0796"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study process and completion</header><text>Except as provided by subsection (c) of this section, section 100507(c) of title 54, United States Code, shall apply to the conduct and completion of the study required by this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id68802D66F62F42C6B5E45A47E57C4E29"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Submission of study results</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date that funds are made available for this section, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report describing the results of the study.</text></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


