<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HDB80D3C37ECD4C79A7EC20DFDF407A3B" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1650 IH: National Adoption and Foster Care Home Study Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1650</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170321">March 21, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000604">Mr. Russell</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a national, research-based, and comprehensive home study assessment process for the
			 evaluation of prospective foster parents and adoptive parents and provide
			 funding to States and Indian tribes to adopt such process.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HDBFC1F58EDD8424894DD889B30741C18" style="OLC">
 <section id="H0B28776EA10F4C36B16344A709F63951" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Adoption and Foster Care Home Study Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H8598CB2EC4A94D3BB14A325861BE39BD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Demonstration program for the implementation of a national home study process</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title II of the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act and Adoption Reform Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5111">42 U.S.C. 5111</external-xref> et seq.) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4F1DB6F1EBC640EAA20DDD0FB8D48891"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 203(b) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5113">42 U.S.C. 5113(b)</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph id="H513A9C40669B4EF4945DE1D33DFFA942"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(A), by striking <quote>(including</quote> and inserting <quote>(including the national database established under section 203A(c) but containing</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9585E18DE8F44BAAAB8E6B4B874567DC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (10), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting <quote>;</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF858B840AD204EF3B7763F3CCE8D9E25"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (11), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D9454DF9B6D4AAA976506EB2C15F417"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H28C220EB057A4239805946E4405C9325" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H83A2711F084B4830A2B9C36F3129CB75"><enum>(12)</enum><text>establish a demonstration program, not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the National Adoption and Foster Care Home Study Act, through which each participating State or Indian tribe—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H558A385E6673499B80B70F6BC0D31FD4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>adopts the uniform, research-based home study methodology for the evaluation of prospective foster parents and adoptive parents developed by the Secretary under section 203A(a); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4D764974D3E94D3BAC6763FB4D70E708"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides data gathered through operation of the program to the Secretary, as the Secretary may require for purposes of the national database under section 203A(c).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1F71D7A7B1A4E1CAA8BAB7A13BFBA83"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after section 203 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5113">42 U.S.C. 5113</external-xref>) the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H9FD2354157B54D72AD0AB55990B48659" style="OLC"> <section id="H5DD1BB2D56654CAA8D1126A258C854CE"><enum>203A.</enum><header>National home study demonstration programs; national database</header> <subsection id="HBC0BCA8FD2F54E4384D62CFC3229F018"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program methodology</header><text>Each demonstration program established by a State or Indian tribe in accordance with section 203(b)(12) shall use a uniform, research-based home study methodology for the evaluation of prospective foster parents and adoptive parents (developed by the Secretary after consultation with stakeholders and professionals in the field of child welfare) that shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H801CDFEA56EA4E1790C8BC699044BAF6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>incorporate—</text> <subparagraph id="H90BB9872559D4A4688281DEB170A5ADD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>information gathering tools, including—</text>
 <clause id="H63459BC23F0A44BC8846045FCC98912E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an initial written questionnaire that is a uniform set of closed-ended questions with a variety of possible answers that provides significant family information;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD8530F029CD6447A8B0A79C9CCD1888F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a secondary in-person questionnaire that is administered in a private setting in the home, and, if applicable, with both applicants present together; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H57C28420B47543A1AB37CCD34A6A03EE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>guidelines that describe standardized questions that an individual serving as a reference for the applicant uses in writing a reference letter, to be sent directly to such individual and not shared with the applicant, and which is consistent with the questionnaires described in clauses (i) and (ii);</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80359973E7074FEC8EF122FA52D7ACC0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a written guidance document to assist home study practitioners in performing a psychosocial evaluation of the applicant that—</text>
 <clause id="H063FF0047AEF48199E20C925D87F83CC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provides instructions on how to systematically analyze information learned from the information gathering tools described in subparagraph (A) in order to identify specific strengths and concerns of the applicant;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4B8E3E2BAF00412B8D02FE1A67B668BB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provides sufficient information for the home study practitioner to determine the significance of behaviors and events in the applicant’s life in relation to being a successful foster care or adoption provider; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA5BEB6B255774973B105A5923A3898FA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>includes a rating system that will be incorporated into the home study report described in subparagraph (C); and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64FC267DAEBE43C289834AA050AC96D3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a model home study report that may, at the discretion of the Secretary, be customized by a State or Indian tribe as necessary to comply with State or tribal and local regulations and requirements;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE6E127D878D415484BD3E7F7A3C3B82"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure ongoing training of home study certified personnel; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H949CD515CF7A4EB6A0EAC809D0F964D0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>designate a home study auditor to ensure quality control and accuracy of information provided to placing agencies.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAAC55480B7164A96B3CBFA5E288F89F9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants</header><text>The Secretary shall make grants to States and Indian tribes to enable and encourage the States and Indian tribes to establish demonstration programs in accordance with section 203(b)(12).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H36494ECB699A414695A446A6E9C21265"><enum>(c)</enum><header>National database</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a secure national database of home study reports filed by home study practitioners using the home study methodology described in subsection (a). Such database shall be accessible only to State and tribal foster care and adoption agencies, or a designated entity, as determined by the lead agency in the State, to assist with the selection of prospective foster parents and adoptive parents.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H99F5F08AEAF94793A47600C7ECEA5ABE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Condition on participation in demonstration project</header><text>As a condition for participating in the demonstration program under section 203(b)(12), a State or Indian tribe shall agree to recognize as valid all home study reports listed in the database described in subsection (c), including such reports filed by other States or Indian tribes.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H99098DF6A3CE4D75A283D00EDB67374C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>The Secretary shall enter into a contract with an independent entity to—</text> <paragraph id="HC88FB1474C3742B2BDA5071DAEB2D363"><enum>(1)</enum><text>carry out a periodic evaluation of the home study methodology established under subsection (a) and the demonstration programs established in accordance with section 203(b)(12); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1D61241A545A49B38A1B60335656106A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to the Secretary a report that includes—</text> <subparagraph id="H46900C2E231948C0A70932D645B051AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the extent to which such methodology—</text>
 <clause id="H147CB86C8E254022A3AAEF109F4666C9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>meets the requirements of each of paragraphs (1) through (3) of subsection (a);</text> </clause><clause id="H8644BA5C61BE4F90B6E7F2FAADFB47FF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>expedites the screening of caregivers to promote more family-based care over institutional care for children;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1DD24E5FEA1541AC87C7CB73CFD742DD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provides cost savings to State or Indian tribe foster care and adoption systems;</text> </clause><clause id="HCF9D72A2AA28479494EF7BF83C266AC2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>reduces the number of children waiting for foster care or adoptive placement; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H87736C18823B4D6DB7C100AE6C27A6BA"><enum>(v)</enum><text>reduces the number of prospective families waiting for foster care or adoptive placement; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H802F0217119542EBA3664E4029DE5125"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommendations for expanding the demonstration program and home study methodology to all States and Indian tribes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0DCC806F01D34ECD979357F9C9C8F369"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 205(b) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5115">42 U.S.C. 5115(b)</external-xref>), by adding at the end the following: <quote>The Secretary may allocate such sums as the Secretary determines to be appropriate from the funds appropriated under subsection (a) for activities under section 203(b)(12) and 203A.</quote>.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


