<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2522D11C0CA94F1CA986115895E83960" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1500 : Robert Emmet Park Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1500</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date date="20170629">June 29, 2017</action-date><action-desc> Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To redesignate the small triangular property located in Washington, DC, and designated by the
			 National Park Service as reservation 302 as <quote>Robert Emmet Park</quote>, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H037BB77BA9D84672BBFBE1CFBADB9C37" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE5E996DCDD5847BBA2A7CFB155F39066" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Robert Emmet Park Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H8A16FE9C31A94CF9A33E823A2CAEA112"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="H6F58E82258214F6BB9811966081E23CF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Robert Emmet was one of Ireland’s most prominent historical figures, having led an effort to secure Irish independence in 1803.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEE8E4C6114A541C386E6DD594D2FF78A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Although Emmet’s efforts initially failed, they succeeded in inspiring new generations of Irish men and women to struggle for independence.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD6E2288D19624856B64B130FE2C1178B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>For his efforts to gain Irish independence, Emmet was found guilty of treason and sentenced to death by hanging.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCFB5C11DAB7941CC8595B846E462C491"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Robert Emmet’s <quote>Speech from the Dock</quote> motivated many of the efforts that led to an independent Ireland following 1916's Easter Rising; (Emmet famously said that <quote>To [Ireland] I sacrificed every selfish, every lasting sentiment * * * I wished to place her independence beyond the reach of any power of earth * * * to procure for my country the guarantee which Washington procured for America * * * to exalt her to that proud station in the world.</quote>). Emmet was strongly influenced by American democracy and the American Revolution.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H09FCAF2B8AC24B5B85605DACC1AC7135"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Emmet had family members similarly admiring of the United States and dedicated to the cause of Irish independence, including his brother Thomas Addis Emmet who went on to become a prominent Attorney General of New York.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB5A4DA9D20454C668A96908F00168000"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Emmet has been revered by generations of Irish-Americans for his leadership, courage, and sacrifice.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB19909BE4B784F12A2C4F5CBE6961C89"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Fifty years ago on April 22, 1966, the Robert Emmet Statue was dedicated on a small parcel of National Park Service land (reservation 302) at the corner of 24th Street NW and Massachusetts Avenue NW in Washington, DC.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H987326724E724144896D67F005922E61"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Robert Emmet’s statue is the central feature of reservation 302.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H53CA2B409A1D46658FB9987188F3BFC6"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Many leading Members of Congress, including Speaker of the House John W. McCormack and Senators Everett Dirksen and Mike Mansfield served on the Robert Emmet Statue Dedication Committee.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0928710DFBB645D0BC80706D653E20E9"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Other members of that committee and participants in the dedication ceremony included Secretary of the Interior Stewart Udall, Representative Michael Kirwan, Ambassador of Ireland William P. Fay, and Rector of St. Matthews Cathedral John K. Cartwright.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HECA483FC17A2441DB0637D652A7B64D6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Redesignation of Robert Emmet Park</header>
 <subsection id="H41E26F882A1F4D4E87FE785CD535DD52"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Redesignation</header><text>The small triangular property designated by the National Park Service as reservation 302, shall be known as <quote>Robert Emmet Park</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFF81297CA5D74BEE8F0E15ACBEBFE6C2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reference</header><text>Any reference in any law, regulation, document, record, map, paper, or other record of the United States to the property referred to in subsection (a) is deemed to be a reference to <quote>Robert Emmet Park</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H97FE77B1170A4367846E23FCEBFF117C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Signage</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior may post signs on or near Robert Emmet Park that include one or more of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H9042FC3A20B145D4BF34F8D8F1009D0D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Information on Robert Emmet, his contribution to Irish Independence, and his respect for the United States and the American Revolution.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA91419B74F864D248D3209A7A77D4AC9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Information on the history of the statue of Robert Emmet located in Robert Emmet Park.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20170627">Passed the House of Representatives June 28, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk</role></attestation-group></attestation> </bill> 

