<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCB785B0C0D4D4536BD30347B41569D02" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1390 IH: To amend title 38, United States Code, to authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to pay costs relating to the transportation of certain deceased veterans to veterans’ cemeteries owned by a State or tribal organization.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1390</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170307">March 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001299">Mr. Banks of Indiana</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001189">Mr. Messer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001305">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000600">Mrs. Radewagen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to pay costs
			 relating to the transportation of certain deceased veterans to veterans’
			 cemeteries owned by a State or tribal organization.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HFA6BB2E358D54A3F918F97773000215D" style="OLC">
		<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0F3E24F17DAB4B0EA8229482E4040924" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Transportation of deceased veterans to veterans’ cemeteries</header>
 <subsection id="H9D613BADA19F439C960F85FE5B6B6CA3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) of section 2308 of title 38, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC81464D856FA4112B5D3C58857D612BA" style="USC"> <subsection id="HB2FA05FA2C384DCD9FA811B8C2ABF03D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0829AFD330234D0FB022E20BE2A260DE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary may pay, in addition to any amount paid pursuant to section 2302 or 2307 of this title, the cost of transportation of the deceased veteran described in paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (b) for burial in a national cemetery or a covered veterans’ cemetery. Such payment shall not exceed the cost of transportation to the national cemetery nearest the veteran’s last place of residence in which burial space is available.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H35BCBE02A0AD428BBDC6BFD660776739" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary may pay, in addition to any amount paid pursuant to section 2302 or 2307 of this title, the cost of transportation of the deceased veteran described in subsection (b)(3) for burial in a national cemetery. Such payment shall not exceed the cost of transportation to the national cemetery nearest the veteran’s last place of residence in which burial space is available.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF369DE3E86044540825ED482FC3270E1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered Veterans’ Cemetery Defined</header><text>Section 2308 of such title is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAFC8CAC7DDA7495E9B8BDCEB6078A317" style="USC"> <subsection id="H9DAA53B4AFED4D2D8828E28482254708"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Covered Veterans’ Cemetery Defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>covered veterans’ cemetery</term> means, with respect to a deceased veteran described in subsection (b), a veterans’ cemetery owned by a State or a tribal organization (as defined in section 3765(4) of this title) in which the deceased veteran is eligible to be buried.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H13AE81CD480E45D4BF767D6B331E01D9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming Amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2308 of such title is amended in the section heading by adding at the end the following: <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">or a veterans’ cemetery</header-in-text></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H132C5F506AF644B8AB221898A35DBE80"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 23 of such title is amended by striking the item relating to section 2308 and inserting the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8917026B61634086811B18BEB62CB0A9" style="USC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">2308. Transportation of deceased veteran to a national cemetery or a veterans’ cemetery.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


