<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HDD13940440854C13858098003A914540" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3174 IH: CHampioning Apprenticeships for New Careers and Employees in TECHnology Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3174</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170710">July 10, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001056">Ms. Herrera Beutler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000584">Mrs. Love</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Labor to enter into contracts with industry intermediaries for purposes
			 of promoting the development of and access to apprenticeships in the
			 technology sector, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H5E7A81B90F7D464FB2625EB40D7E7663" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE49D121D42C54DD18BF9160C43506226" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>CHampioning Apprenticeships for New Careers and Employees in TECHnology Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CHANCE in TECH Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H5919FB1C24DC4E05A0E59D4FE0DFAE36"><enum>2.</enum><header>Congressional findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H7AF19201D90544FDA7D05453B6678BB0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>During any given 90-day period there can be more than 500,000 information technology job openings in the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H280C5E90028B41B0894D94020FB55346"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Employment in the technology sector is growing twice as fast as employment in the United States.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD9645086577B491CB95A7400D52BE97A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Jobs in the technology sector tend to provide higher pay and better benefits than other jobs and have been more resilient to economic downturn than jobs available in other private sector industries.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6A1741CD834E496B9F5BFED5F5C92E7A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Information technology skills are transferable across nearly all industries.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H450CFBAE4D744B95A42E15E0E80806F5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Exceptional education and on-the-job training programs exist and should be scaled to meet the demands of the modern technology workforce.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9CC920BBF12F44BCA93D20F9AD0414F9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Adoption of existing employer-driven intermediary models, such as ApprenticeshipUSA under the Department of Labor, will help grow the information technology workforce.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE382CCC498624788992185B8F1157955"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Career pathway education should start in high school through pathways and programs of study that align with local and regional employer needs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB7145973017946029E04CEBEE869FEB8"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Preparing a student for a job in the technology sector is essential to the growth and competitiveness of the economy in the United States in the 21st century.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5E6BE48F949449DFA0473E17F0B30B3B"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Nearly 800,000 information technology workers will retire between 2017 and 2024.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H128A6A2729F64775AD11EC20BA995F5C"><enum>(10)</enum><text>In 2016, the average salary in the information technology sector was $108,000, while the average salary among all other sectors was $53,040.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H05AC993AA71D448E9145C3F346CB5325"><enum>3.</enum><header>Technology apprenticeship contracts</header>
 <subsection id="H397C168CC0634C278F4B7A2B3F035FB6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Labor (referred to in this section as <quote>the Secretary</quote>) shall enter into contracts with industry intermediaries for the purpose of promoting the development of and access to apprenticeships in the technology sector, from amounts appropriated under subsection (e).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9C6365747B4443B9A6DFED7069D24003"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to be awarded a contract under this section, an industry intermediary shall submit an application to the Secretary, at such time and in such a manner as may be required by the Secretary, that identifies proposed activities designed to further the purpose described in subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H01D1E8ED7F1D4CF3BF23750BE69BEA7C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Selection</header><text>The Secretary shall award contracts under this section based on competitive criteria to be prescribed by the Secretary.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD371BD97FD034608B8E40FD606D4371A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Contractor activities</header><text>An industry intermediary that is awarded a contract under this section may only use the funds made available through such contract to carry out activities designed to further the purpose described in subsection (a), including—</text>
 <paragraph id="H90AA8133E0404A2DB22597AE5D0EE2A5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>facilitating the provision and development of apprenticeships in the technology sector through collaborations with public and private entities that provide job-related instruction, such as on-the-job training, pre-apprenticeship training, and technical training;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF0F36BD908E449EBAABE8513F029546E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encouraging entities to establish such apprenticeships;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H759230B5CC3C42A390202D47A9F651D7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identifying, assessing, and training applicants for such apprenticeships who are—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE737090C69704CC4BFB09DE03FA0CFE0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enrolled in high school;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H502BA49CDBFF43FA9E69ABE17515C659"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enrolled in an early college high school that focuses on education in STEM subjects;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2A04FF607AB4325AD587D7E1D4D0DF0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>individuals aged 18 years or older who meet appropriate qualification standards; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A3F0F06524B4C06907B588CC0D905B1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>enrolled in pre-apprenticeship or apprenticeship training initiatives that allow adults to concurrently increase academic and workforce skills through proven, evidence-based models that connect all learning to the specific apprenticeship involved and significantly accelerate completion of preparation for the apprenticeship; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBAB4E1B72A4641428F1B19C4695B91EA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>tracking the progress of such applicants who participate in such apprenticeships.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8BEB000EDA364D0793FF0C668A3E2D68"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary such sums as may be necessary for the purposes of carrying out this section.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H3B5C58CDD68B48F8BD3551A66F82917B"><enum>4.</enum><header>CHANCE in TECH Awards for 21st Century Schools</header>
 <subsection id="H536C041B12AD4241BAD61C566F1BEA1B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Awards authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Education may issue awards, to be known as <quote>CHANCE in TECH Awards for 21st Century Schools</quote>, to schools (referred to in this section as <quote>covered schools</quote>) that—</text> <paragraph id="H4DF52A751C74427DBA16D68627B3B119"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are secondary schools or junior or community colleges; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2C61B1002B274282A6850BD8E80B29C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demonstrate high achievement in providing students necessary skills to compete in the 21st century workforce.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5F6AB35C9F50446F8EC31F255C7A96D1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>In selecting a covered school for an award under subsection (a), the Secretary shall take into account—</text>
 <paragraph id="H1FC91002D3EF463EB4D51EF79DB91E18"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the availability of STEM, career and technical education, and computer technology courses at the covered school;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9884D97E737E496285038B6C35BA59F6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">State academic assessments, as described in section 111(b)(2) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311(b)(2)</external-xref>), of students at the covered school in STEM subjects;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H096867442E3545208A004733EA99322F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any coordination between the covered school and local and regional employers in the technology sector for the purpose of providing work-based learning programs such as apprenticeships and internships; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H155D962178EC48E7B36DF2266D8AE78A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the availability of individualized plans provided by the covered school to students relating to postsecondary education or training, career paths, and financial aid.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H26B962C640E54A2E97AA1448E2DA901B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Funding</header>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H596B9AC893414FD3867EE646CD07E29E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Fiscal year 2017</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts made available to the Secretary of Labor under the Department of Labor Appropriations Act, 2017 to carry out the Act referred to in section 6(1) may be used to carry out this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6C4BF780E1A2460E8F974DCE4BCF497A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Subsequent years</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2018 and each subsequent fiscal year.</text>
 </subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6DA19928FC964457B804C7714B944588"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA96ADCED2100466B940048D062C33E49"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Apprenticeship</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>apprenticeship</term> means an apprenticeship registered under the Act of August 16, 1937 (commonly known as the “National Apprenticeship Act”; 50 Stat. 664, chapter 663; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/50">29 U.S.C. 50</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8BD17A416BB44F88BBA0F3A70E8F2D2E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Career and technical education</header><text>The term <term>career and technical education</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3 of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2302">20 U.S.C. 2302</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5CE63169DA32492588E03E8CBD571417"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Early college high school</header><text>The term <term>early college high school</term> has the meaning given such term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0FA5EBDC3DC8447A93E86C382313DE47"><enum>(4)</enum><header>High school</header><text>The term <term>high school</term> has the meaning given such term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD61B7DB5753A496694843508FC58C080"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Industry intermediary</header><text>The term <term>industry intermediary</term> means an entity that—</text> <subparagraph id="H96F99484C80348E88FD39230278DE789"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in order to accelerate apprenticeship program development and help establish new apprenticeship partnerships at the national, State, or regional level, serves as a conduit between an employer and an entity, such as—</text>
 <clause id="H623A52E0325C4E02A646AA99E170C471"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an industry partner;</text> </clause><clause id="HDCDBD842E5864FA99549FB9514E4BD27"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Department of Labor; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H54A299BDF7B24E06ACBE8F680843AD38"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a State agency responsible for workforce development programs;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68DA3A2968424550828F5CB1F263413C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demonstrates a capacity to work with employers and other key partners to identify workforce trends and foster public-private funding to establish new apprenticeship programs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE70FC1F50454BC3BD17B737D2440913"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is an entity such as—</text> <clause id="H37B5ECA9AD8546078AF8C1A13821B891"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a business;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB32DC3A00BD349BD8D6BB5B52B395539"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a consortium of businesses;</text> </clause><clause id="H789539B89734487BBDE21B9373EC8B8D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a business-related nonprofit organization, including industry associations and business federations;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9F4055E6EAF94AAE867FF222B1B9D6C1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a private organization functioning as a workforce intermediary for the express purpose of serving the needs of businesses, including community-based nonprofit service providers and industry-aligned training providers; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H58DF5B89760447AAB4A56E0A2952BDD3"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a consortium of any of the entities described in clauses (i) through (iv).</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H823355EA960246119B557F5A5D2749AF"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given such term in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1623F6E2DD024260AC0B2D7A07968C9D"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Junior or community college</header><text>The term <term>junior or community college</term> has the meaning given the term in section 312(f) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1058">20 U.S.C. 1058(f)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE5350AF815AB4C40BB9CA1B88BFED787"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Local educational agency</header><text>The term <term>local educational agency</term> has the meaning given such term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3253994BCF554215B9A9E3C0A6DDF043"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Secondary school</header><text>The term <term>secondary school</term> has the meaning given such term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC4C34D980DA4142999EAF7B9B287E70"><enum>(10)</enum><header>State educational agency</header><text>The term <term>State educational agency</term> has the meaning given such term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF2D2BE1D4078403DA25F0F5AB8EC5C52"><enum>(11)</enum><header>STEM</header><text>The term <term>STEM</term> means science, technology, engineering, and mathematics.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6DC893DADBB84AC1ABA806535D32E8A6"><enum>(12)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Technology sector</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>technology sector</quote> means the industry sector involved in the design or development of hardware, software, or security of digital data.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


