<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H15AC488F773444479DA058086CC9E033" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><form><distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 522</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170113">January 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000289">Mr. Goodlatte</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000258">Mr. Peterson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000244">Mr. Sensenbrenner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000583">Mr. Smith of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000266">Mr. Chabot</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000362">Mr. King of Iowa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000552">Mr. Gohmert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000289">Mr. Jordan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000592">Mr. Poe of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001076">Mr. Chaffetz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001179">Mr. Marino</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000566">Mr. Gowdy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000573">Mr. Labrador</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000460">Mr. Farenthold</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001093">Mr. Collins of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000621">Mr. DeSantis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000820">Mrs. Mimi Walters of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001297">Mr. Buck</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000601">Mr. Ratcliffe</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000475">Mr. Trott</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001293">Mr. Bishop of Michigan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000591">Mrs. Roby</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000578">Mr. Gaetz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000299">Mr. Johnson of Louisiana</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To limit donations made pursuant to settlement agreements to which the United States is a party, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC27DFD818A204F0FB2969E9D97735026" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H990B765336574D91BF582F67FC87D1F5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Settlement Slush Funds Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H06665680903C493392DF1F198E6C516E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limitation on donations made pursuant to settlement agreements to which the united states is a party</header> <subsection id="HB42432ED79B04C87B09009B75C6A4FBE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Limitation on required donations</header><text>An official or agent of the Government may not enter into or enforce any settlement agreement on behalf of the United States, directing or providing for a payment to any person or entity other than the United States, other than a payment that provides restitution for or otherwise directly remedies actual harm (including to the environment) directly and proximately caused by the party making the payment, or constitutes payment for services rendered in connection with the case.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3B57E27FA7FA42B3B1677D8B93C7C45F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>Any official or agent of the Government who violates subsection (a), shall be subject to the same penalties that would apply in the case of a violation of section 3302 of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE3EB9341550E4F62B53C425FA4A60CAC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsections (a) and (b) apply only in the case of a settlement agreement concluded on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE3ED32A5C87E4352A9B820C8E08B9B55"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>The term <quote>settlement agreement</quote> means a settlement agreement resolving a civil action or potential civil action.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF549F3AE4E334DBA8038766DB00F45B6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports on settlement agreements</header> <paragraph id="H36ED6FC5D3764A5BA18BF4044187B72A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning at the end of the first fiscal year that begins after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the head of each Federal agency shall submit electronically to the Congressional Budget Office a report on each settlement agreement entered into by that agency during that fiscal year that directs or provides for a payment to a person or entity other than the United States that provides restitution for or otherwise directly remedies actual harm (including to the environment) directly and proximately caused by the party making the payment, or constitutes payment for services rendered in connection with the case, including the parties to each settlement agreement, the source of the settlement funds, and where and how such funds were and will be distributed.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF176354A79424C358C95714A43F69828"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition on additional funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H087AF59C24A74BD2A2695DACC7531568"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This subsection shall cease to be effective on the date that is 7 years after the date of the enactment of this Act. </text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCF64EBDEF5DD4F13B51E3029663B2C36"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Annual audit requirement</header> 
<paragraph id="H1042D4E9DDEB4902802E008077790CC0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning at the end of the first fiscal year that begins after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Inspector General of each Federal agency shall submit a report to the Committees on the Judiciary, on the Budget and on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, on any settlement agreement entered into in violation of this section by that agency.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H19717104D1A74E0C9FE74A8A2C5B1082"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition on additional funding</header><text>No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

