<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HAEAC8E80F06B478B9D664A5B2A5EBA33" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2951 IH: To allow Members of Congress to carry a concealed handgun anywhere in the United States, with exceptions.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2951</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170620">June 20, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To allow Members of Congress to carry a concealed handgun anywhere in the United States, with
			 exceptions.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HCAED9355C74343D7B6E54F818AD7B8E5" style="OLC">
		<section id="HC732DF117E984DD1B2689F31A45DC7C7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Carrying of concealed handguns by Members of Congress</header>
 <subsection id="H6C255C153934475F9DEDE6CE491EE723"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/44">Chapter 44</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/926C">section 926C</external-xref> the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H466AFD481E2A4678A1641F3E6E03A2C9" style="USC">
					<section id="H174CC0F1623B4330801A157BF570D917"><enum>926D.</enum><header>Carrying of concealed handguns by Members of Congress</header>
 <subsection id="HF279507642C34A30ADFBBA049B3481D3"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a Member of Congress who is carrying the identification required by subsection (e), to whom a State or the United States Capitol Police has issued a license or permit to carry a concealed handgun, and who is not otherwise prohibited by this chapter from transporting, shipping, or receiving a firearm, may carry a concealed handgun for any lawful purpose, subject to the terms and conditions of the license or permit (if issued by the United States Capitol Police), anywhere in the United States, except as provided in subsection (b).</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="HDB5111232A5046458A2CA4D57547EFD7"><enum>(b)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD2CE86322D7C42AB911F45EC2F311151"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) shall not apply in or on the grounds of the White House, or wherever the United States Secret Service is prohibiting the possession of a firearm.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC4A514719718449BAB9EB18E972D5C23" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) shall not apply to a Member of Congress while on an air carrier, unless the Secretary of Homeland Security finds that the Member of Congress has successfully completed the training program established under section 44921(c) of title 49.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H28676667A9AB4220B86CCE900D82260E"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chief of the United States Capitol Police is authorized to issue a license or permit to carry a concealed handgun to a Member of Congress for purposes of this section, under such terms and conditions and in accordance with such criteria as the Chief considers appropriate.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H842744FB5D484DC7B725C406FCC45FB7"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure that the training program established under section 44921(c) of title 49 is made available to any Member of Congress, on request of the Member of Congress.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H847E85FF60384C9AA40A13E0414E1450"><enum>(e)</enum><text>The identification required by this subsection is the photographic identification issued by a House of the Congress that identifies the person photographed as a Member of that House.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAE089D5220A34CE087C61A9CFE389D29"><enum>(f)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>Member of Congress</term> means a Senator or a Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="HBBAFEBB1B5134C598AB137A29E79A5B2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 926C the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE9099F02F1514819A597BC1FE5664C14" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">926D. Carrying of concealed handguns by Members of Congress.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="HCD781EB729184B4BB9D4F207E6E6875C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authorizing Members of Congress to use official funds to pay for firearms training program</header>
 <subsection id="HFC72D3A8846D4268AE39D1F8B200B2BB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Senators</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Senators’ Official Personnel and Office Expense Account may be used to pay for the Senator to receive training under the program established under section 44921(c) of title 49, United States Code.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF8753782727545AC9AE3CE20527D3E67"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Members of the House of Representatives</header><text>Section 101 of the House of Representatives Administrative Reform Technical Corrections Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/5341">2 U.S.C. 5341</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HBEEFB92C5ECA489E8CFD6C0BCBE85198"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (b) through (e) as subsections (c) through (f); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H860786A4B759442FA62948676B960AB5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following new subsection:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H52E8A1B612034BD792AF66533FF35A3B" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HD2668DEA2F5944159C5FDF41B4B023A9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Firearms training program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Members’ Representational Allowance may be used to pay for the Member to receive training under the program established under section 44921(c) of title 49, United States Code.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


