<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD1DD556752294B9BBE2543427F5DD8F2" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4647 IH: Recovering America’s Wildlife Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4647</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171214">December 14, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000449">Mr. Fortenberry</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Pittman-Robertson Wildlife Restoration Act to make supplemental funds available for
			 management of fish and wildlife species of greatest conservation need as
			 determined by State fish and wildlife agencies, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H83540E4D74804FC6AFB5AF41F11DC141" style="OLC">
 <section id="H0B67BB2B5E0943F2AC3D5ED70B5AA5A9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Recovering America’s Wildlife Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HEDCA2FD791294CF0A1E7578DC6D58CFC" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HF2D16F1AC3A24EC6B75230316D09D0B1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A diverse array of species of fish and wildlife is of significant value to the United States for aesthetic, ecological, educational, cultural, recreational, economic, and scientific reasons.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFA4659D1EC6B461593EC1045C13F9690"><enum>(2)</enum><text>More than 100 million citizens of the United States participate in outdoor recreation through hunting, fishing, birding, and other wildlife-dependent recreation, all of which have significant value to the citizens who engage in those activities and provide economic benefits to local communities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3A6FEA70E6A648549DA5B75FE8F73B82"><enum>(3)</enum><text>It is in the interest of the United States—</text> <subparagraph id="H6D4F3FB0ADD64309BED28F79F5689244"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to retain for present and future generations the opportunity to hunt, fish, observe, understand, and appreciate a wide variety of fish and wildlife;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56477B2CA90F4404AB1CA34C16E57483"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to recover species of fish and wildlife listed as threatened species or endangered species under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531</external-xref> et seq.) and to prevent fish and wildlife species from declining to the point of requiring Federal protection under such Act; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72032E0017EB4CD1AC36B19E65F322CE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to support collaborative and proactive conservation that will sustain the diverse fish and wildlife populations of the United States.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H37A770EB108A4BABB5AC267D6A8C082E"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The first nongovernmental conservation organizations to instill fish and wildlife conservation values in hunters, anglers, bird watchers, and all citizens were founded during the 1880s to 1890s at the behest of hunters and anglers, including Theodore Roosevelt and naturalist George Bird Grinnell, who were alarmed that game and sportfish could not sustain unregulated harvest and that avifauna needed protection from commercial take.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5460E3E2F7B54BB38CA9EBF40835DDBB"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the turn of the 20th century, the States—</text> <subparagraph id="HF213C9A524FA4AFB9B0BAB75773546E2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>realized the need to regulate the harvest of game and sportfish for sustainable use;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB2E7211AE8846D688CE7492A9B4C7E4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>required hunters and anglers to obtain licenses and established regulations for game seasons, bag and creel limits, and legal means of take for game and sportfish; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA0ED5B1E70F40118EB2C7C0BCF930C7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>used the funds received for such licenses largely for enforcement of such regulations.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC0718C9F60A44AC83946D8735C6A180"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 1937, an alliance between hunters and conservation organizations, States, the Federal Government, and the shooting sports industry convinced Congress to transfer to the States receipts from an existing Federal excise tax on sporting arms and ammunition, matched by State hunting license dollars, for the management of wildlife and conservation of habitat under the Pittman-Robertson Wildlife Restoration Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/669">16 U.S.C. 669</external-xref> et seq.), which greatly enhanced the States’ ability to move from primarily enforcing game seasons and bag limits to science-based research and management of wildlife.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H26230CC70B3148F4B1AF8ED1EDF1A33C"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 1951, an alliance between anglers and conservation organizations, States, the Federal Government, and the sportfishing industry convinced Congress to impose a Federal excise tax on fishing equipment under the Dingell-Johnson Sportfish Restoration Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/777">16 U.S.C. 777</external-xref> et seq.) and to transfer to the States such receipts, matched by State fishing license revenues, to manage sportfish and conserve aquatic habitats, enhancing the State fish and wildlife agency’s ability to use science-based research and management of fish species.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCFE5AED06C624EC3856D6124E90B2B56"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Such user-pay, public-benefits means of funding fish and wildlife conservation is unique in the world, having been started in the United States by sportsmen and sportswomen who were willing to pay these fees to ensure dedicated funds went to fish and wildlife conservation delivered by the States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA100DB6D30644E3E9F357D24E2623F84"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Such user-pay funds (licenses and excise taxes)—</text> <subparagraph id="H5E5990F498044050BC8E7EB96589F5F7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have benefitted not only hunters and anglers, but all citizens of the United States by providing abundant fish and wildlife (including both game and nongame species), clean water, outdoor recreation, healthy activities, and quality of life; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H583BE1F3E5D54D6BADDD8E06B2A15749"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide, and will continue to provide, a majority of the funds that are available to State fish and wildlife agencies for science-based research and management of fish and wildlife.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H09330CE2662E4153B721633E5B13574D"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">State fish and wildlife agencies are responsible for the conservation and management of all fish and wildlife in the State, but are grossly underfunded because there are few funds available at the State level for fish and wildlife conservation, except those driven by hunting and fishing license revenues and Federal excise tax revenues.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H357E4E9ACB9A4DD1B956070E88C0F052"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress created a subaccount known as the Wildlife Conservation and Restoration Subaccount under section 3(a)(2) of the Pittman-Robertson Wildlife Restoration Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/669b">16 U.S.C. 669b(a)(2)</external-xref>) to support the full array of fish and wildlife conservation needs identified by State fish and wildlife agencies, including for species that are not hunted or fished, but only authorized appropriations for the Subaccount for one year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7BAA87B8896B4A589441A51A9E90F771"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">While appropriated funds have been made available through the State and Tribal Wildlife Grants program of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, the lack of assured and sufficient dedicated funding for the Wildlife Conservation and Restoration Subaccount has left unrealized the goals of the Subaccount, thereby allowing fish and wildlife populations to continue to decline across the United States and resulting in hundreds of species being listed as threatened species or endangered species under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H346B051B02974123993949FE94CF5AFF"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under the Pittman-Robertson Wildlife Restoration Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/669">16 U.S.C. 669</external-xref> et seq.), each State and territory is required to seek public input and produce a comprehensive fish and wildlife conservation strategy, otherwise known as a State Wildlife Action Plan, to guide the State-led conservation of the full array of fish, wildlife, and their habitats.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H97898F55175240A58243B37ECB9E9820"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Providing assured and sufficient dedicated funding to the Wildlife Conservation and Restoration Subaccount will advance the national interest by assuring sustainable populations of fish and wildlife species are available for the use and enjoyment of citizens of the United States through implementing the comprehensive fish and wildlife conservation strategy of each State and territory.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA8C7F7937BAE43D7A37281C26FA4A809"><enum>(15)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As funds become available for the purposes of this Act, sportsmen and sportswomen expect States to secure the needed non-Federal match from sources other than revenue generated by sportsmen and sportswomen through the sale of State hunting and fishing licenses (except when projects or programs benefit habitat for species that are hunted or fished and other associated wildlife).</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HACA70EE30EDB43F9B755E059FB747613"><enum>3.</enum><header>Wildlife Conservation and Restoration Subaccount</header>
 <subsection id="H18ED771A309D4647B6C3DEC705A88A86"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3 of the Pittman-Robertson Wildlife Restoration Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/669b">16 U.S.C. 669b</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H48130981E892494BAD6250D6DE567E09"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB91F91CD72C54CF2B53B320B3574EA51"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(1) An amount equal to</quote> and inserting <quote>An amount equal to</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H409BC95A16CE4507BD19F4E9F3EF5755"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2); and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6FB4940D19048DE95786EDE71D83376"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text> <subparagraph id="H81423D0634274FAFA94C48FBF002D26F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>(c)(1) Amounts transferred to the Wildlife Conservation and Restoration Account</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC7EAE4E2755548459640D1CECA5575E6" style="OLC">
							<subsection id="HF066EE60030144129449773D6EC5625B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Wildlife Conservation and Restoration Subaccount</header>
								<paragraph id="HB0C81F85BD8440B6B674A9E3B4182019"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment of Subaccount</header>
 <subparagraph id="HBA7AF16518B74001AB4461D925406DB5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established in the Federal Aid to Wildlife Restoration Fund a subaccount to be known as the <quote>Wildlife Conservation and Restoration Subaccount</quote> (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>Subaccount</quote>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A0C40AA3AAD45179B3330735CE54C2E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Amounts in the Subaccount shall be available without further appropriation, for each fiscal year, for apportionment in accordance with this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BB58A3D03D54C26A748BEE7A91E1442"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Deposits into Subaccount</header><text>Beginning in fiscal year 2018, the Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer to the fund for deposit in the Subaccount the following:</text>
 <clause id="H8311C8C8EC8C4375B589F5A351E1086E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Outer Continental Shelf revenues</header><text>From amounts deposited in the Treasury under section 9 of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1338">43 U.S.C. 1338</external-xref>), $650,000,000.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC9966DD7C977471BBEBFC40B71C79809"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Mining revenues</header><text>From amounts deposited in the Treasury under section 35 of the Mineral Leasing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/191">30 U.S.C. 191</external-xref>), after the withdrawal of funds to the States under subsection (a) of that section, $650,000,000.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF16F6F494519466ABCCF35D48DD78B24"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Supplement not supplant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts transferred to the Wildlife Conservation and Restoration Subaccount</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H214C27517F274B12823782C0F9B4F915"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2), as added by subparagraph (A)—</text>
 <clause id="HD9B4FCB88E0F48A0B9E2FA91C6D08F1D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>wildlife restoration account and</quote> and inserting <quote>wildlife restoration account.</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="HD23F9B018DC84144BFA5B42F919DC072"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>shall be used for the development,</quote> and all that follows through <quote>existing programs and projects.</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4B86EC394D164A898ADB0C063D60107B" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H63D9DB5DBDFF40FBA720CA38C4BE9601"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds appropriated from the Subaccount—</text> <subparagraph id="H160E36D3C8CD4FF0BED89C85396EF827"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be used to carry out, revise, or enhance existing wildlife conservation and restoration programs and to develop and implement new wildlife conservation and restoration programs to manage wildlife species of greatest conservation need, including species that are not hunted or fished, and their habitats as determined by the appropriate State fish and wildlife department;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD88FF86E5B934B238D9FC67ABD2C4C02"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be used to develop, revise and implement a wildlife conservation strategy of the State as may be required by this Act;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H343518E6DCAE49D185F5CA406B1B897E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be used for wildlife conservation education and wildlife-associated recreation projects;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6258182D7DF4C52B74F7ACE6615CC49"><enum>(D)</enum><text>may be used to assist in the recovery of a species listed as an endangered species or threatened species under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531</external-xref> et seq.);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96327051AEE84E06895A29A5BB4A9B80"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may be used to manage a species of greatest conservation need whose range is shared with a foreign government and the habitat of such species;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19B791D2A4AF46C993B785911208909C"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may be used to manage, control, and prevent invasive and nuisance species and other risks to species of greatest conservation need; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA105E93513F04347B03279607C9D9B38"><enum>(G)</enum><text>may be used for law enforcement activities that are directly related to the protection and conservation of a species of greatest conservation need and the habitat of such species.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2B1C05401D44697BE04F90E4C5BB765"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H75B5481D80724EB0AE580867BCF14C16" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H6D14042CEE034DEC844A6E31821BB355"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public access not required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds apportioned from the Wildlife Conservation and Restoration Subaccount shall not be conditioned upon the provision of public access to private lands, waters, or holdings.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="HC0F02F631E6D4627A93493A198F4502C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Requirements for matching funds</header>
 <subparagraph id="HB2C7E963262A4530828372100C124B6B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For the purposes of the non-Federal fund matching requirement for a wildlife conservation or restoration program or project funded by the Wildlife Conservation Restoration Subaccount, a State—</text>
 <clause id="H1CAD12CFECE146FDBC578A41D2B0B99C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>may use as matching non-Federal funds—</text> <subclause id="HA6E871442CA3465B8F159F98E12BAC44"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">funds from Federal agencies other than the Department of the Interior and the Department of Agriculture; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H1EDDA24D0CF04DE49B0E3C8EBFCA7D44"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">donated private lands and waters, including privately-owned easements; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HD89C133985A14A1EA8279060B72FC08E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may not use as matching non-Federal funds—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" id="HD5947506B3D84FD8BB0F96A8B53044AE"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">revenue from the sale of State hunting and fishing licenses, except if all available Federal funds apportioned to a State fish and wildlife agency from the Wildlife Restoration Program or the Sport Fish Restoration Program have been obligated by the State, then revenue generated through the sale of State hunting and fishing licenses may be used as non-Federal match for projects and programs that benefit the habitat of species that are hunted or fished and other species that have greatest conservation need.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7148A3A803C4647907FD51F68F60671"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="H0A7CE04E02364246ACE482BCCD938398"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Wildlife</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>wildlife</quote> means any species of wild, freeranging fauna, including fish, and also fauna in captive breeding programs the object of which is to reintroduce individuals of a depleted indigenous species into previously occupied range.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB750329FC525455DB3C5E0005378156D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (2) and (3) as paragraphs (7) and (8), respectively; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF8CE060198F54E6DBE846F8E196F2119"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), as redesignated by subparagraph (D), by striking <quote>or an Indian tribe</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB8C09D9BE7AB47CB9D1561D66D0232FC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Allocation and apportionment of available amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 4 of the Pittman-Robertson Wildlife Restoration Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/669c">16 U.S.C. 669c</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H995D36DCBBBC415B96E12B9FF7E86426"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c)(2)(A)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1757CEF7AF2B4B1F9450A909F054F891"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>one-third</quote> and inserting <quote>one-half</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HBF4EB7D323F24C7DAAB25178B1C3A0AD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause (ii), by striking <quote>two-thirds</quote> and inserting <quote>one-half</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H461C611BCCAE4C67A5358B6889DED018"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H70AAB8B9DC3544149ACEDAD9CE9EBDCA" style="OLC"> <subsection commented="no" id="HD59C1E7CCB124E4A8F489959E4306171"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Minimization of planning and reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be interpreted to require a State to create a comprehensive strategy related to conservation education or outdoor recreation.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC26034563B0C43D3BECB98ADC831B4A1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Clarifying amendments</header>
 <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H02F625B6357243239A0E8D9D9F102DC6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2 of the Pittman-Robertson Wildlife Restoration Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/669a">16 U.S.C. 669a</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H9119A4972E2A41D2AAF5AD4B2DAA5D7A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (4);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H134A52490A214290A7520FAE3B11368F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (5) through (8) as paragraphs (4) through (7), respectively; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6FEC31ABFAC74BFCB327F9939C7FCF4D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), as so redesignated by paragraph (2), by inserting <quote>Indian Tribes, academic institutions,</quote> before <quote>wildlife conservation organizations</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4F4040B7ADAD4147A6D0DECBF042938C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Pittman-Robertson Wildlife Restoration Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/669a">16 U.S.C. 669a</external-xref> et seq.) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H0927EBA94CF44EFBAAB22D8D262AC146"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 3 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/669b">16 U.S.C. 669b</external-xref>)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6B1D8EA781FC4964A0D8888B6EEAFB40"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(3), by striking <quote>Account</quote> and inserting <quote>Subaccount</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB468AE69992B41DEB409C65050EE945E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (d), by striking <quote>Account</quote> and inserting <quote>Subaccount</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3F1428FE69E4151A3B7946EFC89B508"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 4 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/669c">16 U.S.C. 669c</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph id="HA30704F4AA4A4F6398009C25525FDCB3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text>
 <clause id="H5B7FEFE1B39D4454BAA9E8EA90C0E8C7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Account</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Subaccount</header-in-text></quote>;</text> </clause><clause id="H53153236FD6244168207E1751A486CA6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>Account</quote> and inserting <quote>Subaccount</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF827BCCF706B48BC871DE7366DAF08A5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the matter preceding paragraph (2)(A)(i), by striking <quote>Account</quote> and inserting <quote>Subaccount</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="HA5236C69191646CCBF8853FE2660E891"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>Account</quote> and inserting <quote>Subaccount</quote>; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7AAE5FD0246D4D7A96D4D4E0326F8CD1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (d)(1), by striking <quote>Account</quote> and inserting <quote>Subaccount</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC88006138FA413DBD020B5FB1BB438C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 8 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/669g">16 U.S.C. 669g</external-xref>), in subsection (a), by striking <quote>Account</quote> and inserting <quote>Subaccount</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB820F9E96D6F4C98832DE1A19923F876"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Technical amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 4 of the Pittman-Robertson Wildlife Restoration Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/669c">16 U.S.C. 669c</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H9A0F50E6A22E4BC7942E0E879249426E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the second subsection (c), by striking <quote>(c)</quote> and inserting <quote>(d)</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB0A83C4683FD466EB3F5C6D8C6AD0200"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (d) as subsection (e).</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA05BE6688B714438BD4DD78C88A5DD8C"><enum>5.</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Pittman-Robertson Wildlife Restoration Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/669">16 U.S.C. 669</external-xref> et seq.) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7FEF0F2AA7944FCE9FBE4D331E3AA07A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating section 13 as section 14; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HADFC67152F9047A397D8F4B1C25FD25D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after section 12 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3096E31623944F748359A90ADAF25CF3" style="OLC">
					<section id="H638E915675DC4E9CAEEBD2E709BB0DD3"><enum>13.</enum><header>Savings clause</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to affect the authority, jurisdiction, or responsibility of a State to manage, control, or regulate fish and wildlife under the law and regulations of the State on lands and waters within the State, including on Federal lands and waters.</text>
					</section><section id="H16320DB274924B35AE52D49A341BF287"><enum>14.</enum><header>Statutory construction with respect to Alaska</header>
 <subsection id="H1B25A99516704D22B96AFB2D7353EDA9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to affect—</text> <paragraph id="H163196347AE44AB0A537289E18C49571"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the provisions for subsistence uses in Alaska set forth in the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3101">16 U.S.C. 3101</external-xref> et seq.), including the such provisions in titles III and VIII of that Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4616B52A2AB14D119BF98FB74F53F8EC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the provisions of section 102 of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3101">16 U.S.C. 3101</external-xref> et seq.), the jurisdiction over subsistence uses in Alaska, or any assertion of subsistence uses in Alaska in the Federal courts; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA97CBA6E8EF0425F9B787413492E45BE"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the manner in which section 810 of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3120">16 U.S.C. 3120</external-xref>) is implemented on Federal lands and waters in Alaska.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1EB1C287FDD2403B88574DCABB438D51"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conflicts of laws</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If any conflict arises between any provision of this Act and any provision of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3101">16 U.S.C. 3101</external-xref> et seq.), then the provision in the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act shall prevail.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


