<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HEF80B346F12A4D6098F638D990CE1F52" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3235 IH: Wetland Determinations Efficiency and Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3235</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170713">July 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000184">Mrs. Noem</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001096">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000258">Mr. Peterson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Food Security Act of 1985 with respect to the administration of wetland
			 determinations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HD44D62D18BC14C93AA10C2423AB3795B" style="OLC">
 <section id="HF5DF21A0379C4ADA964A60F41D1A8E9D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Wetland Determinations Efficiency and Transparency Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HDD1E65996A244238A5BF4695F1ACD72B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Administration of wetland determinations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1222(a) of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3822">16 U.S.C. 3822(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4C9DAD117EDA4CD380A2ED98076DFC49"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>subsection (b) and paragraph (6)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (b), paragraphs (6) and (7), and paragraphs (1)(B) and (2) of section 1244(e)</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC1563FA4DDBD46D88408828F7A5F441A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF43B1361970F4C95A3271B16C3B67BED" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="HC809CF16F2CF4E2BA4ABF570E05B8908"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Administration</header>
						<subparagraph id="H02F91A540CD843F8A35AE14B1E00BDFD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Timely completion</header>
 <clause id="H5B36E8B638834719A63CFFAC4EC2920E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Chief of the Natural Resources Conservation Service, shall ensure the completion of a wetland delineation, determination, or certification by the date that is 60 days after the date on which a person subject to this subtitle requests the delineation, determination, or certification.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCB2C8CEE54DF4A55A6E3F0A52D935F5B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Effect of delay</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a wetland delineation, determination, or certification is not completed by the date described in clause (i), upon completion of the wetland delineation, determination, or certification, the Secretary shall provide for a reasonable transition period for coming into compliance with the wetland delineation, determination, or certification, as necessary, and a person shall not become ineligible under section 1221 for program loans or payments as a result of actions taken, between the date described in clause (i) and the date on which such transition period ends, in violation of the wetland delineation, determination, or certification.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23D63209B0FF4D678AC4366867F3891B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Final agency action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A wetland delineation, determination, or certification made by the Secretary shall be considered a final agency action subject to judicial review, and a person challenging a wetland delineation, determination, or certification shall not be required to exhaust all administrative remedies prior to bringing a suit in Federal court.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HFDFFBDD64C894E938EC1DAF9457B7677"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Duty to disclose</header><text>In the case of a wetland delineation, determination, or certification for which there exists a dispute, the Secretary shall make available a copy of the agency record, to a person involved in the dispute who requests such a copy, not later than 30 days after the date on which the person makes the request.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC76CBAB94E704D14A53B1AEBD9DA3152"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Burden of proof</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a wetland delineation, determination, or certification for which there exists a dispute, the Secretary shall bear the burden of proof by a preponderance of the evidence.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC625CB2549C4435CAE1C33DC6D8078D5"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Effect on existing process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to prohibit a person challenging a wetland delineation, determination, or certification from using the administrative appeal process in place before the date of enactment of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H303DA57C7CE0499DA5DCF1C0B76DDBAF" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Technical assistance permitted</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1244(e) of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3844">16 U.S.C. 3844(e)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAA6CF01FBE1949C68D9C631D17011CA1" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H022FC5849B89460B969A1266B5D1FB71"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Provision of technical assistance by other sources</header> <paragraph id="H5763613206324EACBA7C75135BDB554F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Third party technical assistance permitted</header><text>The Secretary shall permit a person to secure technical assistance from an approved source, as determined by the Secretary, other than the Natural Resources Conservation Service—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H871B29658ACA492F8907B94CEB98DAB0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the preparation and application of a conservation plan under subtitle B or similar plan required as a condition for assistance from the Department of Agriculture; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4A83962D1E84BD499202C183AEC2FAB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the preparation of a wetland delineation or determination to submit to the Secretary under section 1222.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8F099C811AD4C1EAAB5EAC9A866C94E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rejection</header><text>If the Secretary rejects a technical determination made by an approved source pursuant to paragraph (1)(A), or a wetland delineation or determination made by an approved source pursuant to paragraph (1)(B), the basis of the Secretary's rejection must be supported by documented evidence.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H998D7695CB7943D3A97CF094E1787AA4" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header>Date of return of wetland characteristics</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1222(b)(1)(G) of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3822">16 U.S.C. 3822</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>after that date</quote> and inserting <quote>after such original conversion</quote>.</text> </section></legis-body></bill> 

