<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE1681774B89F4C98A3A8A1B7FD1F7166" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2390 IH: PLO Accountability Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2390</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170504">May 4, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000435">Ms. Ros-Lehtinen</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001187">Mr. Meadows</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To strengthen prohibitions regarding the Palestine Liberation Organization, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H8CE38B5088644D79B19FC8103FD57543" style="OLC">
 <section id="HC355C0FA03174666BC1C72F3AF50367F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>PLO Accountability Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H6E9A6CFF218D45A6BD4B79FD6C1D195E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H3B4688AB8E344B34A069FE43600B4ACB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Palestine Liberation Organization (PLO) Mission office, representing the PLO, and by extension, the Palestinian Authority (PA), in Washington, DC, was opened in 1994 in order to implement the Oslo Accords, which initiated direct negotiations between the PLO and the Government of Israel.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H42BA1F2658944307B0885E0D26A2ED33"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 1003 of the Anti-Terrorism Act of 1987 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/100/204">Public Law 100–204</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/5202">22 U.S.C. 5202</external-xref>), makes it unlawful to <quote>establish or maintain an office, headquarters, premises, or other facilities or establishments within the jurisdiction of the United States at the behest or direction of, or with funds provided by the Palestine Liberation Organization or any of its constituent groups, any successor to any of those, or any agents thereof</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9F7DEA3030E346AE9A41CBAE9BE822BC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Using various authorities, the executive branch has waived the provisions of section 1003 of the Anti-Terrorism Act of 1987.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6B7BDC38F075441B96CDE6FC92A6961F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Article XXXI, clause 7, of the Israeli-Palestinian Interim Agreement on the Status of the West Bank and the Gaza Strip (September 28, 1995) states that <quote>Neither side shall initiate or take any step that will change the status of the West Bank and the Gaza Strip pending the outcome of the permanent status negotiations</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H06656A97869C4685B8CE5C91D7DA24DA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In January 2009, the PLO sent a declaration to the International Criminal Court under Article 12(3) of the Rome Statute of the International Criminal Court on behalf of the Palestinian Authority.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7711D678F13F4D22B4CD3B9FD45449CC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>On October 31, 2011, the United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO) voted to admit the <quote>State of Palestine</quote> as its 195th full member. Since being admitted, the Palestinians have used UNESCO to pass anti-Israel resolutions, including a recent effort to deny the historical connection of the Jewish people to holy sites including the Temple Mount and Western Wall in Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6CC6B0BAA5954870A4BD65C429F9DA36"><enum>(7)</enum><text>On November 29, 2012, the United Nations General Assembly voted to accord the <quote>State of Palestine</quote> status as a nonmember observer State at the United Nations.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC2B749CC62E9456D9685720E54DD9D82"><enum>(8)</enum><text>On April 2, 2014, the PLO joined the Geneva Conventions as well as 13 other organizations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H695803B53C2F4DF39281330C064A529A"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On January 2, 2015, the PLO acceded to the Rome Statute, and on January 16, 2015, the Prosecutor of the International Criminal Court opened a <quote>preliminary examination of the situation in Palestine</quote> after accepting jurisdiction of the International Criminal Court over <quote>alleged crimes committed in the occupied Palestinian territory, including East Jerusalem, since June 13, 2014</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8CB25ED94038401D83EB98CBD9FCD680"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The PLO’s decision to accede to the Rome Statute as well as several international organizations is an attempt to change the status of the West Bank and the Gaza Strip outside of direct negotiations between the Israelis and Palestinians.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H53EC21D44E7547438A16CCBEA58F03EA"><enum>(11)</enum><text>On January 7, 2015, the Department of State’s Office of the Spokesperson stated, <quote>we have made clear our opposition to Palestinian action in seeking to join the Rome Statute of the International Criminal Court</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H89811A7FA80F4CF2AF0875A573765B30"><enum>(12)</enum><text>On April 1, 2015, the <quote>State of Palestine</quote> officially became a member of the International Criminal Court.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD8B9D59D3235442884210130ADE4ED12"><enum>(13)</enum><text>The PLO and PA continue to engage in incitement and glorify terrorism, and reward terrorists, their families, and the families of those who died committing terrorist attacks with roughly $300,000,000 annually in salaries and benefits, providing a higher reward to those with longer jail sentences.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4B0ACAD4E16440E9AF79C7401225356A"><enum>(14)</enum><text>On August 30, 2016, Deputy Secretary of State, Anthony J. Blinken, submitted to Congress a report as required under section 804(b) of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1990 and 1991 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/101/246">Public Law 101–246</external-xref>), sections 603 and 604 of the Middle East Peace Commitments Act of 2002 (subtitle A of title VI of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/228">Public Law 107–228</external-xref>), and section 699 of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/228">Public Law 107–228</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HCE5DBF192C9B470FA0F5DA94E54866CF"><enum>(15)</enum><text>In this report, Deputy Secretary of State Blinken, acting under authority delegated to him as Deputy Secretary pursuant to the President’s Delegation of Functions on April 30, 2009, made the determination that <quote>the PLO and PA are not in compliance with certain commitments to prevent violations, discipline violators, and assume responsibility over all PLO elements … thus the sanction specified in section 604(a)(2) of [<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/228">Public Law 107–228</external-xref>], calling for a downgrade in status of the PLO office in Washington, DC, has been imposed</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA7DF3849A04D49A995B6AE2C25F894B7"><enum>(16)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On January 31, 2017, then Acting Secretary of State, Thomas Shannon, pursuant to the President’s Delegation of Functions dated April 30, 2009, submitted to Congress a similar report to Congress as required under section 804(b) of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1990 and 1991, sections 603 and 604 of the Middle East Peace Commitments Act of 2002, and section 699 of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 2003, in which the same determination was made that the PLO and PA are not in compliance with their commitments, and imposed the same sanction of a downgrade in the status of the PLO office in Washington, DC.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEFFF6BE986CC40B6975128DD10AF23D9"><enum>(17)</enum><text>In both the August 30, 2016, and January 31, 2017, reports, the sanctions were immediately waived.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4465BADC989C43AFA86639F2DA197B44"><enum>(18)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 604(a) of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 2003 requires that if the President determines that the PLO or the Palestinian Authority has not complied with each of the commitments specified in such section, the President shall impose one or more of the following sanctions:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H59AE837290E6428799CDE82ABCF711E5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The denial of visas to PLO and PA officials.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE2EEB6DEE01405D86636021C09F8211"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The downgrade in status of the PLO office in the United States.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C9EE845BB09463A82F23FB98F023598"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The designation as a foreign terrorist organization of the PLO, or one or more of its constituent groups (including Fatah).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC39B30D422C546F99001ACDCF8F7468A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The prohibition on United States assistance to the West Bank and Gaza (except humanitarian assistance).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HEF44E372E8314D6689F7419989EEB513"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="H716A0F30EA6C450DB55D3D2E1FB7BCD8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Palestine Liberation Organization (PLO) has failed to live up to its commitment to a bilateral peace process with Israel, renounce violence, accept Israel’s right to exist, honor previous diplomatic agreements made by the Palestinians, and continues to circumvent a negotiated settlement with Israel by seeking unilateral statehood at the United Nations and from other countries, actively endorsing terror, and supporting boycotts, divestments, and sanctions (BDS) against Israel;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCDDC724EA2AB4D4ABB88E62B219C14D0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Palestinian initiation of an International Criminal Court preliminary examination, investigation, or active support for such an investigation, that subjects Israeli nationals to an investigation for alleged crimes against Palestinians, is part of a deliberate effort to engage in diplomatic, legal warfare against Israel and would violate the Palestinians’ commitment to not change the status of the West Bank and Gaza Strip;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H77A518A81B7B4CF894106ECC2390D590"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the only path towards solving the conflict is through direct negotiations between Israel and the Palestinians;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2EFA512430ED47AD8089EE9D95F39278"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Palestinians should not turn to outside parties, including international organizations, to impose or otherwise influence a solution;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF9E499987898459F8452F6933DC3415E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>it is in the national security interests of the United States to close down the PLO office in Washington, DC; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE56C9C2CAF054C5383D35C192E007182"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the executive branch should avail itself of the range of sanctions as allowed under the authority to impose sanctions under section 604 of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/228">Public Law 107–228</external-xref>) in order to hold the Palestinian leadership accountable.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H01ECBF67EC964BC0B8CE34E4C3950ED1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibitions regarding the Palestine Liberation Organization under the Anti-Terrorism Act of 1987</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1003 of the Anti-Terrorism Act of 1987 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/5202">22 U.S.C. 5202</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H56BDF33F2097427A951664B1F1582115"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>It shall be unlawful</quote> and inserting <quote>(a) <header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">In General</header-in-text>.—It shall be unlawful</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5817DFFD0544428A8724640A9B56F577"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HE6019E0E36FC4A29B07BE90DDB247E4D" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HFBE2BB6B965B41F9A68D0CA015D34FD5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, including section 604 of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/228">Public Law 107–228</external-xref>), the President may waive for a period of not more than 6 months the provisions of subsection (a) if the President determines and certifies in writing to Congress, not later than 45 days before the waiver is to take effect, that—</text>
						<paragraph id="H38E77084B9A94B26BC26AF1B8E5B3D7D"><enum>(1)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H9CF5F6DEF2C546DDA212556D90B3290C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Palestinians have not, on or after January 1, 2017, obtained in the United Nations or any specialized agency thereof the same standing as member states or full membership as a state outside an agreement negotiated between Israel and the Palestinians;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70518BA3A544443794B313D1CAB474BF" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Palestinians have officially ceased to be members of the International Criminal Court (ICC) and have withdrawn from the Rome Statute of the International Criminal Court;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7891DD3ACB843E3AA7A283AEA238FCB" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any preliminary examination or ongoing investigation against Israel, the Government of Israel, the Israeli Armed or Security Forces, or any Israeli national initiated by, or on behalf of, the Palestinians, or referred to the ICC by a state party, the United Nations Security Council, or a Pre-Trial Chamber has been withdrawn and terminated;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD79F13C1AF0448D7B51F08EE8A6A3482" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the PLO and the Palestinian Authority no longer provide any financial award, payment, salary or benefit to Palestinians who have committed terrorist attacks, their families, or the families of those who died committing acts of terrorism;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21E92E68BC76425FB6826C221B228ED0" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the PLO and the Palestinian Authority has ceased to engage in a pattern of incitement against or with respect to the United States or Israel; or</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFCCB4C6C3C714A7E8DBD9150AABDA7DF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Palestinians have entered into a final negotiated peace agreement with, and have ceased all hostilities against, Israel.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5230AD67E0E642A0941EA3A14398F8F2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In subsection (b)(1)(E), the term <term>incitement</term> means to advocate, endorse, or express support for violence, martyrdom, or terrorism, or glorify, honor, or otherwise memorialize any person or group that has advocated, sponsored, or committed acts of terrorism, including the naming after or dedication to such person or group of any school, community center, camp, sports team, stadium, public square, street, land, landmark, waterway, or other facility.</text>
					</subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


