<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H508FD7861D6A4035B9A0611D4D9D0FBB" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3105 IH: Supporting Grandparents Raising Grandchildren Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3105</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170629">June 29, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a Federal Task Force to Support Grandparents Raising Grandchildren.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HE96923C17F0246E6A4A171F94C5D71AF" style="OLC">
 <section id="H9AEBD6F1C72946E69F7F35A9F416680E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supporting Grandparents Raising Grandchildren Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HAA138D16755540F6BA5C8E53126E5FE0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H0910943141E04BE1A7CCE59ED10CE910"><enum>(1)</enum><text>More than 80 percent of Americans over the age of 65 are grandparents and more than 2,500,000 grandparents in the United States are the primary caretaker of their grandchildren. Experts report that such numbers are increasing as the opioid epidemic expands.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5E4BCCA34DA848748B1BCCDA9B695A26"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Grandparents' lives are enhanced by caring for their grandchildren; the overwhelming majority of grandparents report experiencing significant benefits in serving as their grandchildren’s primary caregivers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC80CE0C1A6A4812A85845C61CBF4497"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Providing full-time care to their grandchildren may increase grandparents’ likelihood of experiencing physical illness and mental health problems and decrease their ability to save for retirement.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7133FCB2BFDB443E9E6216135AA9F083"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Grandparents raising grandchildren may face difficulty enrolling their grandchildren in school, medical care, and Federal assistance services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEF19596ABBE34CD98E2334C3AA63A63E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Older Americans Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3001">42 U.S.C. 3001</external-xref> et seq.) includes services that support grandfamilies, including the National Family Caregiver Support Program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD6AE6DE66D254D579815DE267C3D3BFE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Grandparents would benefit from better coordination and information about resources available to support them in their caregiving responsibilities.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H71880E21145241A5A39E6A89BFC8980D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Federal Task Force To Support Grandparents Raising Grandchildren</header>
 <subsection id="H12C37B18FBC34E68AB555398DF65E768"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established a Federal Task Force To Support Grandparents Raising Grandchildren (referred to in this section as the <quote>Task Force</quote>).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HB03CF374967C46EEAD2C627344C542A7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header>
 <paragraph id="HBE0F18F995564F1D8DE1D474F2AAEBFF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Task Force shall be composed of the following members, or their designee:</text> <subparagraph id="H16E59C468CBF4D80808391F0F91E941A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F1D77A1ED454148AB51607FA08982E3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Attorney General.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1DDB299220914A8CACC3F54E66333378"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Administrator of the Administration for Community Living.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3EC0FD0DA27042E6B271276E7A26DE82"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96139184DF2D45E9B2913AD84F219B98"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4C4505551F1D4AA78B1EA3BC48E09351"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The Assistant Secretary for the Administration for Children and Families.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H307EF1F4AA194C5F962FE8A22D81A72C"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The head of each Federal department, agency, or other governmental entity identified by the Secretary of Health and Human Services as having responsibilities, or administering programs, relating to current issues affecting grandparents or other relatives raising children in their care.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB048C14F6D964E26BD2EDE06C490C332"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Lead agency</header><text>The Department of Health and Human Services shall be the lead agency for the Task Force.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4B68186998FE4710BDCEE535DCF2025A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Each member of the Task Force shall be an officer or employee of the Federal Government.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFB3BA648B92644E99B708AEF2847FD4C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header>
				<paragraph id="H3422573F56394EB7A0B4927AA45ADD07"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <subparagraph id="HB2EC626C406F4FB3840B96FA213E988E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Information</header><text>The Task Force shall identify, promote, coordinate, and disseminate information publicly about Federal information, resources, and best practices available, on the date of the determination, to help grandparents or other relatives raising children in their care meet the health, educational, nutritional, and other needs of the children in their care as well as maintain their own physical and mental health and emotional well-being, including those raising children in their care as a result of the opioid epidemic.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E5D313650354E688233883E9BE50AE8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Native Americans</header><text>In carrying out the duties described in subparagraph (A), the Task Force shall ensure that the needs of members of Native American tribes are addressed.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0DF294B621C241318784438806B6ABCE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header>
 <subparagraph id="HEC00A25A2B184829B28835ACF91B346C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Task Force shall submit a report to the Special Committee on Aging and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate that includes—</text>
 <clause id="H40C5F9C1B5D8414EB36F779EDDF6D710"><enum>(i)</enum><text>best practices, resources, and other useful information for grandparents and other relatives raising children in their care; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA9B2454CFB8D472191BE05E1D5FD318B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an identification of the gaps in needs of grandparents and other relatives raising children in their care.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H120DCE6A1AB44F8195266A5AC75D4ABA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Follow-up report</header><text>Not later than the date that is 2 years after the date the report under subparagraph (A) is submitted, the Task Force shall submit a follow-up report to the Special Committee on Aging and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate that includes the information described in subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8E89D6A2261C42C08734A0170B94260A"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Process for public input</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Task Force shall establish a process for public input to inform the development of, and updates to, the best practices, resources, and other useful information and the gaps in needs described in paragraph (2), including a process for the public to submit recommendations to the Task Force and an opportunity for public comment.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4411C67BD967486FB692AAE451492333"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The Task Force shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text> </subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

