<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE5945CDE77A84CD7A78AC426E3A23891" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1938 IH: President-Elect Release of Tax Return Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1938</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170405">April 5, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000580">Mr. Garrett</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the President-elect to submit copies to the Committee on House Administration of the
			 House of Representatives and the Committee on Rules and Administration of
			 the Senate of the Federal income tax returns filed for the 4 most recent
			 taxable years, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H275F40AA9CF449048DF87C7734E00348" style="OLC">
 <section id="H14204DAF2D3948ADB834A89588BF7B2A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>President-Elect Release of Tax Return Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H1478418C78554704B61C9C989A6F2F1B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requiring President-elect to submit copies of income tax returns to Committees of Congress</header> <subsection id="H2A4CF5A3D90D440FA6608967E14CE9C7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Submission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President-elect shall submit a copy of each Federal income tax return filed by such individual with the Internal Revenue Service for the 4 most recent taxable years to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H84041910B1464B18B4F290DC9E823D6E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H88942E11A04746B3838132CFED8DD0C6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7DE69AC4ECAC4CBFA1B19FAD8E343635"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Permitted redactions</header><text>The President-elect may redact from the copy of any Federal income tax return submitted under this section any of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H02AF2C26EC6746C59419EC8F617C4D27"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any Social Security number of any individual.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H97FD5D2C3C7A4939922014D1FD7451D7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any taxpayer identification number of any person.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC4E45EA66F974E009F08E18D0C180113"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any account identification number.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0165DEDFD48D4F9383C3503116F4B786"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any name of any dependent of the taxpayer.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H472855F052CC4F408351008638A6F3C2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President-elect shall submit the information required under this section not later than the date of the meeting of the Senate and House of Representatives held pursuant to section 15 of title 3, United States Code, to count the electoral votes for President and Vice President.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HF16B043163E947C6B36885689D65FD41"><enum>3.</enum><header>Alternative disclosure of returns by Secretary of the Treasury; permitting disclosure of
 information by Committees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">Section 6103(l)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8BE74F002C6443F7A73CC44B9AAC7B9B" style="OLC">
				<paragraph id="H028B820EC6F0407EB363A6FBD58C1F0A"><enum>(23)</enum><header>Disclosure of tax returns of president-elect candidates</header>
 <subparagraph id="H7FC29AD930B140FC82634AAFA1B589A4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Disclosure to Committees of Congress if candidate does not meet disclosure requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the President-elect does not submit a copy of a Federal income tax return to the chairs and ranking minority members of the Committees on House Administration of the House of Representatives and Rules and Administration of the Senate, as required under section 2 of the President-Elect Release of Tax Return Act of 2017, by the date specified in subsection (c) of such section (or if any such return so submitted is incomplete or inaccurate), the Secretary shall disclose such return to the chairs and ranking minority members of such Committees not later than 10 days after such date.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA9821A284734C5FAC157DED24655296"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Redactions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall redact the information described in paragraphs (1) through (4) of subsection (b) of section 2 of the President-Elect Release of Tax Return Act of 2017 with respect to a Federal income tax return of the President-elect before disclosing the return under subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6196FFDC527D456288845A87439C951C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Public disclosure of information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The chairs and ranking minority members of the Committees referred to in subparagraph (A) may disclose any information contained in a return submitted by the President-elect under section 2 of the President-Elect Release of Tax Return Act of 2017 or disclosed by the Secretary under subparagraph (A).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


