<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H3A1A6DBC2F534CD7851FA14617E20D73" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3842 IH: Healthy Start Reauthorization Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3842</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170926">September 26, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="J000297">Mr. Jenkins of West Virginia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="Y000062">Mr. Yarmuth</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to reauthorize the Healthy Start for Infants Program.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H0623818011ED400BA3CD7914D73269E9" style="OLC">
 <section id="H29842033C298400497FFD4A26F4D33B9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Healthy Start Reauthorization Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HBA3BA64F88EA40AF9F9842FE3FDFB8C6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H6269AB5B10144DF1A9D2CE202C827D9C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Department of Health and Human Services puts the national infant mortality rate at 5.96 deaths per 1,000 live births.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE87476D1AA78428FB8352A837CED90A1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Despite national reductions in infant mortality, a racial disparity in infant mortality rates exists in every State and territory, with non-Hispanic Black infants more than twice as likely to die before their first birthday than non-Hispanic White infants.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD9F2CAE5A0374DEBA3D4BD2E639E4C58"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Infants born to low-income women are more likely to die before their first birthday than infants born in higher-income households.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA806BEAE3884437F88426C8539B7DB02"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The three leading clinical causes of infant death are prematurity due to preterm birth and low birthweight, birth defects, and sleep-related deaths.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9119D27EC63E4720BBFA808DF84FAB6D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The most recent data from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) shows that the rate of preterm live births is twice the national rate for African-American women, 1.5 times the national rate for American Indians and Alaskan Natives, and 1.4 times the national rate for Latinos.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA3B6B6EB4DD74740A75D6647C2AB6F3F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The long-term medical and social services associated with low birthweight infants and children born premature cost American taxpayers $26.2 billion per year, with first-year expenses for the smallest surviving babies averaging $273,900.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE0272FDCECA749C883BCACC7AFED2E4E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Employers pay 12 times more in health care costs for babies born with complications, and prenatal interventions that result in full-term birth save employers $49,760.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBDC6065A2DE84CF884DEDB664C258E4B"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Women can reduce the risk of mortality to their infants if they have access to culturally appropriate, accurate information from trusted providers about how to improve their health practices and behaviors during preconception, pregnancy, and postpartum.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB41CF870DC65425FAF0FED4EE0CCA460"><enum>(9)</enum><text>For 25 years, the Healthy Start for Infants Program has identified and addressed the aforementioned knowledge gaps, clinical contributors, and upstream social and generational factors leading to infant death, targeting communities with infant mortality rates at least 1.5 times the national rate with the effect of reducing the prevalence of infant mortality in Healthy Start communities to below the national rate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9C3AC46B4BF94A08BF2C5ADBE1382E08"><enum>(10)</enum><text>In collaboration with its partners, including the National Healthy Start Association, March of Dimes, and the Fetal and Infant Mortality Review Program, the Healthy Start for Infants Program has recognized that a relationship-centered, community-based approach to the early delivery of coordinated services to women and families as well as an ongoing, comprehensive approach to women’s health care improve perinatal outcomes.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H69928EEC268249FAA3B491DE94211DCA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reauthorization of Healthy Start for Infants Program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subsection (e)(1) of section 330H of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254c-8">42 U.S.C. 254c–8</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H60F4F837ED854160B92967E8D99EFC01"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>2008</quote> and inserting <quote>2018</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1489E90A97214D5D94EEEE0FED3FB19A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>2009 through 2013</quote> and inserting <quote>2010 through 2023</quote>.</text> </paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

