<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H999BD672AC094B9F928DA82C7684221F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4719 IH: To amend title 49, United States Code, to address delays in commercial driver’s license skills testing and retesting, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4719</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171221">December 21, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000533">Mr. Duncan of Tennessee</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 49, United States Code, to address delays in commercial driver&#8217;s license skills testing and retesting, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8C7FC3877DD84FFE8A9E809CF7F95576" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD41842CE3A8E448CBB95000E9D6F7B11" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Commercial driver’s license skills testing and retesting</header> 
<subsection id="H4AD1EA8552664943A21F949B069203E5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 31305 of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H0A5E950051B84764AE23FED8AC796C79" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HCF2E8205DA114BD183288C66F1B72DA4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>CDL skills testing and retesting wait times</header> <paragraph id="HBC08F62FEF35496E9A7A90F012C21123"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than February 7, 2020, the Secretary shall carry out a program to ensure that States conduct in a timely manner skills tests and retests for individuals applying for a CDL.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBD5740EC7A544C7CA63800198D4554EF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compliance with program requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of section 31311(a), a State shall not be considered to be in compliance with the requirements of the program for a fiscal year if the Secretary determines as of the first day of the fiscal year that—</text> <subparagraph id="H160E75587ADC439AA32F76497DA75C5F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a State that prohibits or currently does not authorize public and private commercial driving schools, or independent CDL testing facilities, from offering a CDL skills test as a third-party tester, there was a skills test delay at 3 or more CDL skills test locations in the State during—</text> 
<clause id="H3AC76BF8D142439C8747B3A8A2B4B929"><enum>(i)</enum><text>2 consecutive calendar quarters in the preceding 12-month period; or</text></clause> <clause id="H58813CEFA26C4DDE91179F3D3DC1D0EA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>3 calendar quarters in the preceding 18-month period; </text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H70573F0755724D0D9453C76BE912C342"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a State that has 2 or fewer CDL skills test locations, there was a skills test delay at any skills test location; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC59BA5CAFBEB4953AA74EF204A672D11"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the State failed to submit reports in accordance with paragraph (4) in the preceding 12-month period.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H59D58BD51FA04998AF1E0724E8922D8C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Information systems</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the program, the Secretary shall add, or require to be added, to an information system described in section 31106 or 31309 (or other provision of law as applicable) appropriate fields to enter information concerning a CDL skills test location for the purpose of permitting the Administration and States to easily track and tabulate the number of days between certification and skills tests and retests conducted at a CDL skills testing location.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEE330D57AD8D4B96A862DBF877B37D3F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>State reporting requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on February 7, 2020, the Secretary shall require each State to submit to the Secretary, on a quarterly basis, a report that describes the status of skills testing for individuals applying for a CDL at a CDL skills test location in the State, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD2B294BF8F18436F91F1DEDEA5A0FE9D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the average wait time beginning on the date an individual is certified by a training provider to sit for the CDL skills test and ending on the date the individual completes the test;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA419B19E5C4E4E05997AA2FCEAC1D8BC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the average wait time beginning on the date an individual fails a CDL skills test and ending on the date the individual retakes the test;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9D85838CC3F04625B13DE9D0CA67EF39"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the actual number of qualified CDL examiners available to test applicants; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H988B13589325424799628C204869F151"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the number of testing sites available through the State agency responsible for administering the CDL skills test and whether this number has increased or decreased from the previous year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCAD6B8473F04402192447B67F5C990B5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Annual report to States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than October 1, 2020, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to each State a report that compiles the average wait times of such State, as described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (4).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCC81D4078D5A4A12933A0837298AEE19"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Annual report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than February 1, 2021, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H052D8D7CCCA64B40B36EB40E831A1866"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contains a summary of the information received from States in the preceding year under paragraph (4); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD7E4B5FB925D42AFB8EB458C9F799CB6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describes specific steps that the Secretary is taking to address skills test delays in States that have such delays.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3401ACBBF21D4D47902C16DF717ABB30"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the following definitions apply:</text> <subparagraph id="H907DFBEAE2594BB787A77A162191A5BF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Calendar quarter</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>calendar quarter</term> means a 3-month period beginning on the first day of January, April, July, or October.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H05370DC065234351BFE9BB1AE112DBC5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>CDL</header><text>The term <term>CDL</term> means a commercial driver’s license, as that term is defined in section 31301.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA2426B45F8374A83B7D77DBF74F78033"><enum>(C)</enum><header>CDL skills test location</header><text>The term <term>CDL skills test location</term> means a CDL skills test location that is exclusively operated by a State and that employs State employees who are responsible for administering CDL skills testing.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H080113B3A0124942AE2774DE8BDAE439"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Independent CDL testing facility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>independent CDL testing facility</term> means a CDL testing facility that is not—</text> <clause id="HB256F4BB0A164C5496F0619EAC5A04DA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a CDL skills test location (as defined in this paragraph);</text></clause> 
<clause id="H68B901A4AEAD4FA3BC39C4F36A7FFA0B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a public or private commercial driving school; or</text></clause> <clause id="H47F976E028C14F19A635604BF0EE6DAC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a trucking company.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA387FB91827343A2AA089895476E04F6"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Physically absent</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>physically absent</term>, with respect to a scheduled skills test, means that the individual scheduled to take the test was not physically present—</text> <clause id="HB83B43EA03A942B7B8F1ADB2DB7F09F3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>at least 10 minutes before the test; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1259CE1E3D284B63A4CD8D932C967675"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for a longer period of time before the test, as determined by the State but not to exceed 1 hour.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA4E1B7FE3A974BEBB64C3E27BA1A2AF7"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Skills test delay</header> <clause id="HBCBA8A387BDD4C2AA0EA961E2A6B1180"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>skills test delay</term> means, with respect to a calendar quarter, an average period in excess of 7 days—</text> 
<subclause id="H0DD8DBAADBC040FBA1442EA8B3A7CAF9" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the case of an initial CDL skills exam, beginning on the date an individual is certified by a training provider to sit for the CDL skills test and ending on the date the individual completes the test (after subtracting from that period any day that is part of a mandatory notification or waiting period under Federal or State law); and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H931ED1B024E6455D998C1BCE8615DB3F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the case of a CDL skills retest, beginning on the date an individual fails a CDL skills test and ending on the date the individual retakes the test (after subtracting from that period any day that is part of a mandatory notification or waiting period under Federal or State law).</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H7460FD99D3524E49A047E9526333F8F5" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of clause (i), any individual scheduled to take a skills exam who is physically absent from the skills exam on the date scheduled shall be recorded as a <quote>no show</quote>. Any State CDL test location that has a <quote>no show</quote> percentage above 25 percent of total appointments scheduled at that location shall not be counted toward the State’s average skill test delays.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HDF9D82AF993444F2BEB02448DCCF7918"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Withholding of apportionments</header> <paragraph id="H644E094417A9476697A3681F0CBFE318"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 31311(a) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H5138225AC0794559B7F9397A03386C11" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H2BBE5E21012A4A76B207F68F79AFA932"><enum>(26)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning in fiscal year 2021, the State shall be in compliance with the program requirements established under section 31305(e), relating to commercial driver’s license skills testing and retesting wait times, as determined by the Secretary under section 31305(e)(2).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCF78FEC30857499FA0ED8887B3E59754"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability of withheld amounts</header><text>Section 31314(d) of title 49, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H2402EE8096984528A74B2D3F5CD972C6" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HFAA6288E5CAD41E58AAE508CE5FA419E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Availability for apportionment</header> 
<paragraph id="H9E82BAEA16C049DEB15DE84BF039D07F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as described in paragraph (2), amounts withheld under this section from apportionment to a State after September 30, 1995, are not available for apportionment to the State.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3E084726E3C64516B1F8797B6CA4C310"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for CDL testing compliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary determines that a State that did not comply substantially with paragraph (26) of section 31311(a) begins to comply substantially with such paragraph, amounts withheld under this section from apportionment to the State as a result of the prior noncompliance shall be provided to the State in the same manner as such amounts would have been provided if not withheld.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H202ADD093FF4478785C8FC93535EA53A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notice to States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary of Transportation makes a determination that a State does not comply substantially with section 31311(a)(26) of title 49, United States Code, the Secretary shall issue a notice to such State that identifies any reason for such determination.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H39B625603FDB45D89A431692ABA730DC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Compliance plans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State having amounts withheld from apportionment under section 31314 of title 49, United States Code, as a result of noncompliance with the requirements of section 31311(a)(26) of such title, shall submit to the Secretary of Transportation, not later than 270 days after the date on which the State is notified of the noncompliance, a plan to satisfy such requirements.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H031B23B51C8947B6BE0A02C6B3BBF35C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Financial assistance program</header><text>Section 31313(a)(3) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H5435469FA4344546A67F054EC46F8591"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D) by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H78E180E3AA5542699A40D7C25FA42C70"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E) by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA620A4C0D97D477AA673083C5F697427"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H58F3937F9E2045A48846533CD7D6416A" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="H1931FBC258834EC1BECEAB4296E86921"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">address delays in commercial driver’s license skills testing and retesting.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFE5FFF66B6104D9E8D9A4441A4246032"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Repeal</header><text>Effective February 7, 2020, section 5506 of the FAST Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/94">Public Law 119–94</external-xref>; 129 Stat. 1553), and the item relating to that section in the table of contents in section 1(b) of that Act, are repealed.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

