<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H342F196E3E6640D99568790D638BA62B" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3117 IH: Transparency and Honesty in Energy Regulations Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3117</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170629">June 29, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000297">Mr. Jenkins of West Virginia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001048">Mr. Culberson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001190">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000809">Mr. Womack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000585">Mr. LaHood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000461">Mr. Flores</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000568">Mr. Griffith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001250">Mr. Bishop of Utah</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001053">Mr. Cole</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000168">Mr. Olson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001195">Mr. Mooney of West Virginia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the Secretary of Energy, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the
			 Secretary of the Interior, and the Chair of the Council on Environmental
			 Quality from considering the social cost of carbon, the social cost of
			 methane, or the social cost of nitrous oxide, in taking any action, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H530A4B0131E14E599199C9FDB14BCE11" style="OLC">
 <section id="HC739DDB1316B4B1F9224B08015A8255D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Transparency and Honesty in Energy Regulations Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HF39FF68CE4C44BBB8D005FA63DBD8E68"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB3FB125D47AC4F05ABEFBF3A71BBB034"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as a tool to justify Federal actions by the Secretary of Energy, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Secretary of the Interior, and the Chair of the Council on Environmental Quality to address greenhouse gas emissions, including the regulation or prohibition of the exploration, mining, production, and use of coal and other fossil fuels as energy sources, the social cost of carbon, the social cost of methane, and the social cost of nitrous oxide represent the hypothetical cost of 1 incremental ton of carbon dioxide, methane, or nitrous oxide emissions in a given year;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC500F126CFB248DA903DCA3263C5ACEF"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the document of the Office of Management and Budget entitled <quote>Circular A–4</quote> and dated September 17, 2003—</text> <subparagraph id="H6D4F277E183748808C5DE248457A0DDB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">guides Federal agencies on the development of regulatory impact analysis required under Executive Order 12866 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/601">5 U.S.C. 601</external-xref> note; relating to regulatory planning and review) and other authorities; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H24128263AEBB4B71981C448F855889E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">instructs Federal agencies to include discount rates of 3 and 7 percent and evaluate the costs and benefits of the regulatory action that accrue to citizens and residents of the United States;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H101EC2D6AFB248B8B6AB57335445ED7D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">first developed in 2009 by an interagency working group that included the Department of Energy, the Environmental Protection Agency, and the Council on Environmental Quality, the estimates for the social cost of carbon, as well as the subsequently developed estimates of the social cost of methane, and the social cost of nitrous oxide fail to comply with the 3- and 7-percent discount rates prescribed by the document of the Office of Management and Budget entitled <quote>Circular A–4</quote> and dated September 17, 2003;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1BE731445CF04303B9B8522B257B5268"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">while the document of the Office of Management and Budget entitled <quote>Circular A–4</quote> and dated September 17, 2003, specifies that, in carrying out an evaluation of the global effects of a rule, regulation, or action, the evaluation shall be reported separately from domestic costs and benefits of that rule, regulation, or action, the social cost of carbon instead calculates the global benefits in lieu of, not in addition to, the domestic costs of a rule, regulation, or action;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5B0ED5ECA1AA4E71A7B3A9C5A6CF7DAA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the use of the estimates for the social cost of carbon, the social cost of methane, and the social cost of nitrous oxide, in the rulemakings of the Department of Energy, the Environmental Protection Agency, the Department of the Interior, and the Council on Environmental Quality without public notice and an adequate opportunity for comment violates scientific peer review requirements;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9AAB0A519DCE414D995EFD1FF77843D4"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the Environmental Protection Agency relied upon the social cost of methane, without appropriate peer review or opportunity for public notice and comment, in justifying the costs and benefits of the September 2015 proposed and the June 2016 finalized rules under the Clean Air Act for methane emissions from new, modified, and reconstructed sources in the oil and gas sector;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H63A4C19918AA414D851E1D1C2DE81A0E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the Department of the Interior used the social cost of methane estimate to justify the costs and benefits of the final rule entitled <quote>Waste Prevention, Production Subject to Royalties, and Resource Conservation</quote> (81 Fed. Reg. 83008 (November 18, 2016));</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2628C4684E1945919067230ECAA32ECA"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the Council on Environmental Quality issued final guidance on August 1, 2016, that, with respect to a monetary cost-benefit analysis for an evaluation of a proposed Federal action under the <act-name parsable-cite="NEPA69">National Environmental Policy Act of 1969</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.), directed the head of each Federal agency to include the social cost of carbon in any consideration of the effect of greenhouse gas emissions;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6E6DC3538D38436998048DE90421944A"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the regulations of the Department of Energy, the Environmental Protection Agency, the Department of the Interior, and the Council on Environmental Quality are costing families of the United States billions of dollars each year and are justified, in large part, by the social cost of carbon, the social cost of methane, and the social cost of nitrous oxide;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB87A2073E28D4FAF87D60A216C4BD1B9"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">continued use of the social cost of carbon, the social cost of methane, and the social cost of nitrous oxide by the Department of Energy, the Environmental Protection Agency, the Department of the Interior, and the Council on Environmental Quality ignores sound science for the purpose of eliminating the exploration, mining, production, and use of the abundant domestic sources of fossil fuel energy of the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE94C6DB8143945BF9AB800F08AADBA09"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Executive Order 13777 (82 Fed. Reg. 12285 (March 1, 2017)) states that the policy of the United States is to alleviate any unnecessary regulatory burden on the people of the United States; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0A39B6B491C445D9AF5AA5CD88DD99D5"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Executive Order 13783 of March 28, 2017 (82 Fed. Reg. 16093 (March 31, 2017))—</text> <subparagraph id="HB814CFC00290448AB82A37A55AE9FFD6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>disbands the interagency working group referred to in paragraph (3);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10E5A557F4C0464F9923095C3658FB95"><enum>(B)</enum><text>withdraws the social cost of carbon, the social cost of methane, and the social cost of nitrous oxide; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD9AE46E41DF4FCD834E9C3692AF240E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>directs Federal agencies, in monetizing the value of changes in greenhouse gas emissions as a result of a regulation, to follow the document of the Office of Management and Budget entitled <quote>Circular A–4</quote> and dated September 17, 2003, by using the discount rates specified in that document and evaluating only the domestic effects of the regulation.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HB2FA1F6F6BA74EAB82062B3A4D2F9D64"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H071D437E13A04DE28282B8924636222F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDBC88EC1EE23446FB1F673CD21ECA753"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Social cost of carbon</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>social cost of carbon</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H83B1E0769DF941268CF1F80704A971D2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the estimate of the social cost of carbon described in—</text>
 <clause id="H173D6ECF68C0493697E9E5E987D05FA6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the document entitled <quote>Technical Support Document: Social Cost of Carbon for Regulatory Impact Analysis Under Executive Order 12866</quote>, published by the Interagency Working Group on Social Cost of Carbon, United States Government, in February 2010; or</text>
					</clause><clause id="HE686223FAE3D4A90A7643BF59E18A3CC"><enum>(ii)</enum>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC76EC4833A03467D91201CD2B7F7AD91"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the document entitled <quote>Technical Support Document: Technical Update of the Social Cost of Carbon for Regulatory Impact Analysis Under Executive Order 12866</quote>, published by the Interagency Working Group on Social Cost of Carbon, United States Government, in May 2013 and revised in November 2013 and July 2015, and published and revised by the Interagency Working Group on the Social Cost of Greenhouse Gases, United States Government, in August 2016; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H472F5819783B4B7C9E65FD420B9F8E8E" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any successor or substantially related document; and</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE05C25358F6A411EBB02626A9C24DCD5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other estimate of the monetized damages associated with an incremental increase in carbon dioxide emissions in a given year.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H893F2DF71C264197BE2CDFAF36688842"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Social cost of methane</header><text>The term <term>social cost of methane</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HA7AFB25523304D2CA7E2F93616534543"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the estimate of the social cost of methane described in—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="HB113E30A70BF48DFA64F4D5A71E115E8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the proposed rule entitled <quote>Oil and Natural Gas Sector: Emission Standards for New and Modified Sources</quote> (80 Fed. Reg. 56593 (September 18, 2015));</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H7F1287A9D0C949DDAC422D1D158D5834"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the final rule entitled <quote>Oil and Natural Gas Sector: Emission Standards for New, Reconstructed, and Modified Sources</quote> (81 Fed. Reg. 35824 (June 3, 2016));</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H61C64EDDB5A54C1FBD8BFF040D059EB9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the regulatory impact analysis entitled <quote>Regulatory Impact Analysis of the Final Oil and Natural Gas Sector: Emission Standards for New, Reconstructed, and Modified Sources</quote>, prepared by the Environmental Protection Agency, Office of Air and Radiation, in May 2016 and identified by docket ID number EPA–HQ–OAR–2010–0505–7630; or</text>
					</clause><clause id="H7A21B344D5054403B30A31C0E8811E51"><enum>(iv)</enum>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H774984D1A09D40358CDA08AD58DF32A3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the document entitled <quote>Addendum to Technical Support Document on Social Cost of Carbon for Regulatory Impact Analysis under Executive Order 12866: Application of the Methodology to Estimate the Social Cost of Methane and the Social Cost of Nitrous Oxide</quote>, published by the Interagency Working Group on Social Cost of Greenhouse Gases, United States Government, in August 2016; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H2ECA05FFA02D4F71BC48004B8B3A47C4" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any successor or substantially related document; and</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H093D9242CE6946D7839AB65279B9570A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other estimate of the monetized damages associated with an incremental increase in methane emissions in a given year.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C5A81ABC76548B7A03C14C3214B9036"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Social cost of nitrous oxide</header><text>The term <term>social cost of nitrous oxide</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H661D55A55D34462CAF2353780E4B8DAA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the estimate of the social cost of nitrous oxide described in—</text>
 <clause id="H1A2030FD24224B7F87594BFCBFE3296F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the document entitled <quote>Addendum to Technical Support Document on Social Cost of Carbon for Regulatory Impact Analysis under Executive Order 12866: Application of the Methodology to Estimate the Social Cost of Methane and the Social Cost of Nitrous Oxide</quote>, published by the Interagency Working Group on Social Cost of Greenhouse Gases, United States Government, in August 2016; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0AF5966B3E4F4C98A2C5466925F53999"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any other successor or substantially related document; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC80A51672B774A7684AFE921D8D13ACC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other estimate of the monetized damages associated with an incremental increase in nitrous oxide emissions in a given year.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HC0E6C575AA224E3AACD168367D6C17EF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibition on considering the social cost of greenhouse gas, including the social cost of carbon,
			 the social cost of methane, and the social cost of nitrous oxide</header>
 <subsection id="H371EEEC9C46F4FAE941AC238871597F7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Energy, under any authority, the Administrator, under the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7401">42 U.S.C. 7401</external-xref> et seq.), the Secretary of the Interior, under any authority, and the Chair of the Council on Environmental Quality, under the <act-name parsable-cite="NEPA69">National Environmental Policy Act of 1969</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.), may not consider the social cost of carbon, social cost of methane, or social cost of nitrous oxide—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6910E7C69401499185A58FC12D67ACF0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as part of any cost-benefit analysis required under—</text> <subparagraph id="H40685B0F681B4173B0A88AD95829D37D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any law;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4129631DC3E5496EA50DEFA8EDDF63F9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Executive Order 12866 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/601">5 U.S.C. 601</external-xref> note; relating to regulatory planning and review); or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5072EF97D1D343B58A6832E1AF16519F"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Executive Order 13563 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/601">5 U.S.C. 601</external-xref> note; relating to improving regulation and regulatory review);</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A511132DF224C098D48960B26EAA99B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in any rulemaking;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFBFBA3CE1BB94546AE4F66D56789EB03"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the issuance of any guidance;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H146E51763A914A4BBE660B9E1C66F3FA"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in taking any other agency action; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE10FC3C2F9C740E1AEE986578FFB17B1"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as a justification for any rulemaking, guidance document, or agency action.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1BB04CE362F94F2EA572B5B070243F05"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Energy, the Administrator, the Secretary of the Interior, and the Chair of the Council on Environmental Quality may consider the social cost of carbon, social cost of methane, or social cost of nitrous oxide in carrying out an activity described in subsection (a) only if, after the date of enactment of this Act—</text>
 <paragraph id="HAA016DA6CBE64AB1B870FD3650A385D3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a Federal law is enacted that explicitly authorizes the consideration; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9D811B0DA7524EFAABEACCFFEA6E1358"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary of Energy, the Administrator, the Secretary of the Interior, or the Chair of the Council on Environmental Quality uses an estimate for the social cost of carbon, social cost of methane, or social cost of nitrous oxide that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3FD343769FA041C38C8D1FB142DA8A17"><enum>(A)</enum><text>complies with the requirements of the document of the Office of Management and Budget entitled <quote>Circular A–4</quote> and dated September 17, 2003;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H78515486F8E04175AC6E7DDEF113C982"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">uses the discount rates of 3 and 7 percent specified in that document;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7D135C2F1F94DC59CC4EAE5804640B7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>considers only the domestic costs and benefits of the activity; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4778AF0464E648C9AFDE66F4EF323DF4"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">uses only—</text>
 <clause id="HBC0BFF62771243F6AB09E4BA5196DA4F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the most up to date and empirically estimated equilibrium climate sensitivity distributions; and</text> </clause><clause id="HA4CC5938D0824E69A951B4430217AA89"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>realistic time horizons.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1C8EE4A521DF463BA1785FA317DD4EAF"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report of the Administrator</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator, in coordination and consultation with the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of the Interior, and the Chair of the Council on Environmental Quality, shall submit to the Committees on Energy and Commerce and Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Environment and Public Works and Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report describing the number of proposed and final rulemakings, guidance documents, and agency actions that, since January 2009, have used the social cost of carbon, the social cost of methane, or the social cost of nitrous oxide, including the use of the social cost of carbon, the social cost of methane, or the social cost of nitrous oxide as part of any cost-benefit analysis required under Executive Order 12866 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/601">5 U.S.C. 601</external-xref> note; relating to regulatory planning and review) or other relevant authority.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


