<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCBB6332EEFA146758F77F791CE43B71A" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1934 IH: To establish a 5-year ban on individuals appointed to Executive Schedule positions and Members of Congress engaging in lobbying activities at the Federal level.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1934</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170405">April 5, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000579">Mr. Gallagher</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a 5-year ban on individuals appointed to Executive Schedule positions and Members of
			 Congress engaging in lobbying activities at the Federal level.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H29C6919039FF4EA59E937C5818B149D0" style="OLC">
		<section id="H679AE426614E41EBA3F952D550ABC05D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>5-year ban on lobbying by individuals appointed to Executive Schedule positions and Members of
			 Congress</header>
			<subsection id="HE04EF495BE984155A45E556F83402290"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Individuals appointed to Executive Schedule positions</header>
 <paragraph id="H1D898F40966C49D2A194A4F9561A829A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 207(d) of title 18, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1FBAF83EC9A44E60A226B21D2D00A6EA" style="OLC"> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD298743ED7194CA3826BEACCCFE9FBBF"><enum>(d)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Restrictions on very senior personnel of the executive branch and independent agencies</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H00516340771049E59B0E15CFF01DA673"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Vice President</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8049394030E640E7A554C6DFE6DD647E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Restrictions</header><text>In addition to the restrictions set forth in subsections (a) and (b), any person who serves in the position of Vice President of the United States and who, within 2 years after the termination of that person's service in that position, knowingly makes, with the intent to influence, any communication to or appearance before any person described in subparagraph (B), on behalf of any other person (except the United States), in connection with any matter on which such person seeks official action by any officer or employee of the executive branch of the United States, shall be punished as provided in section 216 of this title.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H35920087E4F84EFC85591ABC56E636DC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Persons who may not be contacted</header><text>A person described in this subparagraph is—</text> <clause id="H71A874E69A364846A4E884FF80209178"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any officer or employee of any department or agency in which the Vice President served within a period of 1 year before the Vice President's service or employment with the United States Government terminated; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H90D5BF8B7637422EB4D336A920E6FDF2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any person appointed to a position in the executive branch which is listed in section 5312, 5313, 5314, 5315, or 5316 of title 5.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H85379B2DD1A44069AEBA6064B2DDE8D1"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Five-year restriction on individuals in Executive schedule and equivalent positions</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA9F582A6C899475F8F60168C438BCBA7"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraphs (B) and (C), and in addition to the restrictions set forth in subsections (a) and (b), any individual employed in a position in the executive branch for which the rate of pay is the rate of pay payable for any level of the Executive Schedule under subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 5 who, within 5 years after the termination of his or her service or employment in such position, knowingly makes, with the intent to influence, any communication to or appearance before any officer or employee of any department or agency in the executive branch, on behalf of any other person (except the United States), in connection with any matter on which such person seeks official action by any officer or employee of such department or agency, shall be punished as provided in section 216 of this title.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80D81E608F6846ADAD310A47ADB4FF50"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Special Government employees</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to a special Government employee who serves less than 60 days in the 1-year period before his or her service or employment as such employee terminates.</text>
								</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H897194873D4E4782AF646AE7E94E6795"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Waiver</header>
 <clause id="HD18A1979A516403386C1199BD4072E09"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>Except as provided in clause (ii), at the request of a department or agency, the Director of the Office of Government Ethics may waive the restrictions under subparagraph (A) with respect to a position, or a category of positions, if the Director determines that—</text>
 <subclause id="H790606DE7D6D4B7F8E8273EC5876BFCE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the imposition of the restrictions with respect to the position, or category of positions, would create an undue hardship on the department or agency in obtaining qualified personnel to fill the position, or category of positions; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H127EFA609A6C4ADB99BDE9E6522004AA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>granting the waiver would not create the potential for use of undue influence or unfair advantage.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H1E5ACC065FEC44899EA7B9F0948AAE09"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Excluded positions</header><text>The Director of the Office of Government Ethics may not waive the restrictions under subparagraph (A) with respect to—</text>
 <subclause id="H274B9533CF8649E087A7E0D78DF22151"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a position in the executive branch (including any independent agency) for which the rate of pay is the rate of pay payable for level I of the Executive Schedule; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H4A13BC139EE44BDE918151E66F3F2A39"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a position in the Executive Office of the President for which the rate of pay is the rate of pay for level II of the Executive Schedule.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1B53D6B2719D4C6E86E55741B57C055C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header><text>Section 207 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H4FF0BF035294468D852B01074AC3C342"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(2)—</text>
 <clause id="H147FEF0499044E6DA0114FC50D77FB92"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text> <subclause id="H721B0146ED5D4E3684971994E7144F52"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking clauses (i) and (iii);</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H82145F2286B044D9A8B3A74AF2F94C8F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by redesignating clauses (ii), (iv), and (v) as clauses (i), (ii), and (iii), respectively; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HFC006F3E8CAD4C07A7CCA67755BCE2BA"><enum>(III)</enum><text>in clause (i), as so redesignated—</text>
 <item id="H1E75906325A94736A0A454860BB97482"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>by striking <quote>which is not referred to in clause (i)</quote> the first place it appears and inserting <quote>for which the rate of pay is not specified in or fixed according to subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 5</quote>; and</text>
 </item><item id="H96A36D120D214D089580FE0D8FB4D4B9"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>by striking <quote>, or, for a period of 2 years</quote> and all that follows through the end of clause (i) and inserting a comma; and</text> </item></subclause></clause><clause id="H0DC365BAB20149EC9FDEDE57F61EDFBF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>clause (ii) or (iv)</quote> and inserting <quote>clause (i) or (ii)</quote>; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H949781F7CB544BBFA419CE3DDFADDF0A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (h)(2), by striking the second sentence.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8CC892E5679C4D25B18C97933AA82D00"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Members of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 207(e)(1) of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD35EF5FE726343FA96A958275A932E02"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>2 years</quote> and inserting <quote>5 years</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE466214001514C9B815EC0E4FA9BED5A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)(i), by striking <quote>Any person who is a Member of the House of Representatives or an elected officer of the House of Representatives and who, within 1 year after that person leaves office,</quote> and inserting <quote>Any person who is a Member of the House of Representatives and who, within 5 years after that person leaves office, or any person who is an elected officer of the House of Representatives and who, within 1 year after that person leaves office,</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4500869376DB49BD91963C2D60975976"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this Act shall apply with respect to any individual who, on or after the date of the enactment of this Act, leaves a position to which section 207 of title 18, United States Code, applies (as amended by this Act).</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


