<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H0F4770FC485B4D69816516B394B53A93" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3999 IH: To amend title 18, United States Code, to prohibit the manufacture, possession, or transfer of any part or combination of parts that is designed and functions to increase the rate of fire of a semiautomatic rifle but does not convert the semiautomatic rifle into a machinegun, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3999</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171010">October 10, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001107">Mr. Curbelo of Florida</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000567">Mr. Lance</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001181">Mr. Meehan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000608">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000487">Mr. Royce of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000170">Mr. O'Rourke</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000594">Mr. Paulsen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000571">Ms. Gabbard</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001106">Mr. Costello of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000390">Mr. Kihuen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000435">Ms. Ros-Lehtinen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000620">Mr. Delaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000604">Mr. Dent</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000410">Mr. Gene Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000593">Mr. Perlmutter</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 18, United States Code, to prohibit the manufacture, possession, or transfer of any
			 part or combination of parts that is designed and functions to increase
			 the rate of fire of a semiautomatic rifle but does not convert the
			 semiautomatic rifle into a machinegun, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HB1593D262C9347ECA9ACE94A93D124E2" style="OLC">
		<section id="HE514BC6BF3DB4840B91824CCFD933A0E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Prohibition on manufacture, possession, or transfer of any part or combination of parts that is
			 designed and functions to increase the rate of fire of a semiautomatic
			 rifle but does not convert the semiautomatic rifle into a machinegun</header>
 <subsection id="HCFD7A8D7461F47C0A60008FAEAB45576"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 922 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA86A2B620F564E14B4D6BE2477D078AD" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H49ECEB62FCB74AEEAC0C2EB7E7B4F64A"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be unlawful for any person—</text>
 <paragraph id="H11904F77AB7F476BAAA3A0CD56F10A91"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce, to manufacture, possess, or transfer any part or combination of parts that is designed and functions to increase the rate of fire of a semiautomatic rifle but does not convert the semiautomatic rifle into a machinegun; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA3BA22D10DFC49BCA0A426DC75540D8C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to manufacture, possess, or transfer any such part or combination of parts that have been shipped or transported in interstate or foreign commerce.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H11E8FCFEE01D45419F63D96BA90276BC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>Section 924(a)(1)(B) of such title is amended by striking <quote>or (q)</quote> and inserting <quote>(q), or (aa)</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H8FBACE7FCBC64BA5AF257F6BE697D83D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sentencing guidelines</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pursuant to its authority under section 994 of title 28, United States Code, and in accordance with this subsection, the United States Sentencing Commission shall amend and review the Federal sentencing guidelines and policy statements to ensure that the guidelines provide for a penalty enhancement of not less than 2 offense levels for a violation of section 922(aa) of title 18 of such Code if the device described in such section 922(aa) has been—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD1D50D0B8CD2495DAEC8A1CC2428BA28"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">used, carried, or possessed during or in relation to a crime of violence or drug trafficking crime (as such terms are defined in section 924(c)(3) of such title 18); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2F0A87891C3D497EBA98B865127F6115"><enum>(2)</enum><text>smuggled unlawfully into or from the United States.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H777A0D1A446F481A8C68C30BBCBACDE2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section and the amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to conduct engaged in after the 90-day period that begins with the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


