<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1491BAF4B3334248BD55F5CF42A167CA" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4523 IH: Automatic Retirement Plan Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4523</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171201">December 1, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000015">Mr. Neal</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to expand retirement plan coverage, increase retirement
			 security, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HC29154FDDC544339A6FF34EB5B4C2EE8" style="OLC">
		<section id="H4A642FD1943246E6B7B16E36DB86DEA7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="HDF3B7FD852D54A5AA98675AE03D47A1B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Automatic Retirement Plan Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HB06B2F6896044A0AB825B1B8164A0AC7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents of this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
					<toc-entry idref="H4A642FD1943246E6B7B16E36DB86DEA7" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H394D57C5E4E54EDDA740D47240ECD20C" level="section">Sec. 2. Employers required to maintain automatic contribution plan.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H7FF428C2F0CF42E59D363D955029C0FC" level="section">Sec. 3. Deferral-only arrangements.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HA710A96B80FE4295A2F29982FB24AE96" level="section">Sec. 4. Nondiscrimination testing changes to facilitate higher contributions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HEFF2CF5438424771843AA690CF85AB4D" level="section">Sec. 5. Multiple employer plans.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HE2D706DC48EB43198BDA0A1F0DA80A45" level="section">Sec. 6. Limitation on employer liability.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H1D3A7FE201564D1DBC9DFE1EF4F692F1" level="section">Sec. 7. Portability of lifetime income options.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H1A5826D77AB640E986C41D8F171DE724" level="section">Sec. 8. Increase in credit limitation for small employer pension plan startup costs.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H0D38BE4AF47044BB960058BEAFC77CAF" level="section">Sec. 9. Small employer automatic enrollment credit.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H61CC8F3AC4A042A585DDFED854386F74" level="section">Sec. 10. Treatment of automatic contribution plans under State law.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H71B0C585D24249D18F97F746FB00E6A9" level="section">Sec. 11. Matching payments for elective deferral and IRA contributions by certain individuals.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H45F4E87ABC8044458770D4037125F452" level="section">Sec. 12. Authority to require reporting.</toc-entry>
				</toc>
			</subsection></section><section id="H394D57C5E4E54EDDA740D47240ECD20C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Employers required to maintain automatic contribution plan</header>
 <subsection id="H5DE4ACD25D4B4A539812CE76E85B0C1A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Automatic contribution plan</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/414">Section 414</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H43DD25EC02B74FA3816C51D241108DD3" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HD0CA5D93B1484BC69A87D824B4547113"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>Automatic contribution plan</header><text>For purposes of this title—</text>
 <paragraph id="H5240AE3838C543B3A1BE7D229E3EA4D9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>automatic contribution plan</term> means a defined contribution plan that—</text> <subparagraph id="H0D0B088AF5C24DF685B6C9EC6F985066"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is described in clause (i), (ii), or (iv) of section 219(g)(5)(A),</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA793E9C0581641A8AEF610F867DC51D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is described in paragraph (2), and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D4F1EE659484EB4A8A27B1B3A7EAAC7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>meets the eligibility, investment, lifetime income, and fee requirements described in paragraphs (3), (4), (5), and (6), respectively, of this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C87B722204B43F0824664DC8BABE1E9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Plan described</header><text>A plan is described in this paragraph if the plan is one of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H87CA6BF461EC4B0CB1B5D3AA708FC4DB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Deferral only</header><text>A deferral only arrangement that meets the requirements of section 401(k)(14).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74EE454838D94873B6EC23D0D6831C8A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>403(<enum-in-header>b</enum-in-header>) plan</header><text>A 403(b) plan that—</text> <clause id="HD2071239FEC14C51A80AA1241A1D1FA4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>meets the requirements of section 401(k)(14), or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H74C9A8B6F68F47C79DD3F9D59F19B9EB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>would be described in subparagraph (C) without regard to the references to section 416.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE7F41E228D74B4AA3FDF34DE5BD3273"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Testing automatic contribution plan</header><text>A plan that—</text>
 <clause id="H91344EBB0E184DE388C51BFEF9FBDA62"><enum>(i)</enum><text>would qualify as a plan described in subparagraph (A), except that such plan allows employer contributions, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7ED770EB161249818B42750931C3D477"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>satisfies sections 401(k)(3)(A)(ii), 401(m)(2), and 416 taking into account all applicable rules, including—</text>
 <subclause id="HC57053ADF81840DD8A1882F62EA53114"><enum>(I)</enum><text>paragraphs (11), (12), and (13) of section 401(k),</text> </subclause><subclause id="H30FAB38B00544660BAAB825353B9B822"><enum>(II)</enum><text>paragraphs (10), (11), and (12) of section 401(m), and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE2E9F22EBD4F455F9C1FC76338B44A83"><enum>(III)</enum><text>section 416(g)(4)(H).</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA77152ABFBF1453AAF032DAF45AE0A02"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Grandfathered automatic contribution plan</header><text>A plan described in clause (i), (ii), (iv), (v), or (vi) of section 219(g)(5)(A) that—</text>
 <clause id="HEFA22B810D3842A7A439B8683B6983E6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is maintained by an employer as of the date of enactment of the <short-title>Automatic Retirement Plan Act of 2017</short-title>,</text> </clause><clause id="H3F8ACD7F25304842B9F663BB1024661D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has been maintained by such employer (or a predecessor employer) for at least 1 year before such date of enactment, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2B232CA2DD074F7C95F3E6ACA6210AC0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>except as provided by the Secretary, has not had its coverage or benefits substantially decreased for any plan year beginning after such date of enactment.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9C9E63B6EC54CE5BCEF34D403E30C2B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligibility requirements</header>
 <subparagraph id="H0A90ED32D31448D1B6ACFA716587235C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), the eligibility requirements described in this paragraph are that all employees of the employer are eligible to participate in an automatic contribution plan maintained by the employer.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8EAB5246071C47639A8B57467BAF888D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Certain exclusions</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to the following:</text> <clause id="HEBCE88F10DC34FBFB40F5996FD116816"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Individuals less than 21 years old</header><text>The employer may, but need not, include an employee who has not attained age 21 in an automatic contribution plan maintained by the employer.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0736FBE68FBA4CF0A3AC9D3EDC9C1E83"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Certain other employees</header><text>The employer may, but need not, include an employee described in section 410(b)(3) in an automatic contribution plan maintained by the employer.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8C267BEDBFCF465DB63E44D3630D6076"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Part time employees, etc</header><text>No employee may be treated as ineligible in an automatic contribution plan maintained by the employer solely by reason of working on a part-time, temporary, or seasonal basis, except as otherwise provided in this subparagraph.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCDC5CE477FE2404DA1BDE587B554354D"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>New employee</header><text>The employer may, but need not, exclude an employee from an automatic contribution plan maintained by the employer until the first day of the second calendar month beginning on or after the day the individual begins work for the employer.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE5DD12EA9E8847C4BF965B071AE807FF"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Seasonal or temporary employees</header><text>The employer may, but need not, exclude an employee from an automatic contribution plan maintained by the employer to the extent that such employee is not expected to work during more than three months during the 12-month period starting when such employee would otherwise be required to be eligible under such plan.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56F20B922DCB4FDA9015145562B5C5F9"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Special rules for controlled groups</header><text>Eligible employees within an employer need not be eligible to participate in the same automatic contribution plan. For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>employer</term> shall include all employers treated as a single employer under subsection (b), (c), (m), or (o) of section 414.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6F706A1745F4E16AA66AC75D6D85EF4"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Special rules for grandfathered plans</header><text>This paragraph shall not apply to a plan described in paragraph (2)(D) until the sixth plan year beginning on or after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Automatic Retirement Plan Act of 2017</short-title>. In the case of an eligible employer (as defined in section 408(p)(2)(C)(i)), <quote>eighth</quote> shall be substituted for <quote>sixth</quote> in the preceding sentence.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H18782D5665A840BE93767342D3F12E6E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Investment requirements</header><text>Except in the case of a plan that is an automatic contribution plan by reason of paragraph (2)(D), any investment made in the absence of an investment election by a participant or beneficiary shall be invested in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Labor under section 404(c)(5) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H71220378C7844381B5B917425DE0DDA0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Lifetime income requirements</header><text>Except in the case of a plan that is an automatic contribution plan by reason of paragraph (2)(D), the lifetime income requirements described in this paragraph are—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H459F7C3D0AA24ACBBB2428E26DEB7675"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Guaranteed income for life available</header><text>A plan shall not be treated as an automatic contribution plan unless the plan permits participants to elect to receive at least 50 percent of their vested account balance in a form of distribution described in section 401(a)(38)(B)(iii).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB33FECCAF2D943C991C3C37D5BAE843C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>This paragraph shall not apply with respect to any participant whose vested account balance is $5,000 or less at the time of distribution.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2C002F519224534B91DDE456FE17406"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Fee requirements</header><text>Under the fee requirements of this paragraph, no participant may be charged unreasonable fees solely on the basis that the participant’s balance in an automatic contribution plan is small or solely on the basis that adoption of such a plan by the employee’s employer is mandatory.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H13E11E2DADD44787AF7785931C29F54F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Excise tax for failure To maintain automatic contribution plan</header><text>Chapter 43 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block id="H982E640004314618831E9D561EC1A788" style="OLC"> <section id="HBF178941D6174A99AB18449566075634"><enum>4980J.</enum><header>Failure to maintain automatic contribution plan</header> <subsection id="HF30BDD1CDAA54EEAA968C2A7492FBDFF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General rule</header> <paragraph id="HE8A3846BB06B4643A29B3BCEFDC68512"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is hereby imposed a tax on the failure of an employer to make eligible to participate in an automatic contribution plan maintained by the employer any employee of the employer who, under the terms of section 414(aa), would be required to be eligible to participate in an automatic contribution plan maintained by the employer.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="HBBDB8174356A478498E3BF47F8432A9F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header>
 <subparagraph id="H60DFB104416D4E98912C2AEB9E213B82"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall not apply to an employer to the extent such employer participates in an arrangement under a qualified State law under section 514(f)(2) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE98D0E9711E4E85A34FED1D4C05C54F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to an employer with respect to any employee who is eligible to participate in a different automatic contribution plan than one or more other employees of the employer.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H83077F1A34A6422099E69C235CD3BA6A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amount of tax</header>
 <paragraph id="H1C845C22B6ED4136A0AC235891B7E193"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amount of the tax imposed by subsection (a) on any failure with respect to an employee shall be $10 for each day in the noncompliance period with respect to such failure.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6139BDEA9D27488ABE1419CB396A26A8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Noncompliance period</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>noncompliance period</term> means, with respect to any failure, the period—</text> <subparagraph id="H465902391E124AD5BBA2F6C30B14429F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>beginning on the date such failure first occurs, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC3AAFC6EE73452399454A71024FDEF9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ending on the earlier of—</text> <clause id="HCA5104283F614D7781B41C437B361E05"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the date such failure is corrected, or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2A58F278F226466387400EF404A78741"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect to any employer, the date that is 3 months after the last date on which the employee is required to be eligible to participate in an automatic contribution plan maintained by such employer.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H70676BDAC20F495EB2A5E90D8B27DB57"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitations on amount of tax</header>
 <paragraph id="H617867BAE5D8418885D6C7955EF23CF2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Tax not to apply where failure not discovered exercising reasonable diligence</header><text>No tax shall be imposed by subsection (a) on any failure during any period for which it is established to the satisfaction of the Secretary that none of the persons referred to in subsection (e) knew that such failure existed.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC2C620B3E85D42F89127034BC911B85F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Tax not to apply to failures corrected within <enum-in-header>9<fraction>½</fraction></enum-in-header> months</header><text>No tax shall be imposed by subsection (a) on any failure if—</text> <subparagraph id="H0F2D6D3FE7D64A53BC418A5B0C7653E2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such failure was due to reasonable cause and not to willful neglect, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H326F97330F0247B0958B3E4A2E3B1A56"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such failure is corrected during the 9<fraction>½</fraction>-month period beginning on the first date any of the persons referred to in subsection (e) knew that such failure existed.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8EB277D5EBC34E42B7016AE25FE9E335"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Overall limitation for unintentional failures</header><text>In the case of failures which are due to reasonable cause and not to willful neglect—</text> <subparagraph id="H5975C7C207D049E6BB605AB436B2999E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>General rule</header><text>The tax imposed by subsection (a) for failures during the taxable year of the employer shall not exceed $500,000.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF26293F2D4A407C9289E679B5402AFC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Taxable years in the case of certain controlled groups</header><text>For purposes of this subparagraph, if not all persons who are treated as a single employer for purposes of this section have the same taxable year, the taxable years taken into account shall be determined under principles similar to the principles of section 1561.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0AC6183C0E840AABDEA7091E6F2DBC6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Waiver by Secretary</header><text>In the case of a failure which is due to reasonable cause and not to willful neglect, the Secretary may waive part or all of the tax imposed by subsection (a) to the extent that the payment of such tax would be excessive relative to the failure involved.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7E201DF471E24505822B3C7B6385F8D4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Tax not To apply in certain cases</header><text>This section shall not apply in the case of—</text> <paragraph id="H2237CD0A4A7A430C838E406D70FF65EF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any failure of an employer to meet the requirements of subsection (a) with respect to any employee if the failure with respect to such employee occurred during the calendar year immediately following a calendar year during which all employers maintaining such plan normally employed 10 or fewer employees on a typical business day,</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5348C49AFDBA47DD97442917E9F27958"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any governmental plan (within the meaning of section 414(d)),</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HED50DC1DE2AB4626B5E2BA70C6AD0F62"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any church plan (within the meaning of section 414(e)), or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H39A5CA8AC1664AF086601AFB8885AE1E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>employers that have not been in existence for three years, taking into account all predecessor employers.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7F1B7000EC94410B8EF0F8BF155CC0C5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Liability for tax</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The employer shall be liable for the tax imposed by subsection (a) on a failure. All employers, determined without regard to subsection (f)(2), shall be jointly and severally liable for the liability of any other employer with which they are aggregated under subsection (f)(2).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0983C438EAD04302AB12E1E1A8327F6D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H52E86B6DE4A4455AA931F2AF4B6B0191"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>automatic contribution plan</term> has the meaning given such term under section 414(aa), and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB2612111BF4C4565B0850AC0D8067933"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>employer</term> includes all employers treated as a single employer under subsection (b), (c), (m), or (o) of section 414.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H27814BBECBC64E4E90B887A445C8049B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/43">chapter 43</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDA624583A3B845A3B01BCCE81C23F644" style="USC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 4980J. Failure to maintain automatic contribution plan.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H6443A2FF326C438DB3650B6E5D1E8CBD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header>
 <paragraph id="H3C72B6CD54304E05B2525B17482BE166"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall apply to years beginning after December 31, 2017.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0C539BC6971F405BB77C243CC82A3A35"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Delayed effective date</header> <subparagraph id="H4B376DF66B154490A613606F36F75AA9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Large employers</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the amendments made by subsections (b) and (c) shall apply to years beginning after December 31, 2019.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E5F46BBA6874D01A77220870E280EDF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Small employers</header><text>In the case of an eligible employer (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/408">section 408(p)(2)(C)(i)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986), the amendments made by subsections (b) and (c) shall apply to years beginning after December 31, 2021.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H7FF428C2F0CF42E59D363D955029C0FC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Deferral-only arrangements</header>
 <subsection id="HD774D93C80D84CE78F60D0F1B6459F5C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subsection (k) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/401">section 401</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H093DD6491D464F3C8FC567FA06C9A7C0" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="HF912860C452B4F60B936C9BD11641FA3"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Deferral-only arrangement</header>
 <subparagraph id="H71C6413E98324EBD8FC6EB798EBCA6B7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A deferral-only arrangement shall be treated as meeting the requirements of paragraph (3)(A)(ii).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28CB9B7B1E3242ABBD19B2777AC95ABD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Deferral-only arrangement</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>deferral-only arrangement</term> means any cash or deferred arrangement which meets—</text>
 <clause id="HA41C7DE9B7084D6AB104F516A3E62FC4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the automatic deferral requirements of subparagraph (C),</text> </clause><clause id="H88C9C62EE69E47E2B8ED60D00D3A3A65"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the elective contribution requirement of subparagraph (D), and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA92258D988A1405AB4A63FCD95E793D7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the requirements of subparagraph (E) of paragraph (13).</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H905B2A63F8E84B7184B1FD686AF6B6FA"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Automatic deferral</header> <clause id="HD287D479C77743DA881323EC37591492"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The requirements of this subparagraph are met if, under the arrangement, each employee eligible to participate in the arrangement who is not contributing or is contributing less than the qualified percentage applicable to an eligible employee in the first year of eligibility is treated as having elected in applicable years to have the employer make elective contributions in an amount equal to the qualified percentage of compensation applicable under clause (iii). In the absence of an election out as described in clause (ii), such election shall, as adjusted under clause (iii), remain in effect for all subsequent years, regardless of whether such years are applicable years.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3CEFC8CB6FB64DEE9991A7277E3448D2"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Election out</header><text>The election treated as having been made under clause (i) shall cease to apply with respect to any employee if such employee makes an affirmative election—</text>
 <subclause id="H5216134656254A0098A1220C957F6BE5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to not have such contributions made, or</text> </subclause><subclause id="HD3F9320889004580A4519A17D68125D1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to make elective contributions at a level specified in such affirmative election.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H94F23F2EFB8B4D6B84A8FB6355C3C530"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Qualified percentage</header><text>For purposes of this subparagraph, with respect to any employee, the term <term>qualified percentage</term> means, in lieu of the meaning given such term in paragraph (13)(C)(iii), any percentage determined under the arrangement if such percentage is applied uniformly and is—</text>
 <subclause id="H6C2905C05055430698F528E9D94CAB9E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>at least 6 percent, but not greater than 10 percent, during the period ending on the last day of the first plan year which begins after the date on which the first elective contribution described in clause (i) is made with respect to such employee (disregarding any elective contribution made for any preceding year that preceded a year in which the employee made an affirmative election described in clause (ii)),</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H578DB82C39754BC788DA01527B855321"><enum>(II)</enum><text>at least 7 percent during the first plan year following the plan year described in subclause (I),</text> </subclause><subclause id="H8DF4C83D621D43FBB03A1C5EB613D205"><enum>(III)</enum><text>at least 8 percent during the first plan year following the plan year described in subclause (II),</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HFEB84DFC94A2429F9CE9DBE17EB29551"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>at least 9 percent during the first plan year following the plan year described in subclause (III), and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H46DFA574FE604CBAA269E12C6573FEBB"><enum>(V)</enum><text>At least 10 percent during any subsequent plan year.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HA23D0AB3DE7648738787A5A6851C64E1"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Applicable year every third year</header> <subclause id="H9FD8197B2A9F45D4AC82133AEF50C41F"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this subparagraph, the term <term>applicable year</term> means, with respect to an employee, such employee’s first plan year of eligibility under the arrangement, and all subsequent plan years of eligibility.</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H411E49D3B5FE48FF90B3608E49EB4F96"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Following any applicable year of the employee (determined after the application of this subclause), the plan may elect to treat the next one or two plan years as not being applicable years with respect to such employee.</text>
								</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42422F77A8A34978B83A65FFD30B44EF"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Elective contributions</header>
 <clause id="HCAE83D8A504C4842A81D3C057C040F99"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The requirements of this subparagraph are met if under the plan containing the arrangement—</text> <subclause id="HE0940045C4F6406390486ACE086F913D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the only contributions which may be made are elective contributions of employees who are eligible to participate in the arrangement, and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE2526CB9F41941F4B8C2BE7207DE16DD"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the aggregate amount of such elective contributions which may be made with respect to any employee for any calendar year shall not exceed $8,000.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HBBEEC14F395E44098EDF7574F286FE6F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Cost of living adjustment</header><text>In the case of any calendar year beginning after December 31, 2018, the $8,000 amount under clause (i) shall be adjusted in the same manner as cost of living adjustments are made under section 402(g)(4), except that <quote>2017</quote> shall be substituted for <quote>2005</quote>.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1FAEF01CA7C9416B8593678E652B9176"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Cross reference</header><text>For catch-up contributions for individuals age 50 or over, see section 414(v).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H75F5F3401A8D4010999438A712664392"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Catch-Up contributions for individuals age 50 and over</header> <paragraph id="H3E5803D4AA3C4BE3B02DFBFED99ED3FA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Clause (i) of section 414(v)(2)(B) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>, 401(k)(14),</quote> after <quote>401(k)(11)</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB8C9C03C192449E3A18A213EFA9493DD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 414(v)(2)(B) of such Code is amended by adding at the end thereof the following clause:</text> <quoted-block id="HFD66412C23D8453386D65B8B79C9C575" style="OLC"> <clause commented="no" id="H677B73C5929C45068AD05D7214F6C5F9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the case of an applicable employer plan described in section 401(k)(14), the applicable dollar amount is $1,000.</text>
						</clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H26CF418A29D740B3BA4BD95D83BFA43F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Section 414(v)(2)(C) of such Code is amended by—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H6C7D3FE010D24A4B9266C5B9D33B67DF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(B)(i) and</quote> and inserting <quote>(B)(i),</quote> and by inserting after <quote>subparagraph (B)(ii)</quote> the following: <quote>, and the $1,000 amount described in subparagraph (B)(iii)</quote>, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6588C2100CB74027906005BD62734B11"><enum>(B)</enum><text>inserting after <quote>2005</quote> the following: <quote>(the calendar quarter beginning July 1, 2017, in the case of the $1,000 amount described in subparagraph (B)(iii))</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB575E097A1FD47B59B96D6A4B258CFBF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Simplified reporting</header><text>Section 104(a)(2)(A) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1024">29 U.S.C. 1024(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>or for any pension plan which is a deferral-only arrangement described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/401">section 401(k)(14)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986</quote> before the period at the end.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC827E21D21FD44A4AEE052C058358351"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Plans not treated as top-Heavy plans</header><text>Clause (i) of section 416(g)(4)(H) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>or 401(k)(13)</quote> and inserting <quote>401(k)(13), or 401(k)(14)</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H72673F19F8B647C7856000EB213C22F0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to plan years beginning after December 31, 2017.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HA710A96B80FE4295A2F29982FB24AE96"><enum>4.</enum><header>Nondiscrimination testing changes to facilitate higher contributions</header>
 <subsection id="HF6D614735A3C4D76918897CA8D095EFC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Clause (iii) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/401">section 401(k)(13)(C)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>, does not exceed 10 percent, and is at least</quote> and inserting <quote>and is</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H4918D241AE704E4B81F5815689D43FF9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> <paragraph id="HFA7BDC17EF4A437FA62F22818C9AC493"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Subclause (I) of section 401(k)(13)(C)(iii) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>3 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>at least 3 percent, but not greater than 10 percent,</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC0299C7BC249458399780E2FCCC8C7C6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Subclause (II) of section 401(k)(13)(C)(iii) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>4 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>at least 4 percent</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H425B202656A8467B8D8CDF62E7622490"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Subclause (III) of section 401(k)(13)(C)(iii) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>5 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>at least 5 percent</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0447630A0B594DB3879BFF2D1253874E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Subclause (IV) of section 401(k)(13)(C)(iii) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>6 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>at least 6 percent</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H16401C50AD5149F0B4230E2F83FA7C9A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Matching contributions</header><text>Clause (i) of section 401(m)(11)(B) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>6</quote> and inserting <quote>10</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8E6702582A154441A35543EEFFD788B0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to plan years beginning after December 31, 2017.</text> </subsection></section><section id="HEFF2CF5438424771843AA690CF85AB4D"><enum>5.</enum><header>Multiple employer plans</header> <subsection id="H043FB04930864147857A899240C7DCBE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Qualification requirements</header> <paragraph id="H53535432A2804C13A7819D730953A453"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/413">Section 413</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended by this Act, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
					<quoted-block id="HE3224574AC044389ACC7B27791D311A9" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="H2604D309620D47238E5B1A7F1BEF9F4F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Application of qualification requirements for certain multiple employer plans with pooled plan
			 providers</header>
 <paragraph id="H8A837842B5D548B785BDC901E5FD4A19"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), a defined contribution plan to which subsection (c) applies shall not be treated as failing to meet the requirements under this title applicable to a plan described in section 401(a) or to a plan that consists of individual retirement accounts described in section 408 (including by reason of subsection (c) thereof), whichever is applicable, merely because one or more employers of employees covered by the plan fail to take such actions as are required of such employers for the plan to meet such requirements if the plan—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8759060D89EE4C8A8DE2A4FDB8B378FC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is sponsored by employers all of which have both a common interest other than having adopted the plan and control of the plan, or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0511366887F143C9A9C9495F4FE4ACBA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a plan not described in subparagraph (A), has a pooled plan provider.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA39B807167F41D7A07520726A7B3FF9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitations</header> <subparagraph id="H8C9AC240D64B4ABBAF19D8AF41709797"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to any plan unless the terms of the plan provide that in cases of employers failing to take the actions described in paragraph (1)—</text>
 <clause id="H6F42BDCF2CB549C0986E56B74D5C9B62"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the assets of the plan attributable to employees of the employer will be transferred to a plan maintained only by the employer (or its successor), to an eligible retirement plan as defined in section 402(c)(8)(B) for each individual whose account is transferred, or to any other arrangement that the Secretary determines is appropriate, unless the Secretary determines it is in the best interests of such employees to retain the assets in the plan, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H319E1B43C420488396D8E98AD4FD4C65"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the employer described in clause (i) (and not the plan with respect to which the failure occurred or any other participating employer in such plan) shall, except to the extent provided by the Secretary, be liable for any liabilities with respect to such plan attributable to employees of the employer.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74355C80998D4C54BA42D64ECEFA86B7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Failures by pooled plan providers</header><text>If the pooled plan provider of a plan described in paragraph (1)(B) does not perform substantially all of the administrative duties which are required of the provider under paragraph (3)(A)(i) for any plan year, the Secretary, in the Secretary’s own discretion, may provide that the determination as to whether the plan meets the requirements under this title applicable to a plan described in section 401(a) or to a plan that consists of individual retirement accounts described in section 408 (including by reason of subsection (c) thereof), whichever is applicable, shall be made in the same manner as would be made without regard to paragraph (1).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDED95189142A4D61886EFBFD73C2A35D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Pooled plan provider</header><text>For purposes of this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="H7C47376B4A12498BBA26FCDFA7D54F2B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>pooled plan provider</term> means, with respect to any plan, a person who—</text>
 <clause id="H95403E24D3F94BEE8B5D3F787F215829"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is designated by the terms of the plan as a named fiduciary (as defined in section 402(a)(2) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974), as the plan administrator, and as the person responsible to perform all administrative duties (including conducting proper testing with respect to the plan and employees of each participating employer) which are reasonably necessary to ensure that—</text>
 <subclause id="H46A98185DE184C1381AFAC3272871B05"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the plan meets any requirement applicable under the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 or this title to a plan described in section 401(a) or to a plan that consists of individual retirement accounts described in section 408 (including by reason of subsection (c) thereof), whichever is applicable, and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HF1AE13D6AAAE4FD5BE6FEB14445EA0EA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>each participating employer takes such actions as the Secretary or such person determines are necessary for the plan to meet the requirements described in subclause (I), including providing to such person any disclosures or other information which the Secretary may require or which such person otherwise determines is necessary to administer the plan or to allow the plan to meet such requirements,</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HCC360D24499A444894D54FCB6FEB2E7B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>registers as a pooled plan provider with the Secretary, and provides such other information to the Secretary as the Secretary may require, before beginning operations as a pooled plan provider,</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBAB4F703EDA6433F9111FFB0C494257B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>acknowledges in writing that such person is a named fiduciary (within the meaning of section 402(a)(2) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974), and the plan administrator, with respect to the plan, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H25611939D0C54C4AB35823AF87BEC470"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>is responsible for ensuring that all persons who handle assets of, or who are fiduciaries of, the plan are bonded in accordance with section 412 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF26FF11D3E1F4BD1A94580C31A539816"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Audits, examinations, and investigations</header><text>The Secretary may perform audits, examinations, and investigations of pooled plan providers as may be necessary to enforce and carry out the purposes of this subsection.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2199895EEEE84901BEB0D418FF584121"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Guidance</header>
 <subparagraph id="HC25E51525D0243B983A3AE4F9F07F803"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall issue such guidance as the Secretary determines appropriate to carry out this subsection, including guidance—</text>
 <clause id="H58FB429B43AC4B56AF269C8E75F9A402"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to identify the administrative duties and other actions required to be performed by a pooled plan provider under this subsection,</text>
 </clause><clause id="H22F327942B6F4DC58C3E1BB838763A18"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>which describes the procedures to be taken to terminate a plan which fails to meet the requirements to be a plan described in paragraph (1), including the proper treatment of, and actions needed to be taken by, any participating employer of the plan and the assets and liabilities of the plan with respect to employees of that employer, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H789D93ED60524E2D8EB97FCF8803A6BA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>identifying appropriate cases to which the rules of paragraph (2)(A) will apply to employers failing to take the actions described in paragraph (1).</text>
									</clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">The Secretary shall take into account under clause (iii) whether the failure of an employer or
			 pooled plan provider to provide any disclosures or other information, or
			 to take any other action, necessary to administer a plan or to allow a
			 plan to meet requirements applicable to the plan under section 401(a) or
			 408, whichever is applicable, has continued over a period of time that
 clearly demonstrates a lack of commitment to compliance.</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B995C6CCF434271A609AA77929555DD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prospective application</header><text>Any guidance issued by the Secretary under this paragraph shall not apply to any action or failure occurring before the issuance of such guidance.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5014CCA38EDD4583BD37B9BE9A10399D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Model plan</header><text>No later than June 30, 2018, the Secretary shall, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor when appropriate, publish model plan language which meets the requirements of this subsection and of paragraphs (43) and (44) of section 3 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 and which may be adopted in order for a plan to be treated as a plan described in paragraph (1)(B). Such model plans shall also include options under which they can be used by plans that are not pooled employer plans.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4B78D53A190E49E58693D52CFD50EE1B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Paragraph (3) of section 413(b) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>section 401(a)</quote> and inserting <quote>sections 401(a) and 408(c)</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2B8D5BC5E59E49D5A5D8DAEA6AD80D9A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Technical amendment</header><text>Subsection (c) of section 408 of such Code is amended by inserting after paragraph (2) the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H26999824C915497DB77529A06EC8CCC7" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H2FBB4F2706564643B78088825A737946"><enum>(3)</enum><text>There is a separate accounting for any interest of an employee or member (or spouse of an employee or member) in a Roth IRA.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2336E4E0586446E9AB0E412B80B19C65"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No common interest required for pooled employer plans</header><text>Section 3(2) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1002">29 U.S.C. 1002(2)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H3FBDEDB58ADB4115BFFE2892C9966F95" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H30AA9AF9C875405B9B4555B4357B2078"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A pooled employer plan shall be treated as—</text> <clause id="HD81214E0391E4A268941F580C3FA2710"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a single employee pension benefit plan or single pension plan, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB95A2F82CEF54AAD877D87F5EAFD7B08"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a plan to which section 210(a) applies.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H692F1A3CCE424416A399274445E22B23"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Pooled employer plan and provider defined</header> <paragraph id="H2B32BA3DCC0346E99F197DA2974DB713"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 3 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1002">29 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H0AC3533C816E4DE689AA39BDB115B20C" style="OLC">
						<paragraph id="H29A136AF363C4F0B8CA7C609CF07267C"><enum>(43)</enum><header>Pooled employer plan</header>
 <subparagraph id="H8AC31A50A8954A9FB6B9161B8BB0E798"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>pooled employer plan</term> means a plan—</text> <clause id="H2A38A0C678BD4B918AF55864243F0AD6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>which is an individual account plan established or maintained for the purpose of providing benefits to the employees of two or more employers;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0B7194F44A8A43878D4C0D19F4230C3A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>which is a plan described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/401">section 401(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 which includes a trust exempt from tax under section 501(a) of such Code or a plan that consists of individual retirement accounts described in section 408 of such Code (including by reason of subsection (c) thereof); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA914016BB1934E3786E009F7D43F81BC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the terms of which meet the requirements of subparagraph (B).</text> </clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">Such term shall not include a plan with respect to which all of the participating employers have both a common interest other than having adopted the plan and control of the plan.</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1DE4709BC3C44A0A46C0BC63DD996F1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements for plan terms</header><text>The requirements of this subparagraph are met with respect to any plan if the terms of the plan—</text>
 <clause id="HC9840031CA654DA8A71106930C9E700B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>designate a pooled plan provider and provide that the pooled plan provider is a named fiduciary of the plan;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0B9BECB96D15455FB08727DA75B9A8CC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>designate one or more trustees meeting the requirements of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/408">section 408(a)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (other than a participating employer) to be responsible for collecting contributions to, and holding the assets of, the plan and require such trustees to implement written contribution collection procedures that are reasonable, diligent, and systematic;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H39C98B0BFA2A471CA8F98111FBEB295A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>except as provided in section 404(e), provide that each participating employer retains fiduciary responsibility for—</text>
 <subclause id="H0A150D9688E94CF3B474B74FD06004A6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the selection and monitoring in accordance with section 404(a) of the person designated as the pooled plan provider and any other person who, in addition to the pooled plan provider, is designated as a named fiduciary of the plan; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H56EF39E85EDD4607A04B6361E356B540"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to the extent not otherwise delegated to another fiduciary by the pooled plan provider and subject to the provisions of section 404(c), the investment and management of that portion of the plan’s assets attributable to the employees of that participating employer;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H99462290F3EA47A3B4FE9EE525DCC8F0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>provide that a participating employer, or a participant or beneficiary, is not subject to unreasonable restrictions, fees, or penalties with regard to ceasing participation, receipt of distributions, or otherwise transferring assets of the plan in accordance with section 208 or paragraph (44)(C)(i)(II);</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD804073FBF7D4C37A1D5D1D3FC8F251C"><enum>(v)</enum><text>require—</text> <subclause id="HFC10DC1952604E5DBB7214747630BC1F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the pooled plan provider to provide to participating employers any disclosures or other information which the Secretary may require, including, as applicable, any disclosures or other information to facilitate the selection or any monitoring of the pooled plan provider by participating employers; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H3EADB174D62542129FBE68010E720795"><enum>(II)</enum><text>each participating employer to take such actions as the Secretary or the pooled plan provider determines are necessary to administer the plan or for the plan to meet any requirement applicable under this Act or the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to a plan described in section 401(a) of such Code or to a plan that consists of individual retirement accounts described in section 408 of such Code (including by reason of subsection (c) thereof), whichever is applicable, including providing any disclosures or other information which the Secretary may require or which the pooled plan provider otherwise determines is necessary to administer the plan or to allow the plan to meet such requirements; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HCABBA81EA12F40E4B05566204F9A9EB3"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>provide that any disclosure or other information required to be provided under clause (v) may be provided in electronic form and will be designed to ensure only reasonable costs are imposed on pooled plan providers and participating employers.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09688975A15448FD88D9E129204E4E79"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>The term <term>pooled employer plan</term> does not include—</text> <clause id="HC85257A593B547228B97CDDEF43AE712"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a multiemployer plan;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H999235E7CC754358972A03CC0842B836"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a plan established before January 1, 2016, unless the plan administrator elects that the plan will be treated as a pooled employer plan and the plan meets the requirements of this title applicable to a pooled employer plan established on or after such date; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5CBE9BE08AB7488F9ED19F91E90D1905"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a plan with respect to which all of the participating employers have both a common interest other than having adopted the plan and control of the plan.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7032F822705548EAA3D77BBBFFECF6F5"><enum>(44)</enum><header>Pooled plan provider</header>
 <subparagraph id="H3FAA1A0E50C1446CB444F982B126C5A1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>pooled plan provider</term> means a person who—</text> <clause id="HD7407D5532FE41C09474FD98176A1BE3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is designated by the terms of a pooled employer plan as a named fiduciary, as the plan administrator, and as the person responsible for the performance of all administrative duties (including conducting proper testing with respect to the plan and employees of each participating employer) which are reasonably necessary to ensure that—</text>
 <subclause id="H1A9EFF531C2648149D3604E5C01A5175"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the plan meets any requirement applicable under this Act or the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to a plan described in section 401(a) of such Code or to a plan that consists of individual retirement accounts described in section 408 of such Code (including by reason of subsection (c) thereof), whichever is applicable; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HFEBB805E9DA3483F951939C039956B36"><enum>(II)</enum><text>each participating employer takes such actions as the Secretary or pooled plan provider determines are necessary for the plan to meet the requirements described in subclause (I), including providing the disclosures and information described in paragraph (43)(B)(v)(II);</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H69201769823B4153B6883F7842B1433D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>registers as a pooled plan provider with the Secretary, and provides to the Secretary such other information as the Secretary may require, before beginning operations as a pooled plan provider;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBFBD1A4F1B994968AB8F34CE072E86FB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>acknowledges in writing that such person is a named fiduciary, and the plan administrator, with respect to the pooled employer plan; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD1A368B04D30448CA4C6596626DE84C4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>is responsible for ensuring that all persons who handle assets of, or who are fiduciaries of, the pooled employer plan are bonded in accordance with section 412.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1DCEF3AD9EAC475697404287FD7D19D7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Audits, examinations, and investigations</header><text>The Secretary may perform audits, examinations, and investigations of pooled plan providers as may be necessary to enforce and carry out the purposes of this paragraph and paragraph (43).</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H366D96C943C94E76A10657CDDD8E5042"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Guidance</header>
 <clause id="H60D552D297934FC4888E55B29F3E4946"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall issue such guidance as the Secretary determines appropriate to carry out this paragraph and paragraph (43), including guidance—</text>
 <subclause id="HDEE16897BD7243FFBBAE2AA9FEC1ECE1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to identify the administrative duties and other actions required to be performed by a pooled plan provider under either such paragraph; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H4D61A02F240B4A89AF0CCF0BB7CE8707"><enum>(II)</enum><text>which requires in appropriate cases that if a participating employer fails to take the actions required under subparagraph (A)(i)(II)—</text>
 <item id="H462A22E00B9048DD814AAC7ED3464570"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the assets of the plan attributable to employees of the participating employer are transferred to a plan maintained only by the participating employer (or its successor), to an eligible retirement plan as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/402">section 402(c)(8)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 for each individual whose account is transferred, or to any other arrangement that the Secretary determines is appropriate in such guidance; and</text>
 </item><item id="H395CC71EDD4B47209E59E8081DB2A71E"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the participating employer described in item (aa) (and not the plan with respect to which the failure occurred or any other participating employer in such plan) shall, except to the extent provided in such guidance, be liable for any liabilities with respect to such plan attributable to employees of the participating employer.</text>
										</item><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subclause">The Secretary shall take into account under subclause (II) whether the failure of an employer or
			 pooled plan provider to provide any disclosures or other information, or
			 to take any other action, necessary to administer a plan or to allow a
			 plan to meet requirements described in subparagraph (A)(i)(II) has
			 continued over a period of time that clearly demonstrates a lack of
			 commitment to compliance. The Secretary may waive the requirements of
			 subclause (II)(aa) in appropriate circumstances if the Secretary
			 determines it is in the best interests of the employees of the
			 participating employer described in such clause to retain the assets in
 the plan with respect to which the employer’s failure occurred.</continuation-text></subclause></clause><clause id="HA21F4D21E2004C45A070233329D718A0"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Prospective application</header><text>Any guidance issued by the Secretary under this subparagraph shall not apply to any action or failure occurring before the issuance of such guidance.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57E29ABB5F3B41E98A47A03E04242BE0"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Aggregation rules</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph—</text> <clause id="H923237A2D82E41DB85527721F54D6E58"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In determining whether a person meets the requirements of this paragraph to be a pooled plan provider with respect to any plan, all persons who are members of the same controlled group and who perform services for the plan shall be treated as one person.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9A47E845FB634D318469B41C066E4C68"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Members of common group</header><text>Persons shall be treated as members of the same controlled group if such persons are treated as a single employer under subsection (c) or (d) of section 210.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0174E45C5B43402A9BC264E75E82B64E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Bonding requirements for pooled employer plans</header><text>The last sentence of section 412(a) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1112">29 U.S.C. 1112(a)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>or in the case of a pooled employer plan (as defined in section 3(43)</quote> after <quote>section 407(d)(1))</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFECC7693E96F45F2A0951D22A67F5C7C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Conforming and technical amendments</header><text>Section 3 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1002">29 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HE846E79099CC4F719CCC1E1510C80929"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (16)(B)—</text>
 <clause id="HDC7A1CC23C6D41F592C6084060DFC7B5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of clause (ii); and</text> </clause><clause id="HCD630FCC0AAF456D98AF3552105C26A7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>, or (iv) in the case of a pooled employer plan, the pooled plan provider.</quote>; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8693A85BCEA9451CBE6215FBC1C01AAE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking the second paragraph (41).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H55CEFB3AE6B7462B8C30E907791C52E4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header> <paragraph id="H6ACEA0A10DEF46FCB4912B99BF6FC436"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to years beginning after December 31, 2019.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H69A6544CB67942108C054432D5CF746C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in the amendments made by subsection (a) shall be construed as limiting the authority of the Secretary of the Treasury or the Secretary’s delegate (determined without regard to such amendment) to provide for the proper treatment of a failure to meet any requirement applicable under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 with respect to one employer (and its employees) in a multiple employer plan.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE2D706DC48EB43198BDA0A1F0DA80A45"><enum>6.</enum><header>Limitation on employer liability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 404 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1021">29 U.S.C. 1021</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="H715C8BD05BA84446A7EA19431AEDD9A6" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="H038C65C17C5F46AE99E15F87D4E1F86F"><enum>(e)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H4EFD627813CE4C6181F66705C6635AAE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible employer (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/408">section 408(p)(2)(C)(i)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) shall not be a fiduciary in any respect with respect to a pooled employer plan, including with respect to the selection or monitoring of any plan service provider or any investment under the plan, if the pooled plan provider—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2E21E6A6A78B4D07A1553889E1F8F990" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">receives no more than reasonable compensation for its services, as agreed to by the eligible employer, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H76891F2DDB6C4B9D954AFF1020057F82" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>agrees in the plan document to—</text> <clause id="HD9264085D22A4F969B9ED95580420DC8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>comply with all requirements applicable to a pooled plan provider under this title, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H38985C4ED78D413582F3023EE73A74D7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assume, with respect to such eligible employer as agreed to by the eligible employer, all fiduciary responsibility with respect to the plan not retained by the eligible employer, and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9785FBA8C70A41069B3690960ACA3FF7" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notifies the eligible employer of its obligations under the pooled employer plan.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F2B09ADBF5D4EEA857F5225D1584FDD" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding paragraph (1), eligible employers participating in such a pooled employer plan shall be responsible for—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFF835CCAB7B64CCA9CF74A3BF27BE211"><enum>(A)</enum><text>meeting the enrollment requirements applicable to such employer under the plan,</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H708FA69295A748B79790167688923DD1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>transmitting contributions to the plan in accordance with the terms of the plan,</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1DF52659134945809E0611B1561D9E0F"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing such information and assistance as is within the sole control of the eligible employer and is needed by the plan to operate in accordance with the plan document, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BD2111F39094F37B3407635789CD7F9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>providing such other information or assistance in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="H1D3A7FE201564D1DBC9DFE1EF4F692F1"><enum>7.</enum><header>Portability of lifetime income options</header>
 <subsection id="HF365F7ACFF384CEDB6100F4423CC48D8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subsection (a) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/401">section 401</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after paragraph (37) the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFAF9A3FA7CB845FBBB828B3CF7064F38" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="HD27B6D5CFA6042CFAF5AB1D8AD877FFD"><enum>(38)</enum><header>Portability of lifetime income and managed account options</header>
 <subparagraph id="H99CB8312B4CC4724A4917C49826DB8B0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A trust forming part of a defined contribution plan shall not be treated as failing to constitute a qualified trust under this section solely by reason of allowing—</text>
 <clause id="H54E5191D411D4BB5ADB9EE64DDC84EF1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>qualified distributions of a lifetime income investment or a managed account investment, or</text> </clause><clause id="H3048BAF456BD4F81B114AA21D705BBB9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>distributions of a lifetime income investment in the form of a qualified plan distribution annuity contract,</text>
							</clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">on or after the date that is 90 days prior to the date on which such lifetime income investment or
			 such managed account investment is no longer authorized to be held as an
			 investment option under the plan except as may otherwise be provided by
 regulations.</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20D65651431047A7824AA91723012F7F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this subsection—</text> <clause id="H315035EB835B4ADF971F69B04B69C689"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the term <term>qualified distribution</term> means a direct trustee-to-trustee transfer to an eligible retirement plan (as defined in section 402(c)(8)(B)), as described in section 401(a)(31)(A), and in the case of a managed account investment, the eligible retirement plan must be maintained by the account manager of such managed account investment,</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEBCAB9CB5C044764A3CA0134E27E095F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the term <term>lifetime income investment</term> means an investment option that is designed to provide an employee with election rights—</text> <subclause id="H0DA28D190A9F4500B8192C4991A05B53"><enum>(I)</enum><text>that are not uniformly available with respect to other investment options under the plan, and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H9DDE46EBC15748EC89F82CB4B830BFA2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>that are to a lifetime income feature available through a contract or other arrangement offered under the plan or under another eligible retirement plan (as defined in section 402(c)(8)(B)) through a direct trustee-to-trustee transfer to such other eligible retirement plan under section 401(a)(31)(A),</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HAD1C44AABA9D46EEB1BC2979627502B9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the term <term>lifetime income feature</term> means—</text> <subclause id="H51051179B25040E5ABE4EF521F8C22B9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a feature that guarantees a minimum level of income annually (or more frequently) for at least the remainder of the life of the employee or the joint lives of the employee and the employee’s designated beneficiary, or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE833A91BFBC14C46A18A6B646A0C0B18"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an annuity payable on behalf of the employee under which payments are made in substantially equal periodic payments (not less frequently than annually) over the life of the employee or the joint lives of the employee and the employee’s designated beneficiary,</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H1C223791CB9145FDB0F0BCD5B91545EB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>qualified plan distribution annuity contract</term> means an annuity contract purchased for a participant and distributed to the participant by a plan described in subparagraph (B) of section 402(c)(8) (without regard to clauses (i) and (ii) thereof),</text>
 </clause><clause id="H62FEC573C6A4472D8013380C217D90AC"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>managed account investment</term> means an investment option under which the assets of the employee’s individual account are managed by an account manager, applying generally accepted investment theories, to achieve varying degrees of long-term appreciation and capital preservation based on the employee’s age, target retirement date or life expectancy,</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB7FEFA6E35454BBC80293B06C9762520"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>account manager</term> means an investment manager (within the meaning of section 3(38) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act), and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H196AC106E132469A999F173CA2614470"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a lifetime income investment or managed account investment is treated as no longer authorized to be held as an investment under the plan if such treatment applies to all plan participants or to a class of such participants, as determined in any reasonable manner.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE35986AB803B420C92A7794E52CD8DDB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Cash or deferred arrangement</header><text>Clause (i) of section 401(k)(2)(B) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of subclause (IV), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subclause (V) and inserting <quote>or</quote>, and by adding at the end of clause (i) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA6B5B4D8522E437F9924E73C2B605566" style="OLC"> <subclause id="HE476BB7B94C942A3BBE8E786719FC6B3"><enum>(VI)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to amounts invested in a lifetime income investment (as defined in section 401(a)(38)(B)(ii)) or a managed account investment (as defined in section 401(a)(38)(B)(v)), the date that is 90 days prior to the date that such lifetime income investment or such managed account investment may no longer be held as an investment option under the plan (within the meaning of section 401(a)(38)(B)(vii)), provided that any distribution under this subclause must be in the form of a qualified distribution (as defined in section 401(a)(38)(B)(i)) or, in the case of a lifetime income investment, a qualified plan distribution annuity contract (as defined in section 401(a)(38)(B)(iv)), and</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="HD7F3986B45164297BE2C65F501940994"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Section 403(<enum-in-header>b</enum-in-header>) plans</header>
 <paragraph id="HF133427AF29C44D9BD04589ED2ED0838"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Annuity contracts</header><text>Paragraph (11) of section 403(b) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of subparagraph (B), by striking the period at the end of subparagraph (C), and by inserting <quote>, or</quote>, and by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H98C4533DFE714881A9ACB42AC1048D3A" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="HCAE7938CCC524025B182AF62AD44199F"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to amounts invested in a lifetime income investment (as defined in section 401(a)(38)(B)(ii)) or a managed account investment (as defined in section 401(a)(38)(B)(v)), the date that is 90 days prior to the date that such lifetime income investment or such managed account investment may no longer be held as an investment option under the plan (within the meaning of section 401(a)(38)(B)(vii)), provided that any distribution under this subparagraph must be in the form of a qualified distribution (as defined in section 401(a)(38)(B)(i)) or, in the case of a lifetime income investment, a qualified plan distribution annuity contract (as defined in section 401(a)(38)(B)(iv)).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H48E94D3FD129400BA203941F882DA505"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Custodial accounts</header><text>Clause (ii) of section 403(b)(7)(A) of such Code is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB5CB4245DEB34CC3839B63A8C857EF4E" style="OLC"> <clause id="H957D1566ECEB4ADD8D9AE949DA399BFC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>under the custodial account, no such amounts may be paid or made available to any distributee (unless such amount is a distribution to which section 72(t)(2)(G) applies) before—</text>
 <subclause id="H27E750ECC89040FFBDDA98080F515E36"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the employee dies,</text> </subclause><subclause id="HA59F425948434FB89B681093C8605AAD"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the employee attains age 59½,</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HCBEA9A5BAA754007ADA47A8ABB131792"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the employee has a severance from employment,</text> </subclause><subclause id="HD1BAA6C48DD549E4829DEB67D663C993"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the employee becomes disabled (within the meaning of section 72(m)(7)),</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H447ACE3907C04428A25FAE055ADD0672"><enum>(V)</enum><text>in the case of contributions made pursuant to a salary reduction agreement (within the meaning of section 3121(a)(5)(D)), the employee encounters financial hardship, or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HC987C0D1CBE44D20B30D515653930338"><enum>(VI)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to amounts invested in a lifetime income investment (as defined in section 401(a)(38)(B)(ii)) or a managed account investment (as defined in section 401(a)(38)(B)(v)), the date that is 90 days prior to the date that such lifetime income investment or such managed account investment may no longer be held as an investment option under the plan (within the meaning of section 401(a)(38)(B)(vii)), provided that any distribution under this subparagraph must be in the form of a qualified distribution (as defined in section 401(a)(38)(B)(i)) or, in the case of a lifetime income investment, a qualified plan distribution annuity contract (as defined in section 401(a)(38)(B)(iv)).</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0EAD436131AC463F837C1CCC0BB5766C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligible deferred compensation plans</header><text>Subparagraph (A) of section 457(d)(1) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of clause (ii), by inserting <quote>or</quote> at the end of clause (iii), and by adding after clause (iii) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2D640817BA434110BDFA25778591635E" style="OLC"> <clause id="H4457855C38654F10B6AC614F92EAB295"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to amounts invested in a lifetime income investment (as defined in section 401(a)(38)(B)(ii)) or a managed account investment (as defined in section 401(a)(38)(B)(v)), the date that is 90 days prior to the date that such lifetime income investment or such managed account investment may no longer be held as an investment option under the plan (within the meaning of section 401(a)(38)(B)(vii)), provided that any distribution under this subparagraph must be in the form of a qualified distribution (as defined in section 401(a)(38)(B)(i)) or, in the case of a lifetime income investment, a qualified plan distribution annuity contract (as defined in section 401(a)(38)(B)(iv)),</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0CAAC693ACDA4455B9D86FCA0FF82A11"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply to plan years beginning after December 31, 2017.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H1A5826D77AB640E986C41D8F171DE724"><enum>8.</enum><header>Increase in credit limitation for small employer pension plan startup costs</header> <subsection id="HA633C545560F4FF5BFF35AD464CC1D06"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Paragraph (1) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/45E">section 45E(b)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HF0DE2638F4904C5F9A25F8F4A299C7B1" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H16E3F3ACE55346CF901BDCFED9216F52"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for the first credit year and each of the 4 taxable years immediately following the first credit year, the greater of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H363D74D29FB949309E8EE4ACFA2AF7E5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$500, or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4D27184CC69644DDB6663B5554A04E68"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the lesser of—</text>
 <clause id="H86CD192687D5472E83DD715BD3AED65D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>$250 for each employee of the eligible employer who is not a highly compensated employee (as defined in section 414(q)) and who is eligible to participate in the eligible employer plan maintained by the eligible employer, or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H050E87C90C5C4CBDB3B73CF09DAB7A4C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>$5,000, and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H486F3E110A1C4F3A86D51AF5922086FB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Special rule for employers with 25 or fewer employees</header><text>Subsection (a) of section 45E of such Code is amended by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>(100 percent of such costs in the case of an eligible employer with 25 or fewer employees, as determined by substituting <quote>25</quote> for <quote>100</quote> in section 408(p)(2)(C)(i))</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H00C54AD1585A4B69B3E561977F0CC05E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Automatic contribution plan</header><text>Paragraph (2) of section 45E(d) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>a qualified employer plan within the meaning of section 4972(d)</quote> and inserting <quote>an automatic contribution plan within the meaning of section 414(aa)</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HF43D1E6CBEFD439AB202DFAE9F33891D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conforming change</header><text>Paragraph (2) of section 45E(d) of such Code is amended by adding at the end thereof the following: <quote>For purposes of this section, the term <term>qualified employer plan</term> has the meaning given such term under section 4972(d).</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB18912D769F94E2FAADA2CD825135B0E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2017.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H0D38BE4AF47044BB960058BEAFC77CAF"><enum>9.</enum><header>Small employer automatic enrollment credit</header> <subsection id="H817C41BBABBC42C2BCE8123E7F18B295"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H3B78FC58388540D0A38C61FE11328773" style="OLC">
					<section id="H317E19423AC6456A9B589DAC6B394BA2"><enum>45S.</enum><header>Auto-enrollment credit for retirement savings options provided by small employers</header>
 <subsection id="H35AD777BDC4F437698EDCE5D08A40942"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of section 38, in the case of an eligible employer, the retirement auto-enrollment credit determined under this section for any taxable year is an amount equal to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H30A9D1E76A1040DBAD0171462DAB3570"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$500 for any taxable year occurring during the credit period, and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1BB388FD8FE1488BB08BDD26DD5DF394"><enum>(2)</enum><text>zero for any other taxable year.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H90DC3DB0377848F89DE358E5BD3F0CB3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Credit period</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a)—</text> <paragraph id="H9F7270A8AF8E48A5ABCD8251D3D352CE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The credit period with respect to any eligible employer is the 5-taxable-year period beginning with the first taxable year for which the employer adopts an automatic contribution plan (as defined in section 414(aa)), determined without regard to a plan described in section 414(aa)(2)(D) (relating to a grandfathered automatic contribution plan).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB05D6B6DE29B4D6A946F5FDE9AB4A46B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Maintenance of arrangement</header><text>No taxable year with respect to an employer shall be treated as occurring within the credit period unless the arrangement described in section 401(k)(14)(C) is included in the plan for such year.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9FF818DC751C482B813291F788A5CD09"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible employer</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>eligible employer</term> has the meaning given such term in section 408(p)(2)(C)(i).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H273EB85C451C40B594AA0458036B5E32"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Credit To be part of general business credit</header><text>Subsection (b) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/38">section 38</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>plus</quote> at the end of paragraph (35), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (36) and inserting <quote>, plus</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H65F24969540D421A96AAC80155FA0504" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HC22D0C25E1D544DE9D1879F646DB036B"><enum>(37)</enum><text>in the case of an eligible employer (as defined in section 45S(c)), the retirement auto-enrollment credit determined under section 45S(a).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H597E1AB27D2B40348C8F1987418EF23B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 45R the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H549882403E73445DAAB9C4759E844138" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 45S. Auto-enrollment credit for retirement savings options provided by small employers.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB0C73277EE164110B84A68637B5C7843"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2017.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H61CC8F3AC4A042A585DDFED854386F74"><enum>10.</enum><header>Treatment of automatic contribution plans under State law</header> <subsection id="H83F6E519220E400880DDD0A4D6A2F111"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 514 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1144">29 U.S.C. 1144</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H0FA97335D21E4E0884C36C5E4057AD58" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H239E49FDACBC4EB09ABDFFED46201356"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Automatic contribution plans</header>
 <paragraph id="H87F124002F754F3989D21C69B5BC37E5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If an employer maintains an automatic contribution plan (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/414">section 414(aa)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) that satisfies the requirements of section 414(aa)(3) (without regard to subparagraph (D) thereof), the employer—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7AA9523D14194A3DA6A40B7D83AC64CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall not be subject to any requirement imposed by a State or political subdivision thereof to contribute to an individual retirement plan (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7701">section 7701(a)(37)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) established and maintained pursuant to a payroll deduction savings program of a State or political subdivision thereof, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B9A74327E824C0EBA1C13F055D3C412"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall not be required to participate in any manner in such a payroll deduction savings program.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H05FEE2BFD4ED44FD8F6680179FE591C0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified State law exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This subsection shall not apply with respect to any employer to the extent that such employer participates in an arrangement under a qualified State law.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H34BDA6DAE15744029424B98E5C289532"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified State law</header><text>For purposes of this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="HDCEE4C47EE824B15A044A4854E1EBCEA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>qualified State law</term> means a State law that—</text>
 <clause id="HF26073F61D014D69B1CE944CEFF03946"><enum>(i)</enum><text>was enacted before the date of enactment of the <short-title>Automatic Retirement Plan Act of 2017</short-title>,</text> </clause><clause id="HC7D4DC92CCF04AC7A6F2676A4A39AEFC"><enum>(ii)</enum> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7A87D63149974AE299459309AD1338C7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>requires certain employers to contribute to, or participate in, an individual retirement plan (as defined in section 7701(a)(37) of such Code) established and maintained pursuant to a payroll deduction savings program of the State, or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H74065BD7AE5E420FAB3147DF11A3AF06" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">allows certain employers to contribute to, or participate in, a plan described in section 413(c) of such Code established and maintained by the State, and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HF3BF6C3CA4034BDBAB8DC6917EE4331B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is not superseded by this title (determined without regard to this subsection).</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F96BEBE77F548998D916D6BD557A30B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a State law described in subparagraph (A)(ii) is amended after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Automatic Retirement Plan Act of 2017</short-title> to materially expand the scope of the requirement described in subparagraph (A)(ii)(I) or the availability of a plan described in subparagraph (A)(ii)(II), the State law shall, as of the effective date of such amendment, cease to treated as a qualified State law.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8F9CBE8D128E4595BA008FDD1479A423"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to plan years beginning after December 31, 2017.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H71B0C585D24249D18F97F746FB00E6A9"><enum>11.</enum><header>Matching payments for elective deferral and IRA contributions by certain individuals</header> <subsection id="H4D7D14BE175C40DF8DE832EF6B71ABBB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/65">chapter 65</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HBF6B8FF97B6D45DCAAB9A3B1A48DC917" style="OLC">
					<section id="H80329C29FB8946F68FFEA1BA744A5C9E"><enum>6433.</enum><header>Matching payments for elective deferral and IRA contributions by certain individuals</header>
						<subsection id="HC53D9A1C72174EA59DC4A44F2C980B61"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <paragraph id="H3C0CC5F22FAE4C70B58042890E207156"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Allowance of credit</header><text>Any eligible individual who makes qualified retirement savings contributions for the taxable year shall be allowed a credit for such taxable year in an amount equal to the applicable percentage of so much of the qualified retirement savings contributions made by such eligible individual for the taxable year as does not exceed $1,000.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4E337D026AA047B7BD5C411F470C2320"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Payment of credit</header><text>The credit under this section shall be paid by the Secretary as a contribution (as soon as practicable after the eligible individual has filed a tax return for the taxable year) to the applicable retirement vehicle of the eligible individual.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFC022BDDEE72474F918AC01FF1F4E7FA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicable percentage</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H72EC6368F3BD4794986FA05AABD6F58F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the applicable percentage is 50 percent.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H16B97E58B5044DFFB35249E2B106A317"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Phaseout</header><text>The percentage under paragraph (1) shall be reduced (but not below zero) by the number of percentage points which bears the same ratio to 50 percentage points as—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAF144E812B274D1EA09C1910798EA18E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the excess of—</text> <clause id="H319048A9971849A5A054A52CF6DA3739"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the taxpayer’s modified adjusted gross income for such taxable year, over</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE6232ABA6ED84DBAA7965A46749EBB00"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the applicable dollar amount, bears to</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9F9D618C00B4B01B279FD5D34C3BA8A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the phaseout range.</text>
								</subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">If any reduction determined under this paragraph is not a whole percentage point, such reduction
			 shall be rounded to the next lowest whole percentage point.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="HADA024CB907B42D4A6C05840FFCE6D87"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applicable dollar amount; phaseout range</header>
 <subparagraph id="HD4F539A83F464867B0FDEBD008811A85"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Joint returns</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B)—</text> <clause id="H04F928FB63AC4244B4D7E9910CFF2C7B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the applicable dollar amount is $65,000, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8FC0BEEE62CA4A22A278E74EDBBC2309"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the phaseout range is $20,000.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CA8FFAD151E445ABA44A10F03441758"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other returns</header><text>In the case of—</text>
 <clause id="H66C8C2E8781843B1B31A6E604FC08BC2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a head of a household (as defined in section 2(b)), the applicable dollar amount and the phaseout range shall be <fraction>¾</fraction> of the amounts applicable under subparagraph (A) (as adjusted under subsection (g)), and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD85C98A396CE4AB8A9AEB1D320C16A5F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any taxpayer who is not filing a joint return and who is not a head of a household (as so defined), the applicable dollar amount and the phaseout range shall be <fraction>½</fraction> of the amounts applicable under subparagraph (A) (as so adjusted).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H58AACDB218F744A28296131EB15261A5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible individual</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H58804827EE284634940F32D2F4DDF7F1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>eligible individual</term> means any individual if such individual has attained the age of 18 as of the close of the taxable year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H03DF0D3E2D30460DADD9E6C5472AEB55"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Dependents and full-time students not eligible</header><text>The term <term>eligible individual</term> shall not include—</text> <subparagraph id="HB676F8234D384FC095DAB7724481512B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any individual with respect to whom a deduction under section 151 is allowed to another taxpayer for a taxable year beginning in the calendar year in which such individual’s taxable year begins, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0FDC9F8321D24538A46EA28A14A1AF94"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any individual who is a student (as defined in section 152(f)(2)).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8188B3F28B6D478489ED25DA22FF8576"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Qualified retirement savings contributions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text>
 <paragraph id="H97C6F0D05FD4463F9C5A71FA9CAEEBD3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>qualified retirement savings contributions</term> means, with respect to any taxable year, the sum of—</text> <subparagraph id="HDDF4B0A239144848B7F14CB1BABB177C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amount of the qualified retirement contributions (as defined in section 219(e)) made by the eligible individual,</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7A5C376809F493E8CBC734C15CD4553"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount of—</text> <clause id="HB4A30952800847CF9D1DA307C54DA024"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any elective deferrals (as defined in section 402(g)(3)) of such individual, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4033402477CB431BBACE6FF51AE29DE7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any elective deferral of compensation by such individual under an eligible deferred compensation plan (as defined in section 457(b)) of an eligible employer described in section 457(e)(1)(A), and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80EC7228F4864B8F8E792D0A9FB2A5A0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the amount of voluntary employee contributions by such individual to any qualified retirement plan (as defined in section 4974(c)).</text>
								</subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">Such term shall not include any amount attributable to a payment under subsection (a).</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD82C2DF6E894033834F27A9F8901191"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reduction for certain distributions</header>
 <subparagraph id="H907666F008F2437CB301AF546E4843B9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The qualified retirement savings contributions determined under paragraph (1) for a taxable year shall be reduced (but not below zero) by the aggregate distributions received by the individual during the testing period from any entity of a type to which contributions under paragraph (1) may be made.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB5E40BDFFD146B2A440E80426F87551"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Testing period</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the testing period, with respect to a taxable year, is the period which includes—</text>
 <clause id="H152CB11B5AEE4E4AA733EBA08356F500"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such taxable year,</text> </clause><clause id="H57C185204DE64771B39A356357B24168"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the 2 preceding taxable years, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6EF9BD750CE642B6AF046E39BEB38CBF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the period after such taxable year and before the due date (including extensions) for filing the return of tax for such taxable year.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7004FAED29FD4627B683922C6CBFDB15"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Excepted distributions</header><text>There shall not be taken into account under subparagraph (A)—</text> <clause id="H287C09BBD35943C4A41827C5A149C135"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any distribution referred to in section 72(p), 401(k)(8), 401(m)(6), 402(g)(2), 404(k), or 408(d)(4),</text>
 </clause><clause id="H442023A237C04DA692833835D572AE4E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any distribution to which section 408(d)(3) or 408A(d)(3) applies, and</text> </clause><clause id="H41894A0767F34E78BAEC60672A6B2938"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any portion of a distribution if such portion is transferred or paid in a rollover contribution (as defined in section 402(c), 403(a)(4), 403(b)(8), 408A(e), or 457(e)(16)) to an account or plan to which qualified retirement contributions can be made.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C0BCE6DF91443E0821A90D9BA602484"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Treatment of distributions received by spouse of individual</header><text>For purposes of determining distributions received by an individual under subparagraph (A) for any taxable year, any distribution received by the spouse of such individual shall be treated as received by such individual if such individual and spouse file a joint return for such taxable year and for the taxable year during which the spouse receives the distribution.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCF44E74D02CB4C10AD539F6D66A90345"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Applicable retirement savings vehicle</header>
 <paragraph id="H88B2EE8BD8CD4B588FB1A4B302DD7D6B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>applicable retirement savings vehicle</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H1A967A93AD2C471AB3663FA72CBEC983"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an account or plan elected by the eligible individual under paragraph (2), or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HABE2C5BB8A304F97A5A1245294752F41"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if no such election is made, a retirement bond purchased by the Secretary for the benefit of the eligible individual.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE105040C54C64A5888296B045083C39C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other retirement vehicles</header><text>An eligible individual may elect to have the amount determined under subsection (a) contributed to an account or plan which—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3718BB45B3F340D086CD92EF06D6329B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a Roth IRA (as defined in section 408A), or a designated Roth account (within the meaning of section 402A) of an applicable retirement plan (as defined in section 402A(e)(1)),</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF65D9CC20DA4F52946B221AB34CCE7F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is for the benefit of the eligible individual,</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF558CD2853B045C99CEE6F882878AF50"><enum>(C)</enum><text>accepts contributions made under this section, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1083A097B7994D279B2DFEF28F05E06F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is designated by such individual (in such form and manner as the Secretary may provide) on the return of tax for the taxable year.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD361AA21DB734DCE93324F06A9CCFF31"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Retirement bond</header>
 <subparagraph id="HC7A7EFB93F0F43709E59DE789E28D27C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>retirement bond</term> means a bond issued under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, which by its terms, or by regulations prescribed by the Secretary under such chapter—</text>
 <clause id="H501394596FCF4F0C9832F42A80D3616D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provides for interest to be credited at rates that take into account the expected duration of the funds invested in retirement bonds and at rates determined or adjusted in a manner and with sufficient frequency to provide substantial protection from inflation,</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB571184D19D3415EA670D4049AA7ACF8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is not transferable, and</text> </clause><clause id="H7D786B905B974B198E898FCD5E4B6CBE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is designed for investment for retirement.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H700A69EE899E474E91263A8C7285077D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Roth IRA rules applicable</header><text>The provisions of this title applicable to a Roth IRA, including provisions relating to contributions, holding and distributions, shall apply to a retirement bond, except as determined by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A72848E751D4742A2EFC92C38571820"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary may issue such regulations as are necessary to carry out the purposes of this section, including—</text>
 <clause id="H15235B1860124437A1CE4F3D339531F9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>establishment of procedures to communicate to individuals the importance of investment diversification and the transfer option described in clause (ii),</text>
 </clause><clause id="H103804C7D02144CE8DFF9DE69D801E61"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>simplified procedures under which holders of retirement bonds may periodically choose to have the bonds or their proceeds transferred to available Roth IRAs, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAEFDF15179004F66A99075DF0AF840C0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>means by which individuals may elect (or be treated as electing) whether to have retirement bonds or their proceeds so transferred.</text>
									</clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">Any such transfer shall be treated as a rollover contribution for purposes of section 408(d)(3)
			 (other than subparagraph (B) thereof).</continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H20851EB5929F4208987AE94206B79256"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Other definitions and special rules</header>
 <paragraph id="HC6915D11520A452791FA083E981CEF74"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Modified adjusted gross income</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>modified adjusted gross income</term> means adjusted gross income—</text> <subparagraph id="H0163D176B1BF4BB3800E25374B1D6B0F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determined without regard to sections 911, 931, and 933, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0801892C19548258BB3F4AE8678DB3B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>determined without regard to any exclusion or deduction allowed for any qualified retirement savings contribution made during the taxable year.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3407FE7A8FB7406B859219EC19FE9798"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of contributions</header><text>In the case of any contribution under subsection (a)(2)—</text> <subparagraph id="HF0399EDF4B3D4D38A6ACB25BC168B842"><enum>(A)</enum><text>except as otherwise provided in this section or by the Secretary under regulations, such contribution shall be treated in the same manner as a contribution made by the individual on whose behalf such contribution was made,</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE50ADA91F3844FE3860EDAA04BEBD61B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such contribution shall not be treated as income to the taxpayer, and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F512F8B47C84385BD0E1B9982496D6C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such contribution shall not be taken into account with respect to any applicable limitation under sections 402(g)(1), 403(b), 408(a)(1), 408(b)(2)(B), 408A(c)(2), 414(v)(2), 415(c), or 457(b)(2).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H73A67772F2C842E6A347A551C2C55740"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Treatment of qualified plans, etc</header><text>A plan or arrangement to which a contribution is made under this section shall not be treated as violating any requirement under section 401, 403, 408, or 457 solely by reason of accepting such contribution.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA2DA027700F74C01927D1112F6B3E07A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Erroneous credits</header><text>If any contribution is erroneously paid under subsection (a)(2), the amount of such erroneous payment shall be treated as an underpayment of tax.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H260EDAC35ED4480E844BD8F36758DAE5"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Inflation adjustments</header>
 <paragraph id="HE504B02C463441218316ABB5249F8C33"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any taxable year beginning in a calendar year after 2018, each of the dollar amounts in subsections (a)(2) and (b)(3)(A)(i) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H600AA62E6C6C4068A81D6C675945D33C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such dollar amount, multiplied by</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CACF0119A75492FAD3E1FDDF895CB01"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for the calendar year in which the taxable year begins, determined by substituting <quote>calendar year 2017</quote> for <quote>calendar year 1992</quote> in subparagraph (B) thereof.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF62704AB7EDD49E1813F880BEC253F05"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rounding</header><text>Any increase determined under paragraph (1) shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of—</text> <subparagraph id="H7E7E3114DE35483B8D45B98B99E9CEBB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$100 in the case of an adjustment of the amount in subsection (a)(2), and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A28599451214D05A1A08DDD84BB805D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$1,000 in the case of an adjustment of the amount in subsection (b)(3)(A)(i).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="HE6C9AD3ADBA3486EAF6DED73A8068823"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Promotion and guidance</header> <paragraph id="H3D5699ED5410425EB441EE3E254C6F1E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Promotion</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary’s delegate) shall educate taxpayers on the benefits provided under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6433">section 6433</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1851545F3D6B4BDEB7BEF9CE5A8D1F93"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>Not later than December 31, 2017, the Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary’s delegate) shall issue guidance on the implementation and administration of the amendments made by this section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCAB348F9AD67438E90F7F1C8800ECBDE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Payment authority</header><text>Section 1324(b)(2) of title 31, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>or 6431</quote> and inserting <quote>6431, or 6433</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HC0A10307CAC745F099289EA9E214D3C8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Deficiencies</header><text>Section 6211(b)(4) is amended by striking <quote>and 6431</quote> and inserting <quote>6431, and 6433</quote>.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H450D38AE0CCE4FD2A90E58CD17B75991"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="H748A8CEA205E467684DA8F1B528D9841"><enum>(1)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/25B">Section 25B</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking subsections (a) through (f) and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H71344915BBF74EDFA66BBEDE711538D9" style="OLC">
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For payment of credit related to qualified retirement savings contributions, see section 6433.</text><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H35D7FD0624E7413EA40C87BABAF9BEA9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The table of sections for subchapter B of chapter 65 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBC0D14E66A6849778BEEE5457C761DC3" style="OLC">
						<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
							<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 6433. Matching payments for elective deferral and IRA contributions by certain individuals.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H76474E0492274B9785FEFD63E3DCA11C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2017.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H45F4E87ABC8044458770D4037125F452"><enum>12.</enum><header>Authority to require reporting</header> <subsection id="HB78E69382E384DB6922E17F177C3526D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reporting under Internal Revenue Code</header><text>Subsection (a) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6058">section 6058</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end thereof the following: <quote>The Secretary may by regulation require the inclusion in such annual return of such information as may be necessary or appropriate to determine the effects of the alternative methods of satisfying applicable nondiscrimination requirements, which are described in subsections (k)(13), (k)(14), (m)(11), and (m)(12) of section 401, on the contribution levels of employees who are not highly compensated employees (as defined in section 414(q)).</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H67A5294F72A74D589C56FAD049285212"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reporting under employee retirement income security act of 1974</header><text>Section 104(a)(2)(A) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1042">29 U.S.C. 1042(a)(2)</external-xref>), as amended by section 3(c), is further amended by inserting before the period at the end thereof the following: <quote>, except that in the case of such a deferral-only arrangement contained in a pension plan with at least 100 participants, the Secretary may require such reporting as is necessary or appropriate with respect to service providers, investment options, and fees, but not in excess of any reporting applicable to other arrangements.</quote>.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


