<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H09B609CFF0D8441D922D8740C3AA62C4" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4642 IH: Veterans Improved Access and Care Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4642</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171214">December 14, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000470">Mr. Tipton</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Veterans Access, Choice, and Accountability Act of 2014 to include in the Veterans
			 Choice Program all veterans enrolled in the patient enrollment system of
			 the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H7E349D1AC7AC4CB3B86F2E689804E7A3" style="OLC">
 <section id="HBE36D99B91C647939E9F5E6C396709E4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Improved Access and Care Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H0C7F07C2B7C248AB8E70B67B35BDFCA3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Expansion of Veterans Choice Program to include all enrolled veterans</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 101 of the Veterans Access, Choice, and Accountability Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/146">Public Law 113–146</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/1701">38 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE3D45A40197A4FAFA16E8BFD0142E5E9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by amending paragraph (2) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H818A303184FB47C895CE5A917DFF1990" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HA8889CB80E5B498885B1EE866B5BC932"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the veteran elects to receive hospital care or medical services under this section.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H24E6957D444F4588B4694C9AB12C1304"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H5D54EE4D3DAD467788202AAE5DB18D6D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>In the case of an eligible veteran described in subsection (b)(2)(A), the Secretary shall, at the election of the eligible veteran</quote> and inserting <quote>The Secretary shall, at the election of an eligible veteran</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2ACE7AA0688D4CD7951128FFE107AE1A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text> <clause id="HBE719FEA52EA4D9BAB4A1E81020D4C31"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>provide the veteran</quote> and inserting <quote>provide the eligible veteran</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD815161068E04784ACC95B12857F0D18"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>described in such subsection</quote> and inserting <quote>of the Veterans Health Administration</quote>;</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE8BA05742F14AA0873F5997BB3B16DF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (g), by striking paragraph (3); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB0C0BED14355401AB57B6E3680FDE519"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (q)(2)(A), by striking <quote>, disaggregated by</quote> and all that follows through <quote>subsection (b)(2)(D)</quote>.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H90A7C77384534B458D5462973FADB3E0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Pilot program on expediting the Department of Veterans Affairs process for onboarding new medical providers</header> <subsection id="HB58CBBCEFC6C4EB5B04289F6F0C12C5D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Pilot program authorized</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall carry out a pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of expediting the process of the Veterans Health Administration for onboarding new medical providers. Under the pilot program, the Secretary shall seek to reduce the length of time it takes to onboard medical providers to no more than 60 days.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H05BC3646F6C04620831CC6DC67226586"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Locations</header><text>The Secretary shall select medical facilities at which to carry out the pilot program. In selecting such facilities, the Secretary shall give priority to medical facilities facing hiring shortages of licensed independent medical providers.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA4EF102212DB4A289475F577773FE231"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Onboarding process defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>onboarding process</term> means the process of bringing on a medical provider applicant after the medical provider is offered a tentative position, including certification of credentialing, background investigation, assessment of health status, and such other actions are necessary for starting employment.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H5AC816E1D9C547E994A579977337E70A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Strategy to reduce duration of hiring process of Department of Veterans Affairs for licensed
 professional medical providers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to Congress a strategy to reduce the duration of the hiring process of the Department of Veterans Affairs for licensed professional medical providers by half. Such strategy shall describe how the overall certification of credentials process for licensed professional medical providers can be expedited.</text>
		</section><section id="HB5D20CA59B604CE382880439BD5D67B4"><enum>5.</enum><header>Improving accountability within Veterans Health Administration by requiring reporting of major
			 adverse actions taken to national practitioner data bank and State
 licensing boards</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7461 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H02AB6380FFB941F4B9A7FB3398DD525A" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H90298049AF304DA38166DDAFCCB464E2"><enum>(f)</enum><text>Whenever the Under Secretary for Health (or an official designated by the Under Secretary) brings charges based on conduct or performance against a section 7401(1) employee and as a result of those charges a major adverse action is taken against the employee, the Under Secretary shall, not later than 30 days after the date on which such major adverse action is carried out, transmit to the National Practitioner Data Bank and the applicable State licensing board the name of the employee, a description of the major adverse action, and a description of the reason for the major adverse action.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


