<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H45D5E50AFEF34A3894BD4AE0225F062E" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2914 IH: United States-Israel Anti-Tunnel Defense Cooperation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2914</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170615">June 15, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000625">Mr. Donovan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize assistance for anti-tunnel defense capabilities for Israel.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HDCED8416F23C4BE1AA56DFF445BC54AD" style="OLC">
 <section id="H7F9585A913C5420AB9CA120F351151F4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>United States-Israel Anti-Tunnel Defense Cooperation Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HFDBE243A4A6B45479D6A52E1A1BEE82A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HD35916014A15499D84596AD5C327DF53"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Hamas, Hizballah, and the Palestinian Islamic Jihad are United States-designated foreign terrorist organizations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD2CB36C1696844CE8ADA4F96E2D5123E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Designated Palestinian terrorist organizations have killed hundreds of Israelis and dozens of Americans in rocket attacks and suicide bombings.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB7220E8019F643FBAA5F4D535ED8739C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Hamas has used underground tunnels to Israel and Egypt to smuggle weapons, money, and supplies into Gaza and to send members of Hamas out of Gaza for training and to bring trainers into Gaza to teach Hamas how to manufacture rockets and improve construction of tunnels.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDB2325B93A484CA1AA6CCC73AB5A259C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Tunnels in Gaza have also been used as underground rocket launching sites, weapons caches, bunkers, transportation networks, and command and control centers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF3B52EAECCCC47A2B301AF9489D45B96"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In 2006, Hamas kidnapped Israeli soldier Gilad Shalit through a tunnel and held him for five years.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE5ADA8C3752D4567A651598F3C759C9D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Israel Defense Forces discovered and destroyed 32 tunnels during the conflict with Hamas in the summer of 2014, 14 of which crossed into Israel.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBEFCFD13376C447F829C0F7A1162CC92"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Since 2014, Hamas has spent considerable resources to rebuild its tunnel network.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4164183871B44983BA0871E50F6EBE2B"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Hamas intentionally uses civilians as human shields by placing its underground tunnel network in densely populated areas and schools, hospitals, and mosques.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9125B4EA8CC74A34BCBEC24CA52943FA"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Hizballah has used underground tunnels in southern Lebanon to move Hizballah fighters and to launch attacks.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H22EB550B6C3E4C5AB8F8B10633C73282"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The Palestinian Islamic Jihad has also dug tunnels from Gaza that penetrate Israel.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H53013090CE8B4A29A2266678A8931D31"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Israel has a right to defend itself from the violence of Palestinian terrorist groups, including the violence that is facilitated through terrorist tunnel networks.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDDBB6952AA9145339BE833CB4EC79159"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The United States is working cooperatively with the Government of Israel to develop technologies to detect and destroy tunnels penetrating the territory of Israel.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H13810FEE3A0B4ED7A0E1CAD43B60B417"><enum>(13)</enum><text>This joint United States-Israel cooperation will not only benefit Israel, but will also help the United States and allies across the globe that face similar challenges from subterranean tunnels.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H1092664CE893449486ADC9FFD4299E1F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Authorization of assistance for anti-tunnel defense capabilities for Israel</header>
 <subsection id="HD64987A0FA33496E8277EE827EFD89EA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Defense, upon request of the Ministry of Defense of Israel and in consultation with the Secretary of State and the Director of National Intelligence, is authorized to carry out research, development, test, and evaluation, on a joint basis with Israel, to establish anti-tunnel capabilities to detect, map, and neutralize underground tunnels that threaten the United States or Israel.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H18971E83AF6F475B962879E52B05CA71"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the President to carry out this section $47,500,000 for fiscal year 2018.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


