<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H63A03B4F927A43AAB26A0D5B935D121C" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1298 IH: CT Colonography Screening for Colorectal Cancer Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1298</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170301">March 1, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000815">Mr. Wenstrup</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to cover screening computed tomography colonography
			 as a colorectal cancer screening test under the Medicare program.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H81D933C8AC184FAEAD43E35D5566B278" style="OLC">
 <section id="H947917CD5CA349E982FE6C888C659C94" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>CT Colonography Screening for Colorectal Cancer Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H46595CF35DFB4E98A082A891EA6BF12A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Coverage of computed tomography colonography screening as a colorectal cancer screening test under Medicare</header> <subsection id="H54E145088426490D97608F95E17AE15A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1861(pp)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(pp)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H079F2941236049BC940A3A2A6D3FC8D5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (D) as subparagraph (E); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H74A62F629A644A7EA57183066F685633"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (C) the following new subparagraph:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H4E5BD8FDEFE24F6C9BC305C6EAB2AA18" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H19C36A46DFD5456397FC8C19E73664D5" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Screening computed tomography co­lo­nog­ra­phy.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4A0A821DB73440E9B73CA12E542DBB8D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Frequency limits and payment</header><text>Section 1834(d) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(d)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H4413980B9A484A26BFD05751BBD86538" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="H3862E21171C844FE9A0AFDE525C0013F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Screening computed tomography colonography</header>
 <subparagraph id="H8C6B8368A24B42C8A5F481998C791E18"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Fee schedule</header><text>With respect to a colorectal cancer screening test consisting of screening computed tomography colonography, subject to subparagraph (B), payment under section 1848 shall be consistent with payment under such section for similar or related services.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF19C780DEB3E4E9CBFCABC873BC1174E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Payment limit</header><text>In the case of screening computed tomography colonography, payment under this part shall not exceed such amount as the Secretary specifies, based upon rates recognized for diagnostic computed tomography colonography.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE5034085F6C4DFFA864866753E29E6B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Facility payment limit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, in the case of an individual who receives screening computed tomography colonography—</text>
 <clause id="H46A6916FCE864C758C94D58BC78A9BA2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in computing the amount of any applicable coinsurance, the computation of such coinsurance shall be based upon the fee schedule under which payment is made for the services; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4C76DA96F3FF4BAA82003201BE146880"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount of such coinsurance shall not exceed 25 percent of the payment amount under the fee schedule described in subparagraph (A).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8DBF294A53F40F4B873311934C0AAC0"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Frequency limit</header><text>No payment may be made under this part for a colorectal cancer screening test consisting of a screening computed tomography colonography—</text>
 <clause id="H529BFADD70D04C4D8C3F9957206C061D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>if the individual is under 50 years of age; or</text> </clause><clause id="HBE917AFBC261497CA5FF215A2EE3AFEE"><enum>(ii)</enum> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H8A2D39732D194431BF295C886E6F09AE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the case of individuals at high risk for colorectal cancer, if the procedure is performed within the 23 months after a previous screening computed tomography colonography or a previous screening colonoscopy; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H8BB1D364962247AE9E2526814D448799" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the case of an individual who is not at high risk for colorectal cancer, if the procedure is performed within the 119 months after a previous screening co­lo­nos­co­py or within the 59 months after a previous screening flexible sigmoidoscopy or a previous screening computed tomography colonography.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="HB64EF3592019494FA28097535D2E0D8C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming frequency limits for other colorectal cancer screening tests</header>
 <paragraph id="H105ABB16B5994D69A40ACEC8BB118864"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Screening flexible sigmoidoscopy</header><text>Paragraph (2)(E)(ii) of section 1834(d) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(d)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>or screening computed tomography co­lo­nog­ra­phy</quote> after <quote>previous screening flexible sig­moi­dos­co­py</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA1595110F8B244D18989F22B26A11195"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Screening colonoscopy</header><text>Paragraph (3)(E) of such section is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H09941716E9924F0E88B94761CE0E8D1A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or screening computed tomography colonography</quote> after <quote>23 months after a previous screening colonoscopy</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD95C62CA9D334A689871F9351B8A2012"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or screening computed tomography colonography</quote> after <quote>screening flexible sigmoidoscopy</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD649514D95484FD5BCAB8BC2B524AE17"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to items and services furnished on or after January 1, 2018.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H8E4F386911B042769500C91D310DD2CE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Exemption of screening computed tomography colonography from special rule on payment for imaging
			 services</header>
 <subsection id="HDA87FB2C928E4B2288AC609841161548"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1848(b)(4)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-4">42 U.S.C. 1395w–4(b)(4)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>and screening computed tomography colonography</quote> after <quote>diagnostic and screening mammography</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB40EAFC8F56249318267E5390DEFE343"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply to items and services furnished on or after January 1, 2018.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HEA1B4D9D13D84B1A8097FD72B8C6BC78"><enum>4.</enum><header>Reports on the status of covering computed tomography colonography as a colorectal cancer screening
			 test under Medicare</header>
 <subsection id="HF3E03E6926C1453DA609C11D376C42F4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Preliminary report</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit a preliminary report to Congress on the status of coverage of computed tomography colonography as a colorectal cancer screening test under the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act, including the extent to which such coverage as required by the amendments made by sections 2 and 3 has been implemented.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6D508547EDDE44218321902B7E03A586"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not later than September 30 of each fiscal year during the 5-year period beginning with fiscal year 2019, the Secretary shall submit to the Congress, a status report on the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HC333E9FA2C4848BCB70FA4B0B58A5498"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The impact of screening computed tomography colonography on the change in colorectal cancer screening compliance of Medicare beneficiaries.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H777D5B50801D44198F3A50A02F647AA0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The various utilization rates with respect to Medicare beneficiaries for each available colorectal cancer screening option before and after the availability of and coverage of screening computed tomography colonography under the Medicare program pursuant to the enactment of this Act, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6FBB0201B952417180918DA4F4E406C3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by initial CRC screening performed with respect to a Medicare beneficiary per year, including the age of the beneficiary when the initial screening was performed; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFD6B4A195C7444B9E118C811F0E9C7C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by follow-on screening performed, whereby the analysis demonstrates to what extent screening computed tomography co­lo­nog­ra­phy was used as a substitute for a previous screening procedure.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H14FA2ECAB6494EAEBDC9218D943F6F3E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Access to screening computed tomography colonography by Medicare beneficiaries, especially in rural areas or underserved populations, before and after the date of implementation of coverage of such screening benefit under the Medicare program pursuant to the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H251886B72D2B4CEA846253806D2E4A66"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Recommendations for such legislation and administrative action as the Secretary determines appropriate to implement this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


