<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCCF55844BE9841AFA8A65249FBCF480F" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2866 : Reducing Unnecessary Barriers for Relative Foster Parents Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form display="yes">
		<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code>
		<congress>115th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2866</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date date="20170621">June 21, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To review and improve licensing standards for placement in a relative foster family home.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H7D01F35A2E424698AA4E84E328C519CE" style="OLC">
 <section id="H32A379C3B51E4103BAA30277C8C5ACD4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reducing Unnecessary Barriers for Relative Foster Parents Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2BAE37A4AE8346F389451BCF70C048D3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reviewing and improving licensing standards for placement in a relative foster family home</header> <subsection id="HA6FE275B02EF44CF8B3948FCC0C0D06A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Identification of reputable model licensing standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than October 1, 2018, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall identify reputable model licensing standards with respect to the licensing of foster family homes (as defined in section 472(c)(1) of the Social Security Act).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H50DA6B69C54E436A83CA01F2975DC08F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State plan requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 422(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/622">42 U.S.C. 622(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H1206E19F93874C3B834A0E9E930ED714"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (18), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3B422D02BBFF413D95FA6C144818686E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (19), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H685A59AD58934A47A107FBD7CE9C9B4B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9B5E9AB951604B20AF2E0B02346E1E44" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H0A52274609F446128E7E2038A9E4BA01"><enum>(20)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide that, not later than April 1, 2019, the State shall submit to the Secretary information addressing—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA03DC3ECA2384547AF58289591C8893A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the State licensing standards are in accord with model standards identified by the Secretary, and if not, the reason for the specific deviation and a description as to why having a standard that is reasonably in accord with the corresponding national model standards is not appropriate for the State;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF6F4B4716EA4E0D9AEF538DFC94D72A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the State has elected to waive standards established in 471(a)(10)(A) for relative foster family homes (pursuant to waiver authority provided by 471(a)(10)(D)), a description of which standards the State most commonly waives, and if the State has not elected to waive the standards, the reason for not waiving these standards;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34EFBC320B1E4A81B6E6AED51573F727"><enum>(C)</enum><text>if the State has elected to waive standards specified in subparagraph (B), how caseworkers are trained to use the waiver authority and whether the State has developed a process or provided tools to assist caseworkers in waiving nonsafety standards per the authority provided in 471(a)(10)(D) to quickly place children with relatives; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8810D3DDA344EAF96FF09C8902C4E25"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a description of the steps the State is taking to improve caseworker training or the process, if any.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB85F0CA3B47B4D14A4DE09108CD216C3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Effective date</header>
 <subsection id="H0DC5A262A398481D847927BFE4F1C107"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subsection (b), the amendments made by this Act shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDFED29E4FC7C4339A8461A48FE271D8D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transition rule</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3B004896CB644429A049685C5CC26E0B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a State plan under part E of title IV of the Social Security Act which the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines requires State legislation (other than legislation appropriating funds) in order for the plan to meet the additional requirements imposed by the amendments made by this Act, the State plan shall not be regarded as failing to comply with the requirements of such part solely on the basis of the failure of the plan to meet such additional requirements before the first day of the first calendar quarter beginning after the close of the first regular session of the State legislature that begins after the date of enactment of this Act. For purposes of the previous sentence, in the case of a State that has a 2-year legislative session, each year of the session shall be deemed to be a separate regular session of the State legislature.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE3177824B07549BF9D42CE8A01578E30"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application to programs operated by Indian tribal organizations</header><text>In the case of an Indian tribe, tribal organization, or tribal consortium which the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines requires time to take action necessary to comply with the additional requirements imposed by the amendments made by this Act (whether the tribe, organization, or tribal consortium has a plan under section 479B of the Social Security Act or a cooperative agreement or contract entered into with a State), the Secretary shall provide the tribe, organization, or tribal consortium with such additional time as the Secretary determines is necessary for the tribe, organization, or tribal consortium to take the action to comply with the additional requirements before being regarded as failing to comply with the requirements.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
	<attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20170620">Passed the House of Representatives June 20, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill>


