<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H620BF0B2569E4FAD94FA5449CC2D7703" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3459 IH: VA Staffing and Vacancies Transparency Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3459</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170727">July 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001304">Mr. Brown of Maryland</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to make certain improvements in the transparency of the
			 personnel vacancies and staffing levels of the Department of Veterans
			 Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H2A474C3990264679B04FF7AE33D6E81D" style="OLC">
 <section id="H119D499644604FDA94FEF1CC26F5B0E5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>VA Staffing and Vacancies Transparency Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H77D45AD1F8B74776A62761EFD626BB15"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress regarding Department of Veterans Affairs staffing levels</header> <subsection id="HC5F922971F0A4AF2B3DCF9A30B544EE1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text>
 <paragraph id="H0DBB7C55F3904F7D980B7784416B711F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Department of Veterans Affairs needs to fill at least 45,000 positions.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD1C2478DF44A49909C322180DCC04BA2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Prolonged personnel vacancies in the Department result in staffing shortages that cause veterans to receive delayed benefits and services.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8C978D2604974217A7D72A5DC381B9C5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the Department should make the resolution of staffing shortages a top priority.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H0CD448BEE2D6424782A43DC2727023C1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs personnel transparency</header>
			<subsection id="H5B6EF2135F064206A193AB7E19DB9EF8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Publication of staffing and vacancies</header>
 <paragraph id="H199CF0FFF0A542038B4FE1AADCDD43C4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Website required</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall make publicly available on an internet website of the Department of Veterans Affairs the following information, which shall be displayed by departmental component or, in the case of information relating to Veterans Health Administration positions, by medical facility:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H824BC01A0F3B499C871B514AF44E05E6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of personnel encumbering positions.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC3A38955CF3476989C5912EB50D7375"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The number of accessions and de-accessions of personnel during the month preceding the date of the publication of the information.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF23EB01CAC374CE98E1FB11A7BCFB26D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The number of vacancies, by occupation.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61E01B3DE58A4A20B86FE32028BFD622"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The number of active job postings that have been filled during the 30-day period ending on the date of publication of the information, including the length of time for which each position was posted prior to being filled.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA20080E6438F4DDBA0A330117EE46E8A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Update of information</header><text>The Secretary shall update the information on the website required under paragraph (1) on a monthly basis.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDE63EE90F4054D0EA2044FE7584504AA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Treatment of contractor positions</header><text>Any Department of Veterans Affairs position that is filled through a contractor employee may not be treated as a Department position for purposes of the information required to be published under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE08CD47F504B4E619FB7CF2C370B8227"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Inspector General review</header><text>On a semi-annual basis, the Inspector General of the Department shall review the administration of the website required under paragraph (1) and make recommendations relating to the improvement of such administration.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA2FC6DC8585B48CC8C791044AFBB42BA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to Congress an annual report on the steps the Department is taking to achieve full staffing capacity. Each such report shall include the amount of additional funds necessary to enable the Department to reach full staffing capacity.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


