<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB62E29F7E5724B909D0BCB4783A117B4" key="H" public-private="public">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3141 IH: Taxpayer Transparency Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3141</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20170629">June 29, 2017</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000576">Mr. Long</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="F000460">Mr. Farenthold</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To require a Federal agency to include language in certain educational and advertising materials indicating that such materials are produced and disseminated at taxpayer expense, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form> 
<legis-body id="HCECD4FC0E9774E3FBE90839523CB616B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H41A09BE0AFEE4F0688256BA90E7264DF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Taxpayer Transparency Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H74926975289E441C9DFE708CAAE5E45C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requirements for printed materials and advertisements by Federal agencies</header> <subsection id="H7CEEDD29A7D74CAFB92FF528EBD924E9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement To identify funding source for communication funded by Federal agency</header><text>Each communication funded by a Federal agency that is an advertisement, or that provides information about any Federal Government program, benefit, or service, shall clearly state—</text> 
<paragraph id="H575219081E9B42EA8C3ED9E7B10E7676"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the case of a printed communication, including mass mailings, signs, and billboards, that the communication is printed or published at taxpayer expense; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H00581368CCA3448FA550C367D7E01190"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of a communication transmitted through radio, television, the internet, or any means other than the means referred to in paragraph (1), that the communication is produced or disseminated at taxpayer expense.</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H65EBFE33A054479BA721C0EEC811A786"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional requirements</header> 
<paragraph id="H5FC96C00E21348DF803837B5D9F6D725"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Printed communication</header><text>Any printed communication described in subsection (a)(1) shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H9EF5008C4218457EA4E336B44868459D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be of sufficient type size to be clearly readable by the recipient of the communication;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H77E433C5A884423884D667D6A52C9A13"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to the extent feasible, be contained in a printed box set apart from the other contents of the communication; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3EB614F2002C40DB8759F6051244E80E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to the extent feasible, be printed with a reasonable degree of color contrast between the background and the printed statement.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE720A31A9D1B4762B782A5A7EC4CDB59"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Radio, television, and internet communication</header> 
<subparagraph id="H8DDFA3CEDCEC452B991CBD012024D643"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Audio communication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any audio communication described in subsection (a)(2) shall include an audio statement that communicates the information required under that subsection in a clearly spoken manner.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H224358C1183845E0921C8B954693DF6E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Video communication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any video communication described in subsection (a)(2) shall include a statement with the information referred to under that subsection—</text> 
<clause id="H685D0913116D488998A6AA3CE8AA7A04"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that is conveyed in a clearly spoken manner;</text> </clause> <clause id="HFE89029D1FE04B9B8389056C9CF9412D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that is conveyed by a voice-over or screen view of the person making the statement; and</text> </clause>
<clause id="H59CEC402D28948238F0E41F070B653EA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to the extent feasible, that also appears in writing at the end of the communication in a clearly readable manner with a reasonable degree of color contrast between the background and the printed statement, for a period of at least 4 seconds.</text> </clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H97909476F98045AB8BB881AB5F9DDA13"><enum>(C)</enum><header>E-mail communication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any e-mail communication described in subsection (a)(2) shall include the information required under that subsection, displayed in a manner that—</text> 
<clause id="H7B3FD2D7F9B64FDE97B641FF7C38AED7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is of sufficient type size to be clearly readable by the recipient of the communication;</text> </clause> <clause id="H6F52120F503C4D96B1ECB8407D156132"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is set apart from the other contents of the communication; and</text> </clause>
<clause id="H109D937BFB0D4D6B971988C2ED90CD32"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>includes a reasonable degree of color contrast between the background and the printed statement.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H59B556701FC54784892A5A93C7BFBADB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Identification of other funding source for certain communications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a communication funded entirely by user fees, by any other source that does not include Federal funds, or by a combination of such fees or other source, a Federal agency may apply the requirements of subsections (a) and (b) by substituting <quote>by the United States Government</quote> for <quote>at taxpayer expense</quote>.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H7F8B39568FE94DE98766137F5EBAE1E9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H3EB529046DFF4467927EF27CA99B0F37"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal agency</header><text>The term <quote>Federal agency</quote> has the meaning given the term <quote>Executive agency</quote> in section 133 of title 41, United States Code.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H77B52070A4244A6DA25E50DD363A2C3D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Mass mailing</header><text>The term <quote>mass mailing</quote>—</text> <subparagraph id="H6B103C349C53470B9469050F0E2253CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any mailing or distribution of 499 or more newsletters, pamphlets, or other printed matter with substantially identical content, whether such matter is deposited singly or in bulk, or at the same time or different times; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H283E5EF4618644D592BF6D7685F19CC1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include any mailing—</text> <clause id="HEDEEC097344C4A17A4B2804543104890"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in direct response to a communication from a person to whom the matter is mailed; or</text> </clause>
<clause id="HE430B13A33BC40BB8633DDE1FD2A620D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>of a news release to the communications media.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA120E8A97DAA4C3E809FA904EA05885F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Source of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The funds used by a Federal agency to carry out this Act shall be derived from amounts made available to the agency for advertising, or for providing information about any Federal Government program, benefit, or service.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="HD9F5B0208ED9457899A48865B7AE1749"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall apply only to communications printed or otherwise produced after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text> </subsection></section> <section id="H3E7CF1C1C62A4B3D93512B8A10947B9F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Guidance for implementation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall develop and issue guidance on implementing the requirements of this Act.</text> </section>
<section id="H8D0767C0115B41739158BA499C71850D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Judicial review and enforceability</header> 
<subsection id="H2D8F0A78A6804740B1F0D68C628F9A45"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Judicial review</header><text>There shall be no judicial review of compliance or noncompliance with any provision of this Act.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H9DB7A80CBA514E7AA15F2B34D486E34A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforceability</header><text>No provision of this Act shall be construed to create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable by any administrative or judicial action.</text> </subsection></section>
</legis-body>
</bill> 


