<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC3C54DC7F10C4C06B7B1CA60EA3CFE36" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2083 IH: Endangered Salmon and Fisheries Predation Prevention Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2083</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170408">April 8, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001056">Ms. Herrera Beutler</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S001180">Mr. Schrader</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 to reduce predation on endangered Columbia River
			 salmon and other nonlisted species, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H0ECEFC3065724215BA67A0F345DAB0CA" style="OLC">
 <section id="H5D933788359142928AFF5EDACF57E89F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Endangered Salmon and Fisheries Predation Prevention Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H1947DF0031F04208B200EE6117CD16B7" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H93064800DFD74DAB81FAFD1544620864"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are 13 groups of salmon and steelhead that are listed as threatened species or endangered species under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 that migrate through the lower Columbia River. All lower Columbia River tributaries contain listed species including Chinook, Chum and Coho salmon as well as winter-run steelhead.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H06CF3613B9A34E349E6C47E8F37FA1BE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The people of the Northwest United States are united in their desire to restore healthy salmon and steelhead runs because they are integral to the region's culture and economy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4938D073B408477EBB8EDDD12A49F105"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Columbia River treaty Tribes retain important rights with respect to salmon and steelhead.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAE06E349D925466DA9DF8C8C073D47D8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Federal, State, and Tribal governments have spent billions of dollars to assist the recovery of Columbia River basin salmon and steelhead populations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFB625C9F2DA840F2908780ADD8291253"><enum>(5)</enum><text>One of the factors negatively impacting salmonid populations is increased predation by marine mammals, including California sea lions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7CF4A68324274785BFF2585B2CF6E71D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The population of California sea lions has increased 10-fold over the last 3 decades, and is currently approximately 300,000 animals.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HCA7A924AAE464E6F86E67DAB8134E6E5"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Biologists estimate that in recent years as many as 3,000 California sea lions have been foraging from the lower 145 miles of the Columbia River up to Bonneville Dam during the peak spring salmonid run.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6EE0D1D2EB3A4E6EB54D208A9AC3BD08"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Historically, California sea lions, whose habitat is fundamentally salt water, did not venture very far up into the Columbia River.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE7F51ECD319A4BF28AFEA9C988CBA708"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The percentage of the spring salmonid run that has been eaten or killed by California sea lions at Bonneville Dam has increased 7-fold since 2002.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H33D360263323409BA53F768877AFEC3F"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal, State and Tribal estimates indicate that sea lions are consuming at least 20 percent of the Columbia River spring chinook run and 15 percent of Willamette River steelhead run, two salmonid species listed under the Endangered Species Act of 1973.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H548A0CFD187A48FEA1467F7FAFB49BA7"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In recent years, California sea lions have congregated with greater frequency near Willamette Falls and Bonneville Dam and have entered the fish ladders that salmon must use to return to their historic and biological spawning grounds.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7C9CA81BAE2D4DD3BF8534AD1266CFC1"><enum>(12)</enum><text>These California sea lions have not been responsive to extensive hazing methods employed to discourage this behavior.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA1CEEBE2043046AAA436A87FFDE84FC2"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The process established under the 1994 amendment to the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 to address predatory sea lion behavior negatively impacting threatened or endangered salmon runs is protracted and has not worked.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5E6BAB5C705C42879CFA291C6CE5CD7A"><enum>(14)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration has observed that—</text> <subparagraph id="H5BA061BE7EC542BF870F0C2AB36701BE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>management efforts to reduce pinniped predation of endangered and threatened salmon and steelhead in the area around Bonneville Dam has been insufficient to reduce the severity of the threat; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H51CEA5E353834152A8CAAE552FFD61BF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>efforts need to focus more on the lower river and at Willamette Falls.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H96C5D88D87254C6AB9B00B4433C60C44"><enum>(15)</enum><text>In the interest of protecting Columbia River threatened and endangered salmonids, a temporary expedited procedure is urgently needed to allow removal of the minimum number of California sea lions as is necessary to protect the passage of threatened and endangered salmonids in the Columbia River and its tributaries.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section commented="no" id="H4EE4E033750E46F888B6B493CC94F25D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of the Congress that—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HBFE2DD14081A4401B63CCDF6F59D1A3D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">preventing predation by sea lions, recovery of listed salmonid stocks, and preventing future listings of fish stocks in the Columbia River under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531</external-xref> et seq.) is a vital priority; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7C9AD42057824BB08649A6926CB88320"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Federal Government should continue to fund lethal and nonlethal removal measures for preventing such predation.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HE8871A6B843D4EDF85B1BD114D92D4EB"><enum>4.</enum><header>Taking of sea lions on the Columbia River and its tributaries to protect endangered and threatened
 species of salmon and other nonlisted fish species</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 120(f) of the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1389">16 U.S.C. 1389(f)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
			<quoted-block id="HE0C3DF8DFC8C4CDEA6586BA4D4FA6C70" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="H73F5646F105A4169A3476E6C7F2A7EE1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Temporary marine mammal removal authority on the waters of the Columbia River or its tributaries</header>
 <paragraph id="HDDF8878229444B2480DE755524B7D25D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Removal authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, the Secretary may issue a permit to an eligible entity to authorize the intentional lethal taking on the waters of the Columbia River and its tributaries of individually identifiable sea lions that are part of a population that is not categorized under this Act as depleted for the purpose of protecting species of salmon that are listed as endangered species or threatened species under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531</external-xref> et seq.) and other nonlisted fish species.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="HC670FF2060184521BFD851C63DBDB960"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Permit process</header>
 <subparagraph id="HAEDA20AC34054B84848661CF575D8CC5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity may apply to the Secretary for a permit under this subsection.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A10DF4AE6A54D318D4109C3F84214EA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Deadline for consideration of application</header><text>The Secretary shall approve or deny an application for a permit under this subsection by not later than 30 days after receiving the application.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFFF86F3688584EA9818E7B7177F1686A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Duration of permit</header><text>A permit under this subsection shall be effective for no more than one year after the date it is issued, but may be renewed by the Secretary.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H812A7C0355834BD18E3AB9AD2C57CFA6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitations</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H4E0BBA5702B3483D9F8D799C6A827925"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Limitation on permit authority</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), a permit issued under this subsection shall not authorize the lethal taking of more than 100 sea lions during the duration of the permit.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA39DB398AF544F2FB108B0BF252CDAE3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation on annual takings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The cumulative number of sea lions authorized to be taken each year under all permits in effect under this subsection shall not exceed 10 percent of the annual potential biological removal level.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4965F2AD2D894480B588FEF45F597E9A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Training in natural resources management</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Permit holders exercising lethal removal authority pursuant to this Act shall be trained in natural resource management.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H07C5A404762F464D80355465E1E646DE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Delegation of permit authority</header><text>Any eligible entity may delegate to any other eligible entity the authority to administer its permit authority under this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H09D381B0190040E6B598850452A9F934"><enum>(6)</enum><header>NEPA</header><text>Section 102(2)(C) of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4332">42 U.S.C. 4332(2)(C)</external-xref>) shall not apply with respect to this subsection and the issuance of any permit under this subsection during the 5-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H100287A7E78847F3A8D57A9C68720386"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Suspension of permitting authority</header><text>If, 5 years after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Secretary, after consulting with State and tribal fishery managers, determines that lethal removal authority is no longer necessary to protect salmonid and other fish species from sea lion predation, the Secretary may suspend the issuance of permits under this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H70D9D364310048FE9D9202E5982C6103"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Eligible entity defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <quote>eligible entity</quote> means each of the State of Washington, the State of Oregon, the State of Idaho, the Nez Perce Tribe, the Confederated Tribes of the Umatilla Indian Reservation, the Confederated Tribes of the Warm Springs Reservation of Oregon, the Confederated Tribes and Bands of the Yakama Nation, the Columbia River Inter-Tribal Fish Commission, and the Cowlitz Indian Tribe.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE785C42054534C64A778B869475645DE"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Individual pinniped exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, any pinniped located upstream of river mile 112 of the Columbia River and all tributaries that include spawning habitat of threatened or endangered salmon or steelhead is deemed to be individually identifiable.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H4D5F36DB005E445AAF4327CF354F2723"><enum>5.</enum><header>Treaty rights of federally recognized Indian Tribes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act or the amendment made by this Act shall be construed to affect or modify any treaty or other right of any federally recognized Indian Tribe.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


