<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HA36476A8E89544968DCECCB42E8A19E0" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 944 IH: Federal Election Integrity Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 944</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170207">February 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000598">Mrs. Davis of California</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to prohibit certain State election
			 administration officials from actively participating in electoral
			 campaigns.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H432640FB80574AA79837FC0378F70ECF" style="OLC">
 <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA0155ED6FB114284A4D3851788F95730" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short Title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Election Integrity Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H2A4A66DF83E744DB85E859679A237727"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4E7CDD15FA244EF9AF8B5F94A4BDCF97"><enum>(1)</enum><text>chief State election administration officials have served on political campaigns for Federal candidates whose elections those officials will supervise;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H693746413F464BA784D36B6F6057C8A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such partisan activity by the chief State election administration official, an individual charged with certifying the validity of an election, represents a fundamental conflict of interest that may prevent the official from ensuring a fair and accurate election;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5EC14844248E4EF1ACCAE51CC02E635C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>this conflict impedes the legal duty of chief State election administration officials to supervise Federal elections, undermines the integrity of Federal elections, and diminishes the people’s confidence in our electoral system by casting doubt on the results of Federal elections;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H04084CC993C344688880C326CF77E67A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Supreme Court has long recognized that Congress’ power to regulate Congressional elections under article I, section 4, clause 1 of the Constitution is both plenary and powerful; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H332231145E264CB4BCF9D0EEBC8D053C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Supreme Court and numerous appellate courts have recognized that the broad power given to Congress over Congressional elections extends to Presidential elections.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1D9D3359459F4786955042261684E94E" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on campaign activities by chief State election administration officials</header>
 <subsection id="H6C679E2E69FF44CF937FB1D54CCDCC1A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text>Title III of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30101">52 U.S.C. 30101</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by inserting after section 319 the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6AC80BD46CD14AA982ED7C618F940DFA" style="traditional">
 <section id="H966DB155D56B4633882FF0B9C88652AE"><enum>319A.</enum><header>Campaign activities by chief State election administration officials</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA4DFC1C3D9794CF8AD059C2FD5E84317"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>It shall be unlawful for a chief State election administration official to take an active part in political management or in a political campaign with respect to any election for Federal office over which such official has supervisory authority.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H766A6511BD4C4984AA62433634745BEB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Chief State election administration official</header><text>The term <term>chief State election administration official</term> means the highest State official with responsibility for the administration of Federal elections under State law.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H909923626AF5418E8F148D059371638B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Active part in political management or in a political campaign</header><text>The term <term>active part in political management or in a political campaign</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="H0FD9F448E36544ACB4DE813E0257092B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>serving as a member of an authorized committee of a candidate for Federal office;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H792FA328A7034851AB83752AB6196ECB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the use of official authority or influence for the purpose of interfering with or affecting the result of an election for Federal office;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H431671D8D281436899FACE5411B3D6B0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the solicitation, acceptance, or receipt of a contribution from any person on behalf of a candidate for Federal office; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H908F909AB23D4D16A055766E78D998BB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any other act which would be prohibited under paragraph (2) or (3) of section 7323(b) of title 5, United States Code, if taken by an individual to whom such paragraph applies (other than any prohibition on running for public office).</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9B6797D2A0414A53B5B46C333014D952"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exception for Campaigns of Official or Immediate Family Members</header>
 <paragraph id="HAC462FA90158460FB4837274E919C40B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>This section does not apply to a chief State election administration official with respect to an election for Federal office in which the official or an immediate family member of the official is a candidate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0B47B17AAF3F43E5B7FA86EFDC38B820"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Immediate family member defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In paragraph (1), the term <term>immediate family member</term> means, with respect to a candidate, a father, mother, son, daughter, brother, sister, husband, wife, father-in-law, or mother-in-law.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1704621D835D4CD294F777064EFE76A3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective Date</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to elections for Federal office held after December 2017.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


