<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H922700F7A96646F3BA85040A90BF356F" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3257 IH: Promote Accountability and Government Efficiency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3257</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170714">July 14, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000592">Mr. Rokita</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001290">Mr. Brat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000583">Mr. Loudermilk</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001195">Mr. Smith of Missouri</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide certain reforms to promote accountability and efficiency in the civil service, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H04A38FF1DEDC4E5C9FFF095FD86CDC35" style="OLC">
		<section id="H852825BFADA14DE98890494430E47007" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="HC9EAF14F8E89475B8D307DA2DE7612CD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Promote Accountability and Government Efficiency Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HBC7975CB78A24139B97E1150FA81EB02"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
					<toc-entry idref="H852825BFADA14DE98890494430E47007" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HC4876D2DD76D44C592FF2E55309A8F88" level="section">Sec. 2. At-will employment status for new Federal employees.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H75F3EFBF6AB6478694E60603EEAEBB4E" level="section">Sec. 3. Immediate suspension of employees for misconduct or poor performance.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H4920B915D82046DAB118930E48A468E2" level="section">Sec. 4. Limitation on appeal rights.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H7FCDE830371145009616EAFFE2A27211" level="section">Sec. 5. Restriction of pay raises.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HDD040ADDE4834875916AEF9C7515250A" level="section">Sec. 6. Forfeiture of CSRS or FERS annuity for any employee convicted of a felony.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HF7E6ED55E2EB40E1997A378EF1388E29" level="section">Sec. 7. Transfer from Senior Executive Service to General Schedule.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HA9FF312DB8A743FC92945942F74EA8D8" level="section">Sec. 8. Limitation on official time and use of Government resources in carrying out union
			 activities.</toc-entry>
				</toc>
			</subsection></section><section id="HC4876D2DD76D44C592FF2E55309A8F88"><enum>2.</enum><header>At-will employment status for new Federal employees</header>
 <subsection id="H82353B03242E4584A74467229F97405A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any employee in the civil service hired on or after the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act shall be hired on an at-will basis. Such an employee may be removed or suspended, without notice or right to appeal, from service by the head of the agency at which such employee is employed for good cause, bad cause, or no cause at all.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H5165BE0473DF4263A41AEBB9270DD0C1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clarification of employment protections</header>
 <paragraph id="H94540B5F47A34BFF92891550976244E1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the requirements of subsection (a) and consistent with paragraph (2), this Act shall not be construed to extinguish or lessen any right or remedy available to any employee or applicant for employment in the civil service covered by subsection (a) under any law listed in paragraph (3).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1BD5A2E32B864A49A83EA59571B0177C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>No employee or applicant for employment in the civil service may be awarded by any court a remedy (including damages, costs, or attorney fees) under any of the provisions of law listed in paragraph (3) in a dollar amount that, in the aggregate, exceeds $50,000.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4607C9AE13C14C26A0DFFB66E5C33A6F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered laws</header><text>The provisions of law referenced in paragraphs (1) and (2) are as follows:</text> <subparagraph id="H9B338537AB1346D08680F9D630F5CD1C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e">42 U.S.C. 2000e</external-xref> et seq.), prohibiting discrimination on the basis of race, color, religion, sex, or national origin.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8985ABD9D38A4EBD9F33638F52F165D4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/621">29 U.S.C. 621</external-xref> et seq.), prohibiting discrimination on the basis of age.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B01F4E2A66248E49B44E9B846ECB18C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/201">29 U.S.C. 201</external-xref> et seq.), prohibiting discrimination on the basis of sex.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8812EF8B41934AF9816E0EDAD4838B6E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/701">29 U.S.C. 701</external-xref> et seq.), prohibiting discrimination on the basis of handicapping condition.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF8D0E4F43EC4A26AD0C747B434A49AE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Whistleblower Protection Enhancement Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/199">Public Law 112–199</external-xref>).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE67F9C95E1CD4AB499A5771342CBFA2E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The provisions of any law, rule, or regulation prohibiting discrimination on the basis of marital status or political affiliation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C3DD4475E8B4302B12A891398D53693"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The Congressional Accountability Act of 1995, in the case of employees of the legislative branch who are subject to such Act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF58ACDB3556C4C9892F62C8AE877848B"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The protections relating to prohibited personnel practices (as that term is defined in section 2302 of title 5, United States Code).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96462C58C3A5464CA3DB25F0B992B787"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Any law protecting the employment rights of veterans.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCFE3A4DE19FF49899775C6A7B5A1F02A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Collective bargaining</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No collective bargaining unit may be awarded by any court any remedy (including damages, costs, or attorney fees) for any breach of such agreement in an amount that exceeds $10,000 per occurrence, or $300,000 in any given calendar year, whichever is least.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0E6CF6BC8FE24E0E914E8EB3DCF3D186"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>To the extent any remedy of damages, costs, or attorney fees are awarded by a court in an amount that is in excess of the limits of this section, the amount awarded in excess shall be rendered null, void, and unenforceable. Efforts by an employee, applicant for employment, or collective bargaining unit or its members or legal counsel to seek to collect in excess of the statutory amounts, or efforts by any member of an agency to award a remedy in excess of these statutory amounts, shall be grounds for immediate separation of the employee or agency personnel, termination of the applicable collective bargaining agreement, and a prohibition on hiring such an applicant for a period of 5 years beginning on the date of the collection effort in excess.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8D4886F3ABDA4F75A1EA58A4D946FB49"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appeal</header>
 <paragraph id="H8624F8374EF7492B82B1B4FA5733ECBF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any employee or applicant for employment who is subject to subsection (a) and who seeks a remedy under any law listed in subsection (b)(2) with respect to an adverse personnel action may appeal under the procedures set forth in title 5, United States Code, including appealing such action to the Merit Systems Protection Board or the Office of the Special Counsel.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDA3C56347A824632B5CF3E034268CFC4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>An employee or applicant for employment may appeal an adverse personnel action only to a single agency, and may not thereafter bring any appeal pertaining to such dismissal before any other agency. An employee or applicant for employment who files multiple appeals of an adverse personnel action shall have any remedy for the claim limited to not more than $1,000 in the aggregate (including damages, costs, or attorney fees).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA94328E2644A4F13A0E3E8B767D05C84"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><text>This section shall apply with respect to any employee hired, or any individual who becomes an applicant for employment, on or after the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H11832575820E41479884B801206FF310"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, each agency or instrumentality of the Government to which this section applies shall develop operating standards consistent with the requirements of this section, including standards with respect to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H79A992B17EB34EDD813FFA083D2BB52C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>notifying any employee hired on or after the date specified in subsection (a) that such employee is an at-will employee;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H79EF480576D941AD8310EEF2363A9DBF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>determining which senior positions within such agency or instrumentality have the authority to separate an at-will employee from service; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H593FA2998CD145FDA415FFA4AE3ABF6A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensuring adequate oversight is in place to ensure that any separation of an at-will employee is not a result of discrimination or other violation of any law listed under subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8AF512F973684C9FA33C173A183B2C55"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, each agency or instrumentality of the Federal Government to which this section applies shall develop operating standards consistent with the requirements of this section, including standards with respect to—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD24BB1B3845A48C7969802EC04946CE0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>notifying any employee hired on or after the date specified in subsection (a) that such employee is an at-will employee;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H89DF7FF78EAD468585EF4D6049E01C8C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>determining which senior positions within such agency or instrumentality have the authority to separate an at-will employee from service; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF2D031CE6CC14052A27ECC36C75CD6EC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensuring adequate oversight is in place to ensure that any separation of an at-will employee is not a result of discrimination or other violation of any law listed under subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFC9B4A08C0F64095A59BD5C504B76327"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HE77C67F89F264F9882EA8AD320E82C0B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Civil service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>civil service</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 2101 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF2D430E4C68A40178F0EBDAE40DF3293"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Employee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>employee</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 2105 of such title, and includes any officer or employee of the United States Postal Service or the Postal Regulatory Commission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7ACF3AB5FABA45F38C48F6BA9C8E7C21"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Personnel action</header><text>The term <quote>personnel action</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 2302(a)(2)(A) of such title.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H48979841120245BB802ADAE9B641ACBA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Veteran</header><text>The term <quote>veteran</quote> has the meaning given that term under section 2108(1) of such title.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H75F3EFBF6AB6478694E60603EEAEBB4E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Immediate suspension of employees for misconduct or poor performance</header>
 <subsection id="H838E677AA93347B4AABF127B79484B17"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/75">Chapter 75</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8D2F319BEC7744AAABD8C1E753CEE67E" style="USC"> <subchapter id="H9F9C2BA75EB64D98B65A20E52DC4F68D"><enum>VI</enum><header>Immediate Suspension for Misconduct or Poor Performance </header> <section id="H00D47FBF482C4FB6B850D3D0DB49C6DB"><enum>7551.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this subchapter—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8FAA9899F7AE4CA6A2B7C11F793AB252"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <quote>employee</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 7501(1) and includes any employee of the United States Postal Service or the Postal Regulatory Commission, but does not include any at-will employee (as determined under section 2 of the Promote Accountability and Government Efficiency Act); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA4E53CD5DE3748FD9FBD96B09AA5C3ED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <quote>suspend</quote> means the placing of any employee, for misconduct or poor performance, in a temporary status without duties.</text>
							</paragraph></section><section id="HFB2C404A5B2D4B88B4E2329196338B25"><enum>7552.</enum><header>Immediate suspension for misconduct or poor performance</header>
 <subsection id="H46685E78D7EE4378B381B559753BFFF3"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under regulations prescribed by the Office of Personnel Management, the head of an agency may suspend (with or without pay) an employee of such agency if the head determines that the misconduct or performance of the employee warrants such suspension. The period of any such suspension shall be determined by the head.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAEA63DF2C1394AE5B2608AD8EDB4EAAA"><enum>(b)</enum><text>An employee who is suspended under subsection (a) is entitled, after suspension, to—</text> <paragraph id="HA3FFFC671D634B5E84A488B6F02E5588"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a written notice, not later than 10 days after the first day of such suspension, stating the specific reasons for the suspension;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA189CD32734849228D33685C0FDDF008"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a reasonable time, but not less than 10 days, to answer orally and in writing and to furnish affidavits and other documentary evidence in support of the answer;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2361223A13394B139F5DC1619027F070"><enum>(3)</enum><text>be represented by an attorney or other representative; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3FD7A2C9FD2A41F0BADC9B076A4ACBDC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a review of the case by the agency head and a written final decision and the specific reasons therefor at the earliest practicable date.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7DBE8D858F814244A2A73BC431C132F5"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An employee against whom an action is taken under this section is entitled to appeal to the merit systems Protection Board under section 7701 of this title. During such appeal, the Merit Systems Protection Board may not take any action to reinstate the employee to the position of employment from which such employee is suspended until the date of the final decision of such appeal.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H57F7C3D430AB410E86D909DBDB094D04"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Copies of the notice of proposed action, the answer of the employee if written, a summary thereof if made orally, the notice of decision and reasons therefor, and any order affecting the suspension, together with any supporting material, shall be maintained by the agency and shall be furnished to the Merit Systems Protection Board upon its request and to the employee affected upon the employee’s request.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD78AC5626ECD4DE08F6627B6D376902D"><enum>(e)</enum><text>In the case of critical necessity, the head of an agency may immediately replace any employee suspended under subsection (a) without regard to sections 3309 through 3318.</text></subsection></section></subchapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6839F997EEA9405F872184A0341860B6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/75">chapter 75</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H275974B5304B47E3AA5CABE85B9C3A1D" style="USC">
					<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="H8D2F319BEC7744AAABD8C1E753CEE67E" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
						<toc-entry idref="H9F9C2BA75EB64D98B65A20E52DC4F68D" level="subchapter">Subchapter VI—Immediate Suspension for Misconduct or Poor Performance </toc-entry>
						<toc-entry idref="H00D47FBF482C4FB6B850D3D0DB49C6DB" level="section">7551. Definitions.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry idref="HFB2C404A5B2D4B88B4E2329196338B25" level="section">7552. Immediate suspension for misconduct or poor performance.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section id="H4920B915D82046DAB118930E48A468E2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Limitation on appeal rights</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, an employee (as that term is defined in section 2(g)(2)) or applicant for employment may not appeal an adverse personnel action to more than 1 agency.</text>
		</section><section id="H7FCDE830371145009616EAFFE2A27211"><enum>5.</enum><header>Restriction of pay raises</header>
 <subsection id="H2B4E1889354C4E60BDAABF203F28CD4E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, an employee may not receive an increase in annual rate of pay if such employee—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC848F1F4F2724FFDB77927D9D101C0E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>did not receive at least a score of 4 or 5 out of 5 (or an equivalent rating with respect to a performance appraisal system that does provide for such a scoring system) on such employee’s latest performance review under the performance appraisal system applicable to such employee; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H061CC76AE9804F7BA1D44DB4581B3DB4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of employees receiving a score of 4 out of 5 (or an equivalent rating with respect to a performance appraisal system that does provide for such a scoring system) does not exceed 50 percent of all employees in that agency.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE2AF8DEF9F814B5F91629AF4B5EA5EDB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall submit to Congress a report that contains recommendations for a single-agency rating system.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HB2491FE59BF249EFB49658FAFB183079"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Collective bargaining agreements</header>
 <paragraph id="HBF0119F03F7A46B3A6E47CD30C3DCB9B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The requirements of this section shall apply to any collective bargaining agreement entered into by the head of an agency on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H55261270776D44938F17AC32DB450754"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grievance</header><text>In the case of an employee covered by a collective bargaining agreement referred to in paragraph (1), a grievance filed on behalf of such employee that results in an increased performance rating for such employee may not result in an increase in annual rate of pay for such employee.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1095D0E30B514E63857C9EA8431CC4D5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>employee</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 2105 of title 5, United States Code, and includes any officer or employee of the United States Postal Service or the Postal Regulatory Commission.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HDD040ADDE4834875916AEF9C7515250A"><enum>6.</enum><header>Forfeiture of CSRS or FERS annuity for any employee convicted of a felony</header>
 <subsection id="HAE0AFA734E0D49DCB140D78B9F00D8E5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/83">chapter 83</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HE46347D40D9E4D739F4DCE1EAF764D86" style="USC">
					<section id="H923505E0D2CA49A5ACBA7D72A430F7D5"><enum>8323.</enum><header>Forfeiture of annuity for felony conviction</header>
						<subsection id="HB6EBDA42B3754E50984110C2ADA0A965"><enum>(a)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HFE5F11A56C974AE0A8BBB83A8C5CA726"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An individual appointed to the service who is not subject to the requirements of section 2 of the Promote Accountability and Government Efficiency Act may not be paid an annuity or retired pay on the basis of the service of the individual which is creditable toward the annuity if the individual was finally convicted of a felony offense.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4A675B60B8D4455FB70D0991D1C43319" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), the term <quote>felony offense</quote> means any felony offense committed by the individual that is related to the performance of any position within the service occupied by such individual.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H921FF3FB16F544A5B9363436540D013B"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual who is an at-will employee (as determined under section 2 of the Promote Accountability and Government Efficiency Act) may not be paid an annuity on the basis of the service of the individual which is creditable toward the annuity if the individual was finally convicted of a felony offense—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2131E7376A26488F861D7EC2F2A124DE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>when such individual was performing creditable service (as that term is defined in section 8332 or 8411); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1570E3F4B4F947349A0E8DCF4F895322"><enum>(2)</enum><text>after such individual has separated from the service, but only if such offense is related to the performance of any position within the Government formerly occupied by such individual.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA8C41D1D8BCE45DFB71AF4900B90162A"><enum>(c)</enum><text>In this section, the term <quote>finally convicted</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 8332(o)(A)(6).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H5ABE43C7EED34509A2E4290FD44383F5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections of subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/83">chapter 83</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding after the item relating to section 8322 the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H396ABA7B3FD045DF84E9810368DFDB90" style="USC">
					<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="HE46347D40D9E4D739F4DCE1EAF764D86" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
						<toc-entry idref="H923505E0D2CA49A5ACBA7D72A430F7D5" level="section">8323. Forfeiture of annuity for felony conviction.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="HF7E6ED55E2EB40E1997A378EF1388E29"><enum>7.</enum><header>Transfer from Senior Executive Service to General Schedule</header>
 <subsection id="H61F68640B3F74772B48022BC0A3ACB43"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter VIII of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/33">chapter 33</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HDDF740AA642C490CAE21550F8CF60828"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating section 3397 as section 3398; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H118824E4754148FDA0825BBF0EA30BBD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after section 3396 the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H9274B896918048038183F35B8656FE68" style="USC"> <section id="H848213D4E41044DEB2B1C109E47D73B1"><enum>3397.</enum><header>Transfer to General Schedule positions</header> <subsection id="H78E0352EB10C4F0CBC5A3247D9406669"><enum>(a)</enum><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the head of any agency may transfer a covered individual to a position within the General Schedule (subchapter III of chapter 53).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF7FAEE68BAA84F13988D091DD9FF9A68"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, including the requirements of section 3594, any covered individual transferred to a General Schedule position under subsection (a) shall, beginning on the date of such transfer, receive the annual rate of pay applicable to such position.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H07055148EB694AA481BA1DAE672A1AAD"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>covered individual</quote> means an individual occupying a senior executive service position who is not an at-will employee (as determined under section 2 of the Promote Accountability and Government Efficiency Act).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H71AA606BC7FC420CA7E760747F4480FC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections of subchapter VIII of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/33">chapter 33</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking the item relating to section 3397 and inserting the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2E9EB105CE6C42F7A864205C615DBCB5" style="USC">
					<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="H9274B896918048038183F35B8656FE68" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
						<toc-entry idref="H848213D4E41044DEB2B1C109E47D73B1" level="section">3397. Transfer to General Schedule positions.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section commented="no" id="HA9FF312DB8A743FC92945942F74EA8D8"><enum>8.</enum><header>Limitation on official time and use of Government resources in carrying out union activities</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H3A048B8CC3A049B19ADE54C9AB7DE602"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 7131 of title 5, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="H34AFA2E6000544169082FB5DFB9413D1" style="USC"> <section commented="no" id="H66759300CE644D879BF99E3C18308CCE"><enum>7131.</enum><header>Limitation on official time</header> <subsection commented="no" id="HF7BFE1BB8FFB4EB5AB319CBB9A44810D"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out any activities relating to the internal business of a labor organization (including the solicitation of membership, elections of labor organization officials, and collection of dues), an employee may not—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H6FABF073544B40909B4F1CBB52745CBE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>perform such activities unless such employee is in a non-duty status; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC3439244E6D741EB85A0AB1BD7F2C243"><enum>(2)</enum><text>use any Government property (including office space or computers).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H9DAF07215BB14AEAA37EC61521D3A0DC"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Employees engaging in such activities must truthfully and accurately account for their time spent in carrying out such activities, and may not engage in any political activities that may impact such employee’s Agency.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H99BABE9AE5744207BB7F9AC29375E1D5"><enum>(c)</enum><text>Documents, communications and things prepared by or in the possession of employees engaged in any activity relating to a labor organization that is engaged in collective bargaining activities with said employee’s Agency shall maintain the records of such activities for a period of at least two years or the term of the collective bargaining agreement, plus six months, and produce copies of such records in response to Freedom of Information Act requests.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H239B3EA7D7CE4DA8BB0850411E245315"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/71">chapter 71</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking the item relating to section 7131 and inserting the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H42F96751A2D0452CA99AA2F8AABE56C1" style="USC">
					<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="H34AFA2E6000544169082FB5DFB9413D1" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
						<toc-entry idref="H66759300CE644D879BF99E3C18308CCE" level="section">7131. Limitation on official time.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


