<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE amendment-doc PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/amend.dtd//EN" "amend.dtd">
<amendment-doc amend-type="engrossed-amendment"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1616 EAS: Strengthening State and Local Cyber Crime Fighting Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<engrossed-amendment-form>
<congress display="no">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="no">1st Session</session><legis-num display="no">H.R. 1616</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">In the Senate of the United States,</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20171002">October 2, 2017.</action-date></action><legis-type display="yes">Amendment:</legis-type></engrossed-amendment-form><engrossed-amendment-body><section id="id2e23db0ba2cc4820a1f65f87d4fac361" section-type="resolved"><text>That the bill from the House of Representatives (H.R. 1616) entitled <quote>An Act to amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to authorize the National Computer Forensics Institute, and for other purposes.</quote>, do pass with the following</text></section><amendment><amendment-instruction blank-lines-after="0"><text>Strike all after the enacting clause and insert the following:</text></amendment-instruction><amendment-block blank-lines-after="1"><section id="HE12563D9C4D2411E8ABA2AD21E6954E5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthening State and Local Cyber Crime Fighting Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H9C078E3655E348409F1FCDE50DDFF48D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authorization of the national computer forensics institute of the department of homeland security</header><subsection id="HBFF804F8417B4CC2AD97183ED0DD0342"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subtitle C of title VIII of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/381">6 U.S.C. 381</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="H5CA6409560EF4F29AB19FFFEB7278D17" style="OLC"><section id="H063687348CA04F66A51F85356E1B6E47"><enum>822.</enum><header>National computer forensics institute</header><subsection id="H45B79A4A846848B7BD8158540359C62B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized for fiscal years 2017 through 2022 within the United States Secret Service a National Computer Forensics Institute (in this section referred to as the <quote>Institute</quote>). The Institute shall disseminate information related to the investigation and prevention of cyber and electronic crime and related threats, and educate, train, and equip State, local, tribal, and territorial law enforcement officers, prosecutors, and judges.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB5A4503D26364C55BC5F10A217A61F64"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The functions of the Institute shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="HB0D69B59B7434ADD8EBD9F0822EFE82B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Educating State, local, tribal, and territorial law enforcement officers, prosecutors, and judges on current—</text><subparagraph id="H2A158270B85244FC82C026ADBB567450"><enum>(A)</enum><text>cyber and electronic crimes and related threats;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2083EC0F408F4A9B8BBD499E96F3E4C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>methods for investigating cyber and electronic crime and related threats and conducting computer and mobile device forensic examinations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA462256D9C434416A54D8B0B8369C434"><enum>(C)</enum><text>prosecutorial and judicial challenges related to cyber and electronic crime and related threats, and computer and mobile device forensic examinations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H06F976E0B8644300B8E1DF16D503FA76"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Training State, local, tribal, and territorial law enforcement officers to—</text><subparagraph id="H08F4F23C9B8F4D9F8CD83A80E945500A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct cyber and electronic crime and related threat investigations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2855FDA22C8847C0877A806BB26E4BB4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conduct computer and mobile device forensic examinations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H60AB5FB222F244C0B7A1919F27DDD17D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>respond to network intrusion incidents.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B1B2A17BC074AE9A9EB1B65A0101F8C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Training State, local, tribal, and territorial law enforcement officers, prosecutors, and judges on methods to obtain, process, store, and admit digital evidence in court.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA83957A29D3A4617906A87259995870F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Principles</header><text>In carrying out the functions specified in subsection (b), the Institute shall ensure, to the extent practicable, that timely, actionable, and relevant expertise and information related to cyber and electronic crime and related threats is shared with State, local, tribal, and territorial law enforcement officers and prosecutors.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0678DE4B1F654960957CABDD64E2A58F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Equipment</header><text>The Institute may provide State, local, tribal, and territorial law enforcement officers with computer equipment, hardware, software, manuals, and tools necessary to conduct cyber and electronic crime and related threat investigations and computer and mobile device forensic examinations.</text></subsection><subsection id="H28AE405785AE414DBCE7702FCD79CEC9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Electronic crime task forces</header><text>The Institute shall facilitate the expansion of the network of Electronic Crime Task Forces of the United States Secret Service through the addition of State, local, tribal, and territorial law enforcement officers educated and trained at the Institute.</text></subsection><subsection id="H300F38DBC43B4E14B7A9CF45A2087E23"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text>All authorized activities and functions carried out by the Institute at any location as of the day before the date of the enactment of this section are authorized to continue to be carried out at any such location on and after such date.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H1872F0FF21F649A6AC349DD57E61E3B1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>For each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022, amounts appropriated for United States Secret Service, Operations and Support, may be used to carry out this Act and the amendments made by this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H93B460D6F9174E919160E23DF584C963"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/101">6 U.S.C. 101</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 821 the following new item:</text><quoted-block id="HC948838426A446DB84D03484646A27D8" style="OLC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 822. National Computer Forensics Institute.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="HA8FF6084D99F4751A12761A88DA892B9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prevention, investigation, and prosecution of economic, high technology, internet, and other white
 collar crime</header><subsection id="H3A361DBE19EE47498A1610E748683E23"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10101">34 U.S.C. 10101</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H60C8D5FE7A114290A3F960ED5ED79AA7" style="OLC"><part id="H44F3E21DB1E44D0B92C58F58054A9AD8"><enum>MM</enum><header>Prevention, investigation, and prosecution of white collar crime</header><section id="H11F2587C31004155A249300435884799"><enum>3030.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This part may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National White Collar Crime Control Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB594E6F0A8CC4E3FB07D96DFCC0765BF"><enum>3031.</enum><header>Establishment of grant program</header><subsection id="HC7F3EFA8EAD8482BAAE508E0080B3B42"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance is authorized to enter into a cooperative agreement with or make a grant to an eligible entity for the purpose of improving the identification, investigation, and prosecution of white collar crime (including each category of such crimes set forth in paragraphs (1) through (3) of subsection (b)) by providing comprehensive, direct, and practical training and technical assistance to law enforcement officers, investigators, auditors and prosecutors in States and units of local government.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEEC66B92AD58438B9EB9597803D904BC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>White collar crime defined</header><text>For purposes of this part, the term <term>white collar crime</term> includes—</text><paragraph id="H4CCBD253CBA34A1BAF0D6804C18EC482"><enum>(1)</enum><text>high-tech crime, including cyber and electronic crime and related threats;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D312B34E5CA4E349F7BEECD6E3D508D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>economic crime, including financial fraud and mortgage fraud; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H26519D9BDB6A4CA9932C4F8A5A8A2DB5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Internet-based crime against children and child pornography.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC95E83A52902452FA20A36CA013CCB94"><enum>3032.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this part include the following:</text><paragraph id="H0CFAEA1F196B42B582126978E64079F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To ensure that training is available for State, local, tribal and territorial law enforcement agencies and officers nationwide to support local efforts to identify, prevent, investigate, and prosecute cyber and financial crimes, including those crimes facilitated via computer networks and other electronic means, and crimes involving financial and economic impacts such as intellectual property crimes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H40626286119A431DBBA8F1A62C5BB491"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To deliver training to State, local, tribal, and territorial law enforcement officers, and other criminal justice professionals concerning the use of proven methodologies to prevent, detect, and respond to such crimes, recognize emerging issues, manage electronic and financial crime evidence and to improve local criminal justice agency responses to such threats.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E0984482C864499A4BEB4042F4BFEE1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To provide operational and technical assistance and training concerning tools, products, resources, guidelines, and procedures to aid and enhance criminal intelligence analysis, conduct cyber crime and financial crime investigations, and related justice information sharing at the local and State levels.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idCFCAE6FC0BF44B809DC167E01C16BA43"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To provide appropriate training on protections for privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties in the conduct of criminal intelligence analysis and cyber and electronic crime and financial crime investigations, including in the development of policies, guidelines, and procedures by State, local, tribal, and territorial law enforcement agencies to protect and enhance privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties protections and identify weaknesses and gaps in the protection of privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H8E817A067F494E578F152EF0AB028FB2"><enum>3033.</enum><header>Authorized programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A grant or cooperative agreement awarded under this part may be made only for the following programs, with respect to the prevention, investigation, and prosecution of certain criminal activities:</text><paragraph id="H0FB0FEB2E70F42B9AECA48C1FAB3C339"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Programs to provide a nationwide support system for State and local criminal justice agencies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H15C32DCB9827488BA8A739EACF64582A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Programs to assist State and local criminal justice agencies to develop, establish, and maintain intelligence-focused policing strategies and related information sharing.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE118CA67CD734756B949DD147E1C8F5D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Programs to provide training and investigative support services to State and local criminal justice agencies to provide such agencies with skills and resources needed to investigate and prosecute such criminal activities and related criminal activities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE38B3405A86A46DEAAC9C51EAF593B7F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Programs to provide research support, to establish partnerships, and to provide other resources to aid State and local criminal justice agencies to prevent, investigate, and prosecute such criminal activities and related problems.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB24C427291514BB8BA9A56146DD3020D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Programs to provide information and research to the general public to facilitate the prevention of such criminal activities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCDD2D102292441A2AA885F073F34D1AF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Programs to establish or support national training and research centers regionally to provide training and research services for State and local criminal justice agencies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id18bc76236aa14c5aba720e70a66e2e8f"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Programs to provide training and oversight to State and local criminal justice agencies to develop and comply with applicable privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties related policies, procedures, rules, laws, and guidelines.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6C3B98FABB34A368111E6B9BA91F710"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Any other programs specified by the Attorney General as furthering the purposes of this part.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H8CC8F68B996C477391BD592886DDB91C"><enum>3034.</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">To be eligible for an award of a grant or cooperative agreement under this part, an entity shall submit to the Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance an application in such form and manner, and containing such information, as required by the Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance.</text></section><section id="HAB079CDAC16145139B527A64E7E48C51"><enum>3035.</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">States, units of local government, not-for-profit entities, and institutions of higher-education with demonstrated capacity and experience in delivering training, technical assistance and other resources including direct, practical laboratory training to law enforcement officers, investigators, auditors and prosecutors in States and units of local government and over the Internet shall be eligible to receive an award under this part.</text></section><section id="HEB06157C226F42599EF278E65D092D4C"><enum>3036.</enum><header>Rules and regulations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance shall promulgate such rules and regulations as are necessary to carry out this part, including rules and regulations for submitting and reviewing applications under section 3035.</text></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H67C989A82EAE45F3B6AF5B7F4CD89899"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated $13,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022 to carry out —</text><paragraph id="HEBC54E7C62CC446CBBCCE8104CC56705"><enum>(1)</enum><text>part MM of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968, as added by subsection (a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HABB7BB9ED11F46BE82B21F5B13611470"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 401(b) of the Prioritizing Resources and Organization for Intellectual Property Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/30103">34 U.S.C. 30103(b)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></amendment-block></amendment></engrossed-amendment-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestor></attestor><role>Secretary</role></attestation-group></attestation><endorsement></endorsement></amendment-doc>


