<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2090813161E94467B36375735090889F" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 644 IH: Conscience Protection Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 644</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170124">January 24, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001273">Mrs. Black</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000449">Mr. Fortenberry</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000460">Mr. Farenthold</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000580">Mr. Roskam</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000606">Mr. Pittenger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000388">Mr. Kelly of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000563">Mr. Gibbs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001299">Mr. Banks of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001243">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001195">Mr. Mooney of West Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000566">Mr. Latta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001071">Mr. Jody B. Hice of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001096">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000598">Mr. Rothfus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000619">Mr. Rodney Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000815">Mr. Wenstrup</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001192">Mr. Stewart</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000450">Ms. Foxx</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001059">Mr. Hultgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000184">Mrs. Noem</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000299">Mr. Johnson of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000533">Mr. Duncan of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000063">Mr. Yoder</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000582">Mr. Roe of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000798">Mr. Walberg</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001176">Mr. Scalise</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000601">Mr. Palazzo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001201">Mr. Mitchell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001283">Mr. Bridenstine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000569">Mr. Luetkemeyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000552">Mr. Gohmert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000583">Mr. Thomas J. Rooney of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000755">Mr. Brady of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000372">Mr. Allen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000558">Mr. Guthrie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000813">Mrs. Walorski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001158">Mr. Marchant</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000592">Mr. Rokita</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001036">Mr. Hensarling</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000168">Mr. Olson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001187">Mr. Meadows</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000266">Mr. Chabot</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000055">Mr. Aderholt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000546">Mr. Graves of Missouri</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000292">Mr. Johnson of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000065">Mr. Yoho</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000459">Mr. Fleischmann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001290">Mr. Brat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000591">Mrs. Roby</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000583">Mr. Loudermilk</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000592">Mr. Poe of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000588">Mr. Pearce</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000806">Mr. Webster of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001072">Mr. Hill</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to prohibit governmental discrimination against providers of
			 health services that are not involved in abortion.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H9670255DCC91403B87F740DD31C8ADCA" style="OLC">
 <section id="H06F19BC3EE6642018D9268596F795FDF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Conscience Protection Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H694D1DB258CF4AFBAAB76D3CC805D939"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="HA0F25CCDC23D401F8F44EBBDC18AB817"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Thomas Jefferson stated a conviction common to our Nation’s founders when he declared in 1809 that <quote>[n]o provision in our Constitution ought to be dearer to man than that which protects the rights of conscience against the enterprises of the civil authority</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8C45DECDFF7B41A08489744DC43C8636"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In 1973, the Supreme Court concluded that the government must leave the abortion decision <quote>to the medical judgment of the pregnant woman’s attending physician</quote>, recognizing that a physician may choose not to participate in abortion. Roe v. Wade, 410 U.S. 113, 164 (1973). The Court cited with approval a policy that <quote>neither physician, hospital, nor hospital personnel shall be required to perform any act violative of personally-held moral principles</quote>, 410 U.S. at 143 n. 38, and cited State laws upholding this principle. Doe v. Bolton, 410 U.S. 179, 197–8 (1973).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H187B771D937549D3AB75D618683179A4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Congress’s enactments to protect this right of conscience in health care include the Church amendment of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300a-7">42 U.S.C. 300a–7</external-xref>), the Coats/Snowe amendment of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/238n">42 U.S.C. 238n</external-xref>), and the Weldon amendment approved by Congresses and Presidents of both parties every year since 2004.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HBF5C54F807064AD7A46F5EAE75C7B357"><enum>(4)</enum><text>None of these laws explicitly provides a <quote>private right of action</quote> so victims of discrimination can defend their conscience rights in court, and administrative enforcement by the Department of Health and Human Services Office for Civil Rights has been lax, at times allowing cases to languish for years without resolution.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H547BD2E3433C4121A66971E1C60CAB6B"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Defying the Federal Weldon amendment, California’s Department of Managed Health Care has mandated coverage for all elective abortions in all health plans under its jurisdiction. Other States such as New York and Washington have taken or considered similar action, and some States may go farther to require all physicians and hospitals to provide or facilitate abortions. On June 21, 2016, the Obama Administration concluded a nearly two-year investigation of this matter by determining that California’s decision to require insurance plans under the California Department for Managed Health Care authority to cover all legal abortion services did not violate the Weldon amendment. Until the new Administration is able to reverse this finding, individuals will have to choose between ignoring their conscience or forgoing health care coverage.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H1065DA65D3214B6F9A827E9E34F22199"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The vast majority of medical professionals do not perform abortions, with 86 percent of ob/gyns unwilling to provide them in a recent study (Obstetrics &amp; Gynecology, Sept. 2011) and the great majority of hospitals choosing to do so in rare cases or not at all.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H39241A704429433EBB690CCAA33D271C"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A health care provider’s decision not to participate in an abortion, like Congress’s decision not to fund most abortions, erects no new barrier to those seeking to perform or undergo abortions but leaves each party free to act as he or she wishes.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4436C069DB9E4032B182363F9E0F8E19"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Such protection poses no conflict with other Federal laws, such as the law requiring emergency stabilizing treatment for a pregnant woman and her unborn child when either is in distress (Emergency Medical Treatment and Active Labor Act). As the previous Administration has said, these areas of law have operated side by side for many years and both should be fully enforced (76 Fed. Reg. 9968–77 (2011) at 9973).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4D2B533FAC734C61A0D39F8206F41A5C"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Reaffirming longstanding Federal policy on conscience rights and providing a right of action in cases where it is violated allows longstanding and widely supported Federal laws to work as intended.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HB8FADAE531824F2B9CBE4AF527671C13"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibiting governmental discrimination against providers of health services that are not involved
 in abortion</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title II of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/202">42 U.S.C. 202</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by inserting after section 245 the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="H9F1BB90E107549F1993330A2BD604D98">
				<section id="H818398BA9420454B9FC6067D7EC9F1C0"><enum>245A.</enum><header>Prohibiting governmental discrimination against providers of health services that are not involved
			 in abortion</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="HE088857D59644014BBBBB3FDF3FD9D0D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other law, the Federal Government, and any State or local government that receives Federal financial assistance, may not penalize, retaliate against, or otherwise discriminate against a health care provider on the basis that the provider does not—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H63A9F9A2F9A44F3998BCE8674161835E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>perform, refer for, pay for, or otherwise participate in abortion;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H139A481A0FFC408284FAD644AE47CC3D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide or sponsor abortion coverage; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2C6FAAC8F82D434E93B34B5F8E232DC6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>facilitate or make arrangements for any of the activities specified in this subsection.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2814D5FE2E124272870C17A50A569F68"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed—</text>
 <paragraph id="HAFA88EBA1F7F439A8F0F1DE12B0B4CF1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to prevent any health care provider from voluntarily electing to participate in abortions or abortion referrals;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H05FCBA033F8D4CA5A74B4D0C1F6A9615"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to prevent any health care provider from voluntarily electing to provide or sponsor abortion coverage or health benefits coverage that includes abortion;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H73844F8570FA43DCA7D2A295D069758B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to prevent an accrediting agency, the Federal Government, or a State or local government from establishing standards of medical competency applicable only to those who have knowingly, voluntarily, and specifically elected to perform abortions, or from enforcing contractual obligations applicable only to those who, as part of such contract, knowingly, voluntarily, and specifically elect to provide abortions;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDC1B27E73F404E93A9E41F7EF307287D"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to affect, or be affected by, section 1867 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395dd">42 U.S.C. 1395dd</external-xref>, commonly referred to as the <quote>Emergency Medical Treatment and Active Labor Act</quote>); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDB0B5CCDA1D644DCB5F8433CAB28DC9F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to supersede any law enacted by any State for the purpose of regulating insurance, except as specified in subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H06F6E24776A04573A6743CC038CFB5A3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The Secretary shall designate the Director of the Office for Civil Rights of the Department of Health and Human Services—</text>
 <paragraph id="H5D30DE92A80A44BF9C9CFE942BE4ECFB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to receive complaints alleging a violation of this section, section 245 of this Act, or any of subsections (b) through (e) of section 401 of the Health Programs Extension Act of 1973; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4864F219498244C3B3F4F34B5566283C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to pursue the investigation of such complaints in coordination with the Attorney General.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7FAC1491A5214F1D91994B9CF88E12C5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text>
 <paragraph id="H11D8AB52BF064FA1B1358CD32C5834B4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal financial assistance</header><text>The term <term>Federal financial assistance</term> means Federal payments to cover the cost of health care services or benefits, or other Federal payments, grants, or loans to promote or otherwise facilitate health-related activities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H321BB41F07434B2D99920F7582BCCF30"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Health care provider</header><text>The term <term>health care provider</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H970D4D2F29BC480D84FDDC798FD10334"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual physician, nurse, or other health care professional;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDDF1318A93C4C85A1502ACC467839BF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a hospital, health system, or other health care facility or organization (including a party to a proposed merger or other collaborative arrangement relating to health services, and an entity resulting therefrom);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BFE46247F9A41B28896A9CF08C6C5AE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a provider-sponsored organization, an accountable care organization, or a health maintenance organization;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA417376FAF274567A5101F437255D401"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a social services provider that provides or authorizes referrals for health care services;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06DA2A557BCB4A6FAE6E31DC6CA84407"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a program of training in the health professions or an applicant to or participant in such a program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB4E4EFACFE241F8A582B27AED1B64FB"><enum>(F)</enum><text>an issuer of health insurance coverage; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CC01D2DEB7E4687B53F9A1D3F1EEFC8"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a group health plan or student health plan, or a sponsor or administrator thereof.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9877628B1D664D16913457494DF366BD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State or local government that receives Federal financial assistance</header><text>The term <term>State or local government that receives Federal financial assistance</term> includes every agency and other governmental unit and subdivision of a State or local government, if such State or local government, or any agency or governmental unit or subdivision thereof, receives Federal financial assistance.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF0CF487C2DE14429BC98D8FD16759D12"><enum>245B.</enum><header>Civil action for certain violations</header>
 <subsection id="HAB2C71E714C24E32B3418EF7E27B2137"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A qualified party may, in a civil action, obtain appropriate relief with regard to a designated violation.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA7E3AAEA4D924AC98860602BFC50FE51"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section:</text> <paragraph id="H98556BBC5B2546018590D24540DA43F1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Qualified party</header><text>The term <term>qualified party</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7E37305E81114345BD3B80CE03BD5B82"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Attorney General of the United States; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3531D8CEC566450C92BC13D7F7A24279"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any person or entity adversely affected by the designated violation.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD348A50C30CF4C3CBED8302DEA7720B9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designated violation</header><text>The term <term>designated violation</term> means an actual or threatened violation of—</text> <subparagraph id="H041EE9CACD3A4ACA9EA11967B2921ED4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 245 or 245A of this Act; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H149CD4487ACC471C80A516CA8D65ED84"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any of subsections (b) through (e) of section 401 of the Health Programs Extension Act of 1973 regarding an objection to abortion.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0BB4031205E64BCF9AF5D2BE85B6AA3D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administrative remedies not required</header><text>An action under this section may be commenced, and relief may be granted, without regard to whether the party commencing the action has sought or exhausted available administrative remedies.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="H0C8E843F5FAD44B3A0AB027F952C0DC7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Defendants in actions under this section may include governmental entities as well as others</header>
 <paragraph id="HC6BD73FBF7FC44C6A4A77DFECA8064F0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An action under this section may be maintained against, among others, a party that is a Federal or State governmental entity. Relief in an action under this section may include money damages even if the defendant is such a governmental entity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCB54E436F5A94CCEB1330E0F03A4065F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>For the purposes of this subsection, the term <term>State governmental entity</term> means a State, a local government within a State, and any agency or other governmental unit or subdivision of a State or of such a local government.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAB5DBCC376D3457AAF3ABCF103CCD273"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Nature of relief</header><text>In an action under this section, the court shall grant—</text> <paragraph id="HFB4A85A1F1AD44CDB11632B34218C5B4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all necessary equitable and legal relief, including, where appropriate, declaratory relief and compensatory damages, to prevent the occurrence, continuance, or repetition of the designated violation and to compensate for losses resulting from the designated violation; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC38A5F018B5641EA86DA28550AA72B43"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to a prevailing plaintiff, reasonable attorneys’ fees and litigation expenses as part of the costs.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section></legis-body></bill> 

