<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H034FD40FBCE940CC9FDB794C21A520CF" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1271 IH: DXM Abuse Prevention Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1271</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170301">March 1, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000292">Mr. Johnson of Ohio</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to prevent the abuse of dextromethorphan, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H352E13BE362B45CAB3A3464FE4CA9AF0" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE0DACEBCD00B43E8B72D5AB0AEB64F21" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>DXM Abuse Prevention Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H6DC4EC199D8D49D7B4260C3E89C40293"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sales of over-the-counter drugs containing dextromethorphan</header> <subsection id="HA06310DCD7464E4B8EDE701A0C65A13A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibited acts</header> <paragraph id="H59DB6FF1B6BB46CCA8771C3475FBB6D5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Verification system</header><text>Section 301 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/331">21 U.S.C. 331</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H01B448D1FE95441AAE17EEABDFED73F3" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HF6E8AA8A7D7145ACA9CCF3A927E4F472"><enum>(eee)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The failure of a retailer (as defined in section 506H) that offers for sale in interstate commerce covered drugs (as defined in section 506H) to have a verification system as required by section 506H (relating to sales of over-the-counter drugs containing dextromethorphan).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFDF22FDBF54344DDAF652520233EA53F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Identifier for electronic point of sale system; active ingredients</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 301 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/331">21 U.S.C. 331</external-xref>), as amended by paragraph (1), is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4950DA89441C4E10B11A6B5AAF61D2E9" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HCE14F85DC1C14463A0005CC98BED7C70"><enum>(fff)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The introduction or delivery for introduction into interstate commerce of any covered drug (as defined in section 506H) whose labeling does not include—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6E06996B976240099C0B234685E0051C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a universal product code, universal product number, bar code, or similar identifier to allow an electronic point of sale system to recognize that the sale of the covered drug is prohibited to those under the age of 18; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H42728FD75D444208A7FEBFA158A59D8F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the established name of each active ingredient of the covered drug within the first panel of the drug facts labeling required by section 201.66(c) of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations), in no smaller than 6-point type.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H99857F5273D24F45AF09663BC4242261"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Verification system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act is amended by inserting after section 506G of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/356g">21 U.S.C. 356g</external-xref>) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H446896824D8B49838D3967ABF1091131" style="OLC">
					<section id="H4016E341880743B3AAA24A8C542D2E11"><enum>506H.</enum><header>Sales of over-the-counter drugs containing dextromethorphan</header>
 <subsection id="HD243A41AA2314A57AE8A27F6D0F31C35"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Verification system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any retailer selling or offering for sale in interstate commerce a covered drug shall have a verification system in accordance with this section that is intended to ensure that no individual who purchases a covered drug from the retailer is under 18 years of age. Such a system shall be set up to prompt a retailer to examine a purchaser’s identification card.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD53BFC4DBF144340B0B169762F2098EB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Means used To ensure compliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A verification system under subsection (a) may ensure compliance with this section by any of, or any combination of, the following means:</text>
 <paragraph id="H74B730AD87224A589E0EE8B13284FAA3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An electronic point-of-sale system that is coded—</text> <subparagraph id="H35B287A3A0D34F55A7FB547422E4EB88"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to prompt for verification of the age of purchasers of covered drugs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8D1F66B75B64E5F8D8D6A6E6C8F9297"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to deny sales of covered drugs to those under the age of 18.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF63796CF5A5B432586ADD3E5A870BF94"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Training manuals, materials, or programs that instruct employees—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA4BFCB138FBB4F56B1A78919728D0A22"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to verify the age of purchasers of covered drugs; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A6B7931157B4D79A0A206AAB3E14EF0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to deny sales of covered drugs to those under the age of 18.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA34B52CB13EA468E83B08B797931E7F1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Signage in and around the sales counter outlining the age restriction on sales of covered drugs.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0C6F2B09ED7545A58DDBFDE1CD12506C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Designating one on-duty employee to approve sales of covered drugs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3E864B2EDC9B420AB73C87D4594128FD"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other verification measure adopted by a retailer that is designed to ensure that a purchaser of a covered drug is not under 18 years of age if, based on an examination of the purchaser’s identification card, the retailer reasonably concludes the identification card is valid and indicates the purchaser is not under 18 years of age.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD6107EFFA5A6420983BC77ABE2FC711D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exceptions</header>
 <paragraph id="HADF7E759C6324BAAA079D96371736758"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Individuals over 26</header><text>A verification system under subsection (a) need not require verification of the age of any individual over the age of 26.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H88218EE470CA4EE3AF917017911165FC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Valid prescription</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A verification system under subsection (a) need not apply to any sale made by a retailer that is a pharmacy pursuant to a validly issued prescription.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4262B21E79474B00820400D1CAAEE8D6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Valid military identification card</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A verification system under subsection (a) need not apply to any sale to an individual who supplies proof at the time of such sale that such individual is actively enrolled in the military and presents a valid military identification card.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7ACE1F4DB0704EBDBF7603B7E1E8F626"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall coordinate with State entities that regulate retailers, as designated by the State, to perform activities to ensure compliance with this section, including providing for appropriate investigation of complaints related to violations of this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA3973036F3124DC1800FCDB451FF1F38"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Compliance with State system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a State has a law under which a retailer in the State is required to have a system that ensures that no individual who purchases a covered drug from the retailer is under 18 years of age, the Secretary shall treat any such retailer in the State that is in compliance with such law as having a verification system as required by this section, including for purposes of sections 301(eee) and 303(h).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H27C97FC0169340E9B87B6A9EBA624641"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H68E4CB028F4A42DBA75053974AAECC54"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>covered drug</term>—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H27C13E426EF3446D970A073A3CB96D00"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a drug that—</text> <clause id="H16EEB6556DCE431D8EE7E5E54B4A3224"><enum>(i)</enum><text>contains dextromethorphan; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H76E0F9D2960644FC8087F9E4519D0449"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is not subject to section 503(b)(1); and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H652E386618894BB7B8A5B0D2900D826E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">excludes any drug that is packaged in packets or pouches and contains 2 or fewer maximum adult doses of dextromethorphan as allowable under section 341.74 of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC4E2069516A4B7BA77DDA4C5CBA1F74"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>identification card</term> means an identification card that—</text> <subparagraph id="H39B29628EE8147258B04460329890C90"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes a photograph and the date of birth of the individual; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC40E5F09FCD14C4CBA9EED8374D2269E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is issued by a State or the Federal Government or is considered acceptable for purposes of sections 274a.2(b)(1)(v)(A) and 274a.2(b)(1)(v)(B)(1) of title 8, Code of Federal Regulations (including any successor regulations).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE08412EF3F854AB6AB5A2F2C5B707976"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>retailer</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H37EA7539B3FC45EFBFD0F6C4D9D616A3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a grocery store, general merchandise store, drug store, pharmacy, convenience store, or other entity whose activities as a seller of covered drugs containing dextromethorphan are limited almost exclusively to sales for personal use, both in number and volume of sales, including any sales made by the Internet or other means; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7D0404B4AF14AD9BA680394FCF09EFD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>excludes any entity listed in subparagraph (A) that does not sell any covered drug described in paragraph (1)(A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDDF9B24E27404FD89CEB64A7FE88D1F2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Civil penalties</header><text>Section 303 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/333">21 U.S.C. 333</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HACE461C870CF44939455D6E67666AAD4" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HBB736606A48F4338B376DF533159AF9E"><enum>(h)</enum><text>A retailer that violates section 301(eee) shall not be subject to subsection (a) or any civil monetary penalty under this Act for such violation except as follows<italic></italic>:</text>
 <paragraph id="HC40EA08BAFE548CD930181A6674CE5CF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary finds that a retailer fails to have a verification system in violation of section 301(eee)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBA4EED8D1C4449F1997C1CC9CCC837DE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>upon the first such finding, the Secretary shall issue a formal notice of violation and give the retailer a period of at least 30 days (beginning on the receipt of such notice) to correct the violation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD43913D2932D453DB65928FE7FE6B52D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>upon the second such finding, the retailer shall be subject to a civil penalty of not more than $1,000;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA5236AC5F95427EBE47F125B4A97BFF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>upon the third such finding, the retailer shall be subject to a civil penalty of not more than $2,000; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H76F15D8BFA604BABB64A9F47370E5A7C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>upon the fourth and any subsequent such finding, the retailer shall be subject to a civil penalty of not more than $5,000.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF230463E243448782B2B47D4F254DA3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In determining the amount of a civil penalty under this subsection for a retailer, the Secretary shall consider whether the retailer has taken appropriate steps to prevent subsequent violations, such as the establishment and administration of a documented employee training program to ensure all employees are familiar with, and abiding by, the retailer’s verification system established pursuant to section 506H, where such program includes—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H953A0C9B73194E40BB9E2E138381DEE2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>educating employees regarding covered drugs;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33E0CCE007354C159FC1E2969FE74870"><enum>(B)</enum><text>instruction on the correct method of checking a purchaser’s identification card; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02902EDD5EA04484A087C639565D2216"><enum>(C)</enum><text>notifying employees of the civil penalties under this subsection.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H68C5C1D111D9481BA028266FC1BBEE7C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>If a retailer transacts sales of covered drugs at more than one physical location, for purposes of determining the number of violations by that retailer under this subsection, each individual physical location operated by that retailer shall be considered a separate retailer.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H1200B29D8D934FCA8302EF89F3F77374"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Secretary shall notify retailers found to have violated section 301(eee) as soon as practicable after the Secretary discovers such violation. Such notification shall include the date and time when the failure to have a verification system as required by such section was observed to occur.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDE404F94AD294A9CB44BA77DC89654C2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In this subsection, the terms <term>covered drug</term> and <term>retailer</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 506H.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H0C017DEEE3324B50BDADA22A73B46817"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The amendments made by subsections (a), (b), and (c) shall apply with respect to drugs sold or offered for sale on or after the date that is one year after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA873B93B4E3642D0AB0ED5316BEBA432"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Sense of Congress regarding communication by organizations nominated by manufacturers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that organizations nominated by manufacturers of covered drugs (as defined in section 506H of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, as added by subsection (c)) should make reasonable efforts to communicate to retailers (as defined in such section 506H) the requirements of such section 506H, including by making available upon request materials (which may include signage, manuals, materials, or programs) to assist with educating employees regarding such covered drugs.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H9D2556AE3B424EF49A47ECBD158224C9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Restrictions on distribution of bulk dextromethorphan</header>
 <subsection id="H4130161E8DEC4AAC8228F5566387E39C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H2F9644B6258B4423BC9A4FA5127DE73A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 301 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/331">21 U.S.C. 331</external-xref>) (as amended by section 2(a)) by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD5F9920B98FF43DFBE7130674681118D" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HF124577A9B9342729C2A5ED47694B543"><enum>(ggg)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The possession, receipt, or distribution of unfinished dextromethorphan in violation of section 506I.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC3EC3D5BD243468CBA47E0AE51FF67F0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after section 506H (as added by section 2(b)) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE6A3F6792A8C4CD195808802EB58E316" style="OLC"> <section id="H68D8DDDDFCD441F982508189020EE3A1"><enum>506I.</enum><header>Restrictions on the distribution of bulk dextromethorphan</header> <subsection id="H023FC09946D54079857F0C2A649B0251"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No person shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2471F45AAC5A403CAF0E225FB4AE5B37"><enum>(1)</enum><text>possess or receive unfinished dextromethorphan, unless the person is registered under section 510 or otherwise registered, licensed, or approved pursuant to Federal or State law to engage in—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H01D56B527C334BCF80450E668447032B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the practice of pharmacy; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0DE23A9688F4F38BD84E956A43AAF39"><enum>(B)</enum><text>drug or drug ingredient discovery, production, manufacture, or distribution; or</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H469359ACED9F41179BDCBD19054217FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>distribute unfinished dextromethorphan to any person other than a person described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6F012A4EB6A74B4F83A837615D9C6C75"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception for common carriers</header><text>This section does not apply to a common carrier that possesses, receives, or distributes unfinished dextromethorphan for purposes of distributing such unfinished dextromethorphan between persons described in subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H06199CDAC13A4B5C954FE5D148877618"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H10A1CD1B11F344D5AD68FA9BC68452A9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>common carrier</term> means any person that holds itself out to the general public as a provider for hire of the transportation by water, land, or air of merchandise, whether or not the person actually operates the vessel, vehicle, or aircraft by which the transportation is provided, between a port or place and a port or place in the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H486FE4EBBA124CBB8F32568E70E048D8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>unfinished dextromethorphan</term> means dextromethorphan that is not contained in a drug that is in finished dosage form.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCD7E9312C7024BB09D83A27830A9C972"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by amending section 303, as amended by section 2(c), by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA8F912CC637E4FFE891C4C0A2CB5589C" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HF48172AA52CC45B48CB6F0D114D8EC0C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person that violates section 301(ggg) shall not be subject to subsection (a) or any civil monetary penalty under this Act for such violation except such person shall be subject to a civil penalty in an amount of not more than $100,000.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H28A4DF6341BB401D9F511C9D0539BBB4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section apply beginning on the date of enactment of this Act.</text> </subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

