<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H9F6F2B5F39C34F9F9012430A5C34A004" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2630 IH: La Paz County Land Conveyance Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2630</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170524">May 24, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain land to La Paz County, Arizona, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H2B818ADF09D546D988837225A1C13E5C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H6965A35CA066427A8D081D04F295AF5D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>La Paz County Land Conveyance Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H513C2E327D9C4D4CBEC8807CB7B15BF5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEE8A2884158C45F0AAC15065004982F6"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">County</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>County</quote> means La Paz County, Arizona.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1A181D93EA044EE3A7D253B5C31ACEC4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal land</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Federal land</term> means the approximately 8,000 acres of Federal land managed by the Bureau of Land Management and designated as <quote>Federal land to be conveyed</quote> on the map.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAB404A70A2564BC6A7AB653787B635B7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Map</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>map</quote> means the map prepared by the Bureau of Land Management entitled <quote>Proposed La Paz County Land Conveyance</quote> and dated May 24, 2017.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H032B119668ED47BBB73201FB6B19F250"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HB7CEC3BF7BD94EA9A3499B2A419D2DFA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Conveyance to La Paz County, Arizona</header>
 <subsection id="H04D364DAE98D44C6ADEAD49E626BACEF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Conveyance authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to valid existing rights and notwithstanding the land use planning requirements of sections 202 and 203 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1712">43 U.S.C. 1712</external-xref>, 1713), not later than 180 days after the date on which the Secretary receives a request from the County for the conveyance of the Federal land, the Secretary shall convey to the County, without consideration, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the Federal land.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H428A13B30CB94D7FA653D5C40803D6A1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of conveyed land</header>
 <paragraph id="H729E28A2A30543058B66D0451DFE406B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Federal land conveyed under subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="H6C2CACD14F2140D485CF25FF98C0455A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may be used by the County for any public purposes consistent with the Act of June 14, 1926 (commonly known as the <quote>Recreation and Public Purposes Act</quote>) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/869">43 U.S.C. 869</external-xref> et seq.); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD68E02CA04C6406586146295F95BBC6B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall not be disposed of by the County.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H849A8BA218974935933C060C1EA662D1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reversion</header><text>If the County ceases to use a parcel of the Federal land conveyed under subsection (a) in accordance with paragraph (1)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC41698E1C1B34888B9224EAB03436B30"><enum>(A)</enum><text>title to the parcel shall revert to the Secretary, at the option of the Secretary; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H877394D9F9F748CEBA158456C4C2BD93"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the County shall be responsible for any reclamation necessary for the parcel to revert to the United States.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H77B3BBA205DD4059B11BFE6B08E3ECBD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Availability of map</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Bureau of Land Management.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9840746C6E97429ABB6C8A72E5277F58"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Costs</header><text>At the closing for the conveyance of Federal land under subsection (a), the County shall pay or reimburse the Secretary, as appropriate, for the reasonable transaction and administrative personnel costs associated with the conveyance authorized under that subsection, including the costs of title searches, maps, and boundary and cadastral surveys.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC4D277203B0C4C3DA32CED3A984EDD36"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Release of United States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On conveyance of the Federal land under subsection (a), notwithstanding any other provision of law, the United States is released from any and all liabilities or claims of any kind or nature arising from the presence, release, or threat of release of any hazardous substance, pollutant, contaminant, petroleum product (or derivative of a petroleum product of any kind), solid waste, mine materials, or mining-related features (including tailings, overburden, waste rock, mill remnants, pits, or other hazards resulting from the presence of mining-related features) on the Federal land in existence before or on the date of the conveyance.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H8F583DEA60904B5AA95DE94BF8561659"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Acquisition of federal reversionary interest</header>
 <paragraph id="HF5C5D81660894EE8A32835446BAA471B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Request</header><text>After the date of conveyance of the Federal land under subsection (a), the County may submit to the Secretary a request to acquire the Federal reversionary interest in all or any portion of the Federal land.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HA56B8D7CF9F34D0EBA82CA4E7C1DC8C1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appraisal</header>
 <subparagraph id="H39F4FC3649C24543B84EC4298EAA4824"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of receipt of a request under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall complete an appraisal of the Federal reversionary interest in the Federal land requested by the County under that paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97BB85B8363A4B138212CC98D3C1F0CD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>The appraisal under subparagraph (A) shall be completed in accordance with—</text> <clause id="H5AC8FC131BD749838AA4A55D6DCD181E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Uniform Appraisal Standards for Federal Land Acquisitions; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3FDE3643E76746B28B880F0BC525222B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Uniform Standards of Professional Appraisal Practice.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H72267BC9B39D4F989E63253829AC4A70"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Conveyance required</header><text>If, by the date that is 1 year after the date of completion of the appraisal under paragraph (2), the County submits to the Secretary an offer to acquire the Federal reversionary requested under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall, not later than the date that is 30 days after the date on which the offer is submitted, convey to the County the reversionary interest covered by the offer.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3B93F2147B61407684C79055081738E1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>As consideration for the conveyance of the Federal reversionary interest under paragraph (3), the County shall pay to the Secretary an amount equal to the appraised value of the Federal reversionary interest, as determined under paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H788E44DF16E540DEAD54336DCA3C82D3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Costs of conveyance</header><text>As a condition of the conveyance of the Federal reversionary interest under paragraph (3), all costs associated with the conveyance (including the cost of the appraisal under paragraph (2)), shall be paid by the County.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBEF93B84B19B406E9CC22044049209F9"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Restrictions on use not applicable</header><text>On conveyance of the Federal reversionary interest to the County under paragraph (3), the restrictions on the use and disposal of the Federal land under subsection (b) shall not apply to any portion of the Federal land that was subject to the conveyed Federal reversionary interest.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


