<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H45D049F2D365473197C4F9A5DF6B50CF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3516 IH: Reduce Barriers to College Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3516</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170727">July 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barrag&#225;n</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Internal Revenue Service to meet higher standards in security screening and to improve the process for obtaining return information and verification of nonfiling in connection with completing a Free Application for Federal Student Aid (FAFSA).</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBA0925A136534183A0AEB291BC0A80EA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD7DF42BE5D404DD8AB4FF9FCA4203EBC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reduce Barriers to College Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="HED00D4173D2645A0A2805F9743AD0905"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improved IRS identity authentication process</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Commissioner of Internal Revenue shall ensure that the implemented authentication processes used for all current and future online applications provide the level of assurance required by National Institute for Standards and Technology standards for the determined level of authentication risk, as recommended by the Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration.</text></section> 
<section id="H65AC674B18514FAE98FE50172DD98379"><enum>3.</enum><header>Verification of nonfiling in connection with FAFSA application</header> 
<subsection id="HA7CBC005E08547D9BF014DD3D9ED91AF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Online portal</header> 
<paragraph id="H19E50385ADD2446B9D948C6012EB46BF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commissioner of Internal Revenue (in consultation with the Secretary of Education) shall establish an online portal for individuals to request and have submitted a verification of nonfiling for any taxable year to the Secretary of Education as part of the process of completing the individual’s Free Application for Federal Student Aid.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9A7C8138497149EB9C8533CA36A56DBF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authentication</header><text>Any such verification shall not be approved for submission through such portal process unless the individual’s identity is authenticated by a valid social security number and any one of the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE1EF91B716B24D348371E6C0FACEC3F7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Personal account number from a credit card, mortgage, home equity loan, home equity line of credit, or car loan.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEFCA55D8CF07456CBB67BDD229DA355F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Mobile phone with the individual’s name on the account.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7CB4EACE490049939861CE2E34FE4A5B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Household utility bill associated with the individual’s mailing address.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE9BB094CED214E5C9798219E6871E14D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Student transcripts.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H094DFF10466B4410BB070A34349C385B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Bank account statement.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3071A5F1F7D144419D85C2256105F6E2"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Passport or State issued driver’s license.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1D3C00D534834E20A896DCB895794EA4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Response time for verification of nonfiling in connection with FAFSA</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Internal Revenue Service shall, not later than 10 business days after receipt from the individual, process any request for, or respond to any inquiries relating to, a verification of nonfiling in connection with an individual’s Free Application for Federal Student Aid.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HE4CDD128F2EF4A0791D0825B5754F97B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Simplified needs test</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 479 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087ss">20 U.S.C. 1087ss</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H6660D6AC7B5745469F647BFBE8B79796"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1)(B)(i)(II), by inserting before the semicolon at the end the following: <quote>or has obtained a verification of nonfiling from the Commissioner of Internal Revenue</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB7B59318511441888BBBBEF29CA0C1D0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(2)(A)(ii), by inserting before the semicolon at the end the following: <quote>or has obtained a verification of nonfiling from the Commissioner of Internal Revenue</quote>. </text> </paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

