<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H4B9962DFDE8D446196C9E423AF01799D" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 153 IH: Michael E. DeBakey Stamp Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 153</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170103">January 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Al Green of Texas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the issuance of a forever stamp to honor the work of Dr. Michael Ellis DeBakey, who
			 helped develop the mobile army surgical hospital, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H1E6B23878F7A4EDCBB3734FB47640DA6" style="OLC">
 <section id="H51D1759145764C87A15F09FF77EE9387" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Michael E. DeBakey Stamp Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HFEAE5952B414484FA5A4FAA3BA489FE1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H70476D0B6E7C40988FB8B7CB0F464D3A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Dr. Michael E. DeBakey was widely considered to be one of the greatest surgeons ever, according to the Journal of the American Medical Association;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H383B7FD5336544F1952B304EEC5D6F7C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>his surgical inventions, such as the roller pump, which is a component of the heart-lung machine used in open-heart surgery, continue to save countless lives;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4101C4EAB6F947D5B6F08302A3C04CF5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Dr. DeBakey’s surgical innovations, for example the use of Dacron grafts for damaged arteries, revolutionized the practice of medicine nationally and globally;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H205EBDEC27CC4D5096EA97390B8E7B7C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>his commitment to military medicine helped shape the creation of the mobile army surgical hospital or MASH unit, and a medical program for returning veterans; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H24EFC5CBD147449D8A50D3D8744CCEB4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Dr. DeBakey was consulted regarding the health of several world leaders, including President Boris N. Yeltsin during the cold war.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HDE8BD1019077451D8307BCAEAC308B46"><enum>3.</enum><header>Michael E. DeBakey Stamp</header>
 <subsection id="H906BDC108FBF44029C13EA051CB585D0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In order to honor the work of Dr. Michael Ellis DeBakey, who helped develop the mobile army surgical hospital, the Postmaster General shall provide for the issuance of a forever stamp suitable for that purpose that depicts Dr. Michael E. DeBakey.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFA1D16BFC1624B6EBD32A20C9C72132C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>For purposes of this Act, the term <quote>forever stamp</quote> means a definitive stamp which meets the postage required for first-class mail up to one ounce in weight, and which retains full validity for that purpose even if the rate of that postage is later increased.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFA24EE860E1D4C5BB94304E9AAB6B9B7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The stamp described in subsection (a) shall be issued beginning as soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


