<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H5E38E62CF45E41628738C69D3DE34E7D" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1233 IH: Emergency Flood Response Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1233</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170227">February 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001166">Mr. McNerney</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to establish an emergency
			 flood activity pilot program to assist flood response efforts in response
			 to a levee failure or potential levee failure, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H4AE68300349C493F8D74A0317554D97B" style="OLC">
 <section id="HFC492C453D3746A6AEA3AB0BB9A5BFEB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Emergency Flood Response Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H5C3A8A7A061049F29DF7485B4D49EEC1" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Emergency Flood Activity Pilot Program</header> <subsection id="H1F249F6DF6164F8C856D7863D6A043E5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall establish and carry out a pilot program to assist flood response efforts at State and Federal regional levels in response to a levee failure or potential levee failure.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H76C668DE85DB48C1A80AEB42094CAD0A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the pilot program established under subsection (a), the Administrator may award grants to not more than 10 eligible entities to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H21406FBE182A498C944567AC62B962A3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish or maintain a flood emergency fund to be used for emergency flood activities described in subsection (f); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5E1C63A1FAE646AE9F56B33814EB1BDC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure a unified command system organizational framework for such activities.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H12FD205DD9CB438C958E230F17BF5C05"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall submit to the Administrator an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Administrator may require, including the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H2A4CD3D3849949BD8F95C1BC546CC7B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A plan describing the emergency flood activities for which the funds may be used as well as the levee safety plan that contains the unified command system that would carry out such activities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3078D6AD9E284B03976BE0CE48542F06"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A scope of work and tasks, project timeline, budget, and ongoing post-grant management plan.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2F34F6EE70674B33A69B1935D878EDB7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information regarding what entity maintains the flood emergency fund.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE8A0642F18584CB3BD02AF7890AEFA46"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A description of non-Federal contributions to the flood emergency fund.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H68AEA07F88A64BE38E5FE96898AF107C"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of how such plan will benefit the community, environment, and economy of the participating region within the legal boundaries of the applicant.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H11FF4A37EF354CC3A915F45031B26960"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Mechanisms for long-term replenishment of the flood emergency fund and a description of what percentage of the fund will be used—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H318BF274180344159A0AADD166A75590"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to support ongoing administrative project maintenance; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC53DC042E062427C851BEADF95A1CD08"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for the unified command system that would use and apply the fund in a flood emergency or post-flood recovery.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAE264A74613D45C7A906019D33EDAAFD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an eligible entity, in cooperation with appropriate local, State, and Federal agencies, shall establish criteria and procedures for use of the entity’s flood emergency fund in a flood emergency.</text>
			</subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H7E71B40551384D528948F08C94CCFF7A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Selection</header>
 <paragraph id="H5FB5C4AD9DFF4E5C9398C6C75A606356"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall award grants under subsection (b) on a competitive basis.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8DA540A51B4B4D5E9F4076BCDF346CCF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under subsection (b), the Administrator shall prioritize applications—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H8082082022E4450DAECEF82BBC3CF10E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>from eligible entities that represent a geographically diverse cross-section of the United States;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF2C190747EFA447294E51DB5AB68CF8D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that include opportunities to build on existing Federal and non-Federal flood relief efforts;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D447680BBBB49C0B3F3870CAEC40730"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">from eligible entities that have a flood safety plan approved by a levee maintaining agency; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B3E4978ABCC440588A6425CC4348BBF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>from eligible entities that have a local mitigation plan regarding hazard mitigation approved by the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H35DDE701E81A4336BA4447411D00C624"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Use of funds</header>
 <paragraph id="H11E9C24A23964E718C1A8C71BD9A5B6B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds awarded under this section may be used in the case of a flood for emergency flood activities, including planning and preparing to perform emergency flood activities, and to support ongoing administrative project maintenance. Emergency flood activities include prompt emergency action to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9282BD3B7ACB46A3BB811E9A78977347"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prevent levee failure;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35E4D6916D3541F689DBE34E7FFA4261"><enum>(B)</enum><text>close levee breaks;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H720CE4669E5A4B2AB0592EA12770E247"><enum>(C)</enum><text>make relief cuts and dewater flooded areas; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84EDD3D97BAD4B31A3AFC2799BB8A902"><enum>(D)</enum><text>otherwise physically limit the extent, depth, and duration of flood waters in the event of a levee failure.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE99D8AF979674D31A1F97D538A94EF6B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation on use of funds</header><text>Funds awarded under this section may not be used if—</text> <subparagraph id="HE5844B3CACE041B1819B2785CB3E0063"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the emergency flood activity is required by law to be performed by the Corps of Engineers; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F2B7E66EE464A608D74218213EC3567"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Corps of Engineers immediately exercises its authority to perform such activity.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H78FEE03DDA874D63A2CBC5EF158C71AA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Additional guidelines</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator, in consultation with the Corps of Engineers, shall establish any additional guidelines for the use of funds awarded under this section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H33B0ACB971C0400F977819FFA5608B79"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reimbursement of expenditures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a condition of a grant awarded to an eligible entity under subsection (b), the Administrator shall ensure that, following an expenditure of funds from the entity’s flood emergency fund, the entity will—</text>
 <paragraph id="H3707851C1CA4460190EA60B2C6ADAF4C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>seek all available State and Federal disaster assistance reimbursements for such expenditures; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB17350FF8FA24FF9B8F2F4DFAF08F23F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>deposit the reimbursements in the flood emergency fund.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H329E2E6991864D988BC1242757D2CAA6"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Federal share</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal share of the cost of a flood emergency activity carried out using grant funds made available under this section may not exceed 50 percent of the cost of such activity.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB4D45ABB46AF4773A2408943168BF7E6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H507454DF06394CBC8C96C4C91843831B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <quote>eligible entity</quote> means a State local levee maintaining agency or unit of local government that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE84A9621F6574CED94012FA2542A4899"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is responsible for emergency flood response efforts; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86C26690C5964072B9955003D5D24887"><enum>(B)</enum><text>maintains and operates a flood emergency fund.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E7E68185A90405E8C051C70FF397F91"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Flood emergency fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>flood emergency fund</quote> means a fund established, maintained, and operated by a levee maintaining agency or a local designated coordinating agency, including the maintenance of the accounting of all Federal and non-Federal funds and derivation of such funds.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H73920BA59731419EB2C3377A2B71C08D"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $50,000,000 to remain available until expended.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


