<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HDE679BA4998F481E959E67E62DE3F3A1" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4640 IH: National Centers of Excellence in Coastal Flood Research and Education Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4640</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171213">December 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000477">Mr. Taylor</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000804">Mr. Wittman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and in addition to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To designate public colleges and universities that provide research, data, and recommendations on
			 physical science, social science, economic analysis, policy analysis, risk
			 analysis, monitoring, predicting, and planning for coastal flooding as
			 National Centers of Excellence in Coastal Flood Research and Education.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H6E897E97FB17485EB74D223AA837C2AD" style="OLC">
 <section id="HBE523AB459A44548B01EE61FDF5F949D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Centers of Excellence in Coastal Flood Research and Education Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H011DD6E2C5004FC8B424664BF437E229"><enum>2.</enum><header>National Centers of Excellence in Coastal Flood Research and Education</header> <subsection id="H67C5281CDDA94C70A956AA4210E1577F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall designate public colleges and universities as National Centers of Excellence in Coastal Flood Research and Education (in this section referred to as <quote>National Centers of Excellence</quote>). The Administrator shall make the first such designations by not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCE8675C796294B0FB7A6224A9774237F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purposes of such designation are the following:</text> <paragraph id="H2FBE76DC410A4FAAB839D4E2DB80203F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To recognize those institutions of higher education that have exhibited national leadership in research and education in coastal flooding.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H08D860C895024AE3B4CA03A493F7B621"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To identify such National Centers of Excellence as sources for expert advice and guidance for Federal agencies engaged in coastal flooding research and education issues and projects.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9F3B417D05124772860272F59841D0F6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Criteria for designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall designate as National Centers of Excellence only those public universities and colleges that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H543BC1B4BB504F60A7378F922E6D48EE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>have demonstrated proven expertise in physical and environmental science, flooding, and socioeconomic impacts of flooding research;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8AC2C0910E174F58A5540329187C9665"><enum>(2)</enum><text>are located in a State that frequently experiences coastal flooding;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H072BB0565C5340DEAAE4F1E6CDE85000"><enum>(3)</enum><text>have previously partnered with, or received funds from, Federal agencies for coastal flooding and watershed issues, including the Corps of Engineers, the United States Geological Survey, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the Federal Emergency Management Agency, the National Science Foundation, the Department of Housing and Urban Development, and the National Aeronautics and Space Administration;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3776D9590ED240E58F210E6C52BB05C9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>have been designated by State legislation as technical and scientific advisory entities with respect to coastal flooding for State agencies and localities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8B30A6668647481495B264F3C28EBA62"><enum>(5)</enum><text>can demonstrate formal institutional collaborations in coastal flooding research and education with other public universities or colleges within the same State; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H62ECA468C99C4AC1A7E94B6D83F66E01"><enum>(6)</enum><text>can demonstrate a history of convening local, State, and Federal entities, including Department of Defense commands, to develop plans for coastal flooding.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H05830AD538DA416DAAC6B2D1EC434AE1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Partnerships and collaboration with Federal, regional, State, and local governments and
 organizations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">As a condition of designation as a National Center of Excellence under this Act, the Administrator shall require a public college or university to enter into an agreement with the Administrator under which it agrees to—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFD17A2F6EE594E9CA97CAC34826E5A76"><enum>(1)</enum><text>collaborate on Federal flood-related issues with Federal agencies such as the Federal Emergency Management Agency, the Environmental Protection Agency, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the National Science Foundation, and the Department of Agriculture;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFD529A28017A4510A80870224012128F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>collaborate and share best practices on regional, State, and locally specific flooding and flood-related issues with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H32A17E9A37F246D48A4894537E852CFA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>State, county, and local governments;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06FFCD6B880D462BB5FF37F41A493B33"><enum>(B)</enum><text>local councils of governments or regional planning organizations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD89A416BC303457DB4C1D70A7854B5AC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>State agriculture, natural resource, environment, economic development, and water agencies;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC07D5E112F564555A37982C7239AD4F5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>floodplain managers;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5BDF331CD0145A6B21BA6FBAE81B230"><enum>(E)</enum><text>State homeland security personnel, county disaster recovery coordinators, emergency management personnel, and first responders;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6BD8EC54F33485BB6E4AAB6D2218DF4"><enum>(F)</enum><text>resource conservation and development councils;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE3C2EEFA50D343A4A5DA0315EB66DAE8"><enum>(G)</enum><text>watershed organizations and boards;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6FA160E70C45454ABB5FDD0ECAA801E2"><enum>(H)</enum><text>agriculture and commodity organizations and farmers;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC17876DE01804C3C914D8DDDA964B199"><enum>(I)</enum><text>environmental organizations; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD52DB600CB264646A3204177271C5A4E"><enum>(J)</enum><text>business and development organizations; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H18C8BEE19AEA4620B4896E5B124F9FEF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>explore opportunities to collaborate, when appropriate, on Federal flood-related issues with other Federal agencies such as the Bureau of Reclamation, the Tennessee Valley Authority, the Bureau of Land Management, the National Park Service, the Bureau of Indian Affairs, the Public Health Service, the National Science Foundation, the Department of Defense, the Department of the Interior, the Department of Housing and Urban Development, and various national laboratories.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H1AE89CD608914FD39B256D97391AF3A3"><enum>4.</enum><header>Information collection and dissemination; reviews and additional designations</header>
 <subsection id="HAD7C7BF217324653BE37E92C040B932B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>The Administrator shall annually submit to Congress and the President a report describing the activities, partnerships and collaborations, Federal policy recommendations, previous and continuing budgets, and findings of, and any other applicable information from, the National Centers of Excellence, and make such report available to the public in an easily accessible electronic format on website of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H835EAD32E25F4BE59760B082E7C1D36B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review of reports from National Centers of Excellence</header><text>The Administrator shall review reports from National Centers of Excellence to ensure that recommendations and guidance of such Centers in regard to flooding and flood-related issues are communicated to relevant Federal agencies.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6C04A897825F4241A11F5EC0D451B2C5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Review of National Centers of Excellence and potential designees</header><text>The Administrator shall periodically review the National Centers of Excellence and potential new designees as such Centers, to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H38331FAD15744720B7E040B39AE9EB24"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that the National Centers of Excellence continue to meet the criteria for designation under this Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDFEC0B7FB512485D9E3ABFBA523AC249"><enum>(2)</enum><text>designate additional National Centers of Excellence in accordance with this Act.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

