<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H8B74E153201F44EA8456ACD94474ADDE" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4022 IH: Reach Every Mother and Child Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4022</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171011">October 11, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000578">Mr. Reichert</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000625">Mr. Donovan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To implement a strategic approach for providing foreign assistance in order to end preventable
			 child and maternal deaths globally within a generation, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H7592BCA371D64367892BF2529733540E" style="OLC">
 <section id="H66780567BA69438382F9DA37DBAB9BA3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reach Every Mother and Child Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H5164D78B1C2147E19D8286AF7B6CF813"><enum>2.</enum><header>Assistance to end preventable child and maternal deaths</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151">22 U.S.C. 2151</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end of chapter 1 of part I the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="H454513CFBE694EA9BACEFF99AF38482C">
				<section id="HDF898646A052499E98175FBC50A6DD29"><enum>137.</enum><header>Assistance to end preventable child and maternal deaths</header>
 <subsection id="HD77020C36AE147D2A0782E952935FCFD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that United States foreign assistance efforts should focus on countries, regions, and communities with the greatest need and the highest burden of preventable child and maternal deaths.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5A862F68F97846E3984BF47B016260F8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text>It shall be the policy of the United States, in coordination with recipient countries and relevant partner entities, to establish and implement a coordinated, integrated, and comprehensive strategy to combat the leading causes of maternal, newborn, and child mortality globally and ensure healthy and productive lives for women and children, by—</text>
 <paragraph id="HCD8149CF88474E39BD58AF7FBE6C3D82"><enum>(1)</enum><text>scaling up the highest-impact, evidence-based interventions, including for the most vulnerable populations, with a focus on country ownership;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE43BBD7AD9524367B3F30809CA5E0021"><enum>(2)</enum><text>designing, implementing, monitoring, and evaluating programs in a way that enhances transparency and accountability, increases sustainability, and improves outcomes in target countries; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H677304A3D05840B2BFBAFB8CAC992432"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supporting the development and scale-up of innovative tools and approaches to accelerate progress toward ending preventable child and maternal deaths and reach the goal of saving the lives of 15,000,000 children and 600,000 women.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF233D7A3216B432EA9782CD06F578438"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Strategy</header>
 <paragraph id="H412B0B9178794AE7905C8B2E039EAB79"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, the President shall establish and implement a comprehensive five-year, whole-of-government strategy to accelerate progress toward ending preventable child and maternal deaths within a generation and ensure healthy and productive lives for women and children.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE3016AEA0D274F84A47E00C5EAF6B676"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The strategy established under <internal-xref idref="H412B0B9178794AE7905C8B2E039EAB79" legis-path="137.(c)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref> shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H9C4EE6F3EB6B47648F79F5CE7A1DF41B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>set specific, outcome-based, and measurable targets to achieve the goals of the strategy and identify baseline data for each target country and for all areas of focus and programming, as of the date of the publication of such strategy;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0EA934F426384C6BBEA31F0495461FD7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>incorporate existing Federal strategies and frameworks relevant to ending preventable child and maternal deaths, including specific objectives, programs, and approaches to implement highest-impact, evidence-based interventions, to address the leading causes of death in target countries, particularly among the most vulnerable populations, for—</text>
 <clause id="H817678545AF04EF29804779D40FAB1E8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>women, related to pregnancy, childbirth, or the post-delivery period;</text> </clause><clause id="HEE8AEED249304D62B445C206BB225AD6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>newborn children during their first 28 days; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6CC18765352542AF967F0FBE5D4D03B4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>infants and children under the age of five;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5689E4846504A298F38B9910B49D4D8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>include development and scale up of new technologies and approaches, including those supported by public-private partnerships for research and innovation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3462961E98AE42B9BA4D096BF025AF96"><enum>(D)</enum><text>promote coordination and efficiency within and amongst the relevant Federal departments and agencies;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB653181AB47A470EA2557A9290232933"><enum>(E)</enum><text>project the general levels of resources needed to achieve the strategy’s stated objectives;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H246186183935450DB6D5777690F935A7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>identify strategies for leveraging resources with new and innovative financial tools;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H24522940B60C490BBF14C3911ABC6CD7"><enum>(G)</enum><text>align with the maternal, newborn, and child health and survival plans of target countries and improve coordination with foreign governments and international organizations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H46E730C67C7243E0B5175D97AEF935E6"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">outline consultations with target countries and relevant partner entities;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2EDFC39180E5446C8EA3BD1DA61C838F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>implement results-based contracting, such as pay-for-outcome arrangements, and reduce financial and operational risks;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB883680147CC4311B6DB265AA552D874"><enum>(J)</enum><text>promote a shift toward inclusive and sustainable investments;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5B3E10FE38B4845A85DF0BDD7673F3B"><enum>(K)</enum><text>support the transition to sustainably financed, domestic health systems in target countries; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBAB4781512074A549863E6197188E020"><enum>(L)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promote partnerships with organizations that have a long-term presence in target countries and have shown evidence of sustainable community impact, including through the capacity building of local and community-based organizations.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE1BEC059A7A44E6B424AD6739A72E7D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Identification of target countries</header><text>For purposes of the strategy under <internal-xref idref="H412B0B9178794AE7905C8B2E039EAB79" legis-path="137.(c)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref>, the Administrator shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H3C7F934FAEBB49F8902A00B2731E9D27"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify each country that has the greatest need and faces the highest burden of preventable child and maternal deaths, taking into consideration countries that—</text>
 <clause id="HE85CBE1074444055B6D8A3E5F1DE570A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>have high-need, underserved, marginalized, vulnerable, or impoverished communities;</text> </clause><clause id="H08552256BE594BE39CAF8D940C3C49EB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are fragile or conflict-affected countries;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB92AB922FF7E4FEDA35FAD41C3E57A6E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>are low- or middle-income countries; or</text> </clause><clause id="HEE622F0344B54559B2721E2900A2911E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>are located in regions with weak health systems; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDEBD5D57D7B441129D16689C5E84D7B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establish transparent selection criteria for such target countries.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8CAE946C2B7F417CB0DBE98BE2BC7271"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Improving coordination and oversight</header> <paragraph id="H8BED5E54378B4220BE7EE98958ABDBA7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment of senior coordinator for child and maternal survival</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall designate a current employee serving in a career or non-career position in the Senior Executive Service or at the level of a Deputy Assistant Administrator or higher at the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) to serve concurrently as the Senior Coordinator for Child and Maternal Survival.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA55F5CF89FF54AFC99971C51C56DB784"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Senior Coordinator shall—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H743011C206A04EDB826E9552F346B018"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have the primary responsibility for the oversight and coordination of international maternal and child health and nutrition funding managed by the USAID Bureau of Global Health;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9BDF28B4F7A2446D9059B3E10CA01B54"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">lead the development of the strategy established under <internal-xref idref="HF233D7A3216B432EA9782CD06F578438" legis-path="137.(c)">subsection (c)</internal-xref> and its implementation by USAID, including by directing the budget, planning, and staffing with respect to such implementation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC9559A734324CBBA6CBC6FC6CC2BFDC"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilitate program and policy coordination of international maternal and child health and nutrition programs between the USAID, other relevant Federal departments and agencies, and relevant partner entities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A5DB844419E4747A9F9DB87C8AB9B4D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>monitor, evaluate, and report on any activities undertaken by USAID pursuant to the strategy required under <internal-xref idref="HF233D7A3216B432EA9782CD06F578438" legis-path="137.(c)">subsection (c)</internal-xref>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4E87E53749947BC89B2876B8F305AFD"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide direction to the design and oversight of grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements with any recipient of funds under the responsibility of the Senior Coordinator pursuant to <internal-xref idref="H743011C206A04EDB826E9552F346B018" legis-path="137.(d)(2)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C902BD81413495690782441DE168D28"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Restriction on additional or supplemental compensation</header><text>The Senior Coordinator shall not receive any additional or supplemental compensation as a result of carrying out responsibilities and duties under this section.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H29FB9B6E35064E9E8F0A5C00650D8895"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Prioritization of greatest need and maximum impact</header>
 <paragraph id="HB1857E4B7F8A411FA565BDFE13E7DA51"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Targets for increased implementation required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In accordance with the guidelines established under section 3 of the Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act, any grant made available by the Administrator and any contract or cooperative agreement entered into by the Administrator in order to implement the strategy established under <internal-xref idref="HF233D7A3216B432EA9782CD06F578438" legis-path="137.(c)">subsection (c)</internal-xref> of this section shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H138F163ED7464C7A91E7F8849E495F85"><enum>(A)</enum><text>include targets for increased implementation of high-impact, evidence-based interventions and strengthening health systems, as appropriate; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1796BD4F36AB4CC296317A6910CDCDFB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establish baseline measurements from which to quantify progress toward such targets and towards the goal of preventing life-threatening morbidity and mortality for at least 15,000,000 children and at least 600,000 women, as described in <internal-xref idref="H677304A3D05840B2BFBAFB8CAC992432" legis-path="137.(b)(3)">subsection (b)(3)</internal-xref>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H121D5980FCBD4D4B8B39AD24B1204851"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>In exceptional circumstances when the Administrator determines that the inclusion of coverage targets or baseline measures is not reasonable or practicable for a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement, the funding mechanism for such grant, contract, or agreement shall include an explanation of the omission and explicitly state how measurable impact will be targeted and tracked.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H04C62A19D7B448B8A0F45F29CAE96596"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Use of innovative public-Private financing tools</header>
 <paragraph id="H7D2733230C05486F88DB4F4B439A121F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In addition to existing bilateral and multilateral assistance for child and maternal survival, the Administrator shall implement the strategy established under <internal-xref idref="HF233D7A3216B432EA9782CD06F578438" legis-path="137.(c)">subsection (c)</internal-xref> through the use of innovative financing tools, where appropriate, to expand delivery of highest-impact, evidence-based interventions to address the leading causes of preventable child and maternal deaths, particularly among vulnerable populations. The Administrator shall also explore models, whether existing or innovative, to improve the efficiency and effectiveness of investments through results-based contracting (such as pay-for-outcome arrangements) and reduce financial and operational risks with respect to such implementation.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="HED140CCA27294D35BE099A5B583E8AB0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization to fund programs on pay-for-outcome basis</header>
 <subparagraph id="H94FD5796CF9A40CD9F8D334E0D14C7E5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall have the authority to provide assistance for child and maternal survival on a pay-for-outcome basis, as described in <internal-xref idref="HF23B03521C55456B9063BBB08943EB83" legis-path="137.(f)(2)(B)">subparagraph (B)</internal-xref>, to any initiative that meets the requirements described in <internal-xref idref="HF6B6EB137BAE4C168BC28A14A950C8AC" legis-path="137.(f)(2)(C)">subparagraph (C)</internal-xref>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF23B03521C55456B9063BBB08943EB83"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Pay-for-outcome basis described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The pay-for-outcome basis described in this paragraph is a performance-based grant, contract, or cooperative agreement awarded in the form of a commitment to provide payments that is contingent on improved outcomes resulting in a social benefit to the public and in direct cost savings or cost avoidance to the United States Government.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6B6EB137BAE4C168BC28A14A950C8AC"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Requirements for pay-for-outcome funding</header><text>The Administrator may only provide assistance under <internal-xref idref="H94FD5796CF9A40CD9F8D334E0D14C7E5" legis-path="137.(f)(2)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref> to an initiative that includes the following:</text> <clause id="H2028394F6ED94E7DA973409A3208131D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A detailed implementation plan describing how the proposed pay-for-outcome initiative is based on evidence supporting an expectation of improved effectiveness.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2910188C7C3E4E9B998C3D67554E8809"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A rigorous, independent, third-party evaluation, using experimental or quasi-experimental design or other quantitative research methodologies, that allows for the strongest possible causal inferences, when random assignment is not feasible, to determine whether the initiative has achieved the proposed improvement in outcomes.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B58D5F55B50427CA14B9993931EC33C"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Limitation on availability of funding</header><text>Any payments provided to an initiative pursuant to the authorization under <internal-xref idref="H94FD5796CF9A40CD9F8D334E0D14C7E5" legis-path="137.(f)(2)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref> may only be made available for expenditure for not more than 5 years after the date on which such payments are first made available.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE40242C4DDD44CE1AF512CAB94210C61"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reports</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H54DA9C410F0747F1A721A1909C74174D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Report required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the publication of the strategy required under <internal-xref idref="HF233D7A3216B432EA9782CD06F578438" legis-path="137.(c)">subsection (c)</internal-xref>, and annually thereafter, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees, and make publicly available, a report describing the implementation of the strategy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H966BA214A67F4E5DA0FFDC2C40E1FCFA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information included in report</header><text>The report required under <internal-xref idref="H54DA9C410F0747F1A721A1909C74174D" legis-path="137.(g)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref> shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HCC854E0308FC44DEA6F35A4C0D91302D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A summary and evaluation of progress made to achieve the objectives described in <internal-xref idref="H5A862F68F97846E3984BF47B016260F8" legis-path="137.(b)">subsection (b)</internal-xref>, including the goal to end preventable child and maternal deaths, and the progress made toward achieving the goal of reducing life threatening morbidity and mortality for at least 15,000,000 children and at least 600,000 women.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF592D0A34A14E2E8D6F2329239612F9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of the nature and extent of coordination among relevant Federal departments and agencies on the implementation of the strategy.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E063EDFB08B4B3EBC982A20F09A3D15"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A description of how each aspect of the strategy is being implemented, including—</text> <clause id="H2AE72FFC53944EA7B72B95F1F0700877"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the manner in which multi-sectoral approaches and concrete, high-impact, evidence-based interventions are being used to address the leading causes of preventable child and maternal deaths;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H144C242D4650417C822B84B3DD3139E0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the degree to which the strategy increases assistance to and activities by the United States in target countries;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6F9DC731ED7643859A73DE99119B9D58"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the use of programs, projects, or activities to develop and scale-up new technologies and approaches, including those identified by public-private partnerships for research and innovation, and the degree to which such programs, projects, or activities are posed to go to scale; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA95815551D1748828DC80140D1F47808"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the methods used to leverage innovative financing and other public and private resources and the progress made by such methods.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8A2AC689DD64D5D902ADB479F8A7097"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A description of how each program, project, or activity implementing the strategy is designed to—</text> <clause id="HD5CF55F1E7334021B95343F0FA6FCF69"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reach underserved, marginalized, vulnerable, or impoverished populations;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7646374D40B0427486F6AA6A49EF72EA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">address the causes of newborn, infant, child, and maternal morbidity and mortality, including pre-term births, with innovative efforts and interventions;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD64D7262D7104CF6AFE55D50DA64C573"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">invest in programs, projects, or activities that empower women, support voluntarism, and provide quality, respectful, evidence-based maternity care;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5F2A7EC0FCD94B91872FB075D7D4093C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improve transparency and accountability at all levels and include common metrics for tracking progress in achieving the objectives of the strategy;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8E912DED36574825BFCAD37A04657D6E"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that high-impact, evidence-based interventions are prioritized, including interventions promoting healthy pregnancies; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H03BB5A4C5E374C8C90821693A9BB66A9"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expand access to quality services for healthcare workers and for communities in target countries and include measures of accountability to such communities.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD60356A18ADC4B24A2DF1792A6B180EF"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A comprehensive list of grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements awarded to implement the strategy, that includes—</text>
 <clause id="HFC97181FF98C4B86A148EDD956525630"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the targets for coverage of interventions or services supported by such grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements, the baseline against which they are measured, and the status of their progress in meeting the targets; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H53E96985F0D642679DBA4EC46C52C712"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of exceptional circumstances where the inclusion of targets or baseline measurements is not reasonable or practicable, an explanation of how the impact of the grant, contract, agreement, or resulting program is being measured.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9D365AD087A47AF86E4CCD4CE95563B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A description of how the Administrator has partnered with relevant partner entities at the national and local levels, including as subgrantees.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D91D34E99744C5DA47A4CF4558ED27A"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A determination, after applying rigorous monitoring and evaluation methodologies, whether the programs, projects, or activities implementing the strategy have achieved measurable improvements in child and maternal health or survival, particularly among the most vulnerable populations, in each target country and overall, and the specific improvements achieved with respect to—</text>
 <clause id="H9B7B75ABADF94CE587607B4BF0CC8D22"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the maternal mortality ratio per 100,000 live births and the under-5 mortality ratio per 1,000 live births;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB14D26B8C4E44D63AF0684DE81A7A15C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of newborn, infant, child, and maternal deaths averted; and</text> </clause><clause id="H0AC9121C9C3A46AE8A0816F561CEAD70"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the percentage of births attended by skilled health personnel.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC34E9A334904AB283B73592AC60C0E2"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An analysis of the gaps in the health workforce that must be filled in order to end preventable newborn, infant, child and maternal deaths, including an analysis of health workforce density relating to certified health workers and community-based health workers.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34242A81551140CCB7B331332FC4D2AF"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the measured or estimated impact on newborn, infant, child, and maternal survival of each ongoing program, project, or activity implementing the strategy.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4AA52A351E3A49C69D56E58B7499E6B6"><enum>(J)</enum><text>An assessment of progress made toward achieving the targets established pursuant to <internal-xref idref="H9C4EE6F3EB6B47648F79F5CE7A1DF41B" legis-path="137.(c)(2)(A)">subsection (c)(2)(A)</internal-xref>.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93684702EA9E423384597554EEBAB077"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of any innovative public-private financing tools, including an analysis of the feasibility and potential effectiveness, that could be used to fund efforts to end preventable child and maternal deaths.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9681091A667B4882A0CF15F707F69CAB"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H56BDC54074AC48E5A4B14E08AE9D86B0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5F078103673C43C1B04FFDF88129E0BD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HFFC8293994E94B3CBCADE8725AA2F67B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8997948632D742AC8F11CCB25210C230"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD61E73FB1584406CB8B9373EC178350B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Relevant Federal departments and agencies</header><text>The term <term>relevant Federal departments and agencies</term> includes each of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H839A3413671D454BB36CE675686D7C4D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Department of State.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF8C45A4061024E368CBF6D8F222F4B35"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The United States Agency for International Development, including the President’s Malaria Initiative.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0EEFE82602C443DBAAC048750EC99FA8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Department of Health and Human Services.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6DB3F9DAFC624FBCA91AF3E107613655"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Department of the Treasury.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE3E667ED9FFD44C99F4D9A3B336319F1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Department of Defense.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF0E8EF651079414BB5884A2A6A583ECD"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D18939A4D4146F19F0D71BDA08FB871"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The National Institutes of Health.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H408F08C74C414FC298919C38D8A688C8"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The Millennium Challenge Corporation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D468C894D3548648D75BE18FA5ECA4B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The Peace Corps.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB3F0B259838541B186ECEC13A53757A1"><enum>(J)</enum><text>The Office of the Global AIDS Coordinator.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCEDFCEB677F94B5CBAC6B4B821BCDFDE"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other Federal department or agency determined by the President to be relevant to carry out the purposes of this section.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8FEEF69B41F8425CA5BE15AE1C90355A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Relevant partner entities</header><text>The term <term>relevant partner entities</term> means each of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HEF13D1BD3CEB49B19BF6356DFD1677DB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Multilateral and international organizations.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF000ACD412BC48B78BE21ED102E33C0D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>International financial institutions.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA4053CAA0DC4C46B3A98BA2F90D1C9F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The national and local governments of recipient countries.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB39BB134F1D49009A6600180A27007D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Community nongovernmental organizations, including faith-based, professional, and civil society organizations.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF741C2E613BD4B1CBE2A138870137BB2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Entities in the private sector.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D0B3EE74819496A8827D405BD28F04D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Entities in the healthcare sector of recipient countries.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF67CED3319C94F6399DEE69DCE0B28D3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Senior Coordinator</header><text>The term <term>Senior Coordinator</term> means the Senior Coordinator for Child and Maternal Survival established under <internal-xref idref="H8CAE946C2B7F417CB0DBE98BE2BC7271" legis-path="137.(d)">subsection (d)</internal-xref>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H85B15A6A4C944EFABE64D2045F542B34"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Target country</header><text>The term <quote>target country</quote> means a country identified by the Administrator pursuant to <internal-xref idref="HFE1BEC059A7A44E6B424AD6739A72E7D" legis-path="137.(c)(3)">subsection (c)(3)</internal-xref>.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


