<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H765430D2A6C742B89388206890701D2B" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1302 EH: Terrorist and Foreign Fighter Travel Exercise Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IB</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1302</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To require an exercise related to terrorist and foreign fighter travel, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H75A4F365EE8A4FB89A0C6D063F644F02" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H17972AE7A4964392A48F89A94A70F1AA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Terrorist and Foreign Fighter Travel Exercise Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5904B8619AF5408692617B58C1A59FBB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Exercise on terrorist and foreign fighter travel</header> <subsection id="H563A89B9DCB748BC9698C84E443CFB38"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to, or as part of exercise programs currently carried out by the Department of Homeland Security, to enhance domestic preparedness for and collective response to terrorism, promote the dissemination of homeland security information, and test the security posture of the United States, the Secretary of Homeland Security, through appropriate offices and components of the Department and in coordination with the relevant Federal departments and agencies, shall, not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, develop and conduct an exercise related to the terrorist and foreign fighter threat.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H86BDA836B3A3410BA0B36C145B757021"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exercise requirements</header><text>The exercise required under subsection (a) shall include—</text> <paragraph id="HCCF621275CB14C988DEB7D2D2119D262"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a scenario involving—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8B0AF37C66C747AAAE45B702EE9CCF22"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">persons traveling from the United States to join or provide material support or resources to a terrorist organization abroad; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE2608E6C6B8B4AA9A5590361722D4571"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">terrorist infiltration into the United States, including United States citizens and foreign nationals; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9292F57269444CECB8CDABC745E5EDD5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>coordination with relevant Federal departments and agencies, foreign governments, and State, local, tribal, territorial, and private sector stakeholders.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA748409C940F494CB56BEEED2A576604"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the completion of the exercise required under subsection (a), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall, consistent with the protection of classified information, submit an after-action report to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate presenting the initial findings of such exercise, including any identified or potential vulnerabilities in United States defenses and any legislative changes requested in light of the findings. The report shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3A1C57B44AF1417097646D097F49A995"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>material support or resources</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 2339A of title 18, United States Code.</text> </subsection></section> <section id="HAB86993FA6794319881B352A4258A605"><enum>3.</enum><header>Emerging threats in the national exercise program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subparagraph (A) of section 648(b)(2) of the Post-Katrina Emergency Management Reform Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/748">6 U.S.C. 748(b)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5239695E34D147568EA0C0CC2B338C39"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (v), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H155362A0D2614BA08FF4A50C25F38622"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding after clause (vi) the following new clause:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD16D7D852E79427BBE1D7715CB1604AD" style="OLC"> 
<clause id="H0620F530F3F74C2CA52476B582E4E748"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">designed, to the extent practicable, to include exercises addressing emerging terrorist threats, such as scenarios involving United States citizens departing the United States to enlist with or provide material support or resources to terrorist organizations abroad or terrorist infiltration into the United States, including United States citizens and foreign nationals; and</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA2D07B0934074C3A94AD87C3A620E521"><enum>4.</enum><header>No additional funds authorized</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to carry out the requirements of this Act and the amendments made by this Act. Such requirements shall be carried out using amounts otherwise authorized.</text> </section> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20170322" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives March 24, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> 
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> 
</bill> 


