<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD4A55126FEDE4033A5898DA7AA4F15BD" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1615 IH: Get Foreign Money Out of U.S. Elections Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1615</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170317">March 17, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001304">Mr. Brown of Maryland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001049">Mr. Clay</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000754">Mr. Cooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001038">Mr. Higgins of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000390">Mr. Kihuen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001166">Mr. McNerney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000170">Mr. O'Rourke</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001168">Mr. Sarbanes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to apply the ban on contributions and
			 expenditures by foreign nationals under such Act to foreign-controlled,
			 foreign-influenced, and foreign-owned domestic corporations, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H0191B24FDCBE4BCF8E490A3406847375" style="OLC">
 <section id="HA60DD8B8C1D04FAAAFE190C048947C38" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Get Foreign Money Out of U.S. Elections Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H61E40846AC4B480E8D06F495EED9D2B6" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Application of ban on contributions and expenditures by foreign nationals to domestic corporations that are foreign-controlled, foreign-influenced, and foreign-owned</header> <subsection id="H0903EC5DC47E47A595C3241FCCB57092"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Application of ban</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 319(b) of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30121">52 U.S.C. 30121(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0ACAEAB84FD5442EA8959DD874502613"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of paragraph (1);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC7C53908CE804EC9B743334DE23CFA2B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of paragraph (2) and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8EA8B68A93BC4502BAD4B7F7B70A602B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8000BF7EC9394898A841FEE704CF7F20" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H51D52EA774B24B21A4C283C91119DBFD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any corporation which is not a foreign national described in paragraph (1) and—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC3EA1BA3051A4B0BB5CF9D77FA2BAFAE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in which a foreign national described in paragraph (1) or (2) directly or indirectly owns or controls—</text>
 <clause id="HE14B26B3588F4CF290E5C96A27AA5E5A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>5 percent or more of the voting shares, if the foreign national is a foreign country, a foreign government official, or a corporation principally owned or controlled by a foreign country or foreign government official; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD5BA834AD40442E182690C54481FE40F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>20 percent or more of the voting shares, if the foreign national is not described in clause (i);</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD34B52098A74EA88768378CD20FC6DA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in which two or more foreign nationals described in paragraph (1) or (2), each of whom owns or controls at least 5 percent of the voting shares, directly or indirectly own or control 50 percent or more of the voting shares;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H055F104B8DB54AE4983927B809474682"><enum>(C)</enum><text>over which one or more foreign nationals described in paragraph (1) or (2) has the power to direct, dictate, or control the decisionmaking process of the corporation with respect to its interests in the United States; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H187F03FF6249469A8497E955B0015C98"><enum>(D)</enum><text>over which one or more foreign nationals described in paragraph (1) or (2) has the power to direct, dictate, or control the decisionmaking process of the corporation with respect to activities in connection with a Federal, State, or local election, including—</text>
 <clause id="HAE71B1C9D83B4ADD9BD39198C9CCE114"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the making of a contribution, donation, expenditure, independent expenditure, or disbursement for an electioneering communication (within the meaning of section 304(f)(3)); or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H77121234D8664DE59C2E3744395674BC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the administration of a political committee established or maintained by the corporation.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFCDCD109D5B141A4B703EF7E49BC67B6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certification of Compliance</header><text>Section 319 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30121">52 U.S.C. 30121</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9D4C16A42D144A43BFB52F3538056DCE" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H7C8712411EC04872AB243CB84A252EEA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Certification of compliance required prior to carrying out activity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prior to the making in connection with an election for Federal office of any contribution, donation, expenditure, independent expenditure, or disbursement for an electioneering communication by a corporation during a year, the chief executive officer of the corporation (or, if the corporation does not have a chief executive officer, the highest ranking official of the corporation), shall file a certification with the Commission, under penalty of perjury, that the corporation is not prohibited from carrying out such activity under subsection (b)(3), unless the chief executive officer has previously filed such a certification during the year.</text>
					</subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6C602BADAC8F4C5C87F63634D2A4B105"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall take effect upon the expiration of the period which begins on the date of the enactment of this Act, and shall take effect without regard to whether or not the Federal Election Commission has promulgated regulations to carry out such amendments.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HA630ACFECB664DF4933350275E32414E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Clarification of application of foreign money ban to certain disbursements and activities</header>
 <subsection id="H4B5A1AE0BCF0411A9C1B0AB8E0DF274D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Application to disbursements to Super PACs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 319(a)(1)(A) of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30121">52 U.S.C. 30121(a)(1)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by striking the semicolon and inserting the following: <quote>, including any disbursement to a political committee which accepts donations or contributions that do not comply with the limitations, prohibitions, and reporting requirements of this Act (or any disbursement to or on behalf of any account of a political committee which is established for the purpose of accepting such donations or contributions);</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC27AF36B90A64D0AAEFA7822BA45B2BB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conditions under which corporate PACs may make contributions and expenditures</header><text>Section 316(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30118">52 U.S.C. 30118(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA0F1A05390574CA7B772602FA9B5441E" style="traditional">
 <paragraph id="HC139623AE5DA429CAF3A093FA7ECCC1B" indent="up1"><enum>(8)</enum><text>A separate segregated fund established by a corporation may not make a contribution or expenditure during a year unless the year the fund has certified to the Commission the following during the year:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2667F1181A384D949A979D4E6AB1C4EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Each individual who manages the fund, and who is responsible for exercising the decisionmaking authority of the fund, is a citizen of the United States or is lawfully admitted for permanent residence in the United States.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H03268BC9B06041649EADBC41A70032D9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>No foreign national under section 319 participates in any way in the decisionmaking processes of the fund with regard to contributions or expenditures under this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37A096EC2F134480847B6E035A7F5164"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The fund does not solicit or accept recommendations from any foreign national under section 319 with respect to the contributions or expenditures made by the fund.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFADDE08B13F14C448A9C5BC5D94FA3B1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Any member of the board of directors of the corporation who is a foreign national under section 319 abstains from voting on matters concerning the fund or its activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


