<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H7AF029ED183B473C951C3D8BF787073D" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3367 IH: License Natural Gas Now Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3367</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170724">July 24, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To terminate the prohibitions on the exportation and importation of natural gas, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H1A28BE5AF86D415DB3EAC99044FB8F26" style="OLC">
 <section id="HB42C8817EEBD42B98B4139584D7AA12D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>License Natural Gas Now Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>LNG Now Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H7BC676412CA147E383647F149057F988"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H5A0CE74854F1469AB7F6E524EE7C885F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the exportation of natural gas produced in the United States is in the interest of the United States; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H368E401FDF4B452C923BC7883F4F91FF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>because natural gas produced in the United States has a lower greenhouse gas emissions profile than other energy sources used in high volumes in other countries, the exportation of natural gas from the United States may help lower global emissions of carbon dioxide.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HE8A6CF887BA248A6BED8DD6DB8E68E18"><enum>3.</enum><header>Exportation or importation of natural gas</header>
 <subsection id="H7C230FA493A74A40AC201A7D3475D7F4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3 of the Natural Gas Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/717b">15 U.S.C. 717b</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HAF2B8D4CEFD44B4CA3C8C0FC8A2EFB6D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking the section heading and all that follows through <quote>(a) After</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H28F8D8CD558740CFBD9B4E16AFA53636" style="OLC">
						<section id="HD6B10A5187A946E795B978B9D87FB30F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Exportation or importation of natural gas; LNG terminals</header>
							<subsection id="H52E35DFB0AD84E08B0BC2A437C9038AC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization To export or import natural gas</header>
 <paragraph id="H8F50527CB527400B883C84AFD1C42317"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>After</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H75050BDD227040E7BE7208F304F461DD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H52BCB665F7444B3F92D270B7AEC315D2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1) (as so designated)—</text> <clause id="H83481345124F498FBE600637C505C2E3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the second sentence, by striking <quote>, unless,</quote> and all that follows through the period at the end of the sentence and inserting <quote>without modification or delay.</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H516B6A1749AE4C3296F1D04CCC230CA2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the third sentence, by striking <quote>by its order</quote> and all that follows through the period at the end of the sentence and inserting <quote>condition the order on a requirement that the applicant, on request, provide relevant data to the Commission to facilitate the information collection and statistical activities of the Commission.</quote>; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CB1C67942D94CA9AA6E41645F05460A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAD37BC7B7B964A3FBA79524CD4008936" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H66566687010F4225AF81DBBF2FF55331"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authority to limit exportation of natural gas</header> <subparagraph id="H83DF721061054D27B2F6E015543F9809"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Major disaster or emergency in United States</header><text>If the President declares a major disaster or emergency under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121</external-xref> et seq.), the President may limit the volume of natural gas exported from the United States during the 90-day period beginning on the date on which the President declares the major disaster or emergency.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE2BBAAAB5AB642AD86A9F4EC9BD1C484"><enum>(B)</enum><header>National emergency under International Emergency Economic Powers Act</header><text>If the President declares a national emergency under section 202 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref>) with respect to a country, the President may limit the volume of natural gas exported from the United States to that country.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD8C3E6761FFA4C55BD79DFA646AB228E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibitions</header>
 <subparagraph id="HCFEF8CF4EBA644EAB6AA9AA6A8A29AF5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Prohibition on restricting natural gas importation or exportation</header><text>Except as provided in paragraphs (1) and (2) or in any Federal authorization to export natural gas from the United States to a foreign country or to import natural gas into the United States from a foreign country in effect on the date of enactment of the <short-title>LNG Now Act of 2017</short-title>, to promote the efficient exploration, production, storage, supply, marketing, pricing, and regulation of energy resources, including fossil fuels, no employee of the Federal Government shall impose or enforce any restriction or condition on—</text>
 <clause id="H6EB9673F7D484EDB93CFBB92343C33D1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the exportation of natural gas from the United States to a foreign country; or</text> </clause><clause id="H76DCE28442A74AC0B06334FB8679901A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the importation of natural gas into the United States from a foreign country.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2ED12C50382B410DAE938027648EFDA3"><enum>(B)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Secretary of Energy prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Energy shall not treat, on the basis of national origin, any imported natural gas on an unjust, unreasonable, unduly discriminatory, or preferential basis.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5795D0A6C3D4AE8BBFBD84AFAE2F9B9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consideration of imported natural gas as a first sale</header><text>The importation of natural gas into the United States from a foreign country shall be considered to be a first sale (as defined in section 2 of the Natural Gas Policy Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3301">15 U.S.C. 3301</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E792C4FAC224C16813C228C37549EAE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking subsections (b) and (c); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE1CADA0D7859412785367A1DE838D24D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (d) through (f) as subsections (b) through (d), respectively.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H06205F299BD048E583CBDC28885A4EEC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall not affect any Federal authorization to export natural gas from the United States to a foreign country or to import natural gas into the United States from a foreign country in effect on the date of enactment of the <short-title>LNG Now Act of 2017</short-title>.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H562BEB5F328B4AE3A86447E0B20A0682"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report on fostering natural gas exports</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Energy shall submit to Congress a report describing actions taken by the United States Government, and actions that could be taken by the United States Government, to foster the exportation of natural gas from the United States to foreign countries.</text>
 </section><section id="H6EC27D7B731B417CBB1A74069BC3B237"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report on existing regulations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Energy shall submit to Congress a report that identifies regulations in effect as of such date of enactment that inhibit the growth of the market for natural gas exported from the United States.</text>
		</section><section id="H38E42FFDBF2449F3986766F0FA0CF1FD"><enum>6.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header>
 <subsection id="H1FB1C5740CF846CA9A0B95FF58EBB56C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act or an amendment made by this Act shall be construed to limit the authority of the President under—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HE8200DD8939048AEBB5291236AD5149A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Constitution of the United States;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H068315664ED941C1B073264AFE3B9220"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.) or regulations issued under that Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2BC331F0FCF4446497D306505615E9F8"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the National Emergencies Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1601">50 U.S.C. 1601</external-xref> et seq.);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFDFAC661F4084F899C692D0CE487C3AC"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Trading With the Enemy Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4301">50 U.S.C. 4301</external-xref> et seq.); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEB39BFE0ACCD4B0C94142730CB66FB84"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other provision of law that imposes sanctions with respect to a foreign person or foreign government (including any provision of law that prohibits or restricts a United States person from engaging in a transaction with a sanctioned person or government), including a foreign government that is designated as a state sponsor of terrorism.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7990BC2D96BF476F8B7AC10C85548C0E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State sponsor of terrorism defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>state sponsor of terrorism</term> means a country the government of which the Secretary of State has determined to be a government that has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism for purposes of—</text>
 <paragraph id="HAB05537F85A64B4DBFB56F4766D47429"><enum>(1)</enum><text>section 6(j)(1)(A) of the Export Administration Act of 1979 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4605">50 U.S.C. 4605(j)(1)(A)</external-xref>) (as continued in effect pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.));</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDCC5B7381B7443AB9BEACCDF1683B4A4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>section 620A(a) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2371">22 U.S.C. 2371(a)</external-xref>);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEBDB09EFF0C64DF997A307FADE635866"><enum>(3)</enum><text>section 40(d) of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2780">22 U.S.C. 2780(d)</external-xref>); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBE1945A4A3D641CE96AC5705DFB99E62"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any other provision of law.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

