<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HDD3541EBD09C48698B1036EA6C585296" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1318 IH: Preventing Maternal Deaths Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1318</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170302">March 2, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001056">Ms. Herrera Beutler</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001106">Mr. Costello of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To support States in their work to save and sustain the health of mothers during pregnancy,
			 childbirth, and in the postpartum period, to eliminate disparities in
			 maternal health outcomes for pregnancy-related and pregnancy-associated
			 deaths, to identify solutions to improve health care quality and health
			 outcomes for mothers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HD73A2F0AAF694E3E857361596ED2BF7E" style="OLC">
 <section id="HF8953F7E8878462FA553C69E9BC563CB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preventing Maternal Deaths Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HADDC12E9D81F4B96A72198CFCD804E51"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; purposes</header> <subsection id="HF0AC2B3E0DA447DB9C208EE093008CC9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H1D84A856585E44EFAF4E5047FC96C86E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States is ranked 50th globally for its maternal mortality rate, and it is one of eight countries in which the maternal mortality rate has been on the rise.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7C3DCB31AED44933A157BA845EFCB140"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In recent studies, the estimated maternal mortality rate in the United States increased by approximately 26.6 percent from 2000 to 2014, with the rate increasing in nearly all States. This reported increase, along with no improvement in previous years, remains a source of great concern for the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), health care providers, and patient advocates such as the American Congress of Obstetricians and Gynecologists, the Association of Women’s Health, Obstetric, and Neonatal Nurses, and the Preeclampsia Foundation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD7C3616170C64A1493E7A1DBEE91C761"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Maternal deaths in the United States result from pregnancy-related causes such as hemorrhage, hypertensive disease and preeclampsia, embolic disease, sepsis, and substance use disorder and overdose, and violent causes such as motor vehicle accidents, homicide, and suicide.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1B3D21D6134842448731C9EB99BA2718"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Review of pregnancy-related and pregnancy-associated deaths is essential to determining strategies for developing prevention efforts and quality improvement and quality control programs. The United States must identify at-risk populations and understand how to support them to make pregnancy and the postpartum period safer.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H266185393B90483FACB1956DDD526849"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The most severe complications of pregnancy, generally referred to as severe maternal morbidity (SMM), affect more than 65,000 women in the United States every year. The CDC uses ICD–9–CM codes, which indicate a potentially life-threatening maternal condition or complication, to define SMM.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6DC59FA01B8746B38097E348B3184107"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Data from the CDC shows Black women are three times more likely to die from complications of pregnancy or childbirth than White women: 42.8 Black women per 100,000 live births, as opposed to 12.5 White women and 17.3 women of other races.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCDAB0E15687B438F83BE99F9A9F96A07"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The CDC recommends that maternal deaths be investigated through State collaboratives. These State collaboratives would bring together leaders in obstetric and neonatal health care from private, academic, and public health care settings to make recommendations for preventing pregnancy-related and pregnancy-associated deaths and health complications and identify ways to improve quality of care for women and infants.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA0EBBE066B1646FBB3F056EFC28527DD"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A few States, including California, have worked to develop and strengthen maternal morbidity and mortality review systems and utilize data to reduce maternal deaths and injuries to address leading issues such as maternal hemorrhage, hypertension and preeclampsia, and health and racial disparities.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3DE0A9EEEC4549C4B86F02A95282C2AF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this Act are the following:</text> <paragraph id="H3B58B76C25894F92A4D5E58E181CB101"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To establish a shared responsibility between States and the Federal Government to identify opportunities for improvement in quality of care and system changes, and to educate and inform health institutions and professionals, women, and families about preventing pregnancy-related and pregnancy-associated deaths and complications and reducing disparities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA6FB9AAADBF44DC9BB6872717C1EBAD1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To develop a model for States to operate maternal mortality reviews and assess the various factors that may have contributed to maternal mortality, including quality of care, racial disparities, and systemic problems in the delivery of health care, and to develop appropriate interventions to reduce and prevent such deaths.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC5F03B7F0F87411EA343CAC5333FE86E"><enum>3.</enum><header>State maternal mortality review committees on pregnancy-related and pregnancy-associated deaths</header>
			<subsection id="HD8CE49EEF4534D0C90968858EF5BDC6B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program authorized</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H41013ABBFF8349EE8C858894219C49AF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall establish a grant program under which the Secretary may make grants to States for the purpose of—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H806810A21D7B4C7FBE0D50F083ECF449"><enum>(A)</enum><text>carrying out the activities described in subsection (b)(1);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H468010C65F044BAFB0646347DA90C0CF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establishing and sustaining a State maternal mortality review committee, in accordance with subsection (b)(2);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H53434AF7978A414A9A0340D3CC0043B0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensuring that the State department of health carries out the activities described in subsection (b)(3);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4A1244EEB5794748A20B4F9D0C3FB07C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>disseminating the case abstraction form developed under subsection (c); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3532647880BF4088A06DC14A463349E9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>providing for the public disclosure of information, in accordance with subsection (d).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFFAA93B7981D4E46BA6BB7BEEACC6F33"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish criteria for determining eligibility for, and the amount of a grant awarded to, a State under paragraph (1). Such criteria shall provide that in the case of a State that receives a grant under paragraph (1) for a fiscal year and is determined by the Secretary to have not used such grant in accordance with this section, such State may not be eligible for such a grant for any subsequent fiscal year.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H65C3D5DB226F42D1A4003B0649DC1B85"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header>
 <paragraph id="HA059B0B49A314F30BBF6499AAD25EFB0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Review of pregnancy-related and pregnancy-associated deaths</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a State that receives a grant under subsection (a)(1), the following shall apply:</text> <subparagraph id="H817D8E1FB0464118A55F377A7AEF6E98"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Process for mandatory reporting of pregnancy-related and pregnancy-associated deaths</header> <clause id="H7D5581CB5C4142C09BED89F6729C4EB7"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The State, through the State maternal mortality review committee established under subsection (a)(1), shall develop a process that provides for mandatory and confidential case reporting to the State department of health by individuals and entities described in clause (ii) with respect to pregnancy-related and pregnancy-associated deaths.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0736FEB898E041C3AFFDEE1D919BEB2F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Individuals and entities described</header><text>Individuals and entities described in this clause include each of the following:</text> <subclause id="HAC05085E18954CB39139E26A169D1122"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Health care professionals.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H515CAFC45D14438CA9C449CBADBA0C80"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Medical examiners.</text> </subclause><subclause id="H80BDF0DBBECE498CA0F09952386AF13F"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Medical coroners.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H04AA26A0F405462F916686C19924492B"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Hospitals.</text> </subclause><subclause id="H24DC67EB00C84C8A99CBDD25F7409C06"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Birth centers.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H2139A31584C14F52893CABBD49941043"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>Other health care facilities.</text> </subclause><subclause id="HEAB0E7B0C73D41C7A350367E92E7508F"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>Other individuals responsible for completing death records.</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H585E5597D7EA43C4A4C8459BB9DCF88D"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>Other appropriate individuals or entities specified by the Secretary.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9EC8407B567049DFB0C947A70D49F965"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Process for voluntary reporting of pregnancy-related and pregnancy-associated deaths</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The State, through the State maternal mortality review committee established under subsection (a)(1), shall develop a process that provides for voluntary and confidential case reporting to the State department of health by family members of the deceased and other individuals on possible pregnancy-related and pregnancy-associated deaths. Such process shall include—</text>
 <clause id="HF098083FD1BF4E098D76725CF7426FB1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>making publicly available on the website of the State department of health a telephone number, Internet web link, and email address for such reporting; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2FA9674836FA412AB64C4163B1ECC359"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>publicizing to local professional organizations, community organizations, and social services agencies the availability of the telephone number, Internet web link, and email address made available under clause (i).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCDB24D8542004EAD87AF49C3FFFFD95E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Identification of pregnancy-related and pregnancy-associated deaths by State vital statistics unit</header><text>The State, through the vital statistics unit of the State, shall annually identify pregnancy-related and pregnancy-associated deaths occurring in such State in the year involved by—</text>
 <clause id="HB9AE00EB5ED5461C9AB6296EF409984A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>matching each death record of a woman in such year to a live birth certificate or an infant death record for the purpose of identifying deaths of women that occurred during pregnancy and within one year after the end of a pregnancy;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE0CCED499FA443CA9CF12977E29278B2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>identifying each death of a woman reported during such year as having an underlying or contributing cause of death related to pregnancy, regardless of the time that has passed between the end of the pregnancy and the death;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCA2A743C0D004D549FF7ADEF71BEA2A3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>collecting data from medical examiner and coroner reports; and</text> </clause><clause id="HB7F742C09376478386BC38599FFF9788"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>using any other method the State may devise to identify maternal deaths such as reviewing a random sample of reported deaths of women to ascertain cases of pregnancy-related and pregnancy-associated deaths that are not discernable from a review of death records alone.</text>
						</clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">For purposes of effectively collecting and obtaining data on pregnancy-related and
			 pregnancy-associated deaths, the State shall adopt the most recent
			 standardized birth and death records, as issued by the National Center for
			 Vital Health Statistics, including the recommended checkbox section for
			 pregnancy on each death record.</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B050ED8E785474F90ECAE162E817E55"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Case investigation and development of case summaries</header>
 <clause id="HF57C95732E9D4EE48897242D704DDF8D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Following the receipt of reports by the State department of health pursuant to subparagraph (A) or (B) and the collection of cases of pregnancy-related and pregnancy-associated deaths by the vital statistics unit of the State under subparagraph (C), the State, through the State maternal mortality review committee established under subsection (a)(1), shall investigate each case, using the case abstraction form described in subsection (c), and prepare a de-identified case summary for each case, which shall be reviewed by the committee and included in applicable reports. The State department of health or vital statistics unit of the State, as the case may be, shall provide the State maternal mortality review committee with access to the information collected pursuant to subparagraph (A) or (B), or under subparagraph (C), as necessary to carry out this subparagraph.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H785250639EEA4FE9BEEBDA8316DAC100"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Mandatory data and information</header><text>Each case investigation under this subparagraph shall, subject to availability, include data and information obtained through—</text>
 <subclause id="H455A41E9816E4767A13E2F4AAB25AF19"><enum>(I)</enum><text>medical examiner and autopsy reports of the woman involved;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H0D9DFB70CA884344857B6EC488705E4C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>medical records of the woman, including such records related to health care prior to pregnancy, prenatal and postnatal care, labor and delivery care, emergency room care, hospital discharge records, and any care delivered up until the time of death of the woman;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H73EFBC786650489FAF0A049B290537FA"><enum>(III)</enum><text>oral and written interviews of individuals directly involved in the maternal care of the woman during and immediately following the pregnancy of the woman, including health care, mental health, and social service providers, as applicable;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H118ABF5C5D7241649DA808AA33C49273"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>socioeconomic and other relevant background information about the woman;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HB75D91EB47274163B1D811443AC74D7C"><enum>(V)</enum><text>any information collected under subparagraph (C)(i); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H5DABC58A012946B18F26AB37986C43A3"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>any other information on the cause of death of the woman, such as social services and child welfare reports.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HDA157DA10D5C4E2CB2755D18AAFB356A"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Discretionary data and information</header><text>Each case investigation under this subparagraph may include data and information obtained through oral or written interviews of the family of the woman.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H65D7C460954546A991C125382343E169"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State maternal mortality review committees</header>
 <subparagraph id="HBCB757940106473E939F21B712EA31F2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Mandatory activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State maternal mortality review committee established under subsection (a)(1) shall carry out the following activities:</text>
 <clause id="H2D9F2ACC28E148199C68FC322CE108EF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Develop the processes described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1).</text> </clause><clause id="H1E97CB581244405BAABD91B3AC422782"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Review the data and information collected by the vital statistics unit of the State under paragraph (1)(C) regarding pregnancy-related and pregnancy-associated deaths to identify trends, patterns, and disparities in adverse outcomes and address medical, non-medical, and system-related factors that may have contributed to such pregnancy-related and pregnancy-associated deaths and disparities.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8B56256EC7F54B30BAF08E8DC2183F0D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Carry out the activities described in paragraph (1)(D).</text> </clause><clause id="H26064A7DE5FA408EAF3C67A0330920CB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Develop recommendations, based on the case summaries prepared under paragraph (1)(D) and the data and information collected under paragraph (1)(C), to improve maternal care, social and health services, and public health policy and institutions, including improving access to maternal care and social and health services and identifying disparities in maternal care and outcomes.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3285BCF964814CDFBD7C99D7FB4A2A4A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Discretionary activities</header>
 <clause id="HDF2AC2CB772E4E32B871C54F65501392"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State maternal mortality review committee established under subsection (a)(1) may, while subject to confidentiality requirements, present findings and recommendations based on the case summaries prepared under paragraph (1)(D) directly to a health care facility or its local or State professional organization for the purpose of—</text>
 <subclause id="HF433BF4F5C7748A9A249B6E8C4A3CDCD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>instituting policy changes, educational activities, and improvements in the quality of care provided by the facility; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H696BC0D447C448FA9DAEA25E6507043F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>exploring and forming regional collaborations.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H963B657558E94F51AC84BF65CC3AD622"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Investigation of cases of Severe Maternal Morbidity</header><text>A State maternal mortality review committee may investigate cases of severe maternal morbidity and any such investigation may include data and information obtained through—</text>
 <subclause id="H85C57DB49911409AAA2BB1B46B945A9D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>identified patient registries; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="H2AD6E20C3BBF489DB4C508C8B28D9CD9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>oral or written interviews of the woman concerned and the family of such woman.</text>
							</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42E7F222557245AD9EF0601DACE6975C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Composition of State maternal mortality review committees</header>
 <clause id="H0563E45D224F432285E50C772A48812D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State maternal mortality review committee established under subsection (a)(1) shall be multidisciplinary and diverse. Membership on the State maternal mortality review committee shall be reviewed annually by the State department of health to ensure that membership representation requirements are being fulfilled in accordance with this subparagraph.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF459F91C6B9B4393B3D353735171EBD5"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Required membership</header><text>Each State maternal mortality review committee shall include—</text> <subclause id="H0AFA87EC6FE8486186EFEAA034E76C3C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>representatives from medical specialties providing care to pregnant and postpartum patients, including obstetricians (including generalists and maternal fetal medicine specialists) and family practice physicians;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HEBB81ADE7E6D4C6CBF9459D9845D5180"><enum>(II)</enum><text>certified nurse midwives, certified midwives, and advanced practice nurses;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HCBB1393EC75E461898E0EE9D27B2CAD1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>hospital-based registered nurses;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H8FFBD8A9B799461EB153587816E0AB1F"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">representatives of the maternal and child health department of the State department of health;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H8C52A7D4F4634BD8A43AF3FD251DC09A"><enum>(V)</enum><text>social service providers or social workers, including those with experience working with communities diverse with respect to race, ethnicity, and limited English proficiency;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HBAECD5EB76544B8F8B40E0450D28DE48"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>chief medical examiners or designees;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H26B43BD72F9F4836B7DCCBE945B37813"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>facility representatives, such as from hospitals or birth centers;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H87E6B60D9F31413780F3F3AE6D468DEC"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">patient advocates, community maternal health organizations, and minority advocacy groups that represent those diverse racial and ethnic communities within the State that are the most affected by pregnancy-related or pregnancy-associated deaths and by a lack of access to maternal health care services; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HBB46F084B7B84D90BCB1A3807664DB3E"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>representatives of the departments of health or public health of major cities in the State.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H25C5B88DBFF04D04B2089B9270040C19"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Discretionary membership</header><text>Each State maternal mortality review committee may also include representatives from other relevant academic, health, social service, or policy professions or community organizations on an ongoing basis, or as needed, as determined beneficial by the committee, including—</text>
 <subclause id="HFDC27F4733224B31851747C6BA6A7FD6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>anesthesiologists;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H839752C390AE43EDB9D609E1CC499E57"><enum>(II)</enum><text>emergency physicians;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H592094B978414EAA8808830E67A1B590"><enum>(III)</enum><text>pathologists;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H407DC2946F7644C2AE2B0986A4D18FDF"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>epidemiologists;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H859D1EC60A194DAB96D2A3F22E0C83C6"><enum>(V)</enum><text>intensivists;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HD544F99F4CE6449582F483D5162E4040"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>nutritionists;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H0703FE3B55EC4975BC1BC69E6ADFC78A"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>mental health professionals;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H7258BB23FD5F4183BC00BA7721452F75"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>substance use disorder treatment specialists;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H29F4BC64EFBF44A2BD0C49D56E2F3E47"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>representatives of relevant patient and provider advocacy groups;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H20727A9BF6A7469DB8C58943F3D42340"><enum>(X)</enum><text>academics;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H44CD46B8765B4BB09634D1268DD654F2"><enum>(XI)</enum><text>paramedics; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HC9BF7FD57CB44600AF6A25002905F915"><enum>(XII)</enum><text>risk management specialists.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H26329CBAF2A54279A5A4794C8A17721B"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Staff</header><text>Staff of each State maternal mortality review committee shall include—</text> <subclause id="H9BCC3949645548E29E7BE5741C03A821"><enum>(I)</enum><text>vital health statisticians, maternal child health statisticians, or epidemiologists;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HFCAE2918D8E14A9E8EF0A602D59DECE5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a coordinator of the State maternal mortality review committee, to be designated by the State; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HA000D18FCDDF463EB5E8A9F510BF0D94"><enum>(III)</enum><text>administrative staff.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE166166CC184E11A8E9BD0EF18F57AD"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Option for States to establish regional maternal mortality review committees</header><text>States may choose to partner with one or more neighboring States to carry out the activities required of a State maternal mortality review committee under this section. In such a case, with respect to the States in such a partnership, any requirement under this section relating to the reporting of information related to such activities shall be deemed to be fulfilled by each such State if a single such report is submitted for the partnership.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8C55BF858BF348B4A1C8EE16ACA4AD24"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Treatment as public health authority for purposes of HIPAA</header><text>For purposes of applying HIPAA privacy and security law (as defined in section 3009(a)(2) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300jj-19">42 U.S.C. 300jj–19</external-xref>)), each State maternal mortality review committee and regional maternal mortality review committee established under subsection (a)(1) or subsection (b)(2)(D), as the case may be, shall be deemed to be a public health authority described in section 164.501 (and referenced in section 164.512(b)(1)(i)) of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation), carrying out public health activities and purposes described in such section 164.512(b)(1)(i) (or any such successor regulation).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H23E0CD12C5D449669E39D249B7F010AF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State department of health activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a State that receives a grant under subsection (a)(1), the State department of health shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD9BBFBB26E23482A90C0E9917E9A5017"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in consultation with the State maternal mortality review committee and in conjunction with relevant professional organizations and patient advocacy organizations, develop a plan for ongoing health care provider education, based on the findings and recommendations of the committee, in order to improve the quality of maternal care; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49EF6D64C996427CA86DA24E0038902A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>take steps to widely disseminate the findings and recommendations of the State maternal mortality review committee and implement the recommendations of the committee.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H193EE1E5058240078716FE8DAEA9A892"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Case abstraction form</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H29DD4E3C11C748119D0FAA21FC90122A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Dissemination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention shall disseminate a uniform case abstraction form to States and State maternal mortality review committees for the purpose of—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H5CEB91CFF04C4547B88C150FCF1E35CD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensuring that the data and information collected and reviewed by such committees can be pooled for review by the Department of Health and Human Services and its agencies; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0337E9DF547147289D5F650F0DF1CA62"><enum>(B)</enum><text>preserving the uniformity of the information collected for Federal public health purposes.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HBD61C97F0D0C4B00BFD34E17DF3DB164"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Permissible State modification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State may modify the form developed under paragraph (1) for implementation and use by such State or by the State maternal mortality review committee of such State by including on such form additional information to be collected, but may not alter the standard questions on such form, in order to ensure that the information can be collected and reviewed centrally at the Federal level.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1BDDC101E39D4C8C8371D402273D1A1A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Public disclosure of information</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H899C1624BB8E48F4839274679DFD71CD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For fiscal year 2018, or a subsequent fiscal year, each State receiving a grant under this section for such year shall, subject to paragraph (3), provide for the public disclosure, and submission to the information clearinghouse established under paragraph (2), of the information included in the report of the State under subsection (f)(1) for such year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDFAA2B123F1F495080165ABF4D0A5831"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information clearinghouse</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish an information clearinghouse, to be administered by the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, that will maintain findings and recommendations submitted pursuant to paragraph (1) and provide such findings and recommendations for public review and research purposes by State departments of health, State maternal mortality review committees, health providers and institutions, and national patient and provider advocacy groups.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC75C0AA6C4444934827B8D31943B596C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Confidentiality of information</header><text>In no case may any individually identifiable health information be provided to the public, or submitted to the information clearinghouse, under this subsection.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8DECCEACD844465DA56773F43DA91C68"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Confidentiality of proceedings of State maternal mortality review committees</header>
 <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H951F389AC52E442D9FA5086961B4E17D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>All proceedings and activities of a State maternal mortality review committee established under subsection (a)(1), opinions of members of such a committee formed as a result of such proceedings and activities, and records obtained, created, or maintained pursuant to this section, including records of interviews, written reports, and statements procured by the Department of Health and Human Services or by any other person, agency, or organization acting jointly with the Department, in connection with morbidity and mortality reviews under this section, shall be confidential and may not be subject to discovery, subpoena, or introduction into evidence in any civil, criminal, legislative, or other proceeding. Such records shall not be open to public inspection.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H80AB9DE9F3144A8E93003E3FE0ED2D4D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Testimony of members of committee</header>
 <subparagraph id="H425598EC681C41DBA8D49BF76FC0350C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Members of a State maternal mortality review committee established under subsection (a)(1) may not be questioned in any civil, criminal, legislative, or other proceeding regarding information presented in, or opinions formed as a result of, a meeting or communication of the committee.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC57ED9B094A743178D1757E60F3B6E17"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection may be construed to prevent a member of a State maternal mortality review committee established under subsection (a)(1) from testifying regarding information that was obtained independent of such member’s participation on the committee, or public information.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H211E478EEF5D450CA3B5E87768FDC753"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Availability of information for research purposes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection may prohibit a State maternal mortality review committee established under subsection (a)(1) or the Department of Health and Human Services from publishing statistical compilations and research reports that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBED77A16B2AB4EBEADAF7FBF73C27B21"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are based on confidential information, relating to morbidity and mortality reviews under this section; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2B7C72E3D9A4C498EEB23CC24C6E1B7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>do not contain identifying information or any other information that could be used to ultimately identify the individuals concerned.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HB9822A1EFB31486CA1B2D202905F5BE9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reports</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HBE1A7249E0EA4BF2B7DA0D9B2749994B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>State reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the end of fiscal year 2018, and each subsequent fiscal year, each State maternal mortality review committee established under subsection (a)(1) and receiving a grant under this section for such year, shall submit to the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention a report on the findings and recommendations of such committee and information on the implementation of such recommendations during such year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HBFF70B2A411943FDA19CC94A11F66EB7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual reports to Congress</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the deadline for State reports under paragraph (1) for fiscal year 2018, and each subsequent fiscal year, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to Congress a report on—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HE9942D0366074BBBB00CC0711E791236"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the findings, recommendations, and implementation information submitted by any State pursuant to paragraph (1); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3172829426544BB2A45C742324E2A964"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the status of pregnancy-related and pregnancy-associated deaths in the United States, including recommendations on methods to prevent such deaths in the United States.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD8E92ACCD68D4BBCA2A10F86313F0EAE"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HE9DD00C958C14F4C9C75565ADA8F5F14"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>pregnancy-associated death</term> means the death of a woman while pregnant or during the one-year period following the date of the end of pregnancy, irrespective of the cause of such death.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H86D6655C48F44C33857847DED302A6BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>pregnancy-related death</term> means the death of a woman while pregnant or during the one-year period following the date of the end of pregnancy, irrespective of the duration of the pregnancy, from any cause related to, or aggravated by, the pregnancy or its management, excluding any accidental or incidental cause.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H576083BDF7EB436680A0497BEA022D67"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <quote>severe maternal morbidity</quote> means the physical and psychological conditions that result from, or are aggravated by, pregnancy and have an adverse effect on the health of a woman.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFF3C123A35504BD9A8864A6EBF5BA71A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <quote>State</quote> means each of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, and each of the territories.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H1FB464F7E15E4B8D84FE84C22396240A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <quote>vital statistics unit</quote> means the entity that is responsible for maintaining vital records for a State, including official records of live births, deaths, fetal deaths, marriages, divorces, and annulments.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H159F45F60DDF40FB96F6F615780DEA4D"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $7,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HA26F6DAC6AED4C05BFB742A89D13BF79"><enum>4.</enum><header>Eliminating disparities in maternity health outcomes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part B of title III of the Public Health Service Act is amended by inserting after section 317T of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247b-22">42 U.S.C. 247b–22</external-xref>) the following new section:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3924979B8BC145D0A4DA05F61BDD1AC3" style="OLC">
				<section id="HAEC37B26F65E4E91A552B2F06A9520C8"><enum>317U.</enum><header>Eliminating disparities in maternal health outcomes</header>
 <subsection id="H7B681D1D4FC94988B028AD24E02708C6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, in consultation with relevant national stakeholder organizations, such as national medical specialty organizations, national maternal child health organizations, national patient advocacy organizations, and national health disparity organizations, carry out the following activities to eliminate disparities in maternal health outcomes:</text>
 <paragraph id="H3789470C6B2B4A83A6C195922861E681"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Conduct research into the determinants and the distribution of disparities in maternal care, health risks, and health outcomes, and improve the capacity of the performance measurement infrastructure to measure such disparities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H15FFEA289AB741F9B9F4B5F72C456AF4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Expand access to health care services, resources, and information that have been demonstrated to improve the quality and outcomes of maternity care for vulnerable populations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBC3469802F524877A33ACA75E80BD5AC"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Establish a demonstration project to compare the effectiveness of interventions to reduce disparities in maternity services and outcomes and to implement and assess effective interventions.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF3240881171A45C08C0931BEEFC0389F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Scope and selection of States for demonstration project</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The demonstration project under subsection (a)(3) shall be conducted in no more than 8 States, which shall be selected by the Secretary based on—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC9F6D29D866B43E0A4E4BB88A93247D3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>applications submitted by States, which specify which regions and populations the State involved will serve under the demonstration project;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFC074773D86E4706BBFE2CF7F76DFF5F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>criteria designed by the Secretary to ensure that, as a whole, the demonstration project is, to the greatest extent possible, representative of the demographic and geographic composition of communities most affected by disparities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCE9263D8FD9544DE8265136E1BA60F37"><enum>(3)</enum><text>criteria designed by the Secretary to ensure that a variety of models are tested through the demonstration project and that such models include interventions that have an existing evidence base for effectiveness; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF5F2892EFBD04897A31F0896DFD0DA74"><enum>(4)</enum><text>criteria designed by the Secretary to ensure that the demonstration projects and models will be carried out in consultation with local and regional provider organizations, such as community health centers, hospital systems, and medical societies representing providers of maternity services.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0BEBFBE248D84B7D80A772A71C78E1B9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duration of demonstration project</header><text>The demonstration project under subsection (a)(3) shall begin on January 1, 2018, and end on December 31, 2021.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5738F12C905041FF90AEF6DDF03C6D92"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Grants for evaluation and monitoring</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may make grants to States and health care providers participating in the demonstration project under subsection (a)(3) for the purpose of collecting data necessary for the evaluation and monitoring of such project.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="H79704079D0E9416EBBF65DA79C095E5A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports</header>
 <paragraph id="HC432017A10574279ADE5A5FA6AE12F31"><enum>(1)</enum><header>State reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State that participates in the demonstration project under subsection (a)(3) shall report to the Secretary, in a time, form, and manner specified by the Secretary, the data necessary to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H30BC8CDBBACB407194012A55DCC3B658"><enum>(A)</enum><text>monitor the—</text> <clause id="H07FCAA20E4FB4F9F96842F4ADC19D734"><enum>(i)</enum><text>outcomes of the project;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H77594ED12FB343D2982832294691625A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>costs of the project; and</text> </clause><clause id="H447EF373B424462DB1467B7272EFF620"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>quality of maternity care provided under the project; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF72F2129A9094711BB4AE006B96AAF73"><enum>(B)</enum><text>evaluate the rationale for the selection of the items and services included in any bundled payment made by the State under the project.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC93048C1305F4094B5FB2ABEE2011C20"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than December 31, 2022, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the results of the demonstration project under subsection (a)(3).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


