<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H5AA7221740714E50AAA80CD165E61428" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 55 IH: Breath of Fresh Air Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 55</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170103">January 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a grant program for nebulizers in elementary and secondary schools.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H855D17D9F86148B5A96BDB4CB88EC58C" style="OLC">
 <section id="HEB3D75C65E2B44379687BADACC57774B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Breath of Fresh Air Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H10CBD56461BC4E3185117FA616040457"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="HF6763AD95B134DB58E92292B137A8996"><enum>(1)</enum><text>25,000,000 people, including 7,000,000 children, have asthma.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB12FC3CE914043CD9DCCCEADF31FC534"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Almost 13,000,000 people report having an asthma attack in the past year and asthma accounts for nearly 2,000,000 emergency department visits each year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0340FB2F5EF34FAD982F54C045356751"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Every day in the United States—</text> <subparagraph id="HA3683266FBC742C985D1901B8EA0D6B8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>30,000 people have an asthma attack; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H813CE846B566439C8F7FE98FB521DDA1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>11 people die from asthma.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD4B3585A96F422496D5F0A0B36735E2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Nearly 5,000,000 asthma sufferers are under 18 years of age, and 1 out of every 10 school-aged children has asthma.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD126A9C5A53F43FFBB8FEDDC63EE7501"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Minorities are adversely affected by asthma, as—</text> <subparagraph id="HCD4362DA0D614E39B5DF87F076671227"><enum>(A)</enum><text>African-Americans are 3 times more likely to die from asthma; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F61E570E65046BDA34BD5886811C302"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Hispanics may have an elevated risk for exposure to air pollution since a disproportionate number live in areas failing to meet one or more national standards for air pollutants. (It is estimated that 80 percent of Hispanics live in areas that failed to meet one United States Environmental Protection Agency air quality standard, compared to 65 percent of African-Americans and 57 percent of Whites.)</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HAFE748543BF140EC9F7038428B77BBF7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grant program for nebulizers</header>
 <subsection id="H1E7380FF86904E96A0E27A1B5ACD8B01"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program required</header><text>The Secretary of Education shall carry out a program under which the Secretary makes grants to local educational agencies, to be used by the local educational agencies for one or both of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H2C74CA058DC54C1185DBF9E5A12DA7C4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To purchase nebulizers for use in elementary and secondary schools served by the local educational agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4C9D6C3B51F742A7901B729BE8CDCF9D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To provide training to enable elementary and secondary schools served by the local educational agency to meet the requirements of subsection (d)(1), but only if nebulizers are already in use at such schools or are acquired through this program.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H02FE1534E6D64766BEEAB8EC16D87B4A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header>
 <paragraph id="H413C8C77CA7845EF83A9C564D75BC588"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Local educational agencies</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, a local educational agency shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such form, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5F8740FB594144E1BE8F4078C2985D73"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elementary and secondary schools</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a nebulizer through a grant under this section, a school may be any public or private school served by the local educational agency, except that an Internet- or computer-based community school is not eligible.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6E78EEB7F3414365983D468F3521C98F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Matching funds required</header>
 <paragraph id="HD2997623E50E4B30B54EE00A3EECF21C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, the local educational agency must provide matching funds from non-Federal sources equal to not less than 25 percent of the amount of the grant.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H138F1C3A824943F68963399654508519"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall waive the requirement of paragraph (1) for a local educational agency if the number of children counted under section 1124(c)(1)(A) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6333">20 U.S.C. 6333(c)(1)(A)</external-xref>) is 20 percent or more of the total number of children aged 5 to 17, inclusive, served by the local educational agency.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB5BCEA6E1EDB41869F9891628F2BE82D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Training and coordination required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A local educational agency that receives a grant under this section shall demonstrate that, for each elementary and secondary school at which the nebulizers are to be used—</text>
 <paragraph id="H1A729DF5924B4348AD8A7C543E26BBBB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">there is a full-time certified school nurse on staff;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDFCB5B5073644AF7A9CC5B655052D85D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the school has the trained personnel and other resources necessary to use the nebulizers;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB04564E4B50A4B29AE4B92911ED7DA04"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">local paramedics and other emergency services personnel are notified where on school grounds the nebulizers are to be located;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4CB8BF72164D4819A230B1991C0A608B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the nebulizer will be integrated into the school’s emergency response plan or procedures; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF30CCE284A564B9CB9F1B1DD0EE66789"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the school has procedures in place to ensure that parents are notified of the availability of the nebulizers, how to provide their child’s prescription asthma medication to the school, and how to authorize use of a nebulizer to assist their child when medically appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8E0DC1076CD3408BA3D4603AAAACB037"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In making grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to local educational agencies—</text>
 <paragraph id="HAC135B05D2E1495DA6DD4035E45CBAD8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>having jurisdiction over a geographic area with respect to which the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention has determined that the prevalence of asthma is at least 10 percent higher than the national average;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4BAAFADD2B284FBA83B8B2988619FFDC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that do not already have at least one nebulizer in each school served by the local educational agency;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC29C065E3A4B4524AA3743E64E2F7FF8"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">serve schools at which a significant number of students, staff, and visitors are present on school grounds during a typical day; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HDC1C32BD1761421AB037B9540CDF187F"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that have not received funds under the Rural Access to Emergency Devices Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254c">42 U.S.C. 254c</external-xref> note).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1E19A4166ECE45F98ED5DFCCFC0D7200"><enum>(f)</enum><header>ESEA definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms used in this section shall have the meanings given to such terms in section 9101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2EDC203884F044CC9274759CC18E1B49"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2021.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H62C12C95D82A483194D69691EFF7EB61"><enum>4.</enum><header>Construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed—</text> <paragraph id="HF9BEF4E211784D4B8F4BF5AB76082625"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to create liability for use of a nebulizer or affect liability for such use that exists under other law; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBDA9D7FEB7CA4576BA6066410E3A499C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to supersede a State law regulating nursing.</text> </paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

