<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H99860393E4EB4639A80B4E62CF8C4A12" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 225 IH: Restoration of the U.S.-Russia Polar Bear Conservation Fund Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 225</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170103">January 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young of Alaska</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 to allow the importation of polar bear trophies
			 taken in sport hunts in Canada.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H76904F384DDA4ABDB436F0DEF7B1713D" style="OLC">
 <section id="H28A2166D6E894DE898BDF743CC9080C4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Restoration of the U.S.-Russia Polar Bear Conservation Fund Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H19A1835463B54E628E7CD85F6BEC9BC9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H1DB49BE33B8E47279B63FEDFDCE0C578"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The United States Fish and Wildlife Service estimates that the polar bear population is currently at 20,000 to 25,000 bears, up from as low as 5,000 to 10,000 bears in the 1950s and 1960s.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3B43DB829ED14DD2B93C13FB3AF4B75A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A 2002 United States Geological Survey of wildlife in the Arctic National Wildlife Refuge Coastal Plain noted that the polar bear populations <quote>may now be near historic highs</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2BD111E64048453EAE4F93D07A7E4B64"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A permit fee for importing polar bears will invigorate the public-private funding partnership for the United States-Russian Polar Bear Conservation Fund.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H66A8650C309E41329F0D1B281800037B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>TRAFFIC, the wildlife trade monitoring network, has stated both that <quote>the global population of Polar Bears is not small and the species’ area of distribution is not restricted,</quote> and <quote>[t]rade does not appear to be a significant threat to the species.</quote>. TRAFFIC also recommended that the polar bear not be uplisted to appendix 1 at the 16th Conference of the Parties of the Convention on International Trade of Endangered Species of Fauna and Flora (CITES).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1E21B20D7FD84EAA9AA8BD09A03ECBD8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The International Union for Conservation of Nature (IUCN)/Species Survival Commission (SSC) Polar Bear Specialist Group (PBSG), has stated that further trade restrictions on the polar bear are <quote>unlikely to confer a conservation benefit, and could have a negative impact on socioeconomic systems as well as domestic and international partnerships</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H13C433BEBC1A41E588B336302A67AAE7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The International Union for Conservation of Nature has found that <quote>hunting is a form of wildlife use that, when well-managed, may assist in furthering conservation objectives by creating the revenue and economic incentives for the management and conservation of the target species and its habitat, as well as supporting local livelihoods</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H1A1B6AA8EC074893881E8061C310DC18"><enum>3.</enum><header>Permits for importation of polar bear trophies</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H33852E0ED8214B9B9DC19AD14D7420A4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 101(a)(3)(B) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1371">16 U.S.C. 1371(a)(3)(B)</external-xref>), by inserting <quote>or under section 104(c)(5) of this title</quote> after <quote>paragraph (5) of this subsection</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7B52EFFA8EA54E13B7E5DBF2A6AF2180"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 102(b)(3) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1372">16 U.S.C. 1372(b)(3)</external-xref>), by inserting before the semicolon the following: <quote>, except that this paragraph does not prohibit the importation of polar bear parts under a permit issued under section 104(c)(5) of this title</quote>.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


