<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2ED1E22E249C43A3AD1C4529238514A7" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 999 IH: Helping Families Save for Education Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 999</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170209">February 9, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000798">Mr. Walberg</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000380">Mr. Kildee</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to expand access to Coverdell education savings
			 accounts.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H514AD6F8AA6E43BC8D878B1CF08B5383" style="OLC">
 <section id="HC0A56D3D6BCA47DF8AE58FA7E292258B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Helping Families Save for Education Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HA505580380894E0EB7109753C7B3D690"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HD1A5B0CAADA341E691A8F37BDF1B572C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">College costs have increased tremendously over the past decade. When adjusted for inflation, the average published price for in-State students at public 4-year universities is 34 percent higher than it was a decade ago and more than twice as high as it was 20 years ago. The price of private nonprofit 4-year institutions has increased 24 percent during the last 10 years and 51 percent during the last 20 years.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1749E933B4574C7CBA8EC646207BAD9C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Federal financial aid for students has also increased rapidly but failed to mitigate the issues of rising college costs. Between the 2005–2006 academic year and the 2015–2016 academic year, the amount of Federal financial aid in the form of Pell Grants, Federal student aid, campus based aid, veterans educational benefits, and tax credits increased from $82.4 billion to $158.3 billion or by 92 percent. The Federal Government’s share of total student aid is 66 percent.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H39FF376A51204981B46D2793B05751FA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Students continue to borrow more than they can afford. During the 2014–2015 academic year, approximately 61 percent of students who earned bachelor’s degrees from public and private nonprofit institutions at which they began their studies graduated with debt. These students borrowed an average of $28,100, an increase of 8.9 percent compared to 5 years ago and an increase of 18.1 percent compared to 10 years ago.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HAB18847CDE80465FBA76E2D1AF0C3D45"><enum>3.</enum><header>Expansion of Coverdell education savings accounts</header>
 <subsection id="H4B4EFC9021744E1190760FDC030BC45D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Increase in age limitation of beneficiary after which contributions to account cannot be made</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/530">Section 530(b)(1)(A)(ii)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>age 18</quote> and inserting <quote>age 22</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HFE8B170FC366489BBD0B535F852C293D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Increase in annual dollar limitation on contributions to account</header><text>Section 530(b)(1)(A)(iii) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>$2,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$10,000</quote>.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H83BA50A60A5F42558818BE96F3E4EBC3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective dates</header>
 <paragraph id="HDDD8CCFF310347EF93988CCD80C75E29"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Increase in age limitation</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall apply to contributions made after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1FCE4EF1D99443F3807C2746423490EB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Increase in annual dollar limitation on contributions</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (b) shall apply to contributions made in taxable years ending after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


