<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC019443C507348098372226571D6008B" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 677 IH: CBRN Intelligence and Information Sharing Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 677</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170124">January 24, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001197">Ms. McSally</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000625">Mr. Donovan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish chemical, biological, radiological, and
			 nuclear intelligence and information sharing functions of the Office of
			 Intelligence and Analysis of the Department of Homeland Security and to
			 require dissemination of information analyzed by the Department to
			 entities with responsibilities relating to homeland security, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H5A305683A90E4978912D7A4221BC891F" style="OLC">
 <section id="H5684FF37F8DF43DEB27821DEABC741A3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>CBRN Intelligence and Information Sharing Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H09FB5B5E0F8047218F75F84181450F64"><enum>2.</enum><header>Chemical, biological, radiological, and nuclear intelligence and information sharing</header> <subsection id="HF0F5C866353D449FA5F2B3333CECEFEB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle A of title II of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/121">6 U.S.C. 121</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDB896B8E178C4BB8ADD3D075C6B2E32A" style="OLC">
					<section id="H1EEE3B9C9C2F41BB8F5A1A1A4DD80343"><enum>210G.</enum><header>Chemical, biological, radiological, and nuclear intelligence and information sharing</header>
 <subsection id="HD496C0FF03CD49F79F88DBEBCC742F41"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Office of Intelligence and Analysis of the Department of Homeland Security shall—</text> <paragraph id="H64AFDB0AD1764307AD58FD63B22FB473"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support homeland security-focused intelligence analysis of terrorist actors, their claims, and their plans to conduct attacks involving chemical, biological, radiological, or nuclear materials against the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H901CEF84BE054C92ACBF6466DCAC6859"><enum>(2)</enum><text>support homeland security-focused intelligence analysis of global infectious disease, public health, food, agricultural, and veterinary issues;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA129EBBF88E2445C9C7C312276CAA69C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>support homeland security-focused risk analysis and risk assessments of the homeland security hazards described in paragraphs (1) and (2), including the transportation of chemical, biological, nuclear, and radiological materials, by providing relevant quantitative and nonquantitative threat information;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H36DDE56214434DB5B9E25C91E9BD3D3B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>leverage existing and emerging homeland security intelligence capabilities and structures to enhance prevention, protection, response, and recovery efforts with respect to a chemical, biological, radiological, or nuclear attack;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H964AB4E519064731979FC5631834DA63"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">share information and provide tailored analytical support on these threats to State, local, and tribal authorities, other Federal agencies, as well as relevant national biosecurity and biodefense stakeholders, as appropriate; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2EFAC42A7F1F48C8B87B381F3C4D489A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>perform other responsibilities, as assigned by the Secretary.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6181EE6A044F48BA966B48CBBE6B07FD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Where appropriate, the Office of Intelligence and Analysis shall coordinate with other relevant Department components, including the National Biosurveillance Integration Center, other agencies within in the intelligence community, including the National Counter Proliferation Center, and other Federal, State, local, and tribal authorities, including officials from high-threat urban areas, State and major urban area fusion centers, and local public health departments, as appropriate, and enable such entities to provide recommendations on optimal information sharing mechanisms, including expeditious sharing of classified information, and on how such entities can provide information to the Department.</text>
 </subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD53A12F4D0AC4023B6058226609CDD0F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HFF02A147D4DF41D39DCB8AE804DAD43D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Intelligence community</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>intelligence community</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3(4) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/401a">50 U.S.C. 401a(4)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCF6FA40E4C4648EC814C744C8053A031"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National biosecurity and biodefense stakeholders</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>national biosecurity and biodefense stakeholders</term> means officials from Federal, State, local, and tribal authorities and individuals from the private sector who are involved in efforts to prevent, protect against, respond to, and recover from a biological attack or other phenomena that may have serious health consequences for the United States, including infectious disease outbreaks.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H59D3BCDC00E44FA59EADE6201C01790A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 201F the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H492790BDC5694107952BA9045BE1F3EB" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 210G. Chemical, biological, radiological, and nuclear intelligence and information sharing.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="HF0C3C5EF78ED4FA79844A8BDD22D348F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header>
 <paragraph id="H5F0C970B764A4ADFB085A987E8344A4C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall report to the appropriate congressional committees on—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H007DAD083ACE48EDA71577F2A3D1D911"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the intelligence and information sharing activities under section 210G of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (as added by subsection (a) of this section) and of all relevant entities within the Department of Homeland Security to counter the threat from attacks using chemical, biological, radiological, or nuclear materials; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E29830ED912490AAA26D3BB0F1EFD7B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Department’s activities in accordance with relevant intelligence strategies.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C277D86877B4E308A0737EAFACB50D7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assessment of implementation</header><text>The reports required under paragraph (1) shall include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBED0FBF563C84689B608228BED885D74"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an assessment of the progress of the Office of Intelligence and Analysis of the Department of Homeland Security in implementing such section 210G; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21DCA6A04AF84D23870C79D53DF703CE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of the methods established to carry out such assessment.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H50CE77E53D104D20B94AC4E8A35281DD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>This subsection shall terminate on the date that is five years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC207CA29E83547D5951EB5129FE206DE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and any committee of the House of Representatives or the Senate having legislative jurisdiction under the rules of the House of Representatives or Senate, respectively, over the matter concerned.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8FB66513C7A4429C97BE44E7AC8FC286" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Dissemination of information analyzed by the Department to State, local, tribal, and private
 entities with responsibilities relating to homeland security</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Paragraph (8) of section 201(d) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/121">6 U.S.C. 121(d)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>and to agencies of State</quote> and all that follows through the period at the end and inserting <quote>to State, local, tribal, and private entities with such responsibilities, and, as appropriate, to the public, in order to assist in preventing, deterring, or responding to acts of terrorism against the United States.</quote>.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


