<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H96F2BB5E9158408E8F825E2231AE0F7A" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3439 IH: Financial Institution Security Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3439</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170726">July 26, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000606">Mr. Pittenger</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To facilitate better information sharing to assist in the fight against the funding of terrorist
			 activities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HEAF79D97B17141CDA8D843B80206A783" style="OLC">
 <section id="H22E37F6C2D3F471983911CC1F5BD6B02" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Financial Institution Security Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H2897B145AC8A4A2898635F61C4B6640C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Information sharing</header> <subsection id="H8566E873174D4AA9B1BBFAA2C5018B99"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 314 of the USA PATRIOT Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/5311">31 U.S.C. 5311</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE048610099884E7991A19F6D775D1EA7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <subparagraph id="H2B1830794D4C40DBB04DF907A74033FA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>terrorist or money laundering activities</quote> and inserting <quote>terrorist acts, money laundering activities, or a specified unlawful activity (as defined under section 1956(c)(7) of title 18, United States Code)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H27194D97C3B148E6BB40B931F67FAF4B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>activities that may involve terrorist acts or money laundering activities</quote> and inserting <quote>activities that may involve terrorist acts, money laundering activities, or a specified unlawful activity</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF27E1ACD84BE4DF18CA52AF7587DC77F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c), by inserting <quote>or a specified unlawful activity (as defined under section 1956(c)(7) of title 18, United States Code)</quote> after <quote>terrorist acts or money laundering activities</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HBFFBC873BE3A498F8DC38F77210E9770"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Update to regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 314(a) of the USA PATRIOT Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/5311">31 U.S.C. 5311</external-xref> note) is amended by striking <quote>or money laundering activities</quote> each place such term appears and inserting <quote>, money laundering activities, or a specified unlawful activity (as defined under section 1956(c)(7) of title 18, United States Code)</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC5A8F7F0C29B471FAB7EA3ADAEF9B344"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 314 of the USA PATRIOT Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/5311">31 U.S.C. 5311</external-xref> note) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H922E456F8933464EAFBB402B965CEF88" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H87F34B5463B0473E81F20DBD43FE09A1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of the Congress that, in furtherance of efforts to stop the financing of terror and other forms of illicit financing through increased sharing of information, and consistent with the need to prevent inappropriate dissemination of such information—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF672E4CAF99E4D6DB995C7103BD32D1F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal law enforcement agencies and regulators should share information about terrorist activities, money laundering activities, and other specified unlawful activities (as defined under section 1956(c)(7) of title 18, United States Code) to the fullest extent possible and in a timely fashion; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H75B9B8A3E8D4489C95FB66A34A08A14B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">financial institutions, including nonbank financial institutions, should share information about such acts and activities with each other to the fullest extent possible and in a timely fashion.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4CF4D99B98444248883117CBE2A76543" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Disclosure liability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5318(g)(3)(B) of title 31, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H1045F1E1AD7D4763BDC0C02FB4148867"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H89CAAD46E5E44A66904339BB3E77A81B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H66517E11869F449B8B027997B372C882"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H110CDEBDB25F4231BBE4205F02518394" style="OLC">
 <clause id="HCA7CB6E116424690AC64733FA51370B5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any duty or requirement of a financial institution or any director, officer, employee, or agent of such institution to demonstrate to any person, as used in such subparagraph, that a disclosure referenced in such subparagraph is made in good faith.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HE1805CC9BC4643D491AA100BF5341493"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header>
 <subsection id="H1494D0481BEA487FAF70F9BD3EFFCF8D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the end of the 120-day period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury shall report to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate regarding—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB9713427C97543A081A1FDD5C33B2E2A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Department of the Treasury's assessment of the risks and benefits of allowing sharing of information, consistent with appropriate privacy protections—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H24BD973731864EF091EAF637A9322E50"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">between United States financial institutions and foreign financial institutions;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB49C23C92514A7BBCFB18DA0E88A8FC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">between United States financial institutions and their foreign subsidiaries; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H759A8C5EAECF4B9CBB923383FE542E53"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">between United States subsidiaries of foreign financial institutions and their parent financial institutions; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB777470404DB43A58E4050DF2F40668A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether a financial institution defined under section 5312(a)(2) of title 31, United States Code, that is not required under Treasury regulations on the date of the enactment of this Act to maintain an anti-money laundering program, should be authorized to appropriately share information pursuant to subsection (b) of section 314 of the USA PATRIOT Act, if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB0924EA16B4441DA9E8852FD9155F747"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the financial institution voluntarily establishes and maintains such an anti-money laundering program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H325B8EDCFC4B450B8310408ADD114D2D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such program is subject to examination, and has been examined, by the appropriate regulator; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB1EB66B9A0604677B3B1C85A5CBA4CCB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Secretary determines such program to be adequately operating.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9F32709E8653414FACD7DAAD570BA6EE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Separate presentation of classified material</header><text>Any part of the report described under subsection (a) that involves information which is properly classified under criteria established by the President shall be submitted to the committees described under subsection (a) separately in a classified annex and, if requested by the chairman or ranking Member of one of such committees, as a briefing at an appropriate level of security.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H797162408B7C4922A7F1CACCE18604A0"><enum>5.</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than the end of the 180-day period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury shall issue regulations to be consistent with the amendments made by this Act.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


