<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H393641150F104443814AD4E26182687F" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1127 IH: Student Loan Fairness Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1127</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170216">February 16, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To increase purchasing power, strengthen economic recovery, and restore fairness in financing
			 higher education in the United States through student loan forgiveness,
			 caps on interest rates on Federal student loans, and refinancing
			 opportunities for private borrowers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H7DE60AEB9ED34F02BD4ABA180B0D8EEE" style="OLC">
 <section id="H1A1B83B2718C4135AA165C5CA2570A01" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Student Loan Fairness Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HA56000A36DBA499096EE6DCB3222636C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HE0AAC5B771934A1F8BADEA4E2DA348C5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A well-educated citizenry is critical to our Nation’s ability to compete in the global economy.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE655599AE85C4C5E8724A6680D425A2F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Federal Government has a vested interest in ensuring access to higher education.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB3204CEBAA0B4E559E0339365BB7ABE0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Higher education should be viewed as a public good benefitting our country rather than as a commodity solely benefitting individual students.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4948B3A2438F446BB51A8DAB89E06AE2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Recently, total outstanding student loan debt officially surpassed total credit card debt in the United States in 2015, and is on track to exceed $1,230,000,000,000.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H83DA1132E1194C5384D5F5E480FE7122"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Excessive student loan debt is impeding economic growth in the United States. Faced with excessive repayment burdens, many individuals are unable to start businesses, invest, or buy homes. Relieving student loan debt would give these individuals greater control over their earnings and would increase entrepreneurship and demand for goods and services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFA7671AB05DD4D28A5985C12614B7F64"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Because of soaring tuition costs, students often have no choice but to amass significant debt to obtain an education that is widely considered a prerequisite for earning a living wage.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF9D124E5E8044E53B2A927EBE5657529"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Amidst rising tuition rates and stagnant grant funding, many students are forced to supplement Federal loans with private loans, which frequently feature higher interest rates with fewer consumer protections.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6A879D75A4034D3596D9666EAF0B8110"><enum>(8)</enum><text>A borrower who experiences an extended hardship for whatever reason, or a borrower who experiences a series of separate hardships over a longer period of time, will often have no choice but to default on his or her private student loans. Opportunities to put such private loans into forbearance are limited.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2DF1DE9C70A64068BDF466F7885A1592"><enum>(9)</enum><text>During the period of forbearance on private student loans, interest continues to accrue and is capitalized, and once the borrower comes out of forbearance, he or she owes significantly more on the principal of the loan than before the hardship period began.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H36E0576EAC2E4BC5A3DDC275619B20E4" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>10/10 Loan Repayment and Forgiveness</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part G of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="H2B5C21DE184B40569A997E219C4D6563" style="OLC">
				<section id="HC85F5C007F90450CB61C01420BD330B8"><enum>493E.</enum><header>10/10 Loan Repayment and Forgiveness</header>
					<subsection id="HFBC9CE4B3EA4475EB3454191074BF053"><enum>(a)</enum><header>10/10 Loan Repayment Plan</header>
 <paragraph id="H7B3C63DB754E40109029D20E91136D9E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>10/10 Loan Repayment Plan authorized</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, the Secretary shall carry out a program (to be known as the <term>10/10 Loan Repayment Plan</term>) under which—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEC50E306F29F4B659FD20FC63F02C149"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a borrower of an eligible loan who is eligible under paragraph (3) may elect to have the borrower's aggregate monthly payment for all such loans not exceed the monthly payment amount described in paragraph (2);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0F25894BDC345CA909BBD4A6105DB49"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any interest due and not paid under a monthly payment under this subsection—</text> <clause id="HAA5A30B2A80F43E88506C59951F85EAD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall continue to accrue; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5D96656D412D4F20991686E1435F9609"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall be capitalized up to an amount equal to 10 percent of the original principal amount of all the eligible loans that the borrower is repaying under this subsection;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D385239E18F4EFBB443538B8797713C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any principal due and not paid under a monthly payment under this subsection shall be deferred, and shall be forgiven in accordance with <internal-xref idref="H07B2E3F3D5E34D048B56EB79E0065A1F" legis-path="493E.(b)">subsection (b)</internal-xref> if the borrower meets the requirements for forgiveness under such subsection;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB307E5D920434960988658CC98284A8C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the amount of time the borrower makes monthly payments under this subsection may exceed 10 years;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6EC0AB4B6F9C4AD79E5A101F576BAFF6"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a borrower who is repaying an eligible loan pursuant to 10/10 Loan Repayment under this subsection may elect, at any time, to terminate repayment pursuant to 10/10 Loan Repayment and repay such loan under the standard repayment plan, in which case the amount of time the borrower is permitted to repay such loans may exceed 10 years; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF75173730BDF4F52A35132BCB8119574"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the special allowance payment to a lender calculated under section 438(b)(2)(I), when calculated for a loan in repayment under this section, shall be calculated on the principal balance of the loan and on any accrued interest unpaid by the borrower in accordance with this section.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC85282B3606642809DACEADBEC4CF716"><enum>(2)</enum><header>10/10 Loan Repayment monthly payment formula</header><text>A borrower who has elected to participate in the 10/10 Loan Repayment Plan under this subsection shall, during each month the borrower is participating in such Plan, make a monthly payment in an amount equal to—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H3E5E1C8E9E5345B5A4BAB8140CE2CE15"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">one-twelfth of the amount that is 10 percent of the result obtained by calculating, on at least an annual basis, the amount by which—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="HF429D287314F46E3826D5B099428DB71"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the borrower’s, and the borrower’s spouse’s (if applicable), adjusted gross income; exceeds</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HAB94420369F04B92A5BA5CDB64207D06"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>150 percent of the poverty line applicable to the borrower’s family size as determined under section 673(2) of the Community Services Block Grant Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9902">42 U.S.C. 9902(2)</external-xref>); or</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0DB5157789AF41DDAB8300677B795F34"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a borrower who is in deferment due to an economic hardship described in section 435(o), $0.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H46D4F87829EF460394F56A6D97169D49"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish procedures for annually determining the borrower's eligibility for 10/10 Loan Repayment, including verification of a borrower's annual adjusted gross income and the annual amount due on the total amount of eligible loans, and such other procedures as are necessary to effectively implement 10/10 Loan Repayment under this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HBA55817BEACA4795B40EACB28C312D1E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Special rule for married borrowers filing separately</header><text>In the case of a married borrower who files a separate Federal income tax return, the Secretary shall calculate the amount of the borrower's 10/10 Loan Repayment under this subsection solely on the basis of the borrower's student loan debt and adjusted gross income.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H07B2E3F3D5E34D048B56EB79E0065A1F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>10/10 Loan Forgiveness</header>
 <paragraph id="HB1B0BCDEADCB49BA93F65C4B518638FA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall carry out a program (to be known as the <term>10/10 Loan Forgiveness Program</term>) to forgive a qualified loan amount, in accordance with <internal-xref idref="HC10F2521335E4FCF962D20DE6DDE3957" legis-path="493E.(b)(3)">paragraph (3)</internal-xref>, on an eligible loan for a borrower who, after the date that is 10 years prior to the date of enactment of the <short-title>Student Loan Fairness Act</short-title>, has made 120 monthly payments on the eligible loan pursuant to any one or a combination of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFA020123071E4B3A821BE464A4C1A585"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Monthly payment under the 10/10 Loan Repayment Plan under <internal-xref idref="HFBC9CE4B3EA4475EB3454191074BF053" legis-path="493E.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H47DFCC0AE4604875893F3F08B65A48CF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Monthly payment under any other repayment plan authorized under part B or D of an amount that, for a given month, is not less than the monthly payment amount calculated under subsection (a) that the borrower would have owed in the year in which such payment was made, based on the borrower’s adjusted gross income and eligible loan balance for such year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HFF27DAFC689E48FEB9E0FD721F796195"><enum>(C)</enum><text>For any month after such date during which the borrower is in deferment due to an economic hardship described in section 435(o), monthly payment of $0.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA604662D8F5F426DA42EB3BE00A5D279"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Method of loan forgiveness</header><text>To provide loan forgiveness under <internal-xref idref="HB1B0BCDEADCB49BA93F65C4B518638FA" legis-path="493E.(b)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref>, the Secretary is authorized to carry out a program—</text> <subparagraph id="H5EE8ACC2571B4D2280A3E85F060ED37C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>through the holder of the loan, to assume the obligation to repay a qualified loan amount for a loan made, insured, or guaranteed under part B of this title; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61326807D78D4D649E651D09D6D9F0DD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to cancel a qualified loan amount for a loan made under part D of this title.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC10F2521335E4FCF962D20DE6DDE3957"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified loan amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After the borrower has made 120 monthly payments described in <internal-xref idref="HB1B0BCDEADCB49BA93F65C4B518638FA" legis-path="493E.(b)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref>, the Secretary shall forgive—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HABD8B6CAEBE642D685A07586112581A5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to new borrowers on or after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Student Loan Fairness Act</short-title>, the sum of—</text> <clause id="H063AC82C2C7D4D3486DFBD52F32DF704"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the balance of principal and fees due on the borrower’s eligible loans as of the time of such forgiveness, not to exceed $45,520; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA0B3B76436F843C9B66E61C8DA181770"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of interest that has accrued on the balance described in <internal-xref idref="H063AC82C2C7D4D3486DFBD52F32DF704" legis-path="493E.(b)(3)(A)(i)">clause (i)</internal-xref> as of the time of such forgiveness; or</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3193FC44183C47358C02D985384CEC5B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to any other eligible borrower, the balance of principal, interest, and fees due on the borrower’s eligible loans as of the time of such forgiveness.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC50C7A597134423F86E9A4E00279B3AC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exclusion from taxable income</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of a borrower’s eligible loans forgiven under this section shall not be included in the gross income of the borrower for purposes of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H676636FF04FA4D6AA5765FF9D7CDF426"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Supporting documentation required</header><text>A borrower who has elected to participate in the 10/10 Loan Repayment Plan under subsection (a), or who is requesting forgiveness under the 10/10 Loan Forgiveness Program under <internal-xref idref="H07B2E3F3D5E34D048B56EB79E0065A1F" legis-path="493E.(b)">subsection (b)</internal-xref>, shall provide to the Secretary such information and documentation as the Secretary determines, by regulation, to be necessary to verify the borrower’s adjusted gross income and payment amounts made on eligible loans of the borrower for the purposes of such Plan or Program.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H18E49913E61D41FB9CDF0361ED9DC5FB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition of eligible loan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section the term <term>eligible loan</term> means any loan made, insured, or guaranteed under part B or D.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section><section id="HA31E0A48532E4226A30B9D0FE436D46D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Capping interest rates for all Federal Direct loans</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 455(b) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6D7C63C6D3BE4E25AB7E17151B67A757"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (9) and (10) as paragraphs (10) and (11), respectively; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA21F82C3CA7F44CFA551F7CB3721F82A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (8) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H26582A028CA4408B84AF2E4BA98C89EA" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H073795722D534965AC4D2E91FDA82CD2"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Rate of interest for all new Federal Direct loans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, with respect to a loan under this part for which the first disbursement of principal is made (or in the case of a Federal Direct Consolidation Loan, for which the application is received) on or after October 1, 2018, or the date of enactment of the <short-title>Student Loan Fairness Act</short-title>, whichever is later, the applicable rate of interest shall not exceed 3.4 percent.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H02CCA142B16240B591017D669BB92206"><enum>5.</enum><header>10/10 Loan Repayment Plan as plan selected by the Secretary</header>
			<subsection id="H9A66B67701DD445C8A949BBE14F9F74D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>FFEL Loans</header>
 <paragraph id="HC485A6C66ECC46379618D113D1B53386"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 428(b)(9) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1078">20 U.S.C. 1078(b)(9)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H45D61668C4524981AB59767727E318AE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text>
 <clause id="H2F91B86E70C94B4895B0457A69F071EF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of clause (iv);</text> </clause><clause id="HB742C7590432478E9EB2F0CF1EEFFA70"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (v), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H151695CAE55A4ABDA42E1F4C9063E3BE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8D837A1B9B974DFCB577FC62AFB16DF5" style="OLC"> <clause id="H09317E8695C049648C0A239A0ED90893"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">beginning October 1, 2018, a 10/10 Loan Repayment Plan, with varying annual repayment amounts based on the discretionary income of the borrower, in accordance with section 493E.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4778D9DF2C6F434C82615DB63F0BA7CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>(A)(i)</quote> and inserting <quote>(A)(vi)</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC47339587D254666BBACD2F8609AA33D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by paragraph (1)(B) shall be effective beginning October 1, 2018.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3E80370768D649A49D8268ED1F909CD0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Direct Loans</header>
 <paragraph id="H870A6F5689E24630B04D0FE08E961BD2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 455(d) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H87013323170348789E71712303AE2936"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text>
 <clause id="HF4C528D5220E423AAAB8E66C5C4C397B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (D);</text> </clause><clause id="HF1E5625C35EA4481ACCD20FD8E339957"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1F11633B6DCD482792DB452C73E0A1EC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFEE14AD2A85B448CAD586E9019A99784" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H041E39EAC37242C5B5172C77636AC2E7"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">beginning on October 1, 2018, a 10/10 Loan Repayment Plan, with varying annual repayment amounts based on the discretionary income of the borrower, in accordance with section 493E.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C46925D3C224BB6AD228B2EF1EE6E8A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> <clause id="H35C2AABD21964BD58FEE031E5997A260"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>may</quote> and inserting <quote>shall</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC6C376EC4FFB43A18E9AA20D92A09B2D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(A), (B), or (C)</quote> and inserting <quote>(F)</quote>.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H36332B2B235D407F95F23F3F52F718D3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by paragraph (1)(B) shall be effective beginning October 1, 2018.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0F4759B253E04C64994C2C422B5D4B5A"><enum>6.</enum><header>Improving and expanding Public Service Loan Forgiveness</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 455(m) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(m)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HE9085A7B3CC44D4BBCBF071D995FECAB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>120</quote> and inserting <quote>60</quote> each place it appears; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H78AB71056D104B22A8068A4D13867AFD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(B)—</text> <subparagraph id="H550B37A879C14B70AF9028EA47AD5D8B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>or</quote> after the semicolon;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2E6B39E09DB4CE5846094B6AF990F30"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C1804B17F094FF99CF98F6CF44230B4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF9C20D48D7DC42758FB8D83A44D9146B" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H5DD5AC58F5FA4FBFB5F9AF55C9FC9FFC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a full-time job as a primary care physician in an area or population designated as a Medically Underserved Area or Population by the Health Resource and Services Administration.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HC15FD5DD07084ADA9B5F37D2B6FD6052"><enum>7.</enum><header>Refinancing private education loans for certain borrowers</header>
 <subsection id="H8EC3571B54D142649295B3B1FF27896B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Consolidation for certain borrowers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 455(g) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(g)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H66E880FFBEB8479CA959D4173AA3CAB6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>A borrower</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCBBBBBD81A0548C8BF35CECB92E92BFD" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HA6C78A650F4B44B78DAEAF508728F483"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A borrower</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HCDA0F53D8C1A474BA3DAB344A8F43D30"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, and any loan described in paragraph (2)</quote> after <quote>July 1, 2010</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H354469F315774F9CA1C8A575353EF912"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block id="H2F2A213CA2244A40896A1C6A8BF452E2" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HE9B04EE1D9DC46529A96DFB220D6FC39"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consolidation of private education loans as a Federal Direct Consolidation Loan for certain borrowers</header> <subparagraph id="HD64D8D6E8C4046558C84EEBBD5C3DBD9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a borrower who meets the eligibility criteria described in subparagraph (B) shall be eligible to obtain a Federal Direct Consolidation loan under this paragraph that—</text>
 <clause id="H60ABE32F54FC46B1B30E199BE9097188"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall include an eligible private education loan; and</text> </clause><clause id="H06EA5BFFE6B249B7B101ED4473A0D070"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may include a loan described in section 428C(a)(4).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HEDB01BC72A0C4873BF195D8DA293D7CE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligible borrower</header><text>A borrower of an eligible private education loan is eligible to obtain a Federal Direct Consolidation Loan under this paragraph if the borrower—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H60B75C0321C3400BAA17D6F1DC3186CE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>was eligible to borrow a loan under section 428H, a Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loan, a loan under section 428B, or a Federal Direct PLUS loan for a period of enrollment at an institution of higher education, or, with respect to a borrower who was enrolled at an institution of higher education on less than a half-time basis, would have been eligible to borrow such a loan for such period of enrollment if the borrower had been enrolled on at least a half-time basis;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H0315F149DCA44FC588A51E5C5EE7B832"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>borrowed at least one eligible private education loan for a period of enrollment described in <internal-xref idref="H60B75C0321C3400BAA17D6F1DC3186CE" legis-path="(2)(B)(i)">clause (i)</internal-xref>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H8B3E640BAA6E42F29402EAA357F1FD1A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>has an average adjusted gross income (based on the borrower’s adjusted gross income from the 3 most recent calendar years before application for consolidation under this section) that is equal to or less than the borrower’s total education debt (determined by calculating the sum of the borrower’s loans described in section 428C(a)(4) and eligible private education loans) at the time of such application.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10AE168A98454B03ABD655748CF88384"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Definition of eligible private education loan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>eligible private education loan</term> means a private education loan (as such term is defined in section 140 of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1650">15 U.S.C. 1650</external-xref>)) made on or before the date of enactment of the <short-title>Student Loan Fairness Act</short-title>, including the amount of outstanding principal, accrued interest, and related fees and costs (as determined by the Secretary) owed by a borrower on such a loan.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBCC95F31D624A94B7EB9B00F52A7455"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Purchase of loan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each eligible private education loan that a borrower is consolidating under this paragraph, the Secretary shall notify the holder that the Secretary is purchasing the loan, and the Secretary shall then purchase such loan, as described under section 140A of the Truth in Lending Act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE79010AD2F4A4C0EB8CFC054024F8257"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Terms and rate of interest</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Federal Direct Consolidation Loan made under this paragraph shall have the same terms and conditions as a Federal Direct Consolidation loan under paragraph (1), except that the applicable rate of interest for a Federal Direct Consolidation loan made under this paragraph shall not exceed 3.4 percent.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAAA1B84104404B9D984F75ED9B0FBC5C"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Notification of eligible borrowers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall take such steps as may be necessary to notify eligible borrowers of the availability of consolidation under this paragraph no later than 60 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Student Loan Fairness Act</short-title>, including notifying such borrowers of the deadline to apply for such a loan under <internal-xref idref="H3298700441964FAD892C22F70A532C0C" legis-path="(2)(G)">subparagraph (G)</internal-xref>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3298700441964FAD892C22F70A532C0C"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Application deadline for loans under this paragraph</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A borrower may apply for loans under this paragraph during the 1-year period beginning on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Student Loan Fairness Act</short-title>. The Secretary shall not make a Federal Direct Consolidation Loan under this paragraph to any borrower who has not submitted an application for such a loan to the Secretary before the end of such period.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA13C42CFF40045ACA5E0428C14B43A58"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Authorization and appropriation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated, and there are appropriated, such sums as may be necessary to carry out this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H981A6B47CA404E8BB2B651A4A8E72A6D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sale of private education loans to the Government</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chapter 2 of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1631">15 U.S.C. 1631</external-xref> et seq.) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H8E56160556244EA283D7FF22905979DA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating section 140A as section 140B;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2138A753D24B4EAE85080971D38B3DA5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after section 140 the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2B65DEC6D442427FA4E4D2154272F482" style="USC"> <section id="HCC016F0DB8C446A182A23462F8651928"><enum>140A.</enum><header>Sale of private education loans to the Government</header> <subsection id="H6892871B44F54C8B8B413559B99EC5DE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bureau shall issue regulations to require a private education lender to sell an eligible private education loan to the Secretary of Education, upon request of the Secretary, for purposes of consolidating such loan, as described under section 455(g)(2) of the Higher Education Act of 1965.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9FECBDC2840E41A690421DD867A78ADF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Determination of price</header><text>The price paid for a private education loan under subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph id="HEB282C10F143490384BFF058322F02AE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>include the amount of outstanding principal on the loan, the amount of accrued interest on the loan, and any fees or other costs owed by the consumer on the loan; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H226D2F9E16A948338378E26DCD237636"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be adjusted to account for the time value of such amount.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H003C85173829481D85B3660101C64902"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text>
 <paragraph id="H9C77CD2420F0400C97158C7F07C0E5A0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible private education loan</header><text>The term <term>eligible private education loan</term> means a private education loan, as defined under section 140(a), made on or before the date of enactment of the Student Loan Fairness Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H66D1D6AF3A92490CBBF5633E153ACD85"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Private education lender</header><text>The term <term>private education lender</term> has the meaning given such term under section 140(a).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD35284C7509D41479555ABD6469C138B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in the table of contents for such chapter—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5CE28490B4C84DED9A25DCB49822581C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating the item relating to section 140A as item 140B; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H063DC0BCD6D04CC9987359EF699E58DE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after the item relating to section 140 the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC826C41A3ECA4914A58FB5B56A722A07" style="OLC">
							<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
								<toc-entry level="section">140A. Sale of private education loans to the Government.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6ABB0200AAC94E8285046282FB9AAB84"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 428C(a)(3)(B)(i)(V) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1078-3">20 U.S.C. 1078–3(a)(3)(B)(i)(V)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H155CC77B49C344F8BE35F0848E1F5AA0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of item (bb);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H54A50C23F4F345A38A89E0C6EC7E568D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of item (cc) and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF4A426B70395464394417B291CC8D748"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9F893A3531B141D084B9FBA41D56339B" style="OLC"> <item id="H47AD549180834C1A865EB842BDE8A154"><enum>(dd)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for the purpose of consolidating an eligible private education loan under section 455(g)(2), whether such loan is consolidated alone, with other eligible private education loans, or with loans described in paragraph (4).</text></item><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB3C0D8548D9B4C4D927D634653B62A91"><enum>8.</enum><header>Interest-free deferment of unsubsidized loans during periods of unemployment</header>
			<subsection id="H04A890C4A947402EA5893FF1AD056A9E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>FFEL Unsubsidized loan deferment</header>
 <paragraph id="HCFA19439D56D45CCB2169D8792EF9099"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 428H(e)(2) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1078-8">20 U.S.C. 1078–8(e)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H2DFFAEFF1A2D4C24A75DE8E2F57922AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>Interest on</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in subparagraph (C), interest on</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6587AA3F3F014DF2A357157511C50E44"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H65A91895594849448867FA9956B7688D" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HAEC244FDEEEE4E8F8AFFDB10888ACB38" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Interest on loans made under this section for which payments are deferred under clause (ii) of section 428(b)(1)(M), for a period of deferment granted to a borrower on or after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Student Loan Fairness Act</short-title>, shall accrue and be paid by the Secretary during any period during which loans are so deferred, not in excess of 3 years.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A8D4150FFA54AB4A8C17C5A85A5A389"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 428(b)(1)(Y)(iii) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1078">20 U.S.C. 1078(b)(1)(Y)(iii)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>(other than a deferment under clause (ii) of such subparagraph on or after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Student Loan Fairness Act</short-title>)</quote> after <quote>of this paragraph</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE42210F0C209425682F35FE64EDC8B8E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Direct Unsubsidized loan deferment</header><text>Section 455(f)(1) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(f)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H6376EA43B13948BC8697AE00924C1B62"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H047665ACC9E54F4183D321FC566E81C0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of clause (i); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFFB53BED7E4448C380773C84C00BF2D5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4E9A47C0BF7D4F49870AC50ED859A380" style="OLC">
 <clause commented="no" id="HB2F55572A5744DF6897149BD7A669334"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loan, with respect to a period of deferment described in subparagraph (B) of paragraph (2) granted to a borrower on or after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Student Loan Fairness Act</short-title>; or</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8E1C8EEC2F14DAF88D231F5525B478C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by inserting <quote>not described in subparagraph (A)(iii)</quote> after <quote>Unsubsidized Stafford Loan</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H8834276730FB4754BF08436A78D0D0AA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Treatment of consolidation loans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 428C(b)(4)(C)(ii) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1078-3">20 U.S.C. 1078–3(b)(4)(C)(ii)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HB6FE006EC216487B9062D237D76BD498"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of subclause (II);</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H771A67FA42374581897506EB78DA3C95"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subclause (III) as subclause (IV);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HAA4209052D984651A5A85AB4F23BFE23"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subclause (II) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H48E171CBBBCF4471B7B9D2EAB056942B" style="OLC"> <subclause commented="no" id="H8AE4C86A396B4693B7C2C1B225A6860B"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by the Secretary, in the case of a consolidation loan for which the application is received on or after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Student Loan Fairness Act</short-title>, except that the Secretary shall pay such interest only for a period not in excess of 3 years for which the borrower would be eligible for a deferral under clause (ii) of section 428(b)(1)(M); or</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H378EDFFA74474C1C8851D1D7D6FCA8BB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subclause (IV) (as redesignated by paragraph (2)), by striking <quote>(I) or (II)</quote> and inserting <quote>(I), (II), or (III)</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H518D7F2877C54D3B803D12C342349AC2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Income-Based repayment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 493C(b) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/10983">20 U.S.C. 10983(b)</external-xref>)—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF1DA95D010004D6BAE2C0D2FD000FB56"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text> <subparagraph id="H9EC3ADD77C8D4156A8DCE8E16DA70BB5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7702535FEF294C3FB10F4AD3855B9C89"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (B) as subparagraph (C);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF0AE47FFE974A5F94DCC79BE63B3B3A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (A) the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H14D0AB186625424FA3ED9CF90C913A15" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="HB04B6171B6B845088ABE5D31151EB34F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall, on subsidized and unsubsidized loans, be paid by the Secretary for a period of not more than 3 years during which the borrower is eligible for a deferment due to unemployment described in section 455(f)(2)(B) (regardless of whether the student is in such a deferment), except that—</text>
 <clause id="H218B836E652A4AB39C4A00770B40226E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">this subparagraph shall only apply to periods during which the borrower is eligible for such a deferment on or after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Student Loan Fairness Act</short-title>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB86F04F71F8748BC8D34ACFC14D03D58"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a subsidized loan, such period shall not include any period described in subparagraph (A) or any period during which the borrower is in deferment due to an economic hardship described in section 435(o); and</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H378008F10B23477DA2AEE0DB261827B9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C) (as so redesignated by subparagraph (B))—</text> <clause id="H57A222CCDA134A5EB8F36A4BAAAAE3E8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>subparagraph (A)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraphs (A) and (B)</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8AA5436A08A44EB5A31837F86D1B8C20"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by inserting <quote>, subject to subparagraph (B),</quote> after <quote>unsubsidized loan</quote>; and</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD16CA88FEB9D4E07B39AD0B3AC365335"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (8);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H36D33C7A8D154A95AB8DAFE4DBEB4AF0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of paragraph (9) and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8A14EC2CF4674342A25C24D795A806BD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBE0EA2302BEF4D479124D7884C79ADC2" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HF9D2373F37A8480295D7B2F0B23154C2"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of the principal and interest on a borrower’s loans repaid or canceled under paragraph (7) shall not be included in the gross income of the borrower for purposes of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HFF66A65B21FA44F8A2C4F0DB82FC1C47"><enum>9.</enum><header>Excluding loans forgiven under certain repayment programs from gross income</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 455(e)(2) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(e)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H604B6E8374474020938C806FE8E06A8A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">and forgiveness</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">repayment</header-in-text></quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9858B3D5CF6D48ED82C9BAB0688E06D8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: <quote>The amount of the principal and interest on a borrower’s loans forgiven pursuant to income contingent repayment shall not be included in the gross income of the borrower for purposes of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</quote>.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


