<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H64B9290064594C9189D30DB222821F68" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1372 IH: Homeland Security for Children Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1372</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170306">March 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to ensure that the needs of children are considered in
			 homeland security planning, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H5103D07FFBD643BCA5EE676E8F108DDE" style="OLC">
 <section id="H5D49C605A3A2484C95C13D5404624F1E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Homeland Security for Children Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H09BCD0DC25C34B7CA97A956CC337BD7F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Responsibilities of the Under Secretary for Strategy, Policy, and Plans</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subsection (c) of section 709 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/349">6 U.S.C. 349</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE6D7AD5F42C247729C733515F1599F9E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (4) through (7) as paragraphs (5) through (8), respectively; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFC19DB3DF7FB44CB8FA1073DA5CC5804"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (3) the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4A3CD0B6623F40A09425604AC31BCDC3" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H7AF1E9F67ED547A9BC788B4D499EE82B"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">lead, conduct, and coordinate Department-wide identification and integration of the needs of children into the Department’s policies, programs, and activities, in coordination with relevant outside organizations and experts, as necessary.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H9D1DDF6F0F1C45828C6F303FADFA83B2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Technical expert authorized</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Paragraph (2) of section 503(b) of the Homeland Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/313">6 U.S.C. 313(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H194C01CD14B648089D55ED8DE6CCBA72"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (G), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD8EDB7659D9A4278ABAC62D63A9048F9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (H), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD4DA08BA05D64FB098A24ABF4756B4C2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H69ACC49988E5451BAB73C596EEB4FDC5" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H4F48A471B5D841F681738619092CF48C"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify and integrate the needs of children into activities to prepare for, protect against, respond to, recover from, and mitigate against the risk of natural disasters, acts of terrorism, and other manmade disasters, including catastrophic incidents, including by appointing a technical expert, who may consult with relevant outside organizations and experts, as necessary, to coordinate such integration, as necessary.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HC5B874EA6E7348CFB72E58953A22BE71"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter for five years, the Under Secretary for Strategy, Policy, and Plans of the Department of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report describing the efforts the Department has undertaken to identify and integrate the needs of children into the Department’s policies, programs, and activities in accordance with paragraph (4) of section 709(c) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (as added by section 2 of this Act), including information on the following:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HA060F69ADF874A4DBCA06E9DC4AE230D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The designation of any individual responsible for carrying out such paragraph (4).</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB9C62F3D438C481692A29235A1EE8C03"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any review, formal or informal, of any policies, programs, or activities of the Department under such paragraph (4) to assess the suitability of such policies, programs, or activities for children.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3926CC4331EA4036A7272727C2C27F21"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any such review, change, modification, or promulgation of any such policies, programs, or activities to ensure that such policies, programs, or activities are appropriate for children.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC87C1DA1FC544ED1B5C95181279823B7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Coordination with organizations or experts outside the Department pursuant to such paragraph (4) conducted to inform any such review, change, modification, or promulgation of such policies, programs, or activities.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


