<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HADB4AF7923374A7AB8116627257FAE28" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4254 IH: Women in Aerospace Education Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4254</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171106">November 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000387">Mr. Knight</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="E000293">Ms. Esty of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001105">Mrs. Comstock</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the National Science Foundation Authorization Act of 2002 to strengthen the aerospace
			 workforce pipeline by the promotion of Robert Noyce Teacher Scholarship
			 Program and National Aeronautics and Space Administration internship and
			 fellowship opportunities to women, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HDF33651C908540B2AF6E80624B5D33F4" style="OLC">
 <section id="H35E0790874D74AE58B4C23707FA1D765" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Women in Aerospace Education Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HACC0AF91978A4347AA1CC4D0DA2EDF2E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Robert Noyce Teacher Scholarship Program fellowship opportunities</header> <subsection id="H4E0066D9F4334C7B8A7408941BA84C18"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 10 of the National Science Foundation Authorization Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1862n-1">42 U.S.C. 1862n–1</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6D5CBDBAB43948B1B53D3E03F571814F" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HF6E56E2D526C4753B158ABC200050365"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Fellowship placements in national laboratories and NASA centers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Science Foundation shall encourage eligible entities administering a fellowship program using funds awarded under this section to include in such program opportunities for the placement of fellows in research or education internship opportunities at national laboratories and NASA centers. The Director may give priority to proposals for such placements that provide female fellows with research experience in aerospace engineering and related fields in which women are underrepresented.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0006E9E91F894A2C9DB29237E6FBDA41"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to grants awarded on or after October 1, 2018.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H68AB5617E2374C37B7EDDA379BE3295C"><enum>3.</enum><header>NASA internship and fellowship opportunities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than October 1, 2018, the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (in this section referred to as <quote>NASA</quote>) shall institute a process to prioritize the promotion and recruitment of qualified candidates who are women or individuals who are historically underrepresented in the fields of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) and computer science for internships and fellowships at NASA with relevance to the aerospace sector and related fields.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


