<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD2FEA7CDFE8947D4980E122E70C2666C" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4010 RH: Congressional Subpoena Compliance and Enforcement Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
		<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 264</calendar>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4010</legis-num>
		<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 115–360]</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20171011">October 11, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000289">Mr. Goodlatte</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000583">Mr. Smith of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000460">Mr. Farenthold</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HJU00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<action><action-date>October 23, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsor: <cosponsor name-id="M001189">Mr. Messer</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action>
			<action-date>October 23, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the
			 Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
			<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction>
			<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on October 11, 2017</action-instruction>
		</action>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-desc display="yes"><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To amend the Revised Statutes of the United States and title 28, United States Code, to enhance
			 compliance with requests for information pursuant to legislative power
			 under Article I of the Constitution, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body changed="added" committee-id="HJU00" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HA069EBCBE6EC4A91ABFD2ABB6B7A7D1A" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <section id="H63A69B3B327141C7899EF8CB6980CEFC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Congressional Subpoena Compliance and Enforcement Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HC334E054487341589A5DEB420E6E1E22"><enum>2.</enum><header>Enforcement of congressional subpoenas</header> <subsection id="HC49853C413D6451AA356F90CE5E0366F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/85">Chapter 85</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/28/1365">section 1365</external-xref> the following:</text>
				<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HJU00" id="H0BDB11031AFC4775A3D20D491D9FCD54" reported-display-style="italic" style="USC">
					<section id="HB68E05019A614772810215E6DF15435A"><enum>1365a.</enum><header>Congressional actions against subpoena recipients</header>
 <subsection id="H72DC8B01909B4A5B910C0109ADF201D4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Special rules</header><text>In any civil action brought by the United States House of Representatives, the United States Senate, or a committee or subcommittee thereof, against the recipient of a subpoena to secure declaratory, injunctive, or other relief as may be appropriate concerning the failure to comply with a subpoena issued by a congressional committee or subcommittee, the following rules shall apply:</text>
 <paragraph id="H906300F1C5C347A1AA6D29925D27E6FD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The action shall be filed in a United States district court of competent jurisdiction.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H38F451F002174FA28438609FB7299B83"><enum>(2)</enum><text>It shall be the duty of the United States district courts, the United States courts of appeal, and the Supreme Court of the United States to advance on the docket and to expedite to the greatest possible extent the disposition of any such action and appeal.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC945274FF2B347889BD61C96C9F0E2DE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>If a three-judge court is expressly requested by the plaintiff in the initial pleading, the action shall be heard by a three-judge court convened pursuant to section 2284 of title 28, United States Code, and shall be reviewable only by appeal directly to the Supreme Court of the United States. Such appeal shall be taken by the filing of a notice of appeal within 10 days, and the filing of a jurisdictional statement within 30 days, of the entry of the final decision.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDCC0E84A754F41A691EE64B38C8158CE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Monetary penalties in cases involving government agencies</header>
 <paragraph id="H9377F0D7B0E9450DBFDA9848FB6FE88B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The court may impose monetary penalties directly against the head of a Government agency or a component thereof held to have willfully failed to comply with any part of a congressional subpoena.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H70D95F41B7BC4AFBB4572B55BCA60833"><enum>(2)</enum><text>No appropriated funds, funds provided from any accounts in the Treasury, funds derived from the collection of fees, or other Government funds shall be used to pay any monetary penalty imposed by the court pursuant to this section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H95037EA89F1A4C5997442D6865E5DC6F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver of privilege</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any assertion of a privilege or other ground for noncompliance (whether statutory, common law, or otherwise) asserted by the recipient of a congressional subpoena may be determined to have been waived as to any particular record withheld from production if the court finds that the recipient failed in a timely manner to comply with the requirement of section 105 of the Revised Statutes of the United States that it produce a privilege log with respect to such record.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB22E5C96DD6245ABB527DE8133473A6E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>Government agency</quote> means an executive department listed in section 101 of title 5, United States Code, an independent establishment, commission, board, bureau, division, or office in the executive branch, or other agency of the Federal Government, including wholly or partly owned Government corporations.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8C1ACB79B83C48DFA814AFA1A6B8C8E1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/85">chapter 85</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/28/1365">section 1365</external-xref> the following:</text>
				<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HJU00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBAF93CEA7FAE42419E50F6D70A031022" reported-display-style="italic" style="USC">
					<toc changed="added" committee-id="HJU00" regeneration="no-regeneration" reported-display-style="italic">
						<toc-entry level="section">1365a. Congressional actions against subpoena recipients.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H265FA01E334E42FF82B5921BFB554D8D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Compliance with congressional subpoenas</header>
 <subsection id="H2368AE2806CE449EA4CBBB8E8563583E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chapter seven of title II of the Revised Statutes of the United States (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/191">2 U.S.C. 191</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HJU00" id="H68551C15077043E6BD1E6093F8A750F5" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
					<section id="HC39B116EF9A94ED79E55D4EB0E2E8BD6"><enum>105.</enum><header>Response to congressional subpoenas</header>
 <subsection id="H08BD93AAF69D4883A13AF5AF7FC61F9E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Subpoena by congressional committee</header><text>Any recipient of any subpoena from a congressional committee or subcommittee shall appear and testify or produce records in a manner consistent with the subpoena and this section.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H5123ECAE9F7040F78A4FCFAE19369191"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Congressional subpoenas for records</header>
 <paragraph id="H50C341E2A19646418C70CDD2114558C3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Identification of records withheld</header><text>In the case of a record that is withheld, in whole or in part, by the subpoena recipient, the subpoena recipient shall provide a log containing the following information concerning such record:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H957CB2631B94476293C153E024EA6DC1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An express assertion and description of the legal basis asserted for withholding the record.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35E6CE17FB9C4DBC8F6D8ED09B9D6987"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The type of record.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6DC35403386A4E11B33C8470E766F01B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The general subject matter.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8DE7FA9301364F709CDDD924502A19A6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The date, author, and addressee.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34E4B3CBF875474CA18B93DDEFF0AA3D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The relationship of the author and addressee to each other.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H062E202D75B44228A381E8A9AB0A71B5"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The custodian of the record.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CBE9BA0AB21418086C8380F05AFA2F8"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Any other descriptive information that may be produced or disclosed regarding the record that will enable the congressional committee or subcommittee issuing the subpoena to assess the legal basis asserted for withholding the record.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H33CBF7BB478E40D497B494153B32BD9C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Missing records</header><text>In the case of any record responsive to the subpoena submitted under paragraph (1) that was, but no longer is, in the possession, custody, or control of the subpoena recipient, the subpoena recipient shall identify the record (including the date, author, subject, and each recipient of the record) and explain the circumstances under which the record ceased to be in the possession, custody, or control of the subpoena recipient.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H76542DE203E046FAAF4BA8C8B9BB8BEE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Electronic records</header><text>Electronic records shall be produced pursuant to this subsection in their native or original file format. Electronic records shall be delivered on a storage device (such as compact disk, memory stick, or thumb drive) and, to the extent feasible, shall be organized, identified, and indexed electronically and shall include an index describing the contents of the production.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF2F13CC265554F719D87098F63FF56F4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section the term <quote>record</quote> includes any books, papers, documents, data, or other objects requested in a subpoena issued by a congressional committee or subcommittee.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1EA90D473B4C491697C4DF9740C82489"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents for chapter 7 of title II of the Revised Statutes of the United States is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HJU00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6254F4CB1D17422CB6D8AC8583979982" reported-display-style="italic" style="USC">
					<toc changed="added" committee-id="HJU00" regeneration="no-regeneration" reported-display-style="italic">
						<toc-entry level="section">105. Response to congressional subpoenas.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section id="H0F3CE38B85C94E55A2365787DCD2B981"><enum>4.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be interpreted to diminish Congress’ inherent authority or previously established methods and practices for enforcing compliance with congressional subpoenas, nor shall anything in this Act be interpreted to establish Congress’ acceptance of any privilege or other legal basis for noncompliance with a congressional subpoena.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
	<endorsement display="yes">
		<action-date>October 23, 2017</action-date>
		<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the
			 Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill>


