<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H0645318A43734BD3B4DAF96607D5310E" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2880 IH: Promoting Closed-Loop Pumped Storage Hydropower Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2880</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170612">June 12, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000568">Mr. Griffith</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Power Act to promote closed-loop pumped storage hydropower, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H01926C370BCB4A77BA4236F32A27DFE4" style="OLC">
 <section id="HD88CFF80CCD84E3DAF2A9FAD34FCDB95" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Promoting Closed-Loop Pumped Storage Hydropower Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H69D791D0634941A28FC5DD52E3E48798"><enum>2.</enum><header>Closed-loop pumped storage projects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part I of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/792">16 U.S.C. 792</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="HFD1844CDFF7A4F2C928EA60F68F2A823">
				<section id="HED7E7786F0004F058B1ECC246D0FEFFA"><enum>34.</enum><header>Closed-loop pumped storage projects</header>
 <subsection id="HC12E98254016405FBF4509F80FBCE40A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HFBFC488F23F349FA81062133CFFD6A6E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Closed-loop pumped storage project</header><text>The term <term>closed-loop pumped storage project</term> means a project—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H80C6827831E044E8B923919085EDCE82"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in which the upper and lower reservoirs do not impound or directly withdraw water from navigable waters; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF51D86DB997B4827B705957D3F8A82B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that is not continuously connected to a naturally flowing water feature.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC881D701845247DA8D9EA4057AC01868"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal authorization</header><text>The term <term>Federal authorization</term>—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2DC63C21D5994CDF98071BBAA99FE37D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any authorization required under Federal law with respect to an application for a license, license amendment, or exemption under this part; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD7256F994004B5C9F8FCB8CC54E80EB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes any permits, special use authorizations, certifications, opinions, or other approvals as may be required under Federal law to approve or implement the license, license amendment, or exemption under this part.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H31DDC257D2E243ABA594E1023DE00C38"><enum>(b)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As provided in this section, the Commission may issue and amend licenses and preliminary permits, as appropriate, for closed-loop pumped storage projects.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3524873505CE47F296174FC5D947D6C9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Dam safety</header><text>Before issuing any license for a closed-loop pumped storage project, the Commission shall assess the safety of existing dams and other structures related to the project (including possible consequences associated with failure of such structures).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H14398B7680554EEF90ACC35DDF3D4874"><enum>(d)</enum><header>License conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a closed-loop pumped storage project, the authority of the Commission to impose conditions on a license under sections 4(e), 10(a), 10(g), and 10(j) shall not apply, and any condition included in or applicable to a closed-loop pumped storage project licensed under this section, including any condition or other requirement of a Federal authorization, shall be limited to those that are—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6EF6AC531DE04C7887DD8245997805A6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>necessary to protect public safety; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3D8EA38C6C274E91AD6294E5E8E44B9C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reasonable, economically feasible, and essential to prevent loss of or damage to, or to mitigate adverse effects on, fish and wildlife resources directly caused by the construction and operation of the project, as compared to the environmental baseline existing at the time the Commission completes its environmental review.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF5E116FD83BC4DDDA9C25D16273FC100"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Transfers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 5, and regardless of whether the holder of a preliminary permit for a closed-loop pumped storage project claimed municipal preference under section 7(a) when obtaining the permit, the Commission may, to facilitate development of a closed-loop pumped storage project—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA150E04842AE4097B75B5FDEFB7BB1E8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>add entities as joint permittees following issuance of a preliminary permit; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H351A9DD8582747679174F2385CC98CB9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>transfer a license in part to one or more nonmunicipal entities as co-licensees with a municipality.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


