<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H02D7A9F388DF4E02B323DF1B70DEA94D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3032 IH: Mental Health Access Improvement Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3032</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170623">June 23, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for the coverage of marriage and family therapist services and mental health counselor services under part B of the Medicare program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4E1F4028E3604708B2994CA9DB2CC894" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H26F800D7862E472580C5880C791A2473" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Mental Health Access Improvement Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H52709AFBB545470090ED99120A402551"><enum>2.</enum><header>Coverage of marriage and family therapist services and mental health counselor services under part <enum-in-header>B</enum-in-header> of the Medicare program</header> <subsection id="HFF1DDE5DAAA041D89E77228E7228DD3B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Coverage of Services</header> <paragraph id="HED2CF515B82E4C8DB835A50B2EE7940B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1861(s)(2) of the <act-name parsable-cite="SSA">Social Security Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(s)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<subparagraph id="H8C1D99510C604EB58327BAB26720143E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (FF), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon at the end;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF21EEC2B1463480A99FC08BBFFD94701"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (GG), by inserting <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon at the end; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HCF36209AC90F4DA7A9F7389F9B4DF550"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block id="H5A507D48D2D84D1191E135DE1D82AEEA" style="OLC"> <subitem id="H965E9ED7D2CF459F97481425DA7DEAD5" indent="up5"><enum>(HH)</enum><text>marriage and family therapist services (as defined in subsection (jjj)(1)) and mental health counselor services (as defined in subsection (jjj)(3));</text></subitem><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7A0F129A075B419E9BF191E196D9A572"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Section 1861 of the <act-name parsable-cite="SSA">Social Security Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block act-name="Social Security Act" id="H9196F285071E46E2BB1F946220D4B825" other-style="archaic" style="other"> <subsection id="H3DA93D32C169446FA29D1414288C8AC7"><enum>(jjj)</enum><header>Marriage and Family Therapist Services; Marriage and Family Therapist; Mental Health Counselor Services; Mental Health Counselor</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE4D35F8CAEE8422EBBCD17A82104F8D8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>marriage and family therapist services</term> means services performed by a marriage and family therapist (as defined in paragraph (2)) for the diagnosis and treatment of mental illnesses, which the marriage and family therapist is legally authorized to perform under State law (or the State regulatory mechanism provided by State law) of the State in which such services are performed, as would otherwise be covered if furnished by a physician or as an incident to a physician’s professional service, but only if no facility or other provider charges or is paid any amounts with respect to the furnishing of such services.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H914F2D2E72BD42B6B0155262E31896E9" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>marriage and family therapist</term> means an individual who—</text> <subparagraph id="HB569F5F5BBF74652974ACE67B2BE5E31"><enum>(A)</enum><text>possesses a master’s or doctoral degree which qualifies for licensure or certification as a marriage and family therapist pursuant to State law;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD52DF0096D98467EB1D5F28C55843EF8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>after obtaining such degree has performed at least 2 years of clinical supervised experience in marriage and family therapy; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0BE467826E5E41F092211868CC7E797A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the case of an individual performing services in a State that provides for licensure or certification of marriage and family therapists, is licensed or certified as a marriage and family therapist in such State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H63CA36F655864568B5613A83A69C97C1" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>mental health counselor services</term> means services performed by a mental health counselor (as defined in paragraph (4)) for the diagnosis and treatment of mental illnesses which the mental health counselor is legally authorized to perform under State law (or the State regulatory mechanism provided by the State law) of the State in which such services are performed, as would otherwise be covered if furnished by a physician or as incident to a physician’s professional service, but only if no facility or other provider charges or is paid any amounts with respect to the furnishing of such services.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HED7F010C9A2A4F7C91212FF9C1FE0CE7" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>mental health counselor</term> means an individual who—</text>
<subparagraph id="HA0BEF32427C54865962E6BC1426C46A7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>possesses a master’s or doctor’s degree in mental health counseling or a related field;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE3EE2F093CFD48B7B73ECE224923DBC2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>after obtaining such a degree has performed at least 2 years of supervised mental health counselor practice; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H57CB4F74217140A297EABA17EEF89C52"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the case of an individual performing services in a State that provides for licensure or certification of mental health counselors or professional counselors, is licensed or certified as a mental health counselor or professional counselor in such State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA791155569DC4069B21402A9A3ACC856"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Provision for payment under part B</header><text>Section 1832(a)(2)(B) of the <act-name parsable-cite="SSA">Social Security Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395k">42 U.S.C. 1395k(a)(2)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new clause:</text>
<quoted-block act-name="Social Security Act" id="H5566E6DF94B141AA8A5CD7DF0051FBBA" style="OLC">
<clause id="HF9BEA2B1D9B84E848A8AD097F922E707"><enum>(v)</enum><text>marriage and family therapist services (as defined in section 1861(jjj)(1)) and mental health counselor services (as defined in section 1861(jjj)(3));</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE5F70D831E124EC2965A717FCE57AEF9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Amount of payment</header><text>Section 1833(a)(1) of the <act-name parsable-cite="SSA">Social Security Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395</external-xref><added-phrase>l</added-phrase>(a)(1)) is amended—</text>
<subparagraph id="H4341DA24F728461384231B4B58276BE9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and (BB)</quote> and inserting <quote>(BB)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBB76C9ABE95444F593FCF270544FD8CB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting before the semicolon at the end the following: <quote>, and (CC) with respect to marriage and family therapist services and mental health counselor services under section 1861(s)(2)(HH), the amounts paid shall be 80 percent of the lesser of the actual charge for the services or 75 percent of the amount determined for payment of a psychologist under subparagraph (L)</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8F2B8A08C3664129852ED309932ABF9C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Exclusion of marriage and family therapist services and mental health counselor services from skilled nursing facility prospective payment system</header><text>Section 1888(e)(2)(A)(ii) of the <act-name parsable-cite="SSA">Social Security Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395yy">42 U.S.C. 1395yy(e)(2)(A)(ii)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>marriage and family therapist services (as defined in section 1861(jjj)(1)), mental health counselor services (as defined in section 1861(jjj)(3)),</quote> after <quote>qualified psychologist services,</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3293F9C04C9345969F3CFD5C2463305C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Inclusion of marriage and family therapists and mental health counselors as practitioners for assignment of claims</header><text>Section 1842(b)(18)(C) of the <act-name parsable-cite="SSA">Social Security Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395u">42 U.S.C. 1395u(b)(18)(C)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new clauses:</text>
<quoted-block act-name="Social Security Act" id="HB289DC445D7941EF91BDE253711450E3" style="OLC">
<clause id="H4DB5726D7A91490487E2C9B683AFFAA9" indent="up2"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>A marriage and family therapist (as defined in section 1861(jjj)(2)).</text></clause> <clause id="HEDF9C6CCCFEA488582BC9A732A974453" indent="up2"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>A mental health counselor (as defined in section 1861(jjj)(4)).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H6723CA9550D5416EB84B3D77DD679E44"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coverage of Certain Mental Health Services Provided in Certain Settings</header>
<paragraph id="H83F127F83ABE4C8A8D134E97CDD4E8C0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rural health clinics and federally qualified health centers</header><text>Section 1861(aa)(1)(B) of the <act-name parsable-cite="SSA">Social Security Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(aa)(1)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>or by a clinical social worker (as defined in subsection (hh)(1))</quote> and inserting <quote>, by a clinical social worker (as defined in subsection (hh)(1)), by a marriage and family therapist (as defined in subsection (jjj)(2)), or by a mental health counselor (as defined in subsection (jjj)(4))</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC3E00BAAC4D940CCBD998862FE077ADD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Hospice programs</header><text>Section 1861(dd)(2)(B)(i)(III) of the <act-name parsable-cite="SSA">Social Security Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(dd)(2)(B)(i)(III)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, marriage and family therapist, or mental health counselor</quote> after <quote>social worker</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HB60A0BDEF0C545A1A114F26C2C2A5603"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of marriage and family therapists and mental health counselors To develop discharge plans for post-Hospital services</header><text>Section 1861(ee)(2)(G) of the <act-name parsable-cite="SSA">Social Security Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(ee)(2)(G)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, including a marriage and family therapist and a mental health counselor who meets qualification standards established by the Secretary</quote> before the period at the end.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8000658333E948E08A0D1A9A96680CE7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective Date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to services furnished on or after January 1, 2018.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

