<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE5E37204A971455797B7229543E92176" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 739 IH: This Land Is Our Land Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 739</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170130">January 30, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the construction of new border barriers, including walls or fences, on certain Federal
			 land, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HF7539AC89ABF43D7B5FA65126B4F6C8A" style="OLC">
 <section id="H2418A109805C40FEBC2D8DA1189B68FE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>This Land Is Our Land Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HA0E19CD81F2648A49265B4ECB9BAEF1D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on the construction of new border barriers, including walls or fences, on certain Federal land</header> <subsection id="HD9BEE5BCEC0A415CBE6E7DA9D4470F38"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header> <paragraph id="HDEBD9F44C9C84030BBEA1DE1A669344B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, including the waiver provision provided under section 102(c)(1) of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1103">8 U.S.C. 1103</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/208">Public Law 104–208</external-xref>) (including any waivers of laws issued pursuant to such provision on, before, or after the date of the enactment of this Act), the Secretary of Homeland Security may not construct any new border barriers, including walls or fences, on Federal land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture within 100 miles of the international land borders of the United States that are not in existence as of the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4DD61AABC21A4C848B18211F0C59A1E7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The prohibition under paragraph (1) may not be construed to prohibit the maintenance or repair by the Secretary of Homeland Security of any border barriers, including walls or fences, on Federal land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture within 100 miles of the international land borders of the United States that are in existence as of the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5DB9E3CAE9A54999ADBF85CF91A1F31B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Withholding of certain funding</header>
 <paragraph id="HA829026FE65942889C8E292894A04B41"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Homeland Security may not obligate or expend any funds appropriated or otherwise made available (including through fees) to the Secretary to construct any new border barriers, including walls or fences, on Federal land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture within 100 miles of the international land borders of the United States that are not in existence as of the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5ACDC46CC4C344DC8ADD868328EE38A1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>The prohibition under paragraph (1) may not be construed to prohibit the obligation or expenditure of funds described in such paragraph for the maintenance or repair by the Secretary of Homeland Security of any border barriers, including walls or fences, on Federal land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture within 100 miles of the international land borders of the United States that are in existence as of the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H985D5B5C286D46AE89535FD57B2E3713"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effect on State and private land</header><text>This Act shall—</text> <paragraph id="H60DAB8B41CAE400C8D31201A31C770C3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>have no force or effect on State or private lands; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC186FC5FCBBC486192C4014709B7D20D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not provide authority on or access to State or private lands.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD0A9DCCCD7574CED9F39A19AF5587F53"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Tribal sovereignty</header><text>Nothing in this Act supersedes, replaces, negates, or diminishes treaties or other agreements between the United States and Indian tribes.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


