<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC7000719C4C14447AC7AB1649FD0CBD8" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3173 IH: Stark Administrative Simplification Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3173</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170710">July 10, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001158">Mr. Marchant</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001181">Mr. Meehan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to create alternative sanctions for technical
			 noncompliance with the Stark rule under Medicare, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H10196E5021BA4D4F987D861DA179137B" style="OLC">
 <section id="H92D810DD67DA48E1AD09C78084961C8F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stark Administrative Simplification Act</short-title> of 2017</quote>.</text> </section><section id="H91305A908B364964BBB5D354EE70BAB7" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Alternative sanctions for technical noncompliance with Stark rule under Medicare</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1877(g) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395nn">42 U.S.C. 1395nn(g)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HEEBA59A7218146E89DF03A3CBD069288"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>No</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to paragraph (7), no</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDE697299405245A9A78B146FB99C55FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>If</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to paragraph (7), if</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H723E7EF5E0C64BD1904529D96D8E9498"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>Any</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to paragraph (7), any</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1FC51EF6E03F4E5BBAF4A88FC715F5D8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5C8046DC0A3D41689065EC970B6757A3" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="H81E3706A89C64D1EA8C94D78F69CDE83"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Alternative sanctions for technical noncompliance</header>
 <subparagraph id="H888B56C0337A4781B90A1A19385CF78B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Single penalty for compensation arrangements in technical noncompliance</header><text>In the case of a compensation arrangement between a physician (or an immediate family member of such physician) and a person or entity that is in violation of subsection (a)(1) solely due to technical noncompliance, instead of the sanctions described in paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) for any such violation, the person or entity with respect to such arrangement shall be subject to a single civil monetary penalty under this paragraph in an amount that does not exceed—</text>
 <clause id="H57A2E36D593F488DA1C0D731EDA53F50"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case in which the disclosure of the violation is submitted to the Secretary not later than the date that is one year after the initial date of noncompliance, $5,000; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB3AB24C81F284F94976B3C66F04600C2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case in which the disclosure of the violation is submitted to the Secretary after the date that is one year after the initial date of noncompliance, $10,000.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94A22868A6C44A94A026220C57ED21F6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Acceptance of voluntary disclosures</header>
 <clause id="H63F01A2ED7494E8383E1269B1801E6FC"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning as of the date of the enactment of this paragraph, the Secretary shall accept the voluntary disclosure of a technically noncompliant compensation arrangement if such voluntary disclosure is made as described in clause (iii). The Secretary may accept and reasonably rely on information provided by a person or entity that is in violation of subsection (a)(1) only because of a compensation arrangement that is technically noncompliant.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1EA897A212984756A084945F94B5F00A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Acceptance of disclosure</header><text>The Secretary may reject any voluntary disclosure submitted under clause (iii) within 90 days after the receipt of the disclosure only if the Secretary determines that the disclosure does not conform to the requirements described in clause (iii). If the Secretary fails to reject a voluntary disclosure within such 90-day period, the voluntary disclosure is deemed to be accepted.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7FA1B08E788E44BC97443E828DF18724"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Voluntary disclosure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A voluntary disclosure described in this clause is a disclosure concerning a compensation arrangement that is submitted to the Secretary by a party to such arrangement that contains the following:</text>
 <subclause id="H02F122D5689C440AA18B8254A6AB65B2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The identification of the disclosing party and all other parties to the disclosed compensation arrangement.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA468CBAFDBDD4FD49F3CB0B509580608"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the compensation paid under the arrangement and the dates of noncompliance.</text> </subclause><subclause id="H1F52F2E522E74CBDB0C7AD00360AC421"><enum>(III)</enum><text>A certification by the disclosing party that the compensation arrangement satisfies the requirements described in clause (v).</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H18C9D71F8C624AFFA5C13F39E7C10745"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Payment for the full amount of the civil monetary penalty under clause (i) or (ii), as applicable, of subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HF41058AF1E864A84B75BEDE9DBB594D9"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Settlement of liability and payment of claims</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A voluntary disclosure of a technically noncompliant compensation arrangement that is made and accepted under this subparagraph shall constitute a full and complete settlement of liability under this subsection to the extent such liability is with respect to such technically noncompliant compensation arrangement. Any bill or claim for payment related to a technically noncompliant compensation arrangement shall not be subject to the sanctions under this subsection and shall be payable after a voluntary disclosure is made as described in clause (iii).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H61FAE857D03D41B19359059DE3E9591A"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Compensation arrangement requirements</header><text>For purposes of clause (iii)(III), the requirements described in this clause, with respect to a compensation arrangement, are the following:</text>
 <subclause id="H020A851D343D4FF7AB13605BC3B071A6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The compensation arrangement is technically noncompliant (as defined by subparagraph (C)).</text> </subclause><subclause id="H65BAC130414D4F93A71486987CCFADD4"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The compensation arrangement has been cured of the technical noncompliance, or is otherwise terminated.</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HFD4FB3C7940B45FC95C21BABBAE6CA31"><enum>(III)</enum><text>In the case of technical noncompliance described in subparagraph (C)(i), the compensation arrangement is consistent with fair market value, and the remuneration under the arrangement is not determined in a manner that takes into account directly or indirectly the volume or value of any referrals.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H43B54B76DF2A43FBA8EFA2F94BD32B45"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Definition technical noncompliance</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>technical noncompliance</term> means, with respect to a compensation arrangement, such an arrangement that is in violation of subsection (a)(1) only because—</text>
 <clause id="H33DF8AAF63734D59BF3BCDD96BA134B0"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the arrangement is not set forth in writing;</text> </clause><clause id="HD3B8E569E35F4FD9A936BE0BE8091192"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the arrangement is not signed by one or more parties to the arrangement; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H58811F0C1724471EB692BC26B857F9E3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the arrangement became in violation of such subsection by reason of its expiration.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H60B76904E64943A7A04F356C62F9677B"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Applicability to pre-enactment disclosures to relieve backlog</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the application of this paragraph to technically noncompliant compensation arrangements disclosed on or after the date of the enactment of this paragraph, the Secretary shall provide for the application of this paragraph to any technically noncompliant compensation arrangement that has been disclosed, and to which there has not been a final settlement, as of the date of enactment of this paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0420D3962BF4802BD8143EAAE0513A0"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 24 months after the date of enactment of this paragraph, the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services shall submit to Congress a report on the implementation of this paragraph. Such report shall include—</text>
 <clause id="H517057A6BB744A2DA02F11BBC1FD9FA2"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of persons or entities making disclosures of technical noncompliance under this paragraph;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H586AD80434D7449A837220DA68E7D7F3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount and type of alternative sanctions collected or imposed for technical noncompliance;</text> </clause><clause id="H92196CF5E85944159B1B585D9072322D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the types of violations disclosed; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCC7208D6B41E4DE690838007EC6E4C36"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such other information as the Inspector General determines may be necessary to evaluate the impact of this paragraph.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H500B1454288E42E88641AE52FA3EF5B7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Clarification of the writing requirement and signature requirement for arrangements pursuant to the
			 Stark rule under Medicare</header>
 <subsection id="HEDE442B70F214E90859756F7C7145BBE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Writing requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1877(h)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395nn">42 U.S.C. 1395nn(h)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4E790A29CE1C4F80B1A2396AA2D34410" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H5E5C7B13B04945FC958AFF1962B8294A" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Written requirement clarified</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any requirement pursuant to this section for a compensation arrangement to be in writing, such requirement shall be satisfied by such means as determined by the Secretary, including by a collection of documents, including contemporaneous documents evidencing the course of conduct between the parties involved.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA2DCA297859B4092B94FED1F1630E9FA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Signature requirement</header><text>Section 1877(e) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395nn">42 U.S.C. 1395nn(e)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HCFD4B47AA50C4D1181A0B803E6D86D50"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(A)(i), by inserting <quote>before or not later than 90 days after the effective date of the lease</quote> after <quote>signed by the parties</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9FBEE193A1004A4D93F8EC6087F308B4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1)(B)(i), by inserting <quote>before or not later than 90 days after the effective date of the lease</quote> after <quote>signed by the parties</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAECC696508964E2184E67EE5CB038867"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (3)(A)(i), by inserting <quote>before or not later than 90 days after the effective date of the arrangement</quote> after <quote>signed by the parties</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H4FA9153DF9D94323BE3F486603F89FF7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Indefinite holdover for lease arrangements and personal services arrangements pursuant to the Stark
 rule under Medicare</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1877 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395nn">42 U.S.C. 1395nn</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H146F73405F374F73958F1B05442B2B51"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (e)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H11FDB6FF42294314847731BFF3190D14"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAE4099477CC6436D9F6FC510FA76A7D4" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HF18406CCCD16406180735825F017087B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Holdover lease arrangements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a holdover lease arrangement for the lease of office space or equipment, which immediately follows a lease arrangement described in subparagraph (A) for the use of such office space or subparagraph (B) for the use of such equipment and that expired after a term of at least one year, payments made by the lessee to the lessor pursuant to such holdover lease arrangement, if—</text>
 <clause id="H7F4F356368A24CDE8EFA514D573DD060"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the lease arrangement met the conditions of subparagraph (A) for the lease of office space or subparagraph (B) for the use of equipment when the arrangement expired;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAD774438FE0A4A3994B38D3AA5E2FBF5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the holdover lease arrangement is on the same terms and conditions as the immediately preceding arrangement; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFDA8F56D84BC4FE6B4EEF89D79A946EE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the holdover arrangement continues to satisfy the conditions of subparagraph (A) for the lease of office space or subparagraph (B) for the use of equipment.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC577D23B97440E6B8B79AA165A01243"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5081C5F7A22340159948D7BB65D5E4FC" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HDD58756DD170478FACDF7B91988EC495"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Holdover personal service arrangement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a holdover personal service arrangement, which immediately follows an arrangement described in subparagraph (A) that expired after a term of at least one year, remuneration from an entity pursuant to such holdover personal service arrangement, if—</text>
 <clause id="H5A5E38F18C1340A7A995C3F5268C27D5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the personal service arrangement hmet the conditions of subparagraph (A) when the arrangement expired;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3B3785053C614C1797058EEF8E87E6E1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the holdover personal service arrangement is on the same terms and conditions as the immediately preceding arrangement; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1FB48D7B209E46F1834DA681B06FAD8B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the holdover arrangement continues to satisfy the conditions of subparagraph (A).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H50223340F7D840A88785DE91E6D362F3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (h)(1), as amended by section 3(a)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H74FA399FF7C64D5C91CF9FF4BF9E3721"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">; holdover arrangement</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">remuneration</header-in-text></quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H399C998BC0D64F98B0D314012A268906"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA40DDE2E3798468391EA02FF4C72841D" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="HA374693811134B3EB17214C88BA2675F" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Holdover arrangement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>holdover arrangement</term> means an arrangement, with respect to an agreement (including a lease or other arrangement) that has expired but as of the date of such expiration had been in compliance with the applicable requirements of this section, under which the parties to such expired agreement have, since such date of expiration, continued to perform under the terms and conditions of such expired agreement.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


