<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H26D74124AFDA4A8D9153EF2C132FEFCE" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1129 IH: Student Visa Security Improvement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1129</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170216">February 16, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to strengthen student visa background checks and
			 improve the monitoring of foreign students in the United States, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H9BE354304A3E41409CD38C889FD27E2A" style="OLC">
 <section id="HA2CE3AF6FF3F4ACBB611AA34FDE240B7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Student Visa Security Improvement Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H820E66B0CB7243A1B6AA81A8C5342DF6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Enhanced student visa background checks</header> <subsection id="HFD2133AB974F4DEAB61355008CD52AB7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 428(e) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/236">6 U.S.C. 236(e)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE45FC640FFCD4FD398F9696BBA0BAE9C" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H66131D5584334A8F974BDF1FC2878618"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Student visas</header><text>In administering the program under this subsection, the Secretary, not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Student Visa Security Improvement Act</short-title>—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5607BAD89F7D40BF87836131427DEED3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall prescribe regulations to require employees assigned under paragraph (1) to review the applications of all applicants recommended by Department of State personnel for visas under subparagraph (F), (J), or (M) of section 101(a)(15) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)</external-xref>), and conduct in-person interviews where appropriate, prior to final adjudication, with special emphasis on determining whether applicants are inadmissible under section 212(a)(3)(B) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(3)(B)</external-xref>) (relating to terrorist activities);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C49E76FAC2C471786477BAD4980CD8A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall ensure that employees assigned under paragraph (1) conduct on-site reviews of any applications and supporting documentation for visas under subparagraph (F), (J), or (M) of section 101(a)(15) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)</external-xref>) that they deem appropriate prior to final adjudication; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E64F29BECF645619D75504D63510034"><enum>(C)</enum><text>shall update, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the memorandum of understanding between the Department of Homeland Security and the Department of State regarding implementation of this section to clarify the roles and responsibilities of employees assigned under paragraph (1) specifically with regard to the duties prescribed by this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H6E73EAFB5471408BB33E03E79B54E9DD"><enum>3.</enum><header>Student and exchange visitor program</header>
 <subsection id="HBCD1E36D58C04C7680E01705E69ED50C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text>Section 442 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/252">6 U.S.C. 252</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HD03E31A5CCD64EBC8DA0C66E6C242B26"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA88A2CAF0BA54691A06F0B6670ABA1B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (5) as paragraph (11); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2DD61108223479FBED7FE54A69D57BA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (4) the following:</text>
						<quoted-block id="H88F249656C6A460CBB13BFA54550B560" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HFBF7A5065BD4444DAF67670B4D8C0717"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Student and exchange visitor program</header><text>In administering the program under paragraph (4), the Secretary shall, not later than one year after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Student Visa Security Improvement Act</short-title>—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6D7149D32BB741818A4F4253A77E319E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prescribe regulations to require an institution or exchange visitor program sponsor participating in the Student and Exchange Visitor Program to ensure that each covered student or exchange visitor enrolled at the institution or attending the exchange visitor program—</text>
 <clause id="H3837F700E79345B69754A939BC55DCC6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is an active participant in the program for which the covered student or exchange visitor was issued a visa to enter the United States;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD88CD80B00E44F5BB23F41BBC1963632"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is not unobserved for any period—</text> <subclause id="H082A5CFEEBCF4941BC24B9C8203B67EF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>exceeding 30 days during any academic term or program in which the covered student or exchange visitor is enrolled; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H9763260AB32D4AE191F5F0951D2DE88C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>exceeding 60 days during any period not described in subclause (I); and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H8E8BC01078F442FCAF8044C2A1461E65"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is reported to the Department within 10 days of—</text>
 <subclause id="H683C745CF9D7487388FFC4F07A8AA07B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>transferring to another institution or program;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H8819F233FB6045FC8A7AFCE464307B09"><enum>(II)</enum><text>changing academic majors; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H5BE89CFEFD0F43ADBCF6ADC9D96747AB"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any other changes to information required to be maintained in the system described in paragraph (4);</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE8C61135EDE4F3A83A88048DA975483"><enum>(B)</enum><text>notwithstanding subparagraph (A), require each covered student or exchange visitor to be observed at least once every 60 days; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2057B615B2144729CF94BFC1B30770C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prescribe regulations defining what constitutes the commencement of participation of a covered student in a designated exchange visitor program (as defined in section 641(h) of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1372">8 U.S.C. 1372(h)</external-xref>)).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2511B7DBC87A4B35B18316B4B79A3161"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Enhanced access</header><text>The Secretary shall provide access to the Student and Exchange Visitor Information System (hereinafter in this subsection referred to as the <quote>SEVIS</quote>), or other equivalent or successor program or system, to appropriate employees of an institution or exchange visitor program sponsor participating in the Student and Exchange Visitor Program if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF5604516D4B445C5AF9266EA8FE5635D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>at least two authorized users are identified at each participating institution or exchange visitor sponsor;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD500E8A1A09443D3BEF729E0B15E94F7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>at least one additional authorized user is identified at each such institution or sponsor for every 200 covered students or exchange visitors enrolled at the institution or sponsor; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF14BC5AE88974799B392CE1B9E7C83FE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>each authorized user is certified by the Secretary as having completed an appropriate training course provided by the Department for the program or system.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1A36D6B2DAA42A5B6282A6726E19E0F"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Program support</header><text>The Secretary shall provide appropriate technical support options to facilitate use of the program or system described in paragraph (4) by authorized users.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H539A43F7EDCD4608AC69E3E0A433900B"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Upgrades to SEVIS or equivalent data</header><text>The Secretary shall update the program or system described in paragraph (4) to incorporate new data fields that include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBA8B8500729840299E79EB0C0BE2AFDB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>verification that a covered student’s performance meets the minimum academic standards of the institution in which such student is enrolled; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBDAFC66F32DB4677936A3788D730D319"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">timely entry of any information required by paragraph (5) regarding covered students and exchange visitors enrolled at institutions or exchange program sponsors.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEECD5898A52544BDA98B8531589786E5"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text>Nothing in this section shall prohibit the Secretary or any institution or exchange program sponsor participating in the Student Exchange Visitor Program from requiring more frequent observations of covered students or exchange visitors.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBA1946AA0FBF4A509303B7AE6BEE0965"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Decertification</header><text>The Secretary is authorized, without notice, to decertify any approved institution or exchange visitor program sponsor if such institution or exchange visitor program sponsor is engaged in egregious criminal activities or is a threat to national security.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA18EDEA441414FA09429AF16F567C624"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HAA90FC50FD44468DA05C9E82A3EF7BBE" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H2177E549B7EC4B7DBF7E08F6D360E29E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text>
 <paragraph id="H53DB8C8151574C9C823E4C63D4104B63"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>covered student</quote> means a student who is a nonimmigrant pursuant to subparagraph (F), (J), or (M) of section 101(a)(15) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF523A8F2E4E543BEA519CABEB8B44B9D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>observed</quote> means positively identified by physical or electronic means.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H82B06E8F8D8349FE920D5D7BEF9CCED6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <quote>authorized user</quote> means an individual nominated by an institution participating in the Student and Exchange Visitor Program and confirmed by the Secretary as not appearing on any terrorist watch list.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5F682D90FC3C456F8CE0F496C4FDDC49"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Comptroller General Review</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a review of the fees for the Student and Exchange Visitor Program of the Department of Homeland Security. The Comptroller General shall include in such review data from fiscal years 2011 through 2016 and shall consider fees collected by the Department and all expenses associated with the review, issuance, maintenance, data collection, and enforcement functions of the Student and Exchange Visitor Program.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


