<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HA249AD8142414C55B12F9FE205BAFA8D" key="H" public-private="public"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1731 RH: Revitalizing the Economy of Coal Communities by Leveraging Local Activities and Investing More Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 255</calendar>
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1731</legis-num>
<associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 115–351, Part I]</associated-doc>
<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20170327">March 27, 2017</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000395">Mr. Rogers of Kentucky</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000568">Mr. Griffith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000297">Mr. Jenkins of West Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<action>
<action-date date="20171019">October 19, 2017</action-date>
<action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001187">Mr. Stivers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001154">Mr. Shuster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001269">Mr. Barletta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000459">Mr. Fleischmann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000585">Mr. LaHood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001195">Mr. Mooney of West Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000600">Mrs. Radewagen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000604">Mr. Dent</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000598">Mr. Rothfus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001151">Mr. Murphy of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001179">Mr. Marino</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000563">Mr. Gibbs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001227">Mr. Brady of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000533">Mr. Duncan of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000558">Mr. Guthrie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000482">Mr. Michael F. Doyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000292">Mr. Johnson of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000062">Mr. Yarmuth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000565">Mr. Loebsack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000570">Mr. Ben Ray Luján of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000582">Mr. Roe of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000620">Mr. Delaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001106">Mr. Costello of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Brendan F. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000586">Mr. Renacci</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001286">Mrs. Bustos</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor><pagebreak/></action-desc>
</action>
<action>
<action-date date="20171019">October 19, 2017</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HII00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc>
<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction> 
</action>
<action>
<action-date date="20171019">October 19, 2017</action-date>
<action-desc>The <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on March 27, 2017</action-instruction>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 to provide funds to States and Indian tribes for the purpose of promoting economic revitalization, diversification, and development in economically distressed communities through the reclamation and restoration of land and water resources adversely affected by coal mining carried out before August 3, 1977, and for other purposes.<pagebreak/></official-title>
</form> 
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HII00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HED564890966A480B8022DE861509A208">
<section id="H914976E08AC2444980DDD74B6B64AF08" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Revitalizing the Economy of Coal Communities by Leveraging Local Activities and Investing More Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>RECLAIM Act of 2017</short-title></quote> .</text></section> <section id="H71618510FEC3451B9F45FDA7C081F0EF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Economic revitalization for coal country</header> <subsection id="H0149DA39666449A49F9B1880AB71AD42"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title IV of the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1231">30 U.S.C. 1231</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H25073840E64A4BA7A81D0DEF07030333" style="OLC">
<section id="H3B68A4831DDD400986765FDC30C5A620"><enum>416.</enum><header>Abandoned mine land economic revitalization</header>
<subsection id="H4D60BE1860F14A7DB7D0E1E3E4FFB7FD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this section is to promote economic revitalization, diversification, and development in economically distressed mining communities through the reclamation and restoration of land and water resources adversely affected by coal mining carried out before August 3, 1977.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC515C8580BA946D8B19C0B12C4A74E25"><enum>(b)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From amounts deposited into the fund under section 401(b) before October 1, 2007, and not otherwise appropriated to the extent such funds are available, $200,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary, without further appropriation, for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2021 for distribution to States and Indian tribes in accordance with this section for reclamation and restoration projects at sites identified as priorities under section 403(a): <italic>Provided,</italic> That if less than $200,000,000 is available in any fiscal year to the Secretary, such remaining amount shall be made available to the Secretary, without further appropriation, and such fiscal year shall end distributions made available under this section.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H395885F1A05E4F94A7A0DF46F3E0960C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds distributed to a State or Indian tribe under subsection (d) shall be used only for projects classified under the priorities of section 403(a) that meet the following criteria:</text> <paragraph id="HD50D667F300D40A896A385760D8C2EED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Contribution to future economic or community development</header> <subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0BAC7A9F391440AC9DEF3ACB1B8243D4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The project, upon completion of reclamation, is intended to create favorable conditions for the economic development of the project site or create favorable conditions that promote the general welfare through economic and community development of the area in which the project is conducted.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF897F4CBCA2C44A887219EC7E3704E22"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Demonstration of conditions</header><text>Such conditions are demonstrated by—</text> <clause id="H6B928781177841D89E49F80F3CC6EE8F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>documentation of the role of the project in such area’s economic development strategy or other economic and community development planning process;</text></clause>
<clause id="H4017C59578B540D5B11F2BD06EAD6FA2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any other documentation of the planned economic and community use of the project site after the primary reclamation activities are completed, which may include contracts, agreements in principle, or other evidence that, once reclaimed, the site is reasonably anticipated to be used for one or more industrial, commercial, residential, agricultural, or recreational purposes; or</text></clause> <clause id="H7605C795B5B64479B7C18E3D04A23070"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other documentation agreed to by the State or Indian tribe that demonstrates the project will meet the criteria set forth in this subsection.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6F99C95E704C4074AA7FDEDE2639BAE5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Location in economically distressed community affected by recent decline in mining</header>
<subparagraph id="H36A47FDA8A8145EDAEF0B875844C6C79"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The project will be conducted in a community—</text> <clause id="H4A9E6943A41041D38FE9B2A1531FA750"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that has been adversely affected economically by a recent reduction in coal mining related activity, as demonstrated by employment data, per capita income, or other indicators of economic distress; or</text></clause>
<clause id="HE277C79347A74B9BB4B063EBA34076DC"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<subclause id="H1347AF0DB8AA499A8C509ECD43DE2F93" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(I)</enum><text>that has historically relied on coal mining for a substantial portion of its economy; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HE0B4E1ABEF31464996DFE9DBD931666A" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in which the economic contribution of coal mining has significantly declined.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H89BBF20D62A7413E8F55B87C2E1BE3A4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Submission and publication of evidence or analysis</header><text>Any evidence or analysis relied upon in selecting the location of a project under this subparagraph shall be submitted to the Secretary for publication. The Secretary shall publish such evidence or analysis in the Federal Register within 30 days after receiving such submission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HABCA6E2B21524A3AA58FFBB7B559A0FC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Stakeholder collaboration</header> <subparagraph id="H393BA905E0214F1D86BC4AA7668EEB30"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The project has been the subject of project planning under subsection (g) and has been the focus of collaboration, including partnerships, as appropriate, with interested persons or local organizations.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H26B9874AA7FA409C8FD8438B1522E9FB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public notice</header><text>As part of project planning—</text> <clause id="HE7A3E40F95174929B9410421613B4DF7"><enum>(i)</enum><text> the public has been notified of the project and has been given an opportunity to comment at a public meeting convened in a community near the proposed project site; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HECA0C9A192D7466DA55F30002D5BE6E7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the State or Indian tribe published notice of such meetings in local newspapers of general circulation, on the Internet, and by any other means considered desirable by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H878043D4C86B4ADC99029538A8F4399A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Electronic notification</header><text>The State or Indian tribe established a way for interested persons to receive electronically all public notices issued under subparagraph (B) and any written declarations submitted to the Secretary under paragraph (5).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H52FF9580B2CB40EB854E142B4317ECCD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligible applicants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The project has been proposed by entities of State, local, county, or tribal governments, or local organizations, and will be approved and executed by State or tribal programs, approved under section 405 or referred to in section 402(g)(8)(B), which may include subcontracting project-related activities, as appropriate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA898EDF5EDC24A4BAC033D5FA7E9E2E1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>If the State or Indian tribe—</text>
<subparagraph id="H4853869AFBF249F8BA7611DCE7C079A1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>cannot provide documentation described in paragraph (1)(B) for a project conducted under a priority stated in paragraph (1) or (2) of section 403(a), or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H792F572285BE4A1DA4E833CA923E2955"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is unable to meet the requirements under paragraph (2), </text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">the State or Indian tribe shall submit a written declaration to the Secretary requesting an exemption from the requirements of those subparagraphs. The declaration must explain why achieving favorable conditions for economic or community development at the project site is not practicable, or why the requirements of paragraph (2) cannot be met, and that sufficient funds distributed annually under section 401 are not available to implement the project. Such request for an exemption is deemed to be approved, except the Secretary shall deny such request if the Secretary determines the declaration to be substantially inadequate. Any denial of such request shall be resolved at the State’s or Indian tribe’s request through the procedures described in subsection (e).</continuation-text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H9C469C1821E743C28530F71B0300F9A6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Distribution of funds</header>
<paragraph id="H50C2DCF838C94A63A7100B6776D78C95"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Uncertified States</header>
<subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H51BCA52579EA446FBB3D9D2E9F393EBC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From the amount made available in subsection (b), the Secretary shall distribute $195,000,000 annually for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2021 to States and Indian tribes that have a State or tribal program approved under section 405 or are referred to in section 402(g)(8)(B), and have not made a certification under section 411(a) in which the Secretary has concurred, as follows:</text> <clause commented="no" id="HBF1843449C79499D971CC48152A16F0C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Four-fifths of such amount shall be distributed based on the proportion of the amount of coal historically produced in each State or from the lands of each Indian tribe concerned before August 3, 1977.</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="H3D56815530E944949C6D955004F44A87"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">One-fifth of such amount shall be distributed based on the proportion of reclamation fees paid during the period of fiscal years 2012 through 2016 for lands in each State or lands of each Indian tribe concerned.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0487AA1E9477437597525DC839EDEFDA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Supplemental funds</header><text>Funds distributed under this section—</text>
<clause id="H005EBFAF801F40A2BA5DD3646D92127A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be in addition to, and shall not affect, the amount of funds distributed—</text> <subclause id="H5A3E19CF91B5490C8F1C81FADE90ADA1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to States and Indian tribes under section 401(f); and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HC18B10075703412EB0D4229CC98D243A"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to States and Indian tribes that have made a certification under section 411(a) in which the Secretary has concurred, subject to the cap described in section 402(i)(3); and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HD6206AB96890418791D5AB475386A553"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall not reduce any funds distributed to a State or Indian tribe by reason of the application of section 402(g)(8).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H80EAA32183AE4F0FADC7AC96884346FF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional funding to certain States and Indian tribes</header>
<subparagraph id="H8BAFE29117594A62BF24A05CCBC8344F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>From the amount made available in subsection (b), the Secretary shall distribute $5,000,000 annually for each of the five fiscal years beginning with fiscal year 2017 to States and Indian tribes that have a State program approved under section 405 and have made a certification under section 411(a) in which the Secretary has concurred.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBDDF1F45DFF04CBF98548894F747897C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Application for funds</header><text>Using the process in section 405(f), any State or Indian tribe described in subparagraph (A) may submit a grant application to the Secretary for funds under this paragraph. The Secretary shall review each grant application to confirm that the projects identified in the application for funding are eligible under subsection (c).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBAC271D3A3E24730A541EBA8B3D51303"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Distribution of funds</header><text>The amount of funds distributed to each State or Indian tribe under this paragraph shall be determined by the Secretary based on the demonstrated need for the funding to accomplish the purpose of this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCCA83BDE1E79484D8D875F8D979F33DC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reallocation of uncommitted funds</header> <subparagraph id="H663B524E15E44445B852A574362C1FF4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Committed defined</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph the term <term>committed</term>—</text>
<clause id="H5CCCBACA311A4F12A0FAEAF5C0110509"><enum>(i)</enum><text>means that funds received by the State or Indian tribe—</text> <subclause id="HD729D8E365414178A722509B0F8408B0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>have been exclusively applied to or reserved for a specific project and therefore are not available for any other purpose; or</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HEBED4AC2C9034C1A8649C7868FE352D5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>have been expended or designated by the State or Indian tribe for the completion of a project;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H3CE9E565E3D845FFACB86516097BC3CA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>includes use of any amount for project planning under subsection (g); and</text></clause>
<clause id="H9FA432ABB1A7494AB8219BE04991710C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>reflects an acknowledgment by Congress that, based on the documentation required under subsection (c)(2)(B), any unanticipated delays to commit such funds that are outside the control of the State or Indian tribe concerned shall not affect its allocations under this section.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD18E6D0932814D2D9F2BC535951C5E7C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Fiscal years 2020 and 2021</header><text>For each of fiscal years 2020 and 2021, the Secretary shall reallocate in accordance with subparagraph (D) any amount available for distribution under this subsection that has not been committed to eligible projects in the preceding 2 fiscal years, among the States and Indian tribes that have committed to eligible projects the full amount of their annual allocation for the preceding fiscal year.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE12B2D86B8424371B3D835BFE3BB0956"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Fiscal year 2022</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For fiscal year 2022, the Secretary shall reallocate in accordance with subparagraph (D) any amount available for distribution under this subsection that has not been committed to eligible projects or distributed under paragraph (1)(A), among the States and Indian tribes that have committed to eligible projects the full amount of their annual allocation for the preceding fiscal years.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDDD0A540F77849C3A3C54C7A64C2C071"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Amount of reallocation</header><text>The amount reallocated to each State or Indian tribe under each of subparagraphs (B) and (C) shall be determined by the Secretary to reflect, to the extent practicable—</text>
<clause id="HE2318AD11F7845F8B082AA28DDAF403C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the proportion of unreclaimed eligible lands and waters the State or Indian tribe has in the inventory maintained under section 403(c);</text></clause> <clause id="HAFB0740CC25D4699AEC7B0D574578872"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the average of the proportion of reclamation fees paid for lands in each State or lands of each Indian tribe concerned; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H1BF1E49C62FF456CAD1C41EF0928D5E6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the proportion of coal mining employment loss incurred in the State or on lands of the Indian tribe, respectively, as determined by the Mine Safety and Health Administration, over the 5-year period preceding the fiscal year for which the reallocation is made.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6F896C21D015400684AECEA2DE1ED350"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Resolution of Secretary’s concerns; congressional notification</header><text>If the Secretary does not agree with a State or Indian tribe that a proposed project meets the criteria set forth in subsection (c)—</text>
<paragraph id="H2D18B5DAD13B433EBE7EBF7E005074F5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary and the State or tribe shall meet and confer for a period of not more than 45 days to resolve the Secretary’s concerns, except that such period may be shortened by the Secretary if the Secretary's concerns are resolved;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB773CA41966A4D228C2DE8E70ABB5919"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">during that period, at the State’s or Indian tribe’s request, the Secretary may consult with any appropriate Federal agency; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5C8B395485CA46C8BDB8B9A1C03B5418"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at the end of that period, if the Secretary’s concerns are not resolved the Secretary shall provide to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate an explanation of the concerns and such project proposal shall not be eligible for funds distributed under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5E87FF1EF0FE475C8E0A8007AFD84683"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Acid mine drainage treatment</header> <paragraph id="HD778BECBA69C4AAA8F5BC084186258C1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), a State or Indian tribe that receives funds under this section may use up to 30 percent of such funds as necessary to supplement the State’s or tribe’s acid mine drainage abatement and treatment fund established under section 402(g)(6)(A), for future operation and maintenance costs for the treatment of acid mine drainage associated with the individual projects funded under this section. A State or Indian tribe shall specify the total funds allotted for such costs in its application submitted under subsection (d)(2)(B).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA3DD4702E2604B8E98F721BA09A3FC4A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Condition</header><text>A State or Indian tribe may use funds under this subsection only if the State or tribe can demonstrate that the annual grant distributed to the State or tribe pursuant to section 401(f), including any interest from the State’s or tribe’s acid mine drainage abatement and treatment fund that is not used for the operation or maintenance of preexisting acid mine drainage treatment systems, is insufficient to fund the operation and maintenance of any acid mine drainage treatment system associated with an individual project funded under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H40A6ABBA9FFD462F96E1E8007387AD29"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Project planning and administration</header> <paragraph id="H6D450843F89B4B8F955995780332DF4B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>States and Indian tribes</header> <subparagraph id="H55E40C9B67AE4647B5EA001839D77EFD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State or Indian tribe may use up to 10 percent of its annual distribution under this section for project planning and the costs of administering this section.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC8CABBF433204481B646B88AEE187631"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Planning requirements</header><text>Planning under this paragraph may include—</text> <clause id="HC7F7FB9EE77C42DF8539E52E0AF6F517"><enum>(i)</enum><text>identifying eligible projects;</text></clause>
<clause id="H0C9DA79BA0DC436396E7C56B4E587731"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>updating the inventory referred to in section 403(c);</text></clause> <clause id="HDB2E570FF8A14A9099D2FF94205BBE2C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>developing project designs;</text></clause>
<clause id="H0B8EBD06A9DA4E10A0B56FF71500D04D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collaborating with stakeholders, including public meetings;</text></clause> <clause id="H03D99C6F7E0A4725A3FAAFD962D215AB"><enum>(v)</enum><text>preparing cost estimates; or</text></clause>
<clause id="HC2028C2FBF8A433EBDD0F8E5CAA09B59"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>engaging in other similar activities necessary to facilitate reclamation activities under this section.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCC79D1C4C0AE4332825F916C4EEA5670"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may expend, from amounts made available to the Secretary under section 402(g)(3)(D), not more than $3,000,000 during the fiscal years for which distributions occur under subsection (b) for staffing and other administrative expenses necessary to carry out this section.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H88E1D553906742DB9D5FA42C258A81AC"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives, the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate at the end of each fiscal year for which such funds are distributed a detailed report—</text> <paragraph id="HB411860C514342308DEECEA88F7E45ED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on the various projects that have been undertaken with such funds;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD0BAF3FA6F8B4683BECE86D7C5429DBC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the extent and degree of reclamation using such funds that achieved the priorities described in paragraph (1) or (2) of section 403(a);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1766284F3CEC411E8CDAD71237B5D95C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the community and economic benefits that are resulting from, or are expected to result from, the use of the funds that achieved the priorities described in paragraph (3) of section 403(a); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1C7B2E7BD80049DEA931F60324792F7B"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the reduction since the previous report in the inventory referred to in section 403(c).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB7F39BA4C854400EAD9C87C77B8D4803"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Prohibition on certain use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any State or Indian tribe that uses the funds distributed under this section for purposes other than reclamation or drainage abatement expenditures, as made eligible by section 404, and for the purposes authorized under subsections (f) and (g), shall be barred from receiving any subsequent funding under this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="HC4F8DD84FA534DF59496E10EC6362458"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents in the first section of the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 is amended by adding at the end of the items relating to title IV the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H19D3C7C5F8E34847B681698A91C30CDE" style="OLC"> <toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="H25073840E64A4BA7A81D0DEF07030333" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration"> <toc-entry idref="H3B68A4831DDD400986765FDC30C5A620" level="section">Sec. 416. Abandoned mine land economic revitalization.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="H78A030C9D89148EFA6F82C3420D6631D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HBBE0F24661F6438BBD2C963B4974C34B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 401(c) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1231">30 U.S.C. 1231(c)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon at the end of paragraph (10), by redesignating paragraph (11) as paragraph (12), and by inserting after paragraph (10) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H83F27C7478794248AE8AEAF83BAA574E" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H16BA5C760CE4476AA074D48B4C38D129"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to implement section 416; and</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF32AB289BEE34B80A2C4930E827E5EC1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 401(d)(3) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1231">30 U.S.C. 1231(d)(3)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>subsection (f)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (f) and section 416(a)</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H62ED61A6FA59441792E3CBFCEFFE08A7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 402(g) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1232">30 U.S.C. 1232(g)</external-xref>)—</text>
<subparagraph id="H4B74A8F21EDE4DBDA677AD9DD151A90B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>and section 416</quote> after <quote>subsection (h)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9C5C4C5AFCBE4A4097CDDF59D0E402EC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end of paragraph (3) the following:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H03A23FDD627A4C71B1E57B040962897E" style="OLC">
<subparagraph id="H3777C56809E64C5DAFB4C949FD3ED9CD"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purpose of section 416(d)(2)(A).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6266CC022DE04AF68BBE84B8DD18BE94"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in section 403(c) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1233">30 U.S.C. 1233(c)</external-xref>), by inserting after the second sentence the following: <quote>As practicable, States and Indian tribes shall offer such amendments based on the use of remote sensing, global positioning systems, and other advanced technologies.</quote>.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H6B2D3AFC235F481C83CA669CD7282180"><enum>4.</enum><header>Minimum State payments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 402(g)(8)(A) of the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1232">30 U.S.C. 1232(g)(8)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>$3,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$5,000,000</quote>.</text></section> <section id="H33F7BEBAAFEA4895B9F691C19494F7DE"><enum>5.</enum><header>GAO study of use of funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall study and report to the Congress on uses of funds authorized by this Act, including regarding—</text>
<paragraph id="H9873729D11374516AB5F2A76FE23D25D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the solvency of the Abandoned Mine Reclamation Fund; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF0F1FA8C5EB74FA098B2145FA34C4F9B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the impact of such use on payments and transfers under the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1201">30 U.S.C. 1201</external-xref>) to—</text>
<subparagraph id="H0A5CE79914254260A93AAD1239C309C8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>States for which a certification has been made under section 411 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1241">30 U.S.C. 1241</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF73EDB30BC04410AA9362912619BBE36"><enum>(B)</enum><text>States for which such a certification has not been made; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2BB39B54537241038BD80C05B7CBFCDC"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">transfers to United Mine Workers of America Combined Benefit Fund.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="HBF03389039584DD1B9D3A58F29E41E64" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>6.</enum><header>Abandoned mine land reclamation and restoration initiative</header> <subsection id="H45075B3C94774E0CBFF76E154A1DFCB7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/145">chapter 145</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6FF7A3468ECC4FAFAE43F3C8BEBDD4B6" style="USC">
<section id="H3F98C398B24A427D96D422BE71E4DD02"><enum>14510.</enum><header>Abandoned mine land reclamation and restoration initiative</header>
<subsection id="H25E0222420BF42D5A586D5503FADB472"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Appalachian Regional Commission may provide technical assistance, make grants, enter into contracts, or otherwise provide amounts to individuals or entities in the Appalachian region for projects and activities on lands, or on or in waters, that have been reclaimed or restored with amounts provided under title IV of the Surface Mining Control or Reclamation Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1231">30 U.S.C. 1231</external-xref> et seq.) or that are eligible for such reclamation or restoration.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA1E6CC020C9C475FA5A81F1EE38D9F24"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation on available amounts</header><text>Of the cost of any activity eligible for a grant under this section—</text>
<paragraph id="H8405E47675A8404490EC9F655DDE651B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not more than 50 percent may be provided from amounts appropriated to carry out this section; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9C11D4239BB441E3973A811BB3CD32F1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>notwithstanding paragraph (1)—</text>
<subparagraph id="HB0B84994073740D1BF153A6ABA1D2885"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a project to be carried out in a county for which a distressed county designation is in effect under section 14526, not more than 80 percent may be provided from amounts appropriated to carry out this section; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAB639A1625474C898CFD577E9CBDE41B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a project to be carried out in a county for which an at-risk designation is in effect under section 14526, not more than 70 percent may be provided from amounts appropriated to carry out this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H3546909A7EA747CAB92B51634E5D8DDA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sources of assistance</header><text>Subject to subsection (b), a grant provided under this section may be provided from amounts made available to carry out this section in combination with amounts made available—</text> <paragraph id="HDFBC90C3896743C5A1F53C301A38D9A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>under any other Federal program; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H30EFC039FBB0446BB71ABC3220800E15"><enum>(2)</enum><text>from any other source.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE22FFA01F05D47D09D8EFDCEC5DD2063"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Federal share</header><text>Notwithstanding any provision of law limiting the Federal share under any other Federal program, amounts made available to carry out this section may be used to increase that Federal share, as the Appalachian Regional Commission determines to be appropriate.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="H329C4BA8385243AC9EFD3E7C1261BD81"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The analysis for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/145">chapter 145</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/40/14509">section 14509</external-xref> the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H00C9109206BC496CBEC30D26B04AE7D3" style="USC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">14510. Abandoned mine land reclamation and restoration initiative.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="HEF1A26E3F7F34F39A679E76B6676319F"><enum>7.</enum><header>Headquarters of Appalachian Regional Commission</header> <subsection id="H55987274CDBE46EFA9703F84B14D876B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Finding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text>
<paragraph id="H8612841D53F641FC878D8E93089EC5F6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Delta Regional Commission, the Denali Commission, and the Northern Border Regional Commission are each headquartered in their respective region; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H00EA67CD5C624BCAB76D9B0BDC03C675"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the headquarters of the Appalachian Regional Commission should be relocated from the District of Columbia to a more affordable location in the Appalachian Region.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HC7EB2DBB0F944A0B8FEDB8D7FA7A3212"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Location of headquarters</header>
<paragraph id="H3D2D12FDA71747F8A0BD4BEBFACA0E07"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 14301 of title 40, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBBF7CC9C3312427496E8458BD30036FF" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H938A400FA1104737BFB3CBEC8083E2E8"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Headquarters</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The headquarters of the Commission shall be located in the Appalachian Region.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1F9EA65BB5FB4CF49D9B5DC4E59B8B5A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The Federal Cochairman of the Appalachian Regional Commission shall take such actions as may be necessary to carry out the amendment made by paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H8C589E2D68AA40D982B4F5244E1678DD"><enum>8.</enum><header>Payments to certified States not affected</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to reduce or otherwise affect payments under section 402(g) of the Surface Mining Reclamation and Control Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1232">30 U.S.C. 1232(g)</external-xref>) to States that have made a certification under section 411(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1240a">30 U.S.C. 1240a(a)</external-xref>) in which the Secretary of the Interior has concurred.</text></section>
</legis-body>
<endorsement display="yes">
<action-date date="20171019">October 19, 2017</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HII00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc>
<action-date date="20171019">October 19, 2017</action-date>
<action-desc>The <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill> 


