<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCAED2C9C98DF4C7B9602541F30E79906" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2749 IH: Protecting Business Opportunities for Veterans Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2749</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170526">May 26, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001301">Mr. Bergman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster of New Hampshire</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the oversight of contracts awarded by the
			 Secretary of Veterans Affairs to small business concerns owned and
			 controlled by veterans, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HEA61DA39DB4B400BBAF206940D185030" style="OLC">
 <section id="H82B1D7229CC34522B96F6D9DCEDF5E09" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Business Opportunities for Veterans Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H0A8493C2A69240CF8C99D2019B86322B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limitations on subcontracts under contracts with small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans</header> <subsection id="H8007466EE0E84B4D8E0455DC516BEA5C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 8127 of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB84B0CEDA0744344A38749F676EEADFA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (l) as subsection (m); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDC646FCCDBDB45C6863442CF6FFABC0E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (k) the following new subsection (l):</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA97E15AC0D574C40AB3AA0E8B80AE394" style="USC">
						<subsection id="H667170399529460AB9AAE146650E46E6"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Limitations on subcontracting</header>
							<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA09593ACA401486A937851521C16A3B5"><enum>(1)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0AB7CD5AD3554736B600EC966E8B59E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The requirements applicable to a covered small business concern under section 46 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/657s">15 U.S.C. 657s</external-xref>) shall apply with respect to a small business concern owned and controlled by veterans that is awarded a contract under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37CDF8E212E145AF900EBE3C093F2ABC" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of applying the requirements of section 46 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/657s">15 U.S.C. 657s</external-xref>) pursuant to subparagraph (A), the term <term>similarly situated entity</term> used in such section 46 includes a subcontractor for a small business concern owned and controlled by veterans described in such subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H9AD8B3C5C462498E8D7F60F8239C8E67" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may award a contract under this section only after the Secretary obtains from the offeror a certification that the offeror will comply with the requirements described in paragraph (1)(A) if awarded the contract. Such certification shall—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H24EC1054F74F4E49BA655B3A9F385F8A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>specify the exact performance requirements applicable under such paragraph; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H145E3DCF0C2E4439801660FF97BBD9AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>explicitly acknowledge that the certification is subject to section 1001 of title 18.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E7652F31ACE41FA8006492DA7D0CD78" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HEB3FA933FAAF44348F3112108D6F51FA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Director of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization for the Department, established pursuant to section 15(k) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/644">15 U.S.C. 644(k)</external-xref>), and the Chief Acquisition Officer of the Department, established pursuant to section 1702 of title 41, shall jointly implement a process using the systems described in section 16(g)(2) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/645">15 U.S.C. 645(g)(2)</external-xref>), and any other relevant systems available, to monitor compliance with this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA576CABAF0584202BC1F932150DB60A4" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Director of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization and the Chief Acquisition Officer shall jointly refer any violations or suspected violations of this subsection to the Inspector General of the Department.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7ACB0630CB844113BCB7234DFAF25679" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary determines, in consultation with the Inspector General of the Department, that a small business concern that is awarded a contract under this section did not act in good faith with respect to the requirements described in paragraph (1)(A), the small business concern shall be subject to any or all of the following consequences—</text>
 <clause id="H1D60C10BDC324B3C9DFF320E9BCDF1DA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>referral to the Debarment and Suspension Committee of the Department;</text> </clause><clause id="H06F361F9BC5C4F0B9552232D3C8DD313"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a fine under section 16(g)(1) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/645">15 U.S.C. 645(g)(1)</external-xref>); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB2A143D8DCA7432DA2368E660C37FA36"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>prosecution for violating section 1001 of title 18.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F7F98C97AA04683BE7FA24AAF0BDC4B" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Not later than November 30 of each year, the Inspector General shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives a report for the fiscal year preceding the fiscal year during which the report is submitted that includes, for the fiscal year covered by the report—</text>
 <clause id="H494CACDEC4EF4A6DA6640C66B17A01A5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of referred violations and suspected violations received under subparagraph (B); and</text> </clause><clause id="HFF48E554D733466FA76B867214F6E6FE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the disposition of such referred violations, including the number of small business concerns suspended or debarred from Federal contracting or referred to the Attorney General for prosecution.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H4D7C1648593743F3A8B1823BD504F557"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (l) of section 8127 of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to a contract entered into after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


