<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H83C2F3E628AD473DAD00A54C9E6AD545" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2960 IH: Community College Student Success Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2960</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170620">June 20, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000248">Mr. Serrano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000598">Mrs. Davis of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Education to establish and carry out a grant program to make grants to
			 eligible institutions to plan and implement programs that provide
			 comprehensive support services and resources designed to increase transfer
			 and graduation rates at community colleges, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HED155AE8EE5C4CB083FC3BC0BFFC31F4" style="OLC">
 <section commented="no" id="H598C44625D3444BFB51B99B951944FDA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Community College Student Success Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H137AA2BF9EB44887A74D86EE4FDB67DD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Community College Student Success Grant Program authorized</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">From the amounts appropriated under section 10, the Secretary of Education shall establish and carry out the community college student success grant program to award grants under sections 3 and 4, on a competitive basis, to eligible institutions to plan and implement community college student success programs designed to increase—</text>
 <paragraph id="H29C843F95D7241308E656979BC62ADFB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the rate at which eligible students graduate from a program of study at such eligible institution within 150 percent of the normal time for graduation; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE6E07A795D5D4641B4C415D4DF1C39B1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>transfer rates of eligible students.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H149CC7F818134944A6BD402E8D919E0A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grants to plan community college student success programs</header> <subsection id="HC6BE4A54BEE54D23873C0A928FF87A74"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Planning grants authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From the amounts appropriated to carry out this section under section 10 for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall award planning grants for such fiscal year, on a competitive basis, to eligible institutions to develop plans for community college student success programs.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7E1EA97029B1430285E07F5E34F3756B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>A grant awarded under this section shall be for a 1-year period.</text> </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H983BB6AE0A454F0DA9E37171A1672F12"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Peer review process; priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H87AF8AA700F04DAE89796EF4812A30DA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>carry out a peer review process that—</text> <subparagraph id="H80CB643D08E64E51BEC9F2EA758B3E6F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>requires that each application submitted under subsection (d) be peer reviewed by a panel of readers composed of individuals selected by the Secretary, which shall include—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H86B168C86DBE4A8F95CA7ED5A06724E6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not less than 50 percent of readers—</text> <subclause id="H60D59947EEEC40FCB1EB567D1937BEF1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>who are not employees of the Federal Government; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H4644CC9D403547348DD9FCDCE95D953F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>who have relevant research or practical experience with respect to student support programs designed to increase graduation rates and transfer rates at public 2-year institutions of higher education; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="HD85EB570E5974F6A8190039A68C3D02A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to the maximum extent practicable, individuals who are members of groups underrepresented in higher education, including African Americans, Hispanics, Native Americans, Alaska Natives, Asian Americans, and Native American Pacific Islanders (including Native Hawaiians); and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8B382B7B21EB40F382A86EE406B90E76"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensures that no individual assigned under subparagraph (A) to review an application has any conflict of interest with regard to that application that may make the individual unable to impartially conduct such review; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HAE177F1669804940910A4BBED16C600F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>give priority to eligible institutions that are eligible to receive funding under title III or V of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1051">20 U.S.C. 1051</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H57E041BB103A452892A41C965AA23762"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible institution desiring a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, which shall include—</text>
 <paragraph id="H378216A768784958AD97179E4C6364EC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the graduation rate and transfer rate for the most recent academic year for which data are available for eligible students and all students, respectively;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H264E0FD4C5AC49A3A712489CFCFBC30B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an analysis of how implementing a community college student success program may improve the graduation rate or transfer rate for eligible students; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H269688E1D5394B90B4537705D80DC4C8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an analysis of the methods the eligible institution has previously used to improve the graduation rate or transfer rate with respect to eligible students and all students, respectively.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFF4B2439A8614FD2941048A4BEDDB1FC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An eligible institution that receives a grant under this section shall use the grant to develop a plan to implement a community college student success program at the eligible institution.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8E78AC1AC1E94704A603F69ABEEC20E2"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which an eligible institution receives a grant under this section, such eligible institution shall submit to the Secretary a report that includes—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0947E7F44CFA406DA3709FD8C79067CE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a plan for implementing a community college student success program at the eligible institution, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDB5BB27A3F044099B38209FE3FA1B99E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the ambitious outcome goals for achieving significant improvements in graduation rates and transfer rates for eligible students and all students, respectively, as such rates are defined by the eligible institution, in consultation with the Secretary, before the end of the grant period;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB455B92AFB3E4B9FA8300D8ED76311ED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of such eligible students who will participate in such program, including how such eligible students will be identified, referred, and selected, in cases where the interest in the program is larger than the budget for the program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB774167F261A48FA9B1A2518AEF54244"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the demographics (including income, race, and gender) of such eligible students;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDBC5F9D2D7B44A7EAFB6B0C5A90B8528"><enum>(D)</enum><text>based on the most recent academic year for which data are available, disaggregated by eligible students and all students—</text>
 <clause id="HBC364BED733146E384C34B2365FDAD54"><enum>(i)</enum><text>graduation rates;</text> </clause><clause id="H45984489DE534D528E2155A42B2C215D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>transfer rates;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8FAFFC8099534DB081EEB4660C8600F5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>retention rates;</text> </clause><clause id="HD1FF2CD7A31F4B0DBB658A890F805B52"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>rates of completion of remedial courses for students required to complete such courses; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H66CD6A60FA76495B8912B7F2E968BC54"><enum>(v)</enum><text>average number of credits attempted and average number of credits earned;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7C9BE2CF7044712AD26A0FF5688268D"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of the financial needs of the eligible students described in subparagraph (B);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HDFD93D29D99D4D25BA4A724A817E6D80"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of how the eligible institution will collaborate across departments at the institution and with external partners to implement a community college student success program, including the detailed roles and responsibilities of each potential external partner (including each investor, State or local government entity, or other stakeholder);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1740723A16D341E4955594554AF65358"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of how the eligible institution will effectively staff a community college student success program; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDBD58BBC2EA24E7681289F59D06DE7F5"><enum>(H)</enum><text>a timeline for the implementation of such program;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC9271E3C12114A368A09E72B06E840FA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a budgetary analysis that includes—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H88C5F45002DE4844A4AA5DCCDAC24EBD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of how the eligible institution will—</text> <clause id="H8D2E9E6833F0478296C4EBB3EFFF95E6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide non-Federal funds for such program under subsection (d) of section 4; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2F3B11D202E140138A087DFED26B9638"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>meet the requirement of subsection (b)(3) of such section; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9E481FF633A94EDC9019DF4B466ADCBA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of how the eligible institution will continue to fund such program after the end of the grant period for the grant awarded to the institution under section 4;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF41F9FDF643432E9307C31F2A938CE0"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the data system the eligible institution will use to track and evaluate the progress of eligible students participating in such program;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H683128692F2B4C08ADF843791141E5A2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an analysis of the institutional barriers that may hinder implementing such program at such eligible institution; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H24284B0808634C0C9B785ED4D1D43122"><enum>(5)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary may require.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H26E1F464176A441F81726204403F5046"><enum>4.</enum><header>Grants to implement community college student success programs</header> <subsection id="H0386C10B45EC432986B38A959A13A14E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Implementation grants authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From the amounts appropriated to carry out this section under section 10 for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall award grants for such fiscal year, on a competitive basis, to eligible institutions awarded a grant under section 3 to implement community college student success programs.</text>
				<paragraph id="H6500E9EBA3264EADB2F53E30A22ECDD2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H08BD86E96F964932A8BA17EBC404E410"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants under this section for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall consult with the independent evaluator before finalizing which eligible institutions will receive such a grant for such fiscal year.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HADCF36C13AB64B9EBE95B5207015CC6F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements for selection</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an eligible institution shall meet the following requirements:</text>
 <paragraph id="H482FE1546C054BA8A72A88CD8EA0827F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The eligible institution was awarded a grant under section 3 at least 1 year before such eligible institution submits an application under subsection (e).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H015FD3421AB84EADAEB1C501F5F15D62"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The eligible institution submits an application under subsection (e).</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB57FB5C6C327402296C9F5D66B308FB8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The eligible institution demonstrates, on the date of the application described in subsection (e), the availability of non-Federal funding for the matching funds required under subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) of subsection (d)(1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF335002FB31A4256A37A1799BEB9ADC2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>A grant awarded under this section shall be for a 5-year period.</text> </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H9473BEBBAF0C4BE3B63B292B4F210BF4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Non-Federal contribution</header> <paragraph id="H540F8526B9054C13BB336A2132ABBBCD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), an eligible institution awarded a grant under this section shall contribute in cash from non-Federal sources, the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H43DFB30E54A445CBB6D8DEB890628ABC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>For the second year of the grant period, an amount equal to 20 percent of the cost of carrying out the community college student success program at the institution for such year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2873AAEDFB7143E1BDCA5CE36221A5B1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>For the third year of the grant period, an amount equal to 40 percent of the cost of carrying out such program for such year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB93D58117F4541A887D93931EFEFD2AF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>For the fourth year of the grant period, an amount equal to 60 percent of the cost of carrying out such program for such year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D14E746A9264BB1920741569E6909A0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>For the fifth year of the grant period, an amount equal to 80 percent of the cost of carrying out such program for such year.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC96CC482ADC14F42A2A56AA5BDE912DE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header>
 <subparagraph id="HFF857C3F40BA458DB6F07EF693CE1D5D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), with respect to an exempt institution awarded a grant under this section, for each year of the grant period beginning with the second year through the fifth year, the Secretary shall not require the institution to make a cash contribution from non-Federal sources in an amount that is greater than the amount equal to 5 percent of the cost of carrying out the community college student success program at the institution for such year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10DBFCFAD6FF44BA95D75A2FC43E2DD0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph:</text> <clause id="HF8363EAF3D704AEAB690D75269B67A68"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Exempt institution</header><text>The term <term>exempt institution</term> means an eligible institution that is—</text>
 <subclause id="H324475885AB54C50BBBDAC36F5CAB61B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a Tribal college or university; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="HB992C47127EE4B19BBE0C253AB2D1704"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an institution located in the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the United States Virgin Islands, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, or the Republic of Palau.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H1834326C31174E4897187D4200B994CA"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Tribal college or university</header><text>The term <term>Tribal college or university</term> has the meaning given the term in section 316 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059c">20 U.S.C. 1059c</external-xref>).</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF3B0F82CC24442BB945B08F6598648E5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Application</header>
 <paragraph id="HD315209A495F41B28BE082DB1919DAF2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible institution desiring a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, which shall include a copy of the report described in section 3(f).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HEE2F0A5542D346A5B9592CF2188204B4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements for eligible institutions that reapply</header><text>An institution that submits an application under paragraph (1) that is not the first application submitted by such institution under such paragraph shall include the following in such application:</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H97ACE93C0073467ABC9A6B492FDAD270"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The number of applications such eligible institution has submitted under paragraph (1) and the dates on which such applications were submitted.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA0F5545C60DB48838082A85AC2E2C345"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of the changes the eligible institution has made since the most recent application submitted under paragraph (1) to improve the plan to implement a community college student success program at such eligible institution.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H47B7289897924342B905137F925E51A9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Review</header><text>Not later than 60 days after receiving an application under this subsection, the Secretary shall approve or deny such application.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H79922FF35EC044D387D65E21D5B200D9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Required use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible institution that receives a grant under this section shall use the grant funds to—</text> <paragraph id="HEC0D3FE032684F2D9C0F209AB66714A5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">implement a community college student success program;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H71CD25C682D548BEAB8CEC9D358373B7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>regularly review—</text> <subparagraph id="H312C514EAC7C42178E994DC7047799BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>data to monitor the academic progress of eligible students participating in such program; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD93FD70C302E4B608C80CD127E33DB71"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the meeting and program participation requirements described in section 9(1); and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H70C828C24AC847C4807ADD19929D0D17"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">cover the employment of administrators for the program whose sole job shall be to administer the program, without regard to whether the employment is full-time or less than full-time.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA1E1A8F2079847CCA4219094117E028C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Permissible use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible institution that receives a grant under this section may use the grant to—</text> <paragraph id="HD96BC8EF9B2F45799101817B3B4163A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish or expand a data tracking system that includes early alerts to complete the regular reviews required under subsection (f)(2);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1AC0DA5F7A25408DA2955CE2EEFCE7F5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide eligible students participating in the community college student success program for which the grant is awarded with financial assistance to cover the costs described in paragraph (2), (3), or (8) of section 472 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087ll">20 U.S.C. 1087ll</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H107F8578E88140A191F4668CB410D2B0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>establish or expand career development services for such students, such as career workshops or career counseling;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H153E756056604EB1A6FF059FF37794F9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establish or expand tutoring services for such students; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE6BECE3A0E884DF2AA2B56C0E853608A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>provide financial support for eligible students participating in such program to enroll in courses offered during enrollment periods that are outside the fall and spring semesters (or equivalent terms).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6D73CE6A0DAE47B8AC027505DF5F918E"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>An eligible institution that receives a grant under this section shall—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H25EAAC84FC204DF6B2B92DF7D6DB94B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not less than once for each year of the grant period, submit to the Secretary an annual performance report for such year of the grant period, and when data is available, compares such year with the each of the 2 years preceding the date on which the grant was awarded—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HAA7635951A0A492C9F26D5226743A3A1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the demographics of the eligible students participating in the community college student success program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H334FCFEF9B404126BDD746777C7CA276"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the average number of credits attempted and average number of credits earned, rate of retention, rate of degree completion, and transfer rates of such eligible students;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70031848DD9D473D8F905104787F1C0E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the graduation rate of such eligible students within—</text> <clause id="HB05429FB1C914EE89DED301E5C1826B2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>100 percent of the normal time for graduation;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H382E0F0F0F85487E827773F55D35C9CB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>150 percent of the normal time for graduation; and</text> </clause><clause id="HA86F9969050043638023D4914F3EEFA2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>200 percent of the normal time graduation;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H870795D0F7B6403B8854B9033CF93650"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an analysis of the implementation and progress of such program based on the ambitious outcome goals described in the report submitted by the institution under section 3(f)(1)(A), including challenges to and changes made to such program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H07B0CF222DD14DF581ABFD2968553764"><enum>(E)</enum><text>if according to the analysis under subparagraph (D), the program is not on track to meet such ambitious outcome goals, a description of the plans to adjust the program to improve the performance of the program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H43D4367DA1504910A6D516713028839D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the participation of such eligible students in tutoring, career services, and meetings with program advisors;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C7DC309D6EA428EB6146BC3A47923F5"><enum>(G)</enum><text>for the report for the third year of the grant period, the plan to meet the non-Federal contribution requirement under subsection (d)(1)(D); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1E16AECC70D4677A63FB4738CB1246D"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for the report for the fourth year of the grant period, a description of—</text> <clause id="H0BCC54AAAB0243D49A33F2B7F16D006C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the source of the funds to meet the non-Federal contribution requirement under subsection (d)(1)(D);</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5537BEBCAB3D4BF28A37C3B8B19D7A84"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the plans to continue to fund such program after the grant period ends; and</text> </clause><clause id="H67CC1A0A633F4148AE115E0D4A4F3A86"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the plans to use this program as a catalyst for institution-wide reform with respect to graduation rates and transfer rates for all students; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H613FED2939F94144985FEC32665ACF83"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 6 years after the date on which the eligible institution received such grant, submit a final report to the Secretary that includes an analysis of—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HDB1DB5C771F44476B8E73FFA387595F7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the factors that contributed to the success or failure of the community college student success program in meeting the ambitious outcome goals described in the report submitted by the institution under section 3(f)(1)(A);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H86486B792D89476F9D08C540A0C91CCC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the challenges faced in attempting to implement such program;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC22F27840E5D433A9ACB654C20BA9007"><enum>(C)</enum><text>information on how to improve such program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33A3E3CB6F7B4D05B872E41FE1578194"><enum>(D)</enum><text>whether the program has created an institution-wide reform with respect to graduate rates and transfer rates for all students, and if so, how such reform was created; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1149462EBBCA439AA85DCF3119CF01E4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>how the eligible institution will continue to fund such program after the end of the grant period.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H00E58B5DFDC34F0C9ABB360592A827D8"><enum>5.</enum><header>Evaluations</header> <subsection commented="no" id="H99268179B45B4CD2910FC019A26D1491"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Independent evaluations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before finalizing which eligible institutions will receive grants under section 4 for a fiscal year, the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Institute of Education Sciences, shall enter into a contract with an independent evaluator—</text>
 <paragraph id="H874DD4F8DF6D48679BCEA3D63D1700DB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to consult with the Secretary on which eligible institutions should receive the grants; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H04F1580371C94A0AA422CF718F7E1475"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to use the What Works Clearinghouse Standards (without reservations) to evaluate, throughout the duration of the grant period of such grants—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H95C029FBF7E048559EBE7E885835E9C7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each community college student success program for which such grant is awarded, including whether the program met its ambitious outcome goals described in the report submitted by the institution under section 3(f)(1)(A);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HCB8205DCF5F54F04A5C99AEF5D23F493"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the average impact of community college student success programs on graduation rates and transfer rates for eligible students;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC788198405F4EC1B3533A8155C8EA8E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the variation in program impacts across eligible institutions with respect to such rates; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6E5849A949234895B2C59E434D707485"><enum>(D)</enum><text>whether such programs lead to higher graduation rates and transfer rates of eligible students per dollar spent for such students by such institutions compared with such rates at eligible institutions without such programs.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H2ECE670B3DA7461EB70D9FC85DC583F9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Results of evaluations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The results of the evaluations under subsection (a) shall be made publicly available on the website of the Department of Education.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H393BD1F0F2254E05B388D201F6D73A1F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Funding for evaluations</header><text>The Secretary may reserve not more than 15 percent of the funds appropriated under section 10 for a fiscal year to carry out this section for such fiscal year.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HD861D7A0E10F4B4FBBA6455CCC04F2CB"><enum>6.</enum><header>Outreach and technical assistance</header>
 <subsection id="H07EDB341ED1C4A3F8DB4E5AC1608DDE1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Outreach</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall conduct outreach activities to notify eligible institutions of the availability of grants under this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H828FE75073C04E8D9C8EA6888C5719A5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide technical assistance—</text> <paragraph id="HEB41177FBB6B4A8D81B8C863315B7CCD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to eligible institutions that may be interested in applying for grants under this Act, including assistance with applications for such grants; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC6CC3E339C8F4879961082EBFABBFF36"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to eligible institutions awarded grants under this Act, including assistance with—</text> <subparagraph id="HC8BDE622C2A74D65B68DD2284EC6B0D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establishing ambitious outcome goals described in section 3(f)(1)(A); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7503838AAA11484E8654366948572205"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the implementation of a community college student success program.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE9FE793863BD4169B8FE5810209AC897"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Funding for technical assistance for evaluations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may reserve not more than 7 percent of the funds appropriated under section 10 for a fiscal year for technical assistance under this section for such fiscal year.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H968F4394DA1A46D89173F7FE61A42D07"><enum>7.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Secretary receives the final evaluation results under section 5 for eligible institutions that were awarded grants under section 4 for the same fiscal year, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that includes—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0B6D2AB2EB5B4E8B8BF0E867D2EFD79C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of grants awarded under section 4 for such fiscal year, and the amount of such grants;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H57683320E4C14766B49B2AE84ED7C08D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of grants awarded under section 3 to eligible institutions that received or would have been eligible for the grants described in paragraph (1), and the amount of such grants; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H704C09CE03244872AA0EF5EB823B093A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>such final evaluation results.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H66E59F8672EC403492FA7F8A3479BEF5"><enum>8.</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Funds awarded to an eligible institution under this Act shall be used only to supplement the amount of funds that would, in the absence of the Federal funds provided under this Act, be made available from non-Federal sources or other Federal sources to carry out the activities under this Act, and not to supplant such funds.</text>
 </section><section id="H776448AF23F34E6BB739C57C7CF9C8AB"><enum>9.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HE4342C7B1831419EB962234B540352AF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Community college student success program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>community college student success program</term> means a program carried out by an eligible institution under which the institution carries out the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE5BBF921ED4B4FC794E55E04905B3F4F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Provides eligible students participating in such program with an amount that covers the cost of tuition and fees that are not covered by any Federal, State, or institutional financial assistance received by the student.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4BFE39EFCE154CA887AA89D6E84A120E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Requires eligible students participating in such program to—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H6408E2333FC4490FB328EA3630F55F42"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be enrolled in the eligible institution and carry a full-time academic workload during each fall and spring semester (or equivalent terms) during which the student participates in such program;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4BFCAD03BDB042C1A0FA8145957C4533"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the eligible student is referred to remedial courses or on academic probation, meet, on at least a weekly basis, with a tutor, except that in the case of an eligible student who is academically struggling, but who is not referred to remedial courses or on academic probation, the student may meet with a tutor as often as the program advisor for such student requires;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA717DDCCE5D94AC199B648E9F7CF63D0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">meet with a program advisor—</text> <subclause id="H6D340786CFE74C158F37B7CBBE117954"><enum>(I)</enum><text>twice each month during the first semester (or equivalent term) of participation in such program; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H378F742DEF8849588F078940FE06677F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>as directed by the program advisor in subsequent semesters (or equivalent terms) under subparagraph (C)(ii); and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HDBF336A723604280BE92163D73095009"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>meet with an on-campus career advisor or participate in a career services event once each semester (or equivalent term).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2FE38AE0479F448EAD930F404B203CDF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Provides a program advisor to each eligible student participating in such program who—</text> <clause id="H6B3887B2D7BA46BFAF129B358E16ED66"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provides comprehensive academic and personal advising to the eligible student, including—</text>
 <subclause id="HE4FE252EE1A14AEA84444C2FEF70E3F7"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the creation and implementation of an academic plan for the student to graduate from a program of study at the eligible institution within 150 percent of the normal time for graduation from such program;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HE430042275C54F29980E0C514C641852"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if an eligible student is referred to remedial courses, encouraging such student to complete such courses as quickly as possible; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H09CB891DAEAD4EADA11822B0C31C8014"><enum>(III)</enum><text>assisting the eligible student with developing and achieving academic goals, including creating strong transfer pathways that demonstrate programmatic transfer for students interested in transferring to a 4-year institution of higher education;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HD22ECBEB0EC34A8E8C276F28BD3C87FC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>after the eligible student participating in such program completes a semester (or equivalent term), creates for the eligible student a needs-based advising schedule that indicates, based on the eligible student’s academic performance, the frequency with which such eligible student shall be required to meet with a program advisor for each subsequent semester (or equivalent term) of program participation;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4D5D8B425BBA4C63811649A1EDA32D27"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>has a caseload of not more than 150 eligible students;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H7DF2E3CD8ACF496FAF8A776412AFD93C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>tracks the attendance of the eligible student at the meetings described in clauses (ii), (ii), and (iv) of subparagraph (B);</text>
 </clause><clause id="H62847A10CCCF4E9BB14C8D6F6B9D75D3"><enum>(v)</enum><text>monitors the academic progress of the eligible student; and</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HB4CA47CB99374E20B1DBF9884B0D859E"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>provides each eligible student who meets the requirements of subparagraph (B), on at least a monthly basis, with financial incentives, such as a transportation pass or a gas card.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA3B173EFCEF648BFBDCF63664ABFABA1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Provides free tutoring and career services to eligible students participating in such program, and may reserve places in select courses for such eligible students in order to create community within cohorts of eligible students.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2466BA0D9C94E56A5D908E88651791F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible institution</term> means a public 2-year institution of higher education.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H997B9D50F0954E818B91F72627B7902C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible student</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible student</term> means a student enrolled at an eligible institution who—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA832C90314704CD881D1DF2D561B0398"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on the date such eligible student would begin participation in a community college student success program at such eligible institution—</text>
 <clause id="H3975DC39F36E4A3DA6566A16A5EC7B7E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is enrolled in a program of study leading to an associate degree;</text> </clause><clause id="H4FE7C6B88BB14FABB7B797EB6C9852DC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is enrolled at such institution and carrying a full-time academic workload during each fall and spring semester (or equivalent terms) during which the student participates in such program;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0BB0613F56A94FD499E66F4AB83818A4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is—</text> <subclause id="H4C1690CD99FC41B9B7B9263A67286782"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a first-time undergraduate student; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H23960796A82D4D72A9DEE0EF9B30C18C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a continuing or transfer student with not more than 15 credits and a minimum grade point average of 2.0 (or its equivalent); and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H9182DC95B2C04BCE80A148210E59588A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>is considered by the eligible institution to need no more than two remedial courses;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0C17E067D1CA46B5AE60EFED8AFBA531"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the student is eligible for financial aid under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070</external-xref> et seq.), has completed the Free Application for Federal Student Aid or other common financial reporting form under section 483(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1090">20 U.S.C. 1090(a)</external-xref>); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B8B570BE5AF4F008D6AD89B1BCD13F3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>meets any other requirements established by the institution.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C1C0948F007429BA7C70388EFDF4CA6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Full-time academic workload</header><text>The term <term>full-time academic workload</term>, when used with respect to an semester or equivalent term, means at least 12 credits (or the equivalent).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H30E8C4FAFD974694AF34D993ED10547C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term under section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA6897C850D0B43D5A3795B0D68C75E54"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H741BB5C2076B48E8A086C29DEFE7612F"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Transfer rate</header><text>The term <term>transfer rate</term>, when used with respect to students enrolled in a program of study at an eligible institution, means the rate at which such students transfer to a 4-year institution of higher education.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H931D0B207D3D41608AA2A6472D07EC8A"><enum>10.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act $10,000,000,000 for fiscal years 2018 through 2028, to be available until expended.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


