<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HABCA915C4A2141FEA41F623FD1D15F8F" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1877 IH: To establish a research, development, and technology demonstration program to improve the efficiency of gas turbines used in combined cycle and simple cycle power generation systems.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1877</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170404">April 4, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a research, development, and technology demonstration program to improve the
			 efficiency of gas turbines used in combined cycle and simple cycle power
			 generation systems.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H5EF24C616E374878BA56C02397F4A5BA" style="OLC">
		<section id="H8E67078C648A4CDD8059D19E6349E87C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>High efficiency gas turbines</header>
 <subsection id="H85EFD5DC131249E98EC3CFDF4B8B44EE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Energy, through the Office of Fossil Energy, shall carry out a multiyear, multiphase program of research, development, and technology demonstration to improve the efficiency of gas turbines used in power generation systems and to identify the technologies that ultimately will lead to gas turbine combined cycle efficiency of 67 percent or simple cycle efficiency of 50 percent.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB5CE0E01F3474F97B4C7C9A2D94005D7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program elements</header><text>The program under this section shall—</text> <paragraph id="HEFA3993FF1EF4E698ED5EF375AAEC52A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>support first-of-a-kind engineering and detailed gas turbine design for megawatt-scale and utility-scale electric power generation, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3023486FCC504A2DB0DE26DACEBD7BB5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>high temperature materials, including superalloys, coatings, and ceramics;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A57957D442A419DB5510975724198D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>improved heat transfer capability;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H51C143282DAA4664BFA45C333D221972"><enum>(C)</enum><text>manufacturing technology required to construct complex three-dimensional geometry parts with improved aerodynamic capability;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3ED0EB2851914CA68F47EFC7CEC254F8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>combustion technology to produce higher firing temperature while lowering nitrogen oxide and carbon monoxide emissions per unit of output;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D29EDE9E860421C99DBD43246295091"><enum>(E)</enum><text>advanced controls and systems integration;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B4D129E70594A9699F610D392D538B5"><enum>(F)</enum><text>advanced high performance compressor technology; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E3805CA52C443CF81BE555FB0EB9254"><enum>(G)</enum><text>validation facilities for the testing of components and subsystems;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3FC6829F9E584B12893AB219586D3D1E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include technology demonstration through component testing, subscale testing, and full-scale testing in existing fleets;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCBB57FB74BBB425E9073C85EC2FCDB4E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>include field demonstrations of the developed technology elements so as to demonstrate technical and economic feasibility; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9770198C35D44F8B9B4B1F48BBD1A856"><enum>(4)</enum><text>assess overall combined cycle and simple cycle system performance.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4E86A48FCDB74F8DB181CC41DC8AA9FB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Program goals</header><text>The goals of the multiphase program established under subsection (a) shall be—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6EFA01F2CBBE4369BB132ECB337B39A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in phase I—</text> <subparagraph id="H43DEE7C88F4B4FC4926258D5E85B13E7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop the conceptual design of advanced high efficiency gas turbines that can achieve at least 65-percent combined cycle efficiency or 47-percent simple cycle efficiency on a lower heating value basis; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF05270A46334B6ABA0089F1E4AF7AAF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop and demonstrate the technology required for advanced high efficiency gas turbines that can achieve at least 65-percent combined cycle efficiency or 47-percent simple cycle efficiency on a lower heating value basis; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF56E83788C74524A15D4B59D8177514"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in phase II, to develop the conceptual design for advanced high efficiency gas turbines that can achieve at least 67-percent combined cycle efficiency or 50-percent simple cycle efficiency on a lower heating value basis.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H516E2F9D0629460F8DC67B53350DD685"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Proposals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Within 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall solicit grant and contract proposals from industry, small businesses, universities, and other appropriate parties for conducting activities under this Act. In selecting proposals, the Secretary shall emphasize—</text>
 <paragraph id="HAF0F2B4302BA4950B84BA6E73CC038B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the extent to which the proposal will stimulate the creation or increased retention of jobs in the United States; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H00E235D358074C3FB09E857A40E5ECB9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the extent to which the proposal will promote and enhance United States technology leadership.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0B95DC54435D427080A38A1D5DA4B4EE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Competitive Awards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provision of funding under this section shall be on a competitive basis with an emphasis on technical merit.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8ED35F354F1D4721B3753C00A810F694"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Cost sharing</header><text>Section 988 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16352">42 U.S.C. 16352</external-xref>) shall apply to an award of financial assistance made under this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4F13768F841448B6975A4D484FB6C28E"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Limits on participation</header><text>The limits on participation applicable under section 999E of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16375">42 U.S.C. 16375</external-xref>) shall apply to financial assistance awarded under this section.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


