<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1B087EA96C484DFBB15063479EBC63E7" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2534 IH: Rebuilding American Manufacturing Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2534</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170518">May 18, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to reduce the rate of tax on domestic manufacturing
			 income to 20 percent.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H74B57A05BCE942C88C9BC9CB19940E56" style="OLC">
		<section commented="no" id="HDD3A68E566914A2EB666F6F4A352AE9C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; findings</header>
 <subsection id="H018CAD8298DE4F1AB700D4274144606F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rebuilding American Manufacturing Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H842915E023D5419E83B8B3617C1A6899"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HF73849D7F86D44AC9EEE6ED81B006F36"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">American manufacturing is vital to our economy, and those who produce American goods and hire American workers should be a priority.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD2EE70BD048E4689805E7851AA50B645"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Manufacturing is an essential source of innovation that is critical to our continued prosperity in an increasingly competitive global economy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H130C89B393C7453284614D1172BE130E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Approximately 12 million Americans are employed by the manufacturing industry.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0755E495B2B14D6999C836F533EEBD54"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The manufacturing industry provides stable jobs with sustainable wages to Americans in every State.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFBC0FA592DC24CFABCAC307DADBAEC5D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Manufacturing jobs provide, on average, wages that are above the national average and provide a gateway to the middle class.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCB538CB2AF2B4711B00085D7F1A589CF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The effective tax rate of domestic manufacturers ranges from 27 to 31 percent, depending on location and the size of equipment used in production.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H59B458E1ABDC4539A0EA1D796232F3AE"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Tax reform must make the United States more competitive, boost economic growth, and foster the creation of sustainable American jobs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB2DC42BA6E9040EE89D40326AA814F54"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Tax reform should particularly focus on those companies that grow, build, and create goods in the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H45FE0097AF2B44F69FBC5046621603B9"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The tax rate of domestic manufacturers should reflect the industry’s contributions of employment, growth, innovation, and competition in the United States.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HFA5E3D2933DE4C828468559711122890"><enum>2.</enum><header>20-percent income tax rate for domestic manufacturing income</header>
 <subsection id="H5F09091119364F0984FDE834A89143D9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part VI of subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBB5EE11B92D64DF5B446F1BBDC5794D9" style="OLC">
					<section id="H749CDA2DF73E4EBCBDF4B1AEB88AF35D"><enum>200.</enum><header>Domestic manufacturing income</header>
 <subsection id="HE5CFFFDAA36943F68C86F49724A7EC44"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Allowance of deduction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There shall be allowed as a deduction an amount equal to 50.5 percent (43 percent in the case of a C corporation) of the lesser of—</text>
 <paragraph id="H27D57C4635474959A2AB862B37010571"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the domestic manufacturing income of the taxpayer for the taxable year, or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEB35568DD08D466E9FB7AD55CFA78D35"><enum>(2)</enum><text>taxable income (determined without regard to this section and section 199) for the taxable year.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H02DF7B0416FF4217B15BFFAD24979161"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation based on domestic investment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H2F3E25D9A3874854BAE9DC9215861602"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amount of the deduction allowable under subsection (a) for any taxable year shall not exceed 25 percent of the taxpayer’s qualifying domestic investment for the taxable year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H39FDB23F749E4CE8AE7BF039E670D4EC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualifying domestic investment amount</header><text>The term <quote>qualifying domestic investment</quote> means, with respect to any taxpayer for any taxable year, the sum of—</text> <subparagraph id="HAA8B0751668D4120AB7E383E6549A9AA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the W–2 wages of such taxpayer for such taxable year,</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD329F45A57E4F1EA2AB3DE7194D890E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the sum of the deductions allowable under sections 167, 169, 179, and 179D to such taxpayer for such taxable year, plus</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C537B438959499E9FCC5D847572AD52"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the deduction allowable under section 174 to such taxpayer for such taxable year.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6D91CB1CB9D4F2B92E73034C7CDF9A4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>W–<enum-in-header>2</enum-in-header> wages</header><text>The term <quote>W–2 wages</quote> means, with respect to any person for any taxable year, the sum of the amounts described in paragraphs (3) and (8) of section 6051(a) paid by such person with respect to employment of employees by such person during the calendar year ending during such taxable year. Such term shall not include any amount which is not properly included in a return filed with the Social Security Administration on or before the 60th day after the due date (including extensions) for such return.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H45BCC03D0D0143C4BE3E09E8AB44D9B4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitation to amounts attributable to domestic production</header><text>The term <quote>qualifying domestic investment</quote> shall not include any amount which is not properly allocable to domestic manufacturing gross receipts for purposes of subsection (c) (and shall include any amount which is so allocable under subsection (c)(4)).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H494C65503EDD49D481917D1307BDDE35"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Acquisitions and dispositions</header><text>The Secretary shall provide for the application of this subsection in cases where the taxpayer acquires, or disposes of, the major portion of a trade or business or the major portion of a separate unit of a trade or business during the taxable year.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA10D8BBB1F954055A423E54FA989C5A7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Domestic manufacturing income</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H58D82F6CAB944E7ABBA0A8852B784E1E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>domestic manufacturing income</quote> for any taxable year means an amount equal to the excess (if any) of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4C0E41189B3546C3A210345B9353D4EB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the taxpayer’s domestic manufacturing gross receipts for such taxable year, over</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA58384D348E044638315DD2FC98EB9C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the sum of—</text>
 <clause id="HDC881916561B40B3AA3266C095BAB73B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the cost of goods sold that are allocable to such receipts, and</text> </clause><clause id="H11D7364707F949409E10E8D1CF6A7807"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>other expenses, losses, or deductions (other than the deduction allowed under this section), which are properly allocable to such receipts.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H294CD9B113BE49B08B3AF9197124CE47"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Allocation method</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall prescribe rules for the proper allocation of items described in paragraph (1) for purposes of determining domestic manufacturing income. Such rules shall provide for the proper allocation of items whether or not such items are directly allocable to domestic manufacturing gross receipts.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H5087487C050B4640941DA31C581C2EAC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Special rules for determining costs</header>
 <subparagraph id="HA34523778A8147BAAC87B6BFE04534D5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of determining costs under clause (i) of paragraph (1)(B), any item or service brought into the United States shall be treated as acquired by purchase, and its cost shall be treated as not less than its value immediately after it entered the United States. A similar rule shall apply in determining the adjusted basis of leased or rented property where the lease or rental gives rise to domestic manufacturing gross receipts.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE62F80E1CC8F4A0A966E6BFF4F83C6E2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exports for further manufacture</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any property described in subparagraph (A) that had been exported by the taxpayer for further manufacture, the increase in cost or adjusted basis under subparagraph (A) shall not exceed the difference between the value of the property when exported and the value of the property when brought back into the United States after the further manufacture.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8CF224078BEE4614B1C900B0C0EE3773"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Treatment of certain accelerated depreciation deductions</header><text>In the case of property placed in service after December 31, 2007, and before the first taxable year of the taxpayer beginning after December 31, 2016, the deduction under section 168 with respect to such property which is treated as properly allocable to domestic manufacturing gross receipts of the taxpayer for any taxable year shall be determined without regard to section 168(k)(1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA4DE4E3E7B0545A58224C37114AA8A4B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Treatment of deferred compensation under nonqualified plans</header><text>In the case of compensation paid or incurred by the taxpayer which is deferred under a nonqualified deferred compensation plan (as defined in section 409A(d)(1)), the amount under paragraph (1)(B)(ii) shall be determined as though the deduction for such compensation is allowed for the taxable year in which the services for which such compensation was paid or incurred are performed. This paragraph shall not apply with respect to compensation paid or incurred for services performed in taxable years beginning before the first taxable year of the taxpayer beginning after December 31, 2016.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H64267CB7A41747B6BBEBA9F3B8F564D2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Domestic manufacturing gross receipts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H3A3E53A22E204D778695D3C809D7E064"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>domestic manufacturing gross receipts</quote> means the gross receipts of the taxpayer which are derived from any lease, rental, license, sale, exchange, or other disposition of qualified property which was manufactured, produced, or grown by the taxpayer in whole or in significant part within the United States. Such term shall not include gross receipts of the taxpayer which are derived from the sale of food and beverages prepared by the taxpayer at a retail establishment.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCEB05B447FD94941B7E4A72A3C9CC91C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rule for certain government contracts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Gross receipts derived from the manufacture or production of any property shall not fail to be treated as meeting the requirements of paragraph (1) solely because title or risk of loss with respect to such property is held by the Federal Government if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF89835C8BFC349A1BB109CC54A785CF0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such property is manufactured or produced by the taxpayer pursuant to a contract with the Federal Government, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6386AF939D643B0A5887C7C905239BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Federal Acquisition Regulation requires that title or risk of loss with respect to such property be transferred to the Federal Government before the manufacture or production of such property is complete.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5DF4135B482B4DA89446ED73D3FD18E5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified property</header><text>The term <quote>qualified property</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HADE950A5507E461D94DA2136FF22FD81"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any tangible personal property other than—</text>
 <clause id="HDC08748A85154B89860AEDCC177C891B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>oil, gas, and primary products thereof (within the meaning of section 199(d)(9)(C)),</text> </clause><clause id="HB2D55B300C6F45E29DA52E0237511163"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>property with respect to which section 613 applies,</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5DF14E8382C244F093AB192FD7C01DF3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>property described in paragraph (3) or (4) of section 168(f), and</text> </clause><clause id="H30AFA0680011471FA3FD24E04B02C5D4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>electricity and potable water, and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3FBF9BFAB97D436A9C95168E8C000E18"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any computer software other than video games rated M, AO, RP, or any similar rating as determined by the Secretary, by the Entertainment Software Rating Board.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H41ADB3035E38458AA9B8F2A709113B80"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Partnerships owned by expanded affiliated groups</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, if all of the interests in the capital and profits of a partnership are owned by members of a single expanded affiliated group at all times during the taxable year of such partnership, the partnership and all members of such group shall be treated as a single taxpayer during such period.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H8189BCFDD6634E91987D01CE8DAC01F9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Related persons</header>
 <subparagraph id="HD4282C68FF5A404AA65E7709F2229443"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>domestic manufacturing gross receipts</quote> shall not include any gross receipts of the taxpayer derived from property leased, licensed, or rented by the taxpayer for use by any related person.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE6D0B14C443B4A4783419BB1A62F4BE9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Related person</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subparagraph (A), a person shall be treated as related to another person if such persons are treated as a single employer under subsection (a) or (b) of section 52 or subsection (m) or (o) of section 414, except that determinations under subsections (a) and (b) of section 52 shall be made without regard to section 1563(b).</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3EDF3354C5204B79A7512D9C94C3A103"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Special rules</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HB37D47BCABD44AE28AE2CD9B2026409F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Elective application of deduction</header><text>Except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, the taxpayer may elect not to take any item of income into account as domestic manufacturing gross receipts for purposes of this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H642D07A4A7ED40A483962B679FDF46CB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination with section 199</header><text>If a deduction is allowed under this section with respect to any taxpayer for any taxable year, any gross receipts of the taxpayer which are taken into account under this section for such taxable year (and any items properly allocable thereto under subsection (b) or (c)) shall not be taken into account under section 199 for such taxable year.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H6879A97A13C84743BE5B2C377B0583F9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application of section to pass-thru entities</header>
 <subparagraph id="H41AA89D17EEF45E4AB855E9B1AEFAC7B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Partnerships and S corporations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a partnership or S corporation—</text> <clause id="HE21BC4F86ED9414BBA1314921F377C1E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>this section shall be applied at the partner or shareholder level,</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2DE0984B514649759C574218256AC3BB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>each partner or shareholder shall take into account such person’s allocable share of each item described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of subsection (c)(1) (determined without regard to whether the items described in such subparagraph (A) exceed the items described in such subparagraph (B)), and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD2EC2475092E49F5A5E9363A9242A884"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>each partner or shareholder shall be treated for purposes of subsection (b) as having an amount of each item taken into account in determining qualifying domestic investment of the partnership or S corporation for the taxable year equal to such person’s allocable share of such item (as determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1497E13AC2044534A000E04FB9BEF146"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Trust and estates</header><text>In the case of a trust or estate—</text> <clause id="HAD0E87DD6BEA49EC8A5443E018DBEDBC"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the items referred to in subparagraph (A)(ii) (as determined therein) and the qualifying domestic investment of the trust or estate for the taxable year, shall be apportioned between the beneficiaries and the fiduciary (and among the beneficiaries) under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H532E7D19637A41C5B60A99C42618F8F6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for purposes of paragraph (4), adjusted gross income of the trust or estate shall be determined as provided in section 67(e) with the adjustments described in such paragraph.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7570F5C27F954156BBB990FE6468F93E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may prescribe rules requiring or restricting the allocation of items and qualifying domestic investment under this paragraph and may prescribe such reporting requirements as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB1E006CF5F47496AA2C36D85635F2A6A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Application to individuals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an individual, subsection (a)(2) shall be applied by substituting <quote>adjusted gross income</quote> for <quote>taxable income</quote>. For purposes of the preceding sentence, adjusted gross income shall be determined—</text> <subparagraph id="HBA7947E519DB4E91BBF56D197992D12A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>after application of sections 86, 135, 137, 219, 221, 222, and 469, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H11AE55E993104FB28040D40D3EB692EB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>without regard to this section and section 199.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4ADDBD7CF5F54B12B74A6142A857BDBD"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Application of other rules</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of paragraphs (3), (4), (5), (6), (7), and (10) of section 199(d) shall apply for purposes of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5DAA43392ED248A2A213921B0BC321DD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="H47CBF9F509BE42C792FB4E57BA00252A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 56(d)(1)(A) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>deduction under section 199</quote> both places it appears and inserting <quote>deductions under sections 199 and 200</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8350927A2D734D85AFD6F7783CBD5C9A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 56(g)(4)(C) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new clause:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD74016B0FE42468EA672E706DE8AE01C" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H109F6CF1588047788F0EF42D44F40CD3"><enum>(vii)</enum><header>Deduction for domestic business income</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Clause (i) shall not apply to any amount allowable as a deduction under section 200.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9FAAE3BA0E494911B9333D75F4A05FDB"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following provisions of such Code are each amended by inserting <quote>200,</quote> after <quote>199,</quote>.</text>
 <subparagraph id="H649A7E1930784334979C6C6703B383A4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 86(b)(2)(A).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98901D4B445D447A81EC3B3251A7B33E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 135(c)(4)(A).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5DF223328C96432A83AFCFF7A522949E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Section 137(b)(3)(A).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F4DE673A5D940E98BDBB9C2E8FC6312"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Section 219(g)(3)(A)(ii).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H32199710C8E04CC8ABA42CD1D809D2DE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Section 221(b)(2)(C)(i).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB8407B772014995960B790A52699ADB"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Section 222 (b)(2)(C)(i).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C0B81463A83437EA1C0114D470749F9"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Section 246(b)(1).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD09F7993A40E44929E4B1CD742F35FFD"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Section 469(i)(3)(F)(iii).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H92BEDF9E3DC64133B72FF486995527E3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Section 163(j)(6)(A)(i) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subclause (III) and by inserting after subclause (IV) the following new subclause:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE4ACDB09BC9E42FE8AB2AB5226B2EF31" style="OLC"> <subclause id="HA4486B11EBB04B1889D2FA6ADC096B74"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any deduction allowable under section 200, and</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H946573D3D6F44C3A9748AA91F6CA9F33"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Section 170(b)(2)(C) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of clause (iv), by striking the period at the end of clause (v) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and by inserting after clause (v) the following new clause:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4D9F1C88BCD247C8960AEBEEDA899389" style="OLC"> <clause id="H8BD595F9B7794A4B9198B7293871AA68"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 200.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA719B28544F341B58FE025B05992114B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Section 172(d) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H749B64072F094304AFA0224B315D56BB" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H821A2EB4DC514E739E5179F4395EC8FF"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Domestic business income</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The deduction under section 200 shall not be allowed.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF51C6CBC115849B2BD013372DB91A706"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Section 199(d)(2)(A) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>200,</quote> after <quote>137,</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H32AF1FCB51E1478E9583FBD08AA1F72D"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 613(a) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>deduction under section 199</quote> and inserting <quote>deductions under sections 199 and 200</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0A4981026D4F48F7829E5E43255008C5"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Section 613A(d)(1) of such Code is amended by redesignating subparagraphs (C), (D), and (E) as subparagraphs (D), (E), and (F), respectively, and by inserting after subparagraph (B) the following new subparagraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7A56F03AFA004C868A5AB29EAF424639" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H5F585EC68C674125B8F5D042B512B975"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any deduction allowable under section 200,</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC1FF598CE46D430E85456370CC03A612"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Section 1402(a) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (16), by redesignating paragraph (17) as paragraph (18), and by inserting after paragraph (16) the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA82342B9DF3747CBBE530CAD0A5D07D8" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HA5EF5469C3E84DCEA51B97E0E2ED6571"><enum>(17)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the deduction provided by section 200 shall not be allowed; and</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9ACD1E64556649FA8C75FAC9180E6B9C"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for part VI of subchapter B of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H493702FA8336403381B363D4A418399F" style="OLC">
						<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="HBB5EE11B92D64DF5B446F1BBDC5794D9" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
							<toc-entry idref="H749CDA2DF73E4EBCBDF4B1AEB88AF35D" level="section">Sec. 200. Domestic manufacturing income.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3F7ABDCFB8644C5989A2E7B561A68051"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2016.</text> </subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

