<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H5608B5E69B67493BA87C77BC1F196319" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4525 IH: Living Shorelines Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4525</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171201">December 1, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to make grants
			 to States and local governments and nongovernmental organizations for
			 purposes of carrying out shoreline stabilization projects utilizing
			 natural materials.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H9A3F063CB75C441584EA1223266B12E3" style="OLC">
 <section id="H9604185E503644BF81BB54190F8BFACB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Living Shorelines Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H1F83352E3E4349B5BCEA04F2E7EC21E1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Living shoreline grant program</header> <subsection id="H29FB12D9939C4C68A4C926A431588AA5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall make grants to eligible entities for purposes of—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0A6F407E62584260A79B689935572587"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">carrying out large- and small-scale, climate-resilient living shoreline projects; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H09ECAF6E5503440180DB3A6E3AC24D8B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encouraging innovation in the use of natural materials to protect coastal communities.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAC7BD35B95B3498C9D2DEF2F9C01B1C6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>project and selection</header>
 <paragraph id="HF7254DDA8948489497F48B4C9B331D35"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall submit to the Administrator a proposed living shoreline project, including monitoring and data collection with respect to the project.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H7A60767E70574DE8BB43A7F045CF6312"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Selection</header>
 <subparagraph id="H91111B0E3CEF49B0BE1FEF33C62EF7B8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall select recipients based on criteria to be prescribed by the Administrator in consultation with relevant National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration offices, such as the Office of Habitat Conservation, the Office for Coastal Management, and the Restoration Center, and taking into account the potential of proposed projects submitted under this subsection to protect communities and maintain the viability of the environment in areas where such proposed projects are to be carried out.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6DCFD1273074EA58155570C58A63D18"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In selecting recipients the Administrator shall give priority consideration to a proposed project to be conducted in an area for which the President has declared, within the 10-year period preceding the submission of a proposed project, that a major disaster exists pursuant to section 401 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</external-xref>) due to a hurricane, tropical storm, coastal storm, or flooding.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0085A451C7A4FAEBA78026DFC418D91"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Minimum level of protection</header>
 <subparagraph id="H0DAC782A0B044BDC8448C3FE353C49ED"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall select proposed projects for grants under this section that—</text> <clause id="H94EAE6F6004D40E798F1AA293E1F34E0"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are primarily focused on providing protection for a coastal community; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEC62405E8AD24471A46350408D21CDCF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>demonstrate and quantify the ability of the project to meet a minimal level of such protection.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53B824370CC74DCC86C8558C4B885045"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Protection defined</header><text>In this paragraph the term <quote>protection</quote> includes—</text>
 <clause id="H1BF94BB085A948D68F0F0FB2866BAC4D"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">mitigating the effects of erosion;</text> </clause><clause id="HCA68C899040847CBA6B44B79214B7C96"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>absorbing the impact of coastal storms;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H16EAB2C8753340058EBFA33955DF60F6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>mitigating shoreline flooding;</text> </clause><clause id="H5C5846F098B748D1896D2BF1107A277A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">mitigating the effects of sea level rise; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7DF8D2D7CD154EA9869AF864DC14CD3C"><enum>(v)</enum><text>other forms of protection as determined by the Administrator.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC98DE297E7A3469094B50FACD8D522EA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Community protection standards</header> <subparagraph id="H28CCBA21E4614A8AB6645317AC868453"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator—</text>
 <clause id="HDEB0DD387B014CECB32A18AE91FE3124"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall make the determination under paragraph (3) under standards established by the Administrator in consultation with the Corps of Engineers and relevant National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration offices, such as the Office of Habitat Conservation, the Office for Coastal Management, and the Restoration Center; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAA2E0C4B29B2493E9C35AAF8BA2BB439"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in establishing such standards, may consult with relevant interagency councils, such as the Estuary Habitat Restoration Council.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96A05DB6CDBC4EC5960BE032992752C0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such standards shall take into account historic flooding and projected flooding, climate change, erosion, the value of properties in the community, and ecological benefits of a proposed project.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H22892D83742F417F8ACD9B6B42E5F296"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Grants made under this section may be used by recipients only to—</text> <paragraph id="HF4711441B9794A938163DBE6989B96C0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>carry out living shoreline projects; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9F69673867584AE880FF6A0ACBE84392"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">monitor and collect data on the success and deficiencies of projects, in accordance with standards issued by the Administrator under subsection (e)(2).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEA3942DDDDBE4E57A53333C32BC93AFF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Cost-Sharing</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall provide, from non-Federal sources, not less than 50 percent of the funds towards the total cost, including administrative costs, of each living shoreline project funded by such grant.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HDCD326FA69384FF7910785E4388FF520"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Monitoring and report</header>
 <paragraph id="H25F224A6CC694E429E4B1E0EE82675FF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall require each recipient of a grant under this section (or their representative) to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1A5729AF5D29410DB8E6058CE9EEC7F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>transmit to the Administrator data collected with the grant;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8EBE380290146338458C4EC67386994"><enum>(B)</enum><text>monitor approved projects conducted with grants under this section and collect data on the protection provided by such projects and the success and deficiencies of such projects in providing such protection;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F1D5BF2B2324C488A45887E3F650B95"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make such data available to the public through the website of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H978F291BC0C54301BCAB86081EA1ED2F"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by not later than December 31, 2022, publish a report on the effectiveness of the program under this section in increasing protection of coastal communities through living shorelines techniques, including—</text>
 <clause id="HBD9BF84610774A49B482E4208EB63B21"><enum>(i)</enum><text>descriptions of—</text> <subclause id="H6D79AFEFF08D45AEA44009190FA67666"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the projects that were awarded grants;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H67FCB6FDEA674DB0B47DFBC6A9CE472C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the construction carried out under such projects; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HBEC2D1FEA2A84C649EA79889E1CD204B"><enum>(III)</enum><text>what techniques and materials were used in such projects; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H482316A31A7F4D18842814018CB4894E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>data on the performance of such projects in providing such protection.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H318D8187DC764F048DB74FECCB9035C2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Standards</header> <subparagraph id="H30AEC08799C24BBF9F93C1911FA4E642"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act the Administrator shall, in consultation with relevant offices of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and nongovernmental organizations, issue standards for the collection under subsection (c) and this subsection of data regarding the success and deficiencies of projects conducted with grants under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9FF0EBDEE1A64E01B0577155361267A3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>The standards shall require reporting of such data to the Administration on a regular basis.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA4727963C7EC4C7898F13DF8FDD20929"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text>
 <paragraph id="H3684BC4013EF4E43B887A2C3B0CA9FF3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <quote>Administrator</quote> means the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA35BFD326ADF409D987F4AFEC2154C93"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <quote>eligible entity</quote> means each of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8E21F0E7068E45BDB84240C19FFE7D66"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A State or a unit of general local government in a State.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B478C48945D4E78AB5581FBBC399A02"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nongovernmental organizations that are described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from tax under section 501(a) of such Code.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B5B5173287946EFAD2E710D807DF507"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Living shoreline project</header><text>The term <quote>living shoreline project</quote>—</text> <subparagraph id="H992CF530CBF14C0F9E4D858B67E1FF12"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means a project to mitigate the effects of erosion caused by shoreline flooding or innundation, currents, and wave energy, through project design that stabilizes a shoreline by using natural materials to create buffers to absorb the impact of coastal storms, flooding, and wave energy and to prevent or minimize (or both) shoreline erosion, that—</text>
 <clause id="HD3E726253A7A4C3F8FE9527E90F3CE0C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">incorporates as many natural elements as possible, such as native wetlands, submerged aquatic plants, native grasses, shrubs, or trees;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H242506EF19724C059EA48BDB1ED3DD2A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">utilizes techniques that incorporate ecological and coastal engineering principles in shoreline stabilization; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5C78AFEB2B9E4E778B0B76FABF327C30"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the extent possible, maintains or restores existing natural slopes and connections between uplands and adjacent wetlands or surface waters; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9804AC8D95247B48D4CCCC5E3DA24C3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may include, but not be limited to, the use of—</text> <clause id="HC3921C8CC64E4806AA2FBC1A142BB558"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">natural elements, such as sand, wetland plants, logs, oysters or other shellfish, submerged aquatic vegetation, native grasses, shrubs, trees, or coir fiber logs; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H892DFC1CED674E33B2C77E5A61BAC803"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>structural materials, such as stone, concrete, wood, vinyl, oyster domes, or other approved engineered structures.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB031ACF6AB0F4DAE98E6FAF68533E9E2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> means each of the several States, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and each Federally recognized Indian Tribe.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE5DEEC6A17994C6BAEF1150124FD99BC"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated $20,000,000 to the Administrator for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2023 for purposes of carrying out this section.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


