<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H21249A3C3A014A739C2D479353F14D38" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3870 IH: Electronic Books Opening Opportunity for Knowledge Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3870</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170928">September 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="M001179">Mr. Marino</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to lower the cost of college education by establishing
			 pilot programs to expand student access to digital course materials.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H961FA42573204F9AA3688F1A370DC3B8" style="OLC">
 <section id="HDEF711D03B1A48EDAAB72E256ED25B2F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Electronic Books Opening Opportunity for Knowledge Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>E–BOOK Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HB4667E4A33F94670B2CFE07040B74CB8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to identify savings in the cost of higher education for undergraduate students by funding pilot programs to expand student access to digital academic course materials.</text>
 </section><section id="HF27F97E92A1045EE8E977523F61E8F0F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grants to Expand Access to Digital Course Materials</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title VIII of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1161a">20 U.S.C. 1161a</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following new part:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5C5AF54D7DA845F29656E43483BD38BE" style="OLC">
				<part id="H2ACB3630C9F1482788E2454D0DAE4526"><enum>BB</enum><header>Grants for the Expansion of Access to Digital Course Materials</header>
					<section id="H8E22D1F0CA4C454EA3B2166DB0636CD7"><enum>899.</enum><header>Grants for Access to Digital Course Materials</header>
						<subsection id="H00FE65EC87DD40AD8AE6F64476939061"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header>
 <paragraph id="H0F8F185B68714E84B9FAE4AD08FA0681"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From amounts made available by the Secretary that are not otherwise obligated, the Secretary may award grants on a competitive basis to not more than 10 institutions of higher education to reduce the cost of attendance for undergraduate students by providing such students with expanded access to digital course materials.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCB5178056F054CA7AAF242752CFBEF12"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amount of funds to be awarded</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall determine the amount of funds to be awarded for each grant based on the number of students to be served under the grant, except that no grant under this section shall be in an amount that is more than $2,000,000.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H25FBBC509E6342F0A663F9928A6E902A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An institution desiring to obtain a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such form, and accompanied by such information, agreements, and assurances as the Secretary may reasonably require.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6240024698AC41D29D58351F0E738EF6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Preference</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give preference to applications that demonstrate a commitment to serving disadvantaged students.</text>
 </subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9F84224AF8034309895031B6BE353456"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of Funds</header><text>Each grant awarded under this section shall provide to an institution of higher education funds to support a pilot program for the institution to make digital course materials available to undergraduate students in at least two different academic departments. Such funds may be used for any of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HE4FED92F674A4AA79EF95F6BE53E10AA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Purchasing and maintaining electronic equipment or software necessary for the operation of the pilot program, including mobile computer devices and accompanying hardware, software applications, computer systems and platforms, and other digital and online services and support.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H470FF8E1B6444C858DC060AEBFC8DC72"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Maintaining digital and online content for the institution to make available electronically to instructors or students.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H591F617248564892A8B46514F147BE93"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Hiring staff for the administration of the pilot program, with priority given to hiring enrolled undergraduate students.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H448AA3F22A164C2BA1BFA68C7D68C38D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Building or acquiring extra storage space dedicated to equipment used for the pilot program.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7EC13067F1284984A61FB3412C15DF2C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Supporting professional development activities for instructors, instructional aides, or other personnel as needed to support implementation of the pilot program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H83D7AF9194E04FA4BE2BF4910B7E17A4"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Revising and adapting academic curricula as needed to implement the pilot program.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA088A8820F3844D595EF13561205B0EC"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Acquiring such other goods or services as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1DEB0D3EB25C41C1A7EA2C94FA44E378"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header>
 <paragraph id="HBBAE52C6F1EE4C368AA270E4FE831FE4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Report to the Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After a period of time to be determined by the Secretary, each institution of higher education that receives a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary a report that includes—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8AB1B974657A4C8781EF4D89D505DC57"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an assessment of the effectiveness of the pilot program funded by the grant in reducing the cost of attendance for students;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE1B72BCAF0248CBB2F3CBFCA0FFE7EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an assessment of any impact of the pilot program on student achievement;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7CE485CDBEC49618EDDB012951454A8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an accounting of the purposes for which the grant funds were expended; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E81F6859E5149FFB6828BB24A0D6512"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any additional information the Secretary reasonably requires.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C1DBEF5D8E34FA19EF44F5AEC23A8D9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than three years after the end of the first fiscal year in which a grant is awarded under this section, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the effectiveness of the grants. Such report shall include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H06A39C25AF3147FEB3983CCBC2C4712E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an estimate by the Secretary of the amount of money saved by students who participate in the pilot programs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE957718924B485BA2CD02B3AD5AE793"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a summary of the best practices developed in the pilot programs;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HACDBEA4BF7B74A03AE12636AD9AEE263"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the types of digital course materials used in the pilot programs, including electronic books, interactive and adaptive digital learning tools, and open educational resources; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2DAAB00295AA419992028AB62E6B2E88"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any recommendations the Secretary determines appropriate regarding future congressional action related to student access to digital course materials.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H12ED8F2A7BA049C5BE7FC73C50E5B6EA"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HF0C351024A3C4AE491110F7177B10B94"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Cost of attendance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>cost of attendance</term> has the meaning given the term in section 472.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3125A72BF2B94576AD5AC232382AE410"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101(a), except that such term only includes public institutions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H158D753622FE4D5E80EE2E9D106D68D6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Digital course materials</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>digital course materials</term> includes electronic books, portable document format and word-processing documents, internet websites, interactive and adaptive digital learning tools, open educational resources, and other digital and online educational resources.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H98B0E57998564311BB57D025206AEB94"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Open educational resources</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>open educational resources</term> means digital course materials that are made freely available online to the public with a permanent copyright license granting advance permission for the public to access, distribute, adapt, and otherwise use the work with appropriate attribution to the authors as set forth in the materials.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H80DE360FD6214159A1820BA346C4935C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Mobile computer device</header><text>The term <term>mobile computer device</term> means an electronic reader or tablet computer.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H18907B77C9504665983C1E5E2E9487D4"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Disadvantaged student</header><text>The term <term>disadvantaged student</term> means an undergraduate student who is—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDE9F7E508EA94F52A50B433CF5F7070A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>from a low-income family;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6E65E26F10543B9988398C8136A0819"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a minority; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFEA978629C3B47608577E9F234AB9CC3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>from an economically or otherwise dis­ad­van­taged background.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8EF2752B062947679C4D5AD301633E39"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No grants may be awarded under this section after September 30, 2020.</text></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


