<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H8FAA0307ECEB4E599F3A7FF83C48631C" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1599 IH: No Bonuses for Tax Delinquent IRS Employees Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1599</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170317">March 17, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000174">Mr. Sam Johnson of Texas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the provision of performance awards to employees of the Internal Revenue Service who
			 owe back taxes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H630295F96D37424389AE9B6861231278" style="OLC">
 <section id="H43E04CD766F54E848427CC68B29C2ADF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Bonuses for Tax Delinquent IRS Employees Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HEDF97E500B124B97952994C316E23B47"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on performance awards to IRS employees who owe back taxes</header> <subsection id="H3E8ECB547558488B88A23D1DF6CCB214"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner of the Internal Revenue Service shall not provide any performance award (including, but not limited to, bonuses, step increases, and time off) to an employee of the Internal Revenue Service who owes an outstanding Federal tax debt.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2DD693DBCD2F4B31B9B430E1B00DFAEE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Outstanding Federal tax debt</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>outstanding Federal tax debt</quote> means any outstanding debt under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 which has not been paid after an assessment of a tax, penalty, or interest and which is not subject to further appeal or a petition for redetermination under such Code. A debt shall not fail to be treated as an outstanding Federal tax debt merely because it is the subject of an installment agreement under section 6159 of such Code or an offer-in-compromise under section 7121 of such Code.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


