<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HBE0291AC4DAA453BB62EC49636D5DD2E" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1611 IH: Gender Diversity in Corporate Leadership Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1611</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170317">March 17, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000290">Ms. Jenkins of Kansas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Securities and Exchange Commission to establish a Gender Diversity Advisory Group to
			 study and make recommendations on strategies to increase gender diversity
			 among the members of the board of directors of issuers, to amend the
			 Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to require issuers to make disclosures to
			 shareholders with respect to gender diversity, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HC5CDB2A68FE74498ACEFEC00D2A2477E" style="OLC">
 <section id="H535EE38DBC1C4982BF0EA2A1EE260016" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Gender Diversity in Corporate Leadership Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H9AC94CCFD4834C2E9DE21C1938BDDC51"><enum>2.</enum><header>Gender diversity study and disclosures</header> <subsection id="H7A0251F7362640FBB4E4C641E5E5BEC6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Gender Diversity Advisory Group</header> <paragraph id="H823096D15B0C47DBBB496CCD41A4B7D9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Securities and Exchange Commission shall establish a Gender Diversity Advisory Group (the <quote>Advisory Group</quote>), which shall be composed of representatives from the Government, academia, and the private sector.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9C12609D38D848E3B7C41B672ADCCE20"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Study and recommendations</header><text>The Advisory Group shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H72254938D25846CD9C5B0702C97CBC2B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>carry out a study on strategies to increase gender diversity among the members of the board of directors of issuers; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CF5FE10CE5144BC925F19DC5F0230D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 9 months after the establishment of the Advisory Group, issue a report to the Commission, the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate containing the findings and determinations made in carrying out such study, along with recommendations to increase gender diversity among the members of the board of directors of issuers.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD3D26F1D19A4AF1AA34AB278205588C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year following the issuance of the report under paragraph (2)(B), and annually thereafter, the Commission shall issue a report to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate on the status of gender diversity among the members of the board of directors of issuers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H00903A7AC51343DE8EF08F73B4C816AE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public availability of reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall make all reports of the Advisory Group available to issuers and the public, including on the website of the Commission.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2EBD268AD0DE49C4822C672552E44302"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Disclosures</header><text>The Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78a">15 U.S.C. 78a</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by inserting after section 14B the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFA7D80C6CD45457896B6A0DA17A50BB6" style="OLC">
 <section id="H750996D49826436296EA7BFA7A201B08"><enum>14C.</enum><header>Gender diversity disclosures</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Commission shall, by rule, require each issuer to disclose, in any proxy or consent solicitation material for an annual meeting of the shareholders of the issuer, the gender composition of the issuer’s board of directors and nominees for the board of directors.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


