<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H44A3814682CF44E5A7BA19ECACA094D2" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3312 : Systemic Risk Designation Improvement Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code>
		<congress>115th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3312</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date date="20171220">December 20, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To amend the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act to specify when bank holding
			 companies may be subject to certain enhanced supervision, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H5F2F40E4B66649C5BFF199C0AF546A76" style="OLC">
 <section id="H36971C6617E546308545008B88D06A6E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Systemic Risk Designation Improvement Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H026C89C3C8724E688B35EFE5473EC54C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Revisions to Council authority</header> <subsection id="H35B000CC2C40475CAA7F89CB2E148DC7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purposes and duties</header><text>Section 112 of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5322">12 U.S.C. 5322</external-xref>) is amended in subsection (a)(2)(I) by inserting before the semicolon <quote>, which have been identified as global systemically important bank holding companies pursuant to section 217.402 of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations, or subjected to a determination under subsection (l) of section 165</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H38E639B01D89446292281010DF0B810B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enhanced supervision</header><text>Section 115 of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5325">12 U.S.C. 5325</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H5A6589B8BBA64BE5BC6532E7832A0190"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1), by striking <quote>large, interconnected bank holding companies</quote> and inserting <quote>bank holding companies which have been identified as global systemically important bank holding companies pursuant to section 217.402 of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations, or subjected to a determination under subsection (l) of section 165</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7E42FA125B2343378B5EFA37AFA67983"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(2)—</text> <subparagraph id="HD5881CA2B89442B7A67C19C6C3FB2B5B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>; or</quote> at the end and inserting a period;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7006FC38AAB647189A969A3AC2887169"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the Council may</quote> and all that follows through <quote>differentiate</quote> and inserting <quote>the Council may differentiate</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C0CF01EB5974149B2C7E0800340E6E9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (B).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2DEBAB27C7AB4099BD97AB7C00F4B7D0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Section 116(a) of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5326">12 U.S.C. 5326(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>with total consolidated assets of $50,000,000,000 or greater</quote> and inserting <quote>which has been identified as a global systemically important bank holding company pursuant to section 217.402 of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations, or subjected to a determination under subsection (l) of section 165</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2D8C3834C0534065B9A85EDF2FBAF2B2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Mitigation</header><text>Section 121(a) of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5331">12 U.S.C. 5331</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>with total consolidated assets of $50,000,000,000 or more</quote> and inserting <quote>which has been identified as a global systemically important bank holding company pursuant to section 217.402 of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations, or subjected to a determination under subsection (l) of section 165</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1AB3C1943D874B0394BFD95AB7960DE1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Office of financial research</header><text>Section 155 of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5345">12 U.S.C. 5345</external-xref>) is amended in subsection (d) by striking <quote>with total consolidated assets of 50,000,000,000 or greater</quote> and inserting <quote>which have been identified as global systemically important bank holding companies pursuant to section 217.402 of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations, or subjected to a determination under subsection (l) of section 165</quote>.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H7DF999ED5B7B4606B65680D26070BA2A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Revisions to Board authority</header>
 <subsection id="H7169225FF3824D7E9E76D5AD79682D8B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Acquisitions</header><text>Section 163 of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5363">12 U.S.C. 5363</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>with total consolidated assets equal to or greater than $50,000,000,000</quote> each place such term appears and inserting <quote>which has been identified as a global systemically important bank holding company pursuant to section 217.402 of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations, or subjected to a determination under subsection (l) of section 165</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H916D6F78042F4274BA983621E5B25410"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Management interlocks</header><text>Section 164 of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5364">12 U.S.C. 5364</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>with total consolidated assets equal to or greater than $50,000,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>which has been identified as a global systemically important bank holding company pursuant to section 217.402 of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations, or subjected to a determination under subsection (l) of section 165</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8C7D13D833944609BB8483D389801889"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enhanced supervision and prudential standards</header><text>Section 165 of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5365">12 U.S.C. 5365</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HBED277F50941486C91BF069F76D93779"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>with total consolidated assets equal to or greater than $50,000,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>which have been identified as global systemically important bank holding companies pursuant to section 217.402 of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations, or subjected to a determination under subsection (l)</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD2461414B77F4FD8993FA233BDF04CFA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(2)—</text> <subparagraph id="H38423B6989A141558AA7721B71685682"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>(A) <header-in-text level="subparagraph">In general.—</header-in-text></quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66F1A39E1292445296A5C680DCBCE03A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>may</quote> and inserting <quote>shall</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F0BC1EB4FD7470AACB5B2A00A583413"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (B); and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D0DFDDBBA5C44FF8E7493F7E74AF107"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (j), by striking <quote>with total consolidated assets equal to or greater than $50,000,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>which has been identified as a global systemically important bank holding company pursuant to section 217.402 of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations, or subjected to a determination under subsection (l)</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HC6BBB1C793AF462FB11329B01D34CD3F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Advanced tailoring</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 165 of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5365">12 U.S.C. 5365</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE0A69C3F9AC041F0817D22711B9AFA93" style="OLC">
					<subsection commented="no" id="HD1441CD37B66469BABD8873359A455C0"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Additional bank holding companies subject to enhanced supervision and prudential standards by
			 tailored regulation</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HCF31C0ADF23345DD9859BAB2A0E9F248"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board of Governors may, within the limits of its existing resources—</text> <subparagraph id="H27DC2DDF6AEB41F085067E78CD61D465"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determine that a bank holding company that has not been identified as a global systemically important bank holding company pursuant to section 217.402 of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations, shall be subject to certain enhanced supervision or prudential standards under this section, tailored to the risks presented, based on the considerations in paragraph (3), where material financial distress at the bank holding company, or the nature, scope, size, scale, concentration, interconnectedness, or mix of the activities of the individual bank holding company, could pose a threat to the financial stability of the United States; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H504DDF32C15A427BB2602AC49D0305E2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by regulation determine that a category of bank holding companies that have not been identified as global systemically important bank holding companies pursuant to section 217.402 of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations, shall be subject to certain enhanced supervision or prudential standards under this section, tailored to the risk presented by the category of bank holding companies, based on the considerations in paragraph (3), where material financial distress at the category of bank holding companies, or the nature, scope, size, scale, concentration, interconnectedness, or mix of the activities of the category of bank holding companies, could pose a threat to the financial stability of the United States.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4ECB288486C3467384C9EE78B59ADA2A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Council approval of regulations with respect to categories</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding paragraph (1)(B), a regulation issued by the Board of Governors to make a determination under such paragraph (1)(B) shall not take effect unless the Council, by a vote of not fewer than two-thirds of the voting members then serving, including an affirmative vote by the Chairperson, approves the metrics used by the Board of Governors in establishing such regulation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H71246A559EDA425D956C94176B3E3861"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In making any determination under paragraph (1), the Board of Governors shall consider the following factors:</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H5E2DCD03182841CF964CB5EAA8705D01"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The size of the bank holding company.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H17CD154F273F423A9C05E8C6CB275E7F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The interconnectedness of the bank holding company.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9690E856E8294943AA3AB370E05E6171"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The extent of readily available substitutes or financial institution infrastructure for the services of the bank holding company.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE4463FFDEA174891944E9FBB0C9CCEED"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The global cross-jurisdictional activity of the bank holding company.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HEA66C0D01F7B48D299BD27EF519FEAB3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The complexity of the bank holding company.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE6EB3A9FA8984DDAB98E287C5C7414B3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consistent application of considerations</header><text>In making a determination under paragraph (1), the Board of Governors shall ensure that bank holding companies that are similarly situated with respect to the factors described under paragraph (3), are treated similarly for purposes of any enhanced supervision or prudential standards applied under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE71F7336058941728101BDDE89BBD16C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Use of currently reported data to avoid unnecessary burden</header><text>For purposes of making a determination under paragraph (1), the Board of Governors shall make use of data already being reported to the Board of Governors, including from calculating a bank holding company’s systemic indicator score, in order to avoid placing an unnecessary burden on bank holding companies.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCFDA041669D74E1FAED777EBC644630A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Systemic identification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 165 of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5365">12 U.S.C. 5365</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (d), is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7415066B2139427886440A4AA2964371" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H6B34D188B6E745F3B1B90F12AA8CB1D9"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Systemic identification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the identification of bank holding companies as global systemically important bank holding companies pursuant to section 217.402 of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations, or subjected to a determination under subsection (l), the Board of Governors shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4B5AB741AC36434C969EB694725D4D11"><enum>(1)</enum><text>publish, including on the Board of Governors’s website, a list of all bank holding companies that have been so identified, and keep such list current; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC876C5EB4D2D4CE39D09B4A1C35FBA72"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">solicit feedback from the Council on the identification process and on the application of such process to specific bank holding companies.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section id="HCF34F9D4B7E14E14BE5891948D9D3AA1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act or the amendments made by this Act shall be construed to prohibit the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System from prescribing enhanced prudential standards for any bank holding company which the Board of Governors determines, based upon the bank holding company’s size, interconnectedness, substitutability, global cross-jurisdictional activity, and complexity, could pose a safety and soundness risk to the stability of the United States banking or financial system but has not been designated as a global systemically important bank holding company.</text>
		</section><section id="H1F082A8EF047452499F4D1D041CE4C0F"><enum>5.</enum><header>Existing assessment termination schedule</header>
			<subsection id="HC14EDB6DDF3C40AA857521DEB3DA1386"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Temporary extension of existing assessment</header>
 <paragraph id="H4643D0B6A2484AFD80B0616A4BEB27E5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each bank holding company that, on the day that is 24 months following the date of the enactment of this Act, has total consolidated assets equal to or greater than $50,000,000,000, has not been identified as a global systemically important bank holding company pursuant to section 217.402 of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations, and has not been subjected to a determination under subsection (l) of section 165 of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act, shall be subject to assessments by the Secretary of the Treasury to the same extent as a bank holding company that has been so identified or subjected.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H00283CD6CD484A2C9179407EC3A1554B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In making assessments pursuant to paragraph (1), the Secretary of the Treasury shall take into account differences among the bank holding companies subject to such assessment, based on the considerations for establishing the prudential standards under section 115 of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5325">12 U.S.C. 5325</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8178A59E94DF45D4BA525D488F16872F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation on amount of assessments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The aggregate amount collected pursuant to paragraph (1) from all bank holding companies assessed under such paragraph shall be $58,000,000.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H48B922E7F2914040BC6E43BF117371F9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Payment period options</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall offer the option of payments spread out before the end of the 48-month period following the date of the enactment of this Act, or shorter periods including the option of a one-time payment, at the discretion of each bank holding company paying assessments pursuant to paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDF653FF6BD864F6D83646CB0843C1F85"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Assessments to be made in addition to any other assessments</header><text>The assessments collected pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be in addition to, and not as a replacement of, any assessments required under any other law.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HC491B1FEB6474D24A202A75A372482F9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment upon determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A bank holding company assessed under this section shall no longer be subject to such assessments in the event it is identified as a global systemically important bank holding company pursuant to section 217.402 of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations, or subjected to a determination under subsection (l) of section 165 of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act. Any prior payments made by such a banking holding company pursuant to an assessment under this section shall be nonrefundable.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H6B0B261E126A4B3EA19B06D73F8FB0DE"><enum>6.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments made by this Act shall take effect after the end of the 18-month period following the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
	<attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20171219">Passed the House of Representatives December 19, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill>


