<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HDF3EF024A96E437EAEEF70637FBCF4A8" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 787 IH: Streamlined and Improved Methods at Polling Locations and Early (SIMPLE) Voting Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 787</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170201">February 1, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to promote early voting in elections for Federal office
			 and to prevent unreasonable waiting times for voters at polling places
			 used in such elections, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H1FAD18E3600A4F77B5FC05CDB4DCD294" style="OLC">
 <section id="H14120287A47848B5A3A1EFBABD3A9EFD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Streamlined and Improved Methods at Polling Locations and Early (SIMPLE) Voting Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HD2FA1783BF134CA18DB623A8DFE11ECD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Minimum requirements for early voting and for reducing waiting times for voters in federal elections</header> <subsection id="H25A320BB37F04DE9A9C72516555F47F4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirements for States</header> <paragraph id="HBE5A023054E74AA5B15A1AA342C7EF33"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subtitle A of title III of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21081">52 U.S.C. 21081</external-xref> et seq.) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H70D2BA96162D472A814F78C1FC3A4E39"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating sections 304 and 305 as sections 306 and 307; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7CA300EEA9F7498B8437AB40B0C43DA2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after section 303 the following new sections:</text>
						<quoted-block id="H161CF24C2BCB4EDB8D3D5A9A2BEDE759">
							<section id="HDA161D92B1C941D4A4AF8E51E123D1A5"><enum>304.</enum><header>Early voting</header>
 <subsection id="HB1540AF79AB54C6BBDC20D65FFE7F374"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each State shall allow individuals to vote in an election for Federal office on each day occurring during the 15-day period which ends on the second day immediately preceding the date of the election, in the same manner as voting is allowed on such date.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE4681F49C5FB4DABA218E893559A68B3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Minimum early voting requirements</header><text>Each polling place which allows voting prior to the date of a Federal election pursuant to subsection (a) shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6FAAD06865E04AB188B13237C31B2FEE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>allow such voting for not less than 10 hours on each day; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H950B52B82F1947AABE32ADA5477EF4BD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>have uniform hours each day for which such voting occurs.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC2AC8E1ED871446FA491C3BDBA27BFC2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Location of polling places near public transportation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the greatest extent practicable, a State shall ensure that each polling place which allows voting prior to the date of a Federal election pursuant to subsection (a) is located within reasonable walking distance of a stop on a public transportation route.</text>
								</subsection><subsection id="H93F07D54BDFD42B3AAD1120C78CCA050"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Standards</header>
 <paragraph id="HA7C7E8EE8C354B65A841B63E171375BE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall issue standards for the administration of voting prior to the date scheduled for a Federal election. Such standards shall include the nondiscriminatory geographic placement of polling places at which such voting occurs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBA1EFBC9F14A49079AF11CDCA32C0043"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deviation</header><text>The standards described in paragraph (1) shall permit States, upon providing adequate public notice, to deviate from any requirement in the case of unforeseen circumstances such as a natural disaster, terrorist attack, or a change in voter turnout.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFF2856585D34497F855A6E0FB4137952"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall apply with respect to elections held on or after January 1, 2018.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H36A67C52A01A44EAA1076E93B0732D45"><enum>305.</enum><header>Preventing unreasonable waiting times for voters</header> <subsection id="H8090B3F8C6B34577BFDE4EE411ACDD6E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Preventing unreasonable waiting times</header> <paragraph id="H353BA3B3D7C04C4AA7768E6171E2110A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each State shall provide a sufficient number of voting systems, poll workers, and other election resources (including physical resources) at a polling place used in any election for Federal office, including a polling place at which individuals may cast ballots prior to the date of the election, to ensure—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD18DD3E0AAD64B2986CC7DF6D3B16E66"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a fair and equitable waiting time for all voters in the State; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H324B4DBEFC5F43D8B580DD6DD11BAF7A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that no individual will be required to wait longer than one hour to cast a ballot at the polling place.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D386EBBFAD344FCB69CE581C53F9F91"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>In determining the number of voting systems, poll workers, and other election resources provided at a polling place for purposes of paragraph (1), the State shall take into account the following factors:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H693101D460A0413FB807AB4E25F998D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The voting age population.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD7A4A090BEA4B0983BDE12DBB83DF59"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Voter turnout in past elections.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF80CCCAF17E444EC9FE8B224512B2C69"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The number of voters registered.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50B7B3EC3C0D457CB7E2F30242DA5011"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The number of voters who have registered since the most recent Federal election.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB7A4E319A154FA1A900C7D594041449"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Census data for the population served by the polling place, such as the proportion of the voting age population who are under 25 years of age or who are naturalized citizens.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0CA38E6225A456CA62D9B0DFB4FA025"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The needs and numbers of voters with disabilities and voters with limited English proficiency.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2306434EA3DC4F9D84C1A563ECB7536B"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The type of voting systems used.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8CD8D7E108574D65A1BD5761EBAF3293"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The length and complexity of initiatives, referenda, and other questions on the ballot.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6CED04230D74BF086CEC12C9475DD94"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Such other factors, including relevant demographic factors relating to the population served by the polling place, as the State considers appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H27271C0BF52042508580074130572773"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Guidelines</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Commission shall establish and publish guidelines to assist States in meeting the requirements of this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7CE3F36B2AA143EF8A4C51B4D1745BFA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to authorize a State to meet the requirements of this subsection by closing any polling place, prohibiting an individual from entering a line at a polling place, or refusing to permit an individual who has arrived at a polling place prior to closing time from voting at the polling place.</text>
									</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1242BF7AE90241E9A96A62C22D1B7657"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Development and implementation of contingency plans</header>
 <paragraph id="H13B6FAD561414E53915C24CB475FC7F5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each State shall develop, and implement to the greatest extent practicable, a contingency plan under which the State shall provide additional poll workers, machines, ballots, and other equipment and supplies (as the case may be) on the date of the election to any polling place used in an election for Federal office, including a polling place at which individuals may cast ballots prior to the date of the election, at which waiting times exceed one hour.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H38F58A9AD856441BB8A7D34F67916733"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Approval of plan by Commission</header><text>The State shall ensure that the contingency plan developed under paragraph (1) is approved by the Commission prior to the date of the election involved, in accordance with such procedures as the Commission may establish.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC2CBF30F30CA49C48E6F4E94406FC0F7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall apply with respect to elections held on or after January 1, 2018.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE0792B8F4619408CABAA38B8C74E9BF4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents of such Act is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H824B78737AE04CF59B57C6397090857E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating the items relating to sections 304 and 305 as relating to sections 306 and 307; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H544A0C4501A146EF8F5A6E0B786ADE87"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after the item relating to section 303 the following new items:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD996C88A84D845A78B6E8BE03CB21A4B" style="OLC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 304. Early voting. </toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 305. Preventing unreasonable waiting times for voters.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H614675533DD1442FAEEBE4DE5E532AFE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report by election assistance commission</header><text>Not later than June 30 of each odd-numbered year, the Election Assistance Commission shall submit to Congress a report assessing the impact of sections 304 and 305 of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (as added by subsection (a)) on the administration of elections for Federal office during the preceding 2-year period, and shall include in the report such recommendations as the Commission considers appropriate.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H336ED957AA894719A577126705AF8436"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No effect on authority of state To provide for longer periods of early voting or greater amount of
 resources at polling places</header><text>Nothing in this section or in any amendment made by this section may be construed to prohibit a State, with respect to any election for Federal office—</text>
 <paragraph id="HAAE2CFE8688A4BAF8EA5C3CF4A01E695"><enum>(1)</enum><text>from providing (in an equitable and nondiscriminatory manner) a longer period for early voting than the minimum period required under section 304 of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (as added by subsection (a)); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB9C88BAAA2ED44ECBC1B6F9696F89ECA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>from providing (in an equitable and nondiscriminatory manner) a greater number of systems, poll workers, and other election resources at any polling place than the minimum number required under section 305 of such Act (as added by subsection (a)).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2229857B224B4C8D96EB3E6AB11A319F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Requirements for counting provisional ballots; establishment of uniform and nondiscriminatory
			 standards</header>
 <subsection id="HF3585A8A82754AA19B6F9DC204D7864E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 302 of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21082">52 U.S.C. 21082</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H3C55B8567F414214962D0C12103F1AF0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (d) as subsection (f); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H78E895B05F354E57ABD6A244D78DA75D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (c) the following new subsections:</text> <quoted-block id="H5F071DEFE74F47D1AD5D6C571A912961"> <subsection id="HA69A6C67FFA84968B86BB18FE7AA25DB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Statewide counting of provisional ballots</header> <paragraph id="H876C3474730C4FDFA17F3ABCEDE8A15E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a)(4), notwithstanding the precinct or polling place at which a provisional ballot is cast within the State, the appropriate election official shall count each vote on such ballot for each election in which the individual who cast such ballot is eligible to vote.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1BB30EE6E8F04C5AA4C0A33B19CCE77F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This subsection shall apply with respect to elections held on or after January 1, 2018.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H38CF4C65FF0349CA977230106E3DC589"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Uniform and nondiscriminatory standards</header> <paragraph id="HD26C7BD1BA424B3CB6592B6351619A5D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Consistent with the requirements of this section, each State shall establish uniform and nondiscriminatory standards for the issuance, handling, and counting of provisional ballots.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H40D604ACF1264CD9B807BDFD55B2143F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This subsection shall apply with respect to elections held on or after January 1, 2018.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBF7E316575474EF1A2675F911D8AE488"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 302(f) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21082">52 U.S.C. 21082(f)</external-xref>), as redesignated by subsection (a), is amended by striking <quote>Each State</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in subsections (d)(2) and (e)(2), each State</quote>.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H0536A61796FD400681926C9496B320E5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Availability of civil penalties and private rights of action to enforce Help America Vote Act of
			 2002</header>
 <subsection id="HDFA7EDDE14FC46AFAA73C05F0037B3B3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Availability of civil penalties and private rights of action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 401 of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21111">52 U.S.C. 21111</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H034FFED6394C4CFBB291F15DCFFD502D" style="OLC"> <section id="H80710F655E3943B38F0377163621F9A3"><enum>401.</enum><header>Enforcement</header> <subsection id="HC3D78BEB0B424C0081B0789074D42CCB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Action by Attorney General</header> <paragraph id="H620FF701865044FAA12221A33D2B1178"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General may bring a civil action against any State or jurisdiction in an appropriate United States District Court for such declaratory and injunctive relief (including a temporary restraining order, a permanent or temporary injunction, or other order) as may be necessary to carry out the requirements of subtitle A of title III.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H174BC59CB5D84BC7A862B12B8A61078D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assessment of civil money penalty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In a civil action brought under paragraph (1), if the court finds that the State or jurisdiction violated any provision of subtitle A of title III, it may, to vindicate the public interest, assess a civil penalty against the State or jurisdiction—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4993603F2AEA4A3BBC747571E36A693E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in an amount not to exceed $110,000 for each such violation, in the case of a first violation; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H241FAB8F83364413A5311D75A80185D8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in an amount not to exceed $220,000 for each such violation, for any subsequent violation.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0DBBEB71000E47F08685D8AFA9DB8AEB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Intervention</header><text>Upon timely application, a person aggrieved by a violation of subtitle A of title III with respect to which a civil action is commenced under paragraph (1) may intervene in such action, and may obtain such appropriate relief as the person could obtain in a civil action under subsection (b) with respect to that violation, along with costs and a reasonable attorney fee.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC423A6A86C1E4E57A71F33690154D9AB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than December 31 of each year, the Attorney General shall submit to Congress an annual report on any civil action brought under paragraph (1) during the preceding year.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7A88A8E499544B74A12A92ACD52991D4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Private right of action</header>
 <paragraph id="H3A585690367B4C5EB529136B61F0AD24"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>A person who is aggrieved by a State's or jurisdiction’s violation of subtitle A of title III may bring a civil action in an appropriate United States District Court for such declaratory or injunctive relief as may be necessary to carry out the requirements of such subtitle.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4037FA1492E6416AB85FB5F9FEE9883A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Costs and attorney fees</header><text>The court may award to a person aggrieved by a violation of subtitle A of title III who prevails in an action brought under paragraph (1) the costs of the action, including a reasonable attorney fee.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H46E1376733074E23B8F9D1A733C1236A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents of such Act is amended by amending the item relating to section 401 to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBB8E7F67E62B4E238E1C9233C9C8DC2D" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 401. Enforcement.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA568885EEDA64FFFB5E317EC17C4D90D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to violations alleged to have occurred on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


