<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H9C1A2B59C62C4C12B414EE1DEC06B41B" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3544 IH: Aircraft Ownership Transparency Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3544</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170728">July 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the disclosure of beneficial ownership by a foreign person of aircraft registration, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H35293DEA596A4635A24CF03DCCB71BD5" style="OLC">
 <section id="HCD9D2AD2A7B04A6880A3560FA1A24C18" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Aircraft Ownership Transparency Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H7C24E756AF46489D91F30B53091719F2" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Certification of aircraft registration</header> <subsection id="H956EE6EBC0E34D6C89AB6286DBB498FC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before approving a certificate of registration issued under section 44103 of title 49, United States Code, with a covered entity, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall require the covered entity to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H580C840B2E374F1CA294AA414C4AAE3F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify each beneficial owner of the covered entity by—</text> <subparagraph id="H99249052432240A1A9B40A16DB2EEFDE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>name;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5286C934B2C4C2A9B43502A8DA0A20F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">current residential or business street address;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB029CFBC4C4B45B38BF238FA6F8BA1E3"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a unique identifying number from a nonexpired passport issued by the United States or a nonexpired drivers license issued by a State or if neither is available, a legible and credible copy of the pages of a nonexpired passport issued by the government of a foreign country bearing a photograph, date of birth, and unique identifying information for the person;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H342D148039D84E70BD979F0F7C61F90E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>nationality; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H72805634CA5F43FCA8ECBFBD5299A4A8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the make, model, and serial number of the aircraft to be registered;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H01F78E3A1AFA485FBE744456E6B17F04"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of a covered entity that is owned or controlled by more than one entity, identify how each entity relates to every other entity, including the extent to which each entity holds an ownership interest in or exercises control over another entity, and the relationship of each such entity with the beneficial owners who are natural persons; and in addition to each beneficial owner, identify each trust grantor, trustee, trust protector, and beneficiary owner of the covered entity that is a foreign person;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3B9B68610E1143188B53716C78F2D3E1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in the case of a trust or association, identify the chain of control that includes the owner, trustee, and beneficiary; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB454A99A13D74785AC57F5189C58B4E0"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disclose to the Administrator any beneficial owner of the covered entity that is a foreign person.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H43B7CC526AD342D2B4173224A0E63AEF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Timing</header> <paragraph id="H4CA2AC35A8F349688A946B05B4DAC520"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall require a covered entity to provide the information described in subsections (a)(1) and (a)(2) when submitting an application for aircraft certification.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEC5DFAA2643B4B75970459B7ACB40EED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Updates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall require a covered entity to update a submission of the information described in subsections (a)(1) and (a)(2) not later than 60 days after the date of any change in—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H354BE9DF298F42D6A6A912BDAE496D9F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the list of beneficial owners of the covered entity; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BA236B2A30D46568AE4E2313A9E9AAF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the information required to be provided relating to each such beneficial owner.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6266DCC04F5444DAAA81A5E8591DA6FA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the following definitions apply:</text> <paragraph id="H4D9AB69D75C5484DA60FD3AF4DB9AEF8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Beneficial owner</header> <subparagraph id="HEC929492F60E43B58496AB9B6CE5A108"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term <term>beneficial owner</term> means, with respect to a covered entity, each natural person who, directly or indirectly—</text>
 <clause id="H9E02CFA49C514FDD80854697E9640E2F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">exercises control over the covered entity through ownership interests, voting rights, agreements, or otherwise; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD97DBA3CB218470CA9F6043D8B9FA687"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has an interest in or receives substantial economic benefits from the assets of the covered entity.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C933B7F5CA24740B4416D9E5A7925AE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>beneficial owner</term> does not include, with respect to a covered entity—</text>
 <clause id="H50F5CA9A50D54CE1B74D7B357CDF8532"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a minor child;</text> </clause><clause id="H206CB9D31CF04DAC906B38047C24BC4F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a person acting as a trustee, nominee, intermediary, custodian, or agent on behalf of another person;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFEA5FF28968D47C2806EFA8E42EEC96A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a person acting solely as an employee of the covered entity and whose control over or economic benefits from the covered entity derives solely from the employment status of the person;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFE97F0690CBF4C59BA11822F096EF99E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a person whose only interest in the covered entity is through a right of inheritance, unless the person also meets the requirements of subparagraph (A); or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9445D6DA78314D6DA0D7F7BA8B6C61E1"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a creditor of the covered entity, unless the creditor also meets the requirements of subparagraph (A).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H047FABC564034D6C8204FFD4926B4E75"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Anti-abuse rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The exceptions under subparagraph (B) shall not apply if used for the purpose of evading, circumventing, or abusing the requirements of this section.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCCE0F8949D134871AAFB34CB1261E00A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered entity</term> means a person, trust, association, copartnership, corporation, or other public or private entity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7E77916D9FEB4F04B3F751EDE61668C3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>foreign person</term> means an individual who is not a United States person or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence into the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H725A654429874ECABA89C6473787D569"><enum>(4)</enum><header>United States person</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>United States person</term> means a natural person who is a citizen of the United States or who owes permanent allegiance to the United States.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


