<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H0C3F9FD9BB3544EF8C2CADE74EEB38A0" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2454 IH: Department of Homeland Security Data Framework Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2454</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170516">May 16, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001073">Mr. Hurd</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish a data framework to provide access for
			 appropriate personnel to law enforcement and other information of the
			 Department, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H543E36B662E442BC86F1783F5CD00D76" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE55B241D31E049E181358446F8786D8E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Department of Homeland Security Data Framework Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H1D146A7B4BD44D84AAF02CDA9E65EAA0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text>
 <paragraph id="HA29F3ACA331E4C729CEB111D863F0206"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Department of Homeland Security was established pursuant to the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/296">Public Law 107–296</external-xref>) and has the statutory mission to prevent terrorist attacks and reduce the vulnerability of the United States to terrorism, among other critical functions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H09104E3F40434BFB8451CE9052C2E829"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Department is comprised of more than 22 component agencies and offices with different legal mandates and restrictions regarding collecting, storing, and sharing information.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0C24B83B71CF4D18BA0E8A2216EFFBB8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In November 2013, the Department issued a privacy impact assessment for the Department of Homeland Security Data Framework, which is intended to be a scalable information technology program to connect numerous databases located in different Department component agencies.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H033F1C1BA8A84EE8B2180DAC914D4332"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The privacy impact assessment referred to in paragraph (3) stated that such Framework “will enable the implementation of efficient and cost-effective search and analysis across DHS databases in both classified and unclassified domains.”.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF9CF27EFC3324EF9B386043398D8C36D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Given the size and purpose of such Framework, it is essential that the Department appropriately manages the timeline, budget, privacy, and security requirements for the system, as well as ensures the Department has the specialized and trained personnel to fully utilize the Framework.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HBF54220ED1E44E64BABFD8786D4BDBF4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Department of Homeland Security data framework</header>
 <subsection id="HF41D2A0D150E4552A80F1268A0894061"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall develop a data framework to integrate existing Department of Homeland Security datasets and systems, as appropriate, for access by authorized personnel in a manner consistent with relevant legal authorities and privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties policies and protections. In developing such framework, the Secretary shall ensure, in accordance with all applicable statutory and regulatory requirements, the following information is included:</text>
 <paragraph id="H094F952AC98C42A3B8DF6912E54A0610"><enum>(1)</enum><text>All information acquired, held, or obtained by an office or component of the Department that falls within the scope of the information sharing environment, including homeland security information, terrorism information, weapons of mass destruction information, and national intelligence.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H58A9103A36A5467894F300F326DE4052"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any information or intelligence relevant to priority mission needs and capability requirements of the homeland security enterprise, as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFC16B13D30674537949D31CA5331CB15"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Data framework access</header>
 <paragraph id="HC8BF02522BFA437F848E9EAA850ABD6C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure that the data framework required under this section is accessible to employees of the Department of Homeland Security who the Secretary determines—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0BBAB7CA4DDB4FA3A48D5315EF4950E3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have an appropriate security clearance;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10EA54DE63AF47A199323AC71D4BC547"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are assigned to perform a function that requires access to information in such framework; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFEA254AD0F81411FA2E11E81F4B82C47"><enum>(C)</enum><text>are trained in applicable standards for safeguarding and using such information.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6ABB2236234468D8A4AF8819E4D4574"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H05F02E2187214D70AC44961C4831360A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>issue guidance for Department of Homeland Security employees authorized to access and contribute to the data framework pursuant to paragraph (1); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69FE3C452EDC43CDB9BA4F0BD704F82F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that such guidance enforces a duty to share between offices and components of the Department when accessing or contributing to such framework for mission needs.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE5B7BC01DA854498AB68F3FF82E818A3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Efficiency</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall instruct components of the Department of Homeland Security to make available information through the data framework under this section in a machine-readable format, to the greatest extent practicable.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H497CDBA41EDD42D0B865353C9A4CA63F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exclusion of information</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security may exclude from the data framework information that the Secretary determines access to or the confirmation of the existence of could—</text>
 <paragraph id="HECDF18642CA14E0ABFE2D2149ED85117"><enum>(1)</enum><text>jeopardize the protection of sources, methods, or activities;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF7CE3D1955FE4CAF9A63AB28A6EA3B42"><enum>(2)</enum><text>compromise a criminal or national security investigation;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1B7B47C825CC47E9AFD2052B39F6E418"><enum>(3)</enum><text>be inconsistent with the other Federal laws or regulations; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1AB0EFF454A442D580CBDB0772B37F9E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>be duplicative or not serve an operational purpose if included in such framework.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4CA0EC6854214E5FA1355B83875C0E2A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Safeguards</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall incorporate into the date framework systems capabilities for auditing and ensuring the security of information included in such framework. Such capabilities shall include the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HE80C4DF53EF4478BB59C5FC1395A7745"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Mechanisms for identifying insider threats.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFFAA6F85C44D458B8A5EFFC6F87BDAA8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Mechanisms for identifying security risks.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H37935E88350D4377B837E73C41D9D8E0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Safeguards for privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H07C799127D604EACB80A643AB047478F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Deadline for implementation</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure the completion of the data framework required under this section and that such framework includes all appropriate information in existence within the Department of Homeland Security.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HC54D185AAD9841AA800BA168F41A08C3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Notice to Congress</header>
 <paragraph id="HC37BE83653D241118596AAEC67B5B1CD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Operational notification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date on which the data framework required under this section is fully operational, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide notice to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate of such.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9154BB5EEB494BE9A6305E1F1B5795A5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regular status</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate regular updates on the status of the data framework required under this section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDDD5E34F3C984BFF945074E7039134A1"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HAC4BBD3F102C45FDA1826C025B5C7897"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Finished analysis</header><text>The term <quote>finished analysis</quote> means any document, briefing, report, or presentation for which an analyst has evaluated, interpreted, integrated, or placed into context information that falls within the scope of the information sharing environment, including homeland security information, terrorism information, weapons of mass destruction information, and national intelligence.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H78EFAC932E6741ECA445FA55CEE73832"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Intelligence component of the Department</header><text>The term <quote>intelligence component of the Department</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 2(11) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/101">6 U.S.C. 101(11)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H99A8E0D9818140B0BB180FCC6605ED6C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>National intelligence</header><text>The term <quote>national intelligence</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 3(5) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003(5)</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


