<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H675DF7AEE13D4C12AF94025A1E584FDB" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3847 IH: Yurok Lands Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3847</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170927">September 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001053">Mr. Cole</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To revise the Yurok Reservation, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HA8FD92DA53A54084A7E3AE19CDA8BE50" style="OLC">
 <section id="H28E2B502AF7C4985ACFA54414EACF515" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Yurok Lands Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H46059A7320364FABBD40C2E1BEFD9154"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the purposes of this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="H1B4A1DF5B66A4A65A93995642E64CC78"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal agency</header><text>The term <term>Federal agency</term> has the same meaning given that term in section 1508.12 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, except that such term shall not include States, units of general local government, and Indian Tribes.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1D74FF72038841C082DFB02828F24131"><enum>(2)</enum><header>NEPA</header><text>The term <term>NEPA</term> means the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5F30275203C74A8D9FF4171B3FBF97F9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Revised Yurok Reservation</header><text>The term <term>revised Yurok Reservation</term> means the land within the Yurok Reservation exterior boundary as revised in section 5(a), except land owned in fee by or held in trust by the United States for the benefit of a federally recognized Indian Tribe other than the Yurok Tribe.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H739348F3AA81475B9BE4E4DA98CC524D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Agriculture, or the Secretary of Transportation, as appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD15CE88B8678402D9911C602E9A08269"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Tribe</term> means the Yurok Tribe, a federally recognized Indian Tribe.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="HEAFD540E0D7C49338C8E51EBE4199C68"><enum>3.</enum><header>Tribal-Federal partnerships for Federal land and resource management</header> <subsection id="H0480D27A022A486AB9E85D66F9971DB8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of any process triggered by a requirement under NEPA regarding a major Federal action on Federal land within the revised Yurok Reservation, at the Tribe’s option, the Tribe shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H121701CE56344994A0CC26962AD9199D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">act as a joint lead agency in accordance with a Memorandum of Understanding entered into between the lead Federal agency and the Tribe not later than 30 days after the date of notice of initiation of the process; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3B6E2F014D654881B8DE0EFD9CD211EB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>act as a participating or cooperating agency if a Memorandum of Understanding is not executed within the 30-day period (or an additional time period agreed to by the Tribe and the Federal lead agency) or is terminated.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0B3523B06F3343CBB6B5EA03AA766881"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements for Memorandum of Understanding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Memorandum of Understanding entered into under this section shall—</text> <paragraph id="H667A5E2BEE754E0AB4F090FF3625250C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be negotiated in good faith;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8A567F8B4344423A9399BA7CC4BE0EC6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>comply with NEPA regulations; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB36858A6E4BE44DF9238364FBF44D82E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4DAC0F0B06964FC4AF3DDAD93B072C45"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the respective roles and responsibilities of the Tribe and the lead Federal agency in the NEPA process;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A902CEC1D0D4271883A00AF41B86915"><enum>(B)</enum><text>mechanisms for dispute resolution; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7F7AF1A4BB9048BAA3B7E2A38532F335"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a requirement that environmental impact statements shall discuss any inconsistency of a proposed action with any plan or environmental requirement of the Tribe (whether or not federally sanctioned), and, where such an inconsistency exists, a requirement that the environmental impact statement shall describe—</text>
 <clause id="HA6DA796CE63B4812BACC3EBB9CCB9A7A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the extent to which the lead Federal agency would reconcile its proposed action with the plan or environmental requirement; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB37E3C6B22D14058B286E2C429358295"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>what mitigation measures are being imposed to lessen adverse environmental impacts of the proposal identified by the Tribe.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6C43D960048E45A3A36C792593FD604C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Cooperating agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purpose of any process triggered by a requirement under NEPA regarding a major Federal action on Federal land that may affect the revised Yurok Reservation, at the option of the Tribe, the Tribe shall act as a cooperating agency.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H71680F6A1A73433C969B1D4BC2327D13"><enum>(d)</enum><header>No limitation on existing authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall limit ability of the Tribe or any other federally recognized Indian Tribe to participate in any process triggered by a requirement under NEPA as a joint lead or a cooperating agency.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HDAEA305698BA4E86B01FC57931B69EF7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Cooperative agreements with the Tribe</header>
 <paragraph id="H523F8DEC678E4CCCA42CEFB42F00C605"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Redwood National Park</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall enter into a cooperative agreement with the Tribe for system unit natural resource protection for the purpose of protecting natural resources of Redwood National Park pursuant to section 101702 of title 54, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0DA3FE47D14B47029B061F4B45A18AC0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Forest service</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture shall enter into a cooperative agreement with the Tribe that includes, at a minimum, provisions that implement section 4.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H81C4177BACA74A6D8972D33E025E5A28"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Tribe as an agency</header><text>The Tribe shall be considered a State or local government agency for purposes of section 101703 of title 54, United States Code, and the Secretary shall enter into a cooperative management agreement with the Tribe pursuant to that section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB806215FF3344AD4B858145E9A4FB9AA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Confirmation and authorization of cooperative agreement related to the Klamath River Basin</header><text>The 2006 <quote>Cooperative Agreement between the Department of the Interior and the Yurok Tribe for the Cooperative Management of Tribal and Federal Lands and Resources in the Klamath River Basin of California</quote> is confirmed and the Secretary is authorized to take such actions as are necessary to effectuate the agreement.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H997B95A134DA4D98AAC70B12A380B890"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Self-Governance agreements</header><text>Federal agencies, as appropriate, shall negotiate, in good faith, self-governance agreements under this Act pursuant to the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5301">25 U.S.C. 5301</external-xref> et seq.). Program functions, services, and activities, or portions thereof, carried out by the National Park Service on Federal land within the revised Yurok Reservation shall be included in a contract or compact to the extent allowed under title I or title IV of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H5640E32ED45E43BF9B7F723B0D149401"><enum>4.</enum><header>Land to be held in trust for the Tribe</header>
 <subsection id="HD2681B5965764CE9B6B3405D7ECB4C5D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to any valid existing rights, the Secretary of Agriculture shall transfer to the Secretary of the Interior administrative jurisdiction over approximately 1,229 acres in the Yurok Experimental Forest administered by the Forest Service, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Experimental Forest</quote> and dated October 4, 2016. The map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Forest Service.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB56B5098BC83489C8206AC5E8925E421"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior shall hold the land transferred under subsection (a) in trust for the benefit of the Tribe.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE0EF00BF02C748EF9F991B356E32CAB4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Tribal Land Use Management Plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Tribe shall develop a Tribal Land Use Management Plan in accordance with NEPA requirements for the land held in trust pursuant to subsection (b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3E8E09FB6DE34FD888A23CFC85E1EC55"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Government-to-Government agreements</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture and the Tribe—</text>
 <paragraph id="HBF10C0D1BA0044458579DA5918426D47"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall enter into government-to-government consultations;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF92FA7796A1F4CEF90527990B1CCE10D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall develop protocols to ensure that research activities of the Forest Service on lands taken into trust pursuant to subsection (b) shall continue in perpetuity; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H30C45FED699647688873F88441B0FB5F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>may enter into cooperative agreements between the Secretary of Agriculture and the Tribe for the purpose of implementing this section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H673ED1D97DCD42F4A45A33EF542AFC7E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Survey</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior shall complete a survey to establish the exterior boundaries of the land taken into trust pursuant to subsection (b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB7CECC94FD53413D99F663D65498CCFD"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Use of trust land</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Land taken into trust pursuant to subsection (b) shall—</text> <paragraph id="H051A77DB77A84F6292705B67FDBA4451"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be managed by the Tribe for conservation and research purposes;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3CC07E87E27247E597A942FA47A925EB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not be eligible or used for any gaming activity carried out under the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2701">25 U.S.C. 2701</external-xref> et seq.); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEE91161A07D14D22935DC6B10EF9B7B8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>not be subject to old growth logging.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8AD5ECDC92144749AA21B37BD4012AB6"><enum>5.</enum><header>Yurok Reservation Boundary adjustment</header> <subsection id="H073A9045ADD54311B56FEDA53E2029C7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall revise the boundary of the Yurok Reservation as depicted on the map entitled <quote>Revised Yurok Reservation Boundary</quote> and dated September 20, 2017, copies of which shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Bureau of Indian Affairs.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5D857E76488448AEA2169C828CF8FC71"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Land management</header><text>Subject to the requirements of sections 3 and 4—</text> <paragraph id="H3B72851DE4A940B9B4683873DAA768A3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all National Forest System land within the revised Yurok Reservation shall continue to be administered by the Forest Service in accordance with applicable laws and regulations; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2581E6765AA04B108CB9A6EED6CB8F03"><enum>(2)</enum><text>all National Park System land within the revised Yurok Reservation shall continue to be administered by the National Park Service in accordance with applicable laws and regulations.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0A902E0348504D2A9D17E1439BFC3DD4"><enum>6.</enum><header>Yurok Scenic Byway designation</header>
 <subsection id="H0D0012D3C5204775917C18D0ABDB62A8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation of the Yurok Scenic Byway</header><text>Bald Hills Road from its junction with U.S. Highway 101 to its terminus on the Klamath River shall be designated as the <quote>Yurok Scenic Byway</quote>, an Indian Tribe scenic byway, and the Tribe shall be eligible for appropriate grants and technical assistance as authorized in section 162(b) of title 23, United States Code.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDCF2DA8C4B2C4C17B5C9CF1A5D1FFAB5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Continued access and use retained</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Tribe shall not prohibit or limit, and the Secretary of Interior shall allow, continued access and use of the Bald Hills Road in accordance with section 3(b)(1) of the Act entitled <quote>An Act to establish a Redwood National Park in the State of California, and for other purposes</quote>, approved October 2, 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/79c">16 U.S.C. 79c</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H402FBADFEC8643CDB46805A341A23F61"><enum>7.</enum><header>Confirmation of governing body and documents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The governing documents of the Tribe and the governing body established and elected thereunder, as recognized by the Secretary and in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act, are hereby ratified and confirmed and shall only have effect within the revised Yurok Reservation.</text>
 </section><section id="H99F4461441044BBAAD1368B3EB4EDE49"><enum>8.</enum><header>No delegation of Federal authority over non-Tribal land or people</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act (including the ratification and confirmation by section 7 of the governing documents of the Tribe and the governing body established and elected thereunder) shall be construed as a delegation of Federal or other authority to the Tribe, the Tribal body, or any member of the Tribe, over or related to land or interests in land that are not within the revised Yurok Reservation.</text>
 </section><section id="H701C3E4C018E4CEE86C7C93CA778526E"><enum>9.</enum><header>No additional authority or rights</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall increase, diminish, or otherwise affect the rights, privileges, or authorities of any federally recognized Indian Tribe in relation to any other federally recognized Indian Tribe.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


