<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF5CD2182155F4A8DB94148F46D718542" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4561 IH: Security Assessment Feasibility for Equipment Testing and Evaluation of Capabilities for our Homeland Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4561</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171206">December 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000628">Mr. Dunn</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for third party testing of transportation security screening technology, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H17F04B068BB945DF8B4BF92521AFCC32" style="OLC">
 <section id="H84CA374495114AA695E4F3CAE961A86F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Security Assessment Feasibility for Equipment Testing and Evaluation of Capabilities for our Homeland Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SAFE TECH Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="H251BE6E72947449796E8C54209497601"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H3309677FC0444FEBBB9C9B82041E7584"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The term <quote>Administration</quote> means the Transportation Security Administration.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H32E3E4968D1D4FF8B42BA40DE1C52905"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <quote>Administrator</quote> means the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H8C00AED045F34BBE9367BD5418E83AE9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Third party testing of security screening technology</header> <subsection id="HCFBF8206AA8C41698CC92E9ED21FC167"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator, in consultation with the Under Secretary for Science and Technology of the Department of Homeland Security, shall develop a program to enable a vendor of transportation security screening technology to obtain testing, including as an alternative to the Administration’s testing process under paragraph (9) of section 114(f) of title 49, United States Code, by an appropriate third party, as determined by the Administrator, in consultation with the Under Secretary, of such technology before procurement or development of such technology.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HF082391AF23849498A3A8A79A8DF05F5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Detection testing</header>
 <paragraph id="HA49B3F80DFB84DF5A701F6AFFF31598C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The third party testing program authorized under subsection (a) shall include detection testing to evaluate the performance of a security screening technology relating to the probability of detection, the probability of false alarm, and other indicators that such technology is able to meet the Administration’s mission needs for detection of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H09E4303657A44AA0BC69FC5BC45FBE91"><enum>(A)</enum><text>explosives; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF189D33A1F14471D8CB5BD686BC94F80"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prohibited items.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A8CB8E8E5D5480AA0C328D21CE70B0D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination with final processes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent practicable, and without compromising the integrity of the Administration’s testing process under paragraph (9) of section 114(f) of title 49, United States Code, or the Department of Homeland Security’s oversight of such testing process, or increasing costs to the Administration, the Administrator shall coordinate the third party detection testing under paragraph (1) with any associated subsequent final Government Department of Homeland Security testing.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBBAA1D017F0D40D996F6B0F381194271"><enum>(3)</enum><header>International partnerships</header><text>To the extent practicable and permissible under law, and in accordance with national security interests of the United States, the Administrator shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2C665A78DC6949708E1FC28CCE4205E6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>share with appropriate international partners detection testing information and standards; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC28ABB33BB8042018538603BB5F9877B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>coordinate with such appropriate international partners to align such testing information and standards to maximize the capability to detect explosives and other threats.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4867A23E1308481D9FE855F11DE4B69B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Alternative testing factors</header><text>Third party testing under subsection (a) may include as an alternative, at the discretion of the Administrator, the testing at the TSA Systems Integration Facility of the Administration, including testing for—</text>
 <paragraph id="H285AA2316AFB494C82D3698ADEA230BE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>health and safety factors;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7DA33B31C1984B4190A2B59A5EC1C53A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>operator interface;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H57C149DC200D4FE6BCE551152726D7AC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>human factors;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF5DB16DC293B4B2E856B7C4D6393ED15"><enum>(4)</enum><text>environmental factors;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3DF073FCB8BB4DA3861EFC48047481EB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>throughput;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC5DD6C7D245240E4B32D107A7115375F"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reliability, maintainability, and availability factors; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB619144F7BFB4BF3B0D5147D775BE146"><enum>(7)</enum><text>interoperability.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA70D50A7694A4F1183CAF66EC67AE3F6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Testing framework</header> <paragraph id="HACC0EB2C981C42EC8BFD9BF12E0C0EA6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator, in consultation with the Under Secretary for Science and Technology of the Department of Homeland Security, shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEB53B9A790764D09A4959EB47D29D64E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish a framework for the third party testing under this section to determine if the security screening technology that is the subject of such testing satisfies the Administration’s requirements before such technology may enter or re-enter, as applicable, operational testing at an airport or other transportation facility; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H737841A1F35C484B80A8FBE83207FFA6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>use phased implementation to allow the Administration and the third party concerned to establish best practices.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB84FEC37D1A04681B76D977FD136AB80"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Prioritization of third party testing</header><text>The Administrator may prioritize, when appropriate, the field testing of security screening technology and equipment by third parties.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H5E6E881955AF4D4C87960ECDB7A2D252"><enum>4.</enum><header>Reciprocal recognition of security standards</header>
 <subsection id="H66159AB4B64E426BB68FFEC01423F84F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator, in coordination with the European Civil Aviation Conference, shall continue development of a validation process for the reciprocal recognition of security validation processes for recognition of security screening technologies or certification authorities for deployment.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H97ADF857C3ED4CC98F64F3A689742CEE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>The validation process under subsection (a) shall ensure that the certification process of each participating international security partner or recognized certification authority complies with Administration standards.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


