<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HFCD54203408641258F6F994AD94FACEC" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4619 IH: To amend the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to provide temporary relief from the annual fee imposed on health insurance providers, to the extent that such fee is due to Puerto Rican health insurance.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4619</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171212">December 12, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001107">Mr. Curbelo of Florida</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001202">Mrs. Murphy of Florida</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000582">Miss González-Colón of Puerto Rico</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to provide temporary relief from the annual
			 fee imposed on health insurance providers, to the extent that such fee is
			 due to Puerto Rican health insurance.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H6AF7FA7B40154565827E26E6DF31FE60" style="OLC">
		<section id="HA9EC484224974909AE1C23DDE19500EC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Temporary relief from annual fee on health insurance providers in Puerto Rico</header>
 <subsection id="H0B7FB3E6289F47DBAF936142CE8D87B8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 9010 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H71EC1F496ABE4B578235A7542FFC7BF3" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H44372D77A49B492692C14F448961C48A"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Temporary relief for Puerto Rico</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For calendar years 2018 and 2019, the fee described in subsection (a)(1) for a covered entity shall be reduced by the portion of such fee that such entity demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Secretary of the Treasury is the portion attributable to net premiums written for health insurance regulated by the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</text>
					</subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H40135FFCE5DB4F6687D6D268CE1F736D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) of section 9010(b) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act is amended by striking <quote>the fee under this section</quote> and inserting <quote>the amount determined under this subsection</quote>.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


